import{_ as k,o as i,c as o,a as n,m as l,t as h,C as b,M as y,U as w,F as c,p,e as f,f as j,q as v}from"./chunks/framework.B1z0IdBH.js";const q={name:"PoemCard",props:{poem:{type:Object,required:!0}}},z={class:"poem-container"},A={class:"review"},N={class:"review-title"},S={class:"review-content"};function T(e,a,s,m,t,u){return i(),o("div",z,[n("div",A,[n("div",N,[a[0]||(a[0]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"question:",-1)),l(h(s.poem.question),1)]),a[2]||(a[2]=n("div",{class:"divider"},null,-1)),n("p",S,[a[1]||(a[1]=n("span",{class:"icon"},"answer:",-1)),l(h(s.poem.answer),1)])])])}const x=k(q,[["render",T],["__scopeId","data-v-ac5b588e"]]),M=JSON.parse(`[{"question":"Các nhân viên cứu hộ đã tìm kiếm suốt đêm nhằm đưa các thi thể và những người sống sót ra khỏi đống đổ nát tại Bắc Vũ Độ thuộc huyện Vũ Dương.Giới chức cho biết, trong số những người bị thương, có chín người trong tình trạng nguy hiểm và hiện đang được điều trị tại bệnh viện ở thị trấn Tháp Hà gần đó.Việc cải tạo tòa nhà đang được thực hiện đối với phần móng vào thời điểm xảy ra vụ tai nạn, theo lời các quan chức.Chính quyền địa phương tại huyện Vũ Dương nay đã cho dừng việc tìm kiếm nạn nhân.Công tác điều tra hiện đang diễn ra nhằm xác định lý do dẫn tới vụ tai nạn chiều hôm thứ Sáu.Vụ tai nạn khiến xã hội tiếp tục quan ngại về tình trạng an toàn xây dựng ở Trung Quốc.Hồi tháng Năm, một nhà dưỡng lão tại tỉnh Hà Nam bị hỏa hoạn khiến 38 người thiệt mạng, và nguyên do được cho là bởi chất lượng xây dựng kém, dùng toàn vật liệu dễ bắt cháy.Một trong những người sống sót khỏi vụ sập nhà hôm thứ Sáu nói với hãng truyền hình nhà nước CCTV rằ... Continue the article for another 4000 characters max:","answer":"ng các công nhân là những người đến từ thành phố Nam Dương ở tây nam tỉnh Hà Nam. Một số bạn thợ của người này trước đó từng là nông dân và hầu như không được hướng dẫn hoặc huấn luyện về các kỹ năng an toàn lao động cũng như các kỹ thuậ xây dựng chuyên môn.Họ khi đó đang dùng giá nâng để nâng một phần góc tầng một lên, nhưng bộ giá nâng đột nhiên khiến cho cả tòa nhà đổ sụp, ông nói.Các quan chức nói tòa nhà đã được xây dựng trong thập niên 1990."},{"question":"Is nidaamis?","answer":"~~ISNADAAMIS~~    (Scabies)Wa maxay isnadaamis??Wa cayayaan kudhasha maqarka jirka kuna tarma kadibna dhigta ugu mihiisa Cudurkan wuxu sifudud kugu dhici karaa hadad taabato qof qaba ama aad jiifsato sariir qof qaba ama aad xirato dharkiisaba Wa muhiim isnadaamis ka laguma kala qaado galmada MAXA SABABA??waxa sababa cayayan lagu magacaabo sarcoptes scabiei YUU KUDHICI KARAA??Qof kasta ayu kudhici kara maxa yeelay qof qabaa aad taabto wa sababta ugu weyn ee kuqadi karto YAA UNUGULDadka unugul inu kudhaco waxa kamidaCaruurta Dadka lajiifiyo isbitaalada Kalkaaliyaasha Dadka difaca jirkodo hoseyo sida dadka qaba  HIV AIDS  kansarka Dadka loogaliyay xubin CALAAMADAHA QOFKA QABA??Cuncun badan kaso sidaran habeenki Nabro gaduudan Intabadan faraha barida xubnaha taranka ayu cuncunku kudaranyahy SIDEE LOO DAWEYA?Dawoyinka ugu fican ee lasiiyo qofka qaba isnadaamis ka Permethrin cream Benzyl benzoate lotion Sulfur ointment Sidokle qofka waxa logu daraa dawada Benadryl taso qofka kabi ineeysa cuncunka badan Sidookale antibiotics wainu qaata sian infection kle u imaan."},{"question":"Hãy tiếp tục đoạn văn sau: Tối 31/7, tại tại Quảng trường Hoà Bình, thành phố Hoà Bình, tỉnh Hòa Bình tổ chức Chương trình nghệ thuật \\"Hoà Bình-Thanh âm xứ Mường\\", Carnival năm 2022 và Lễ đón Bằng công nhận 2 Di sản văn hóa phi vật thể quốc gia: Tri thức dân gian Lịch tre và Lễ hội truyền thống Khai Hạ của dân tộc Mường tỉnh Hòa Bình. Dự chương trình có Phó Chủ tịch nước Võ Thị Ánh Xuân cùng lãnh đạo các ban, bộ, ngành Trung ương. Phát biểu khai mạc, ông Bùi Văn Khánh, Chủ tịch UBND tỉnh Hòa Bình cho biết, địa phương là cửa ngõ vùng Tây Bắc của Tổ quốc, có vị trí chiến lược quan trọng, được mệnh danh là \\"miền đất sử thi\\", nơi lưu giữ nhiều giá trị văn hóa đặc sắc của đồng bào các dân tộc, với gần 800 di sản văn hóa phi vật thể và trên 18 nghìn hiện vật có giá trị. Trong đó, tiêu biểu nhất là dân tộc Mường với các di sản văn hóa nổi tiếng như Mo Mường, Sử thi Đẻ đất đẻ nước... Với lịch sử sinh sống lâu đời ở Hòa Bình, người Mường đã sáng tạo ra nhiều di sản văn hóa vật thể và phi vật thể đặc sắc, góp phần làm giàu thêm kho tàng văn hóa Việt Nam. \\"Chương trình nghệ thuật hòa bình âm thanh Mường và Carnival năm 2012 được tổ chức lần đầu tiên tại tỉnh Hòa Bình. Đây là sự kiện văn hóa được dàn dựng và tổ chức công phu hoành tráng có sự kết hợp hài hòa giữa yếu tố văn hóa truyền thống và hiện đại, góp phần giới thiệu quảng bá những hình ảnh về đất nước con người cũng như tiềm năng thế mạnh của tỉnh tới đông đảo người dân bạn bè quốc tế và du khách gần xa\\" – ông Bùi Văn Khánh nhấn mạnh. Tại buổi lễ, Thứ trưởng Bộ Văn hoá - Thể thao và Du lịch Hoàng Đạo Cương trao bằng công nhận Di sản văn hoá phi vật thể cấp quốc gia cho Di sản văn hoá Lễ hội truyền thống Khai hạ và tri thức dân gian Lịch tre (Lịch Đoi/Roi) của người Mường cho tỉnh Hoà Bình Phát biểu tại buổi lễ, Phó Chủ tịch nước Võ Thị Ánh Xuân nêu rõ, văn hóa có vai trò vô cùng quan trọng đối với mỗi quốc gia, dân tộc. Trong bối cảnh hiện nay, việc bảo tồn, tôn tạo và phát huy các giá trị văn hóa vật thể và phi vật thể của các vùng miền, các dân tộc là nhiệm vụ rất quan trọng. Phó Chủ tịch nước cho rằng, với lịch sử sinh sống lâu đời ở Hòa Bình, người Mường đã sáng tạo ra nhiều di sản văn hóa vật thể và phi vật thể đặc","answer":"sắc, góp phần làm giàu thêm kho tàng văn hóa của 54 dân tộc anh em. Trong đó tri thức dân gian Lịch tre và Lễ hội truyền thống Khai Hạ được vinh danh Di sản văn hóa phi vật thể quốc gia gắn liền với nền sản xuất nông nghiệp lúa nước, thể hiện trình độ phát triển cao, không chỉ là niềm tự hào của dân tộc Mường, mà còn là niềm vui chung của các dân tộc tỉnh Hòa Bình. Những giá trị văn hóa đặc sắc này chính là sợi dây gắn kết cộng đồng, là cội nguồn sức mạnh được gìn giữ, bồi đắp, trao truyền từ đời này qua đời khác, giúp cho người dân ở mảnh đất này vượt qua mọi khó khăn, thử thách để vững bước đi lên, xây dựng và phát triển quê hương ngày càng giàu đẹp. Phó Chủ tịch nước ghi nhận và đánh giá cao những nỗ lực của Bộ Văn hóa, Thể thao và Du lịch, các nhà khoa học, nhà nghiên cứu trong quá trình lập hồ sơ đề cử, xem xét, đánh giá, công nhận 2 Di sản văn hóa phi vật thể quốc gia tại buổi lễ hôm nay. Bà Võ Thị Ánh Xuân tin tưởng, với bề dày lịch sử, truyền thống cách mạng và những giá trị văn hóa đa dạng, giàu bản sắc, trong thời gian tới, tỉnh Hòa Bình tiếp tục phát huy những kết quả rất đáng tự hào, khắc phục các tồn tại, hạn chế; quán triệt và triển khai thực hiện tốt Nghị quyết Đại hội XIII của Đảng, nhất là ý kiến chỉ đạo của Tổng Bí thư Nguyễn Phú Trọng tại Hội nghị Văn hóa toàn quốc vào tháng 11/2021. \\"Tôi mong rằng, 02 Di sản văn hóa phi vật thể quốc gia được vinh danh hôm nay, cùng hệ thống di sản văn hóa vật thể, phi vật thể phong phú của tỉnh nhà sẽ tiếp tục được cấp ủy, chính quyền, các ban, ngành, đoàn thể và nhân dân các dân tộc tỉnh Hòa Bình giữ gìn, bồi đắp, trở thành động lực và nguồn lực quan trọng để phát triển kinh tế - xã hội, góp phần xây dựng nền văn hóa Việt Nam tiên tiến, đậm đà bản sắc dân tộc, để văn hóa thực sự trở thành sức mạnh nội sinh, động lực xây dựng và bảo vệ Tổ quốc Việt Nam xã hội chủ nghĩa\\" – bà Võ Thị Ánh Xuân nói. Chương trình nghệ thuật \\"Hoà Bình - Thanh âm xứ Mường\\" gồm 3 chương: Miền đất cổ, Bản hoà ca xứ Mường và Vang xa thanh âm xứ Mường với các tiết mục văn hoá văn nghệ đặc sắc, ca ngợi vẻ đẹp lịch sử, truyền thống, văn hoá đa sắc màu nhưng đầy bản sắc của vùng đất, con người Tây Bắc nói chung, tỉnh Hoà Bình nói riêng. Cùng với những tiết mục ca múa nhạc đặc sắc, Chương trình có tiết mục \\"Vui hội xứ Mường\\" lồng ghép chương trình xiếc nghệ thuật với các trò chơi dân gian của người Mường như ném còn, thi bắn nỏ, giã gạo, đánh cù, đánh mảng…"},{"question":"C શાર્પ (c#) પ્રોગ્રામિંગ ભાષાનો ઉપયોગ શેના માટે થાય છે?","answer":"C# (ઉચ્ચાર: સી શાર્પ)એ મલ્ટી પેરાડિગમ પ્રોગ્રામિંગ ભાષા છે. તે માઇક્રોસોફ્ટ દ્વારા .NET Framework માં વિકસાવવામાં આવેલ હતી. પાછળથી તેને Ecma (ECMA-334) અને ISO (ISO/IEC 23270) દ્વારા પ્રમાણભૂત કરવામાં આવી. C#એ સરળ, આધુનિક, સામાન્ય હેતુ માટે તથા ઓબ્જેક્ટ ઓરીએન્ટેડ પ્રોગ્રામિંગ ભાષા છે. એન્ડર્સ હાઈલ્સબર્ગ તેની ડેવલોપમેન્ટ ટીમના સંચાલક છે. "},{"question":"වෛරස වල ලක්ෂණ මොනවාද?","answer":"වෛරස යනු නිදහස් ජිවී ආකාරයක් නොවේ. අසෛලීය ජීවීන්‍ය. සෛලීය සංවිධානයක් රහිතය. ස්වාධීන පරිවෘත්තියක් නොමැත. එනම් ශක්තිය නිපදවීම හෝ ප්‍රෝටීන සංස්ලේෂණය සදහා කිසිදු ස්වාධීන යාන්ත්‍රණයක් නොදරයි. වෛරසයක් ජීවී සෛලයක් තුලට ආසාදනය වූ විට පමණක්, ජීවී ලක්ෂණ පෙන්නුම් කරයි. මිහිමත පුළුල් ව්‍යාප්තියක් පෙන්වන ක්ෂූද්‍ර ජීවී කොට්ඨාශයකි. ඊට හේතුව වන්නේ පියවි ඇසින් දැකිය නොහැකි වීමයි. සාමාන්‍යයෙන් වෛරසයක් ප්‍රමාණයෙන් 20-25nm පමණ වේ. කිසිදු වෛරසයක් සාමාන්‍ය අන්වීක්ෂයකින් නිරීක්ෂණය කළ නොහැකි අතර දැකගත හැකි වන්නේ ඉලෙක්ට්‍රෝන අන්වීක්ෂයක් භාවිතයෙන් පමණි. විවිධාකාර හැඩවලින් එනම් විවිධ රූපීය ආකාරවලින් වෛරස දැකගත හැකිය."},{"question":"ආර්පිථාර්ත යන වචනයේ තේරුම කුමක්ද?","answer":"අර්පිතාර්ථ යනු ආරෝපිත අර්ථ යන්න යි. ඉංග්‍රීසි arbitrary යන්න ට මහාචාර්ය විමල් ජී බලගල්ලේ විසින් මෙය අර්පිතාර්ථවත් වශයෙන් යොදා තිබේ. ආරෝපණය කරන ලද නැතහොත් පටවන ලද අර්ථ ඇති යන්න අර්පිතාර්ථවත් යන්නෙහි අදහස යි. "},{"question":"Noocyada Sadaqada tee baa ugu fadli badan?","answer":"Waxaa ugu fadli badan Biyaha oo lays waraabsho."},{"question":"Inona no tanjona sy fanamby amin'ny diplaomasia nokleary amin'ny tontolon'ny fitaovam-piadiana nokleary?","answer":"Ny diplaomasia nokleary dia mikendry ny hisorohana ny fihanaky ny fitaovam-piadiana niokleary, hampihenana ny tahiry fitaovam-piadiana nokleary efa misy ary hampiroborobo ny fanafoanana ny fitaovam-piadiana. Anisan'ny fanamby ny fiarovam-paritra, ny fitoniana stratejika ary ny fitantanana ny loza ateraky ny fisian'ny fitaovam-piadiana nokleary."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai si buta pergi bergajah\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud pekerjaan yang sia-sia (tidak mungkin dapat dilakukan)."},{"question":"కలబంద","answer":"పరిచయము  (Red Aloe) అనేది Ascent of sap అనే కృత్రిమ రసాయనిక పద్ధతి ద్వారా ప్రయోగశాలలో ఎర్రగా మార్చబడిన మామూలు అలో వెరా మొక్క.Ascent of sap ప్రక్రియకాలేజీలలోనూ, ప్రయోగశాలల్లోనూ ఈ ప్రయోగం జరుపుతారు. ముందుగా కలబందలో ఉన్న నీటిని చేరవేసే Xylem కణాల ద్వారా ఇయోసిన్ (Eosin) అనే ఎర్రటి రసాయనాన్ని కలబందలోకి పంపిస్తారు. కొన్ని గంటల తర్వాత కలబందలో ఉన్న ప్రతి కణానికి ఈ రసాయనం ప్రవేశిస్తుంది. ఫలితంగా క్లోరోఫిల్ నాశనమయ్యి, కణాలు బ్రద్దలయ్యి ఆకులు, కాండం, వేర్లు అన్నీ ఎర్రగా మారిపోతాయి. అయితే ఇలా మార్చబడిన మొక్క బ్రతికే అవకాశం లేక క్రమేణా చనిపోతుంది.పుకార్లుతయారీదారులు ఇలా కలబందలను రహస్యంగా తయారుచేసి, వాటికి 'ఎర్ర కలబంద' అని పేరు పెట్టి మధ్యవర్తులకు ఇచ్చి మార్కెటింగ్ చేయిస్తున్నారు. మధ్యవర్తులు ఈ మొక్కల కాండాలకు మట్టిని అంటించి - ఎర్రకలబంద మొక్కలు చాలా అరుదుగా దట్టమైన నల్లమల అడవుల్లో దొరుకుతున్నాయని వినియోగదారులను నమ్మంచి వారికి అమ్మి కేజీ లక్ష రూపాయలకు చొప్పున వసూలు చేసుకుంటానికి ప్రయత్నిస్తున్నారు. ఎర్ర కలబంద మామూలు కలబంద కంటే చాలా శక్తివంత మైన ఔషధ విలువలున్నాయని, మంత్రశక్తులున్నాయని వినియోగదారులు విశ్వసిస్తున్నారు. ఈ పుకార్లు దాదాపు దేశమంతటా ప్రాకినది. ఎర్ర కలబంద అనే లేని మొక్క గురించి చాలా మంది తమ డబ్బును భారీగా ఖర్చు పెట్టి అడవులలో అన్వేషణ చేస్తున్నారు. అయితే ఇప్పటి వరకు ఏ ఒక్కరూ ఈ మొక్కలను కొనుగోలు చేసినట్లు ఆధారాలు లభించలేదు.కొన్ని వాస్తవాలునీరు లభ్యం కాని సమయాల్లో కలబంద ఆకుల్లో క్లోరోఫిల్ (Chrophyill) నాశనమయ్యి ఆ ప్రదేశాల్లో రోఢోక్సాన్థిన్ (Rhodoxanthin) అనే ఎర్రటి పిగ్మెంట్ అభివృద్ధి చెందుతుంది. ఫలితంగా ఆకు ఎర్రగా తయారవుతుంది. నీరు లభ్యమైనప్పుడు క్లోరోఫిల్ ఏర్పడుట వలన ఆ ఎర్రటి పిగ్మెంట్ ప్రదేశంలో తిరిగి ఆకుపచ్చ రంగు వస్తుంది. ఈ లక్షణం చాలా కలబంద రకాల్లో ఉంటుంది.కలబంద యొక్క ఔషధ గుణాలు అందులో ఉండే ఎమినో యాసిడ్లు, పోలీసాకరైడ్లు, జెల్ చేదు తనాన్ని బట్టి అంచనా వేయబడుతుంది కాని ఎరుపు రంగును బట్టిని కాదు.Eosin ను కలబందలోకి వెళ్ళినప్పుడు ఔషధ గుణాలు నాశనమౌతాయి.Eosin విషపూరితమైన ద్రావకము. కనుకు ఇది కలిగియున్న కలబంద యొక్క జెల్ ను సేవించరాదు.సర్వ సాధారణంగా ఏ రకమైన కలబందయొక్క జెల్ అయినా లేత పసుపు లేదా ముదురు పసుపు రంగులో ఉంటుంది.కలబంద జాతుల జన్మస్థానం భారతదేశం కాదు. భారత దేశానికి కలబందను పరిచయం చేసినవారు..."},{"question":"Tohizo ity ohabolana ity: “Ny marina mitavozavoza ... ”","answer":" “Ny marina mitavozavoza tsy mahaleo ny lainga tsara lahatra.”"},{"question":"В оповіданні «Вултонська в’язниця» Шерлок Холмс та доктор Ватсон визначили, як злодій, Тадеус Стамп, знаходячись за гратами, міг спілкуватися зі своїми спільниками. Він виконував це за допомогою картоплі (з якої нібито робив компреси) та звичайної газети.Як саме ув’язнений передавав послання своїм «колегам»? ","answer":"Він використовував хімічну реакцію йоду з крохмалем, яка забарвлює картоплю у синій колір. "},{"question":"在加拿大，法例規定泊車時應該距離消防栓（救火喉）多少距離？","answer":"3公尺/公尺（10尺）"},{"question":"ഇനിപ്പറയുന്ന ഖണ്ഡിക വായിച്ച് ചോദ്യത്തിന് ഉത്തരം നൽകുക. ഖണ്ഡിക:\\"പീസോ ഇലക്‌ട്രിസിറ്റി എന്നതിന്റെ ചുരുക്കെഴുത്ത്, പീസോ ഇലക്‌ട്രിസിറ്റിയുടെ സ്വഭാവം പ്രകടിപ്പിക്കുന്ന ഒരു മെറ്റീരിയലിനെയോ ഉപകരണത്തെയോ സൂചിപ്പിക്കുന്നു. മെക്കാനിക്കൽ സ്ട്രെസ് അല്ലെങ്കിൽ വൈകല്യത്തിന് വിധേയമാകുമ്പോൾ പീസോ ഇലക്ട്രിക് മെറ്റീരിയലുകൾക്ക് ഒരു വൈദ്യുത ചാർജ് സൃഷ്ടിക്കാൻ കഴിയും, നേരെമറിച്ച്, ഒരു വൈദ്യുത മണ്ഡലം അവയിൽ പ്രയോഗിക്കുമ്പോൾ അവയ്ക്ക് മെക്കാനിക്കൽ രൂപഭേദം സംഭവിക്കാം.പദാർത്ഥത്തിനുള്ളിലെ ആറ്റങ്ങളുടെയോ തന്മാത്രകളുടെയോ ക്രമീകരണം മൂലമാണ് പീസോ ഇലക്ട്രിക് പ്രഭാവം സംഭവിക്കുന്നത്, ഇത് ഒരു ദ്വിധ്രുവ നിമിഷം സൃഷ്ടിക്കുന്നു. മെറ്റീരിയൽ രൂപഭേദം വരുത്തുകയോ കംപ്രസ് ചെയ്യുകയോ ചെയ്യുമ്പോൾ, ക്രിസ്റ്റൽ ലാറ്റിസിന്റെ സമമിതി മാറുന്നു, ഇത് പോസിറ്റീവ്, നെഗറ്റീവ് ചാർജുകളുടെ വേർതിരിവിലേക്ക് നയിക്കുന്നു, അങ്ങനെ ഒരു വൈദ്യുത സാധ്യത സൃഷ്ടിക്കുന്നു. ഈ പ്രോപ്പർട്ടി വിവിധ ആപ്ലിക്കേഷനുകളിൽ ചൂഷണം ചെയ്യപ്പെടുന്നു.പീസോഇലക്‌ട്രിക് ട്രാൻസ്‌ഡ്യൂസറുകൾ അല്ലെങ്കിൽ സെൻസറുകൾ പോലെയുള്ള പീസോ ഇലക്ട്രിക് ഉപകരണങ്ങൾ മെക്കാനിക്കൽ ഊർജത്തെ വൈദ്യുത സിഗ്നലുകളാക്കി മാറ്റുന്നു അല്ലെങ്കിൽ തിരിച്ചും. അൾട്രാസൗണ്ട് ഇമേജിംഗ്, സോണാർ സിസ്റ്റങ്ങൾ, പ്രഷർ സെൻസറുകൾ, വൈബ്രേഷൻ അനാലിസിസ്, പ്രിസിഷൻ പൊസിഷനിംഗ്, കൂടാതെ ഇലക്ട്രിക് ഗിറ്റാറുകൾ പോലെയുള്ള ചില സംഗീതോപകരണങ്ങൾ എന്നിവയുൾപ്പെടെ വിപുലമായ ആപ്ലിക്കേഷനുകളിൽ അവ ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നു.പൈസോ ഇലക്ട്രിക് സാമഗ്രികൾ ഊർജ്ജ വിളവെടുപ്പിലും ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നു, അവിടെ അവർക്ക് ആംബിയന്റ് വൈബ്രേഷനുകളോ മെക്കാനിക്കൽ ചലനങ്ങളോ വൈദ്യുതോർജ്ജമാക്കി മാറ്റാൻ കഴിയും. ഈ സാങ്കേതികവിദ്യ സ്വയം പവർ ചെയ്യുന്ന സെൻസറുകൾ, ധരിക്കാവുന്ന ഉപകരണങ്ങൾ, കൂടാതെ സുസ്ഥിര ഊർജ്ജ ഉൽപ്പാദനത്തിനായുള്ള ചില നൂതന സമീപനങ്ങളിൽ പോലും ആപ്ലിക്കേഷനുകൾ കണ്ടെത്തുന്നു.\\"ചോദ്യം: എന്താണ് പീസോ, വിവിധ ആപ്ലിക്കേഷനുകളിൽ ഇത് എങ്ങനെയാണ് ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നത്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: മെക്കാനിക്കൽ സമ്മർദ്ദത്തിൽ വൈദ്യുത ചാർജ് സൃഷ്ടിക്കാൻ കഴിയുന്ന പീസോ ഇലക്ട്രിക് വസ്തുക്കളുടെ സ്വത്തിനെയാണ് പീസോ സൂചിപ്പിക്കുന്നത്. അൾട്രാസൗണ്ട് ഇമേജിംഗ്, പ്രഷർ സെൻസറുകൾ, ഊർജ്ജ വിളവെടുപ്പ്, കൃത്യമായ സ്ഥാനനിർണ്ണയം തുടങ്ങിയ വിവിധ ആപ്ലിക്കേഷനുകളിൽ ഇത് ഉപയോഗിക്കുന്നു. പീസോ ഇലക്ട്രിക് ഉപകരണങ്ങൾ മെക്കാനിക്കൽ ഊർജ്ജത്തെ വൈദ്യുത സിഗ്നലുകളാക്കി മാറ്റുന്നു അല്ലെങ്കിൽ തിരിച്ചും."},{"question":"Shekarar Robert Mugabe nawa akan mulki?","answer":"Yayi mulki daga 1987 zuwa 2017"},{"question":"Jubbantil mbind mii:Ñu topp nag la séytaane ya doon jàng ca nguurug Suleymaan. Weddiwul de, séytaane ya ñoo weddi: Daan nañu jàngal nit ña ag njibar ak la ñu wàcce woon ca ñaari Malaaka ya ca (Baabil) (Haaruut ak Maaruut); te daawuñu jàngal kenn te waxuñu ko ne: \\"Nun dey danoo ànd ak sànje: kon book bul weddi de\\" ; mu am ñu jàng ci ñoom loo xam ne mën nañu caa téqale jëkkër ak jabaram. Te daawuñu mën a lor kenn ca njibar googule, lu dul ci coobare Yàlla. Te it jàng nañu loo xam ne daf leen di lor te mënuleeen a jariñ. Xam nañu xéll ne ku jënde loolu [weccee ko ak waxi Yàlla] du am benn cër ca àllaaxira. La ñu jaaye seen bakkan bon na! Cëy bu ñu xamoon!","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:Ñu topp nag la séytaane ya doon jàng ca ngùurug Suleymaan. Weddiwul de, séytaane ya ñoo weddi: Daan na ñu jàngal nit ña ag njibar ak la ñu wàccewoon ca ñaar i Malaaka ya ca (Baabil) (Haaruut ak Maaruut); te daawu ñu jàngal kenn te wàxu ñu ko ne: \\"Nun dey da noo ànd ak sànje: kon boog bul weddi de\\"; mu àm ñu jàng ci ñoom loo xàm ne man na ñu caa téqale jëkkar ak jabaram. Te daawu ñu man a lor kenn ca njibar googule, lu dul ci coobare Yàlla. Te ìt jàng na ñu loo xàm ne da'f léen di lor te manu léen a jàriñ. Xàm na ñu xéll ne ku jënde loolu [weccee ko ak wàx i Yàlla] du àm benn cër ca àllaaxira. La ñu jaaye séen bakkan bon na! Cëy bu ñu xàmoon!"},{"question":"Pilih jawapan yang betul untuk soalan berikut: Apakah tindakan yang harus diambil jika kenderaan lain ingin memotong kenderaan anda di Malaysia?A. Memperlahankan kenderaan dan menghimpit ke kiri jika perluB. Menambahkan kelajuan kenderaan dan membunyikan honC. Menambahkan kelajuan dan menghimpit ke kanan","answer":"Jawapannya ialah A. Memperlahankan kenderaan dan menghimpit ke kiri jika perlu"},{"question":"Responda à pergunta: quem criou a linguagem de programação Rust?","answer":"Rust foi criada pelo engenheiro de software canadense Graydon Hoare. Graydon iniciou o desenvolvimento da linguagem Rust como um projeto pessoal em 2006 enquanto trabalhava como engenheiro na empresa Mozilla. Ele apresentou o projeto da linguagem Rust para o seu gerente na Mozilla e foi autorizado a criar um time dentro da empresa para desenvolver a linguagem. Oficialmente, Rust foi anunciada para o mundo em 2010 com o objetivo de ser segura, concorrente e prática. Inicialmente, Rust foi implementada em OCaml, porém atualmente ela é desenvolvida em Rust. Em 2013, Graydon deixou o seu papel de liderança no desenvolvimento da linguagem devido a um burnout que ele estava sofrendo."},{"question":"قم بإنشاء قصيدة قصيره من بحر المنسرح.","answer":"قَد ضَمَنا وَالكِرام بُستانُكَأَنَّنا في الجِنان سُكانُمُلوك فَضل عَليهُمُ حللبِنَسج العُلا وَالوَقار تيجانُأَخلاقُهُم رَوضة مُطَهرةيَجمَع فيها روح وَرَيحانُكَأَنَّهُم لِلعُيون تَبصرةكَأَنَّهُم في القُلوب إِيمانُوَهُم وُجوه لِكُل مكرمةوَمُصطفانا في العَين إِنسانفَمَجدُهُ الصدق لا يَشك بِهِوَفي سِواهُ يَعد بُهتانُ"},{"question":"Inis dom faoi Marina and the Diamonds. ","answer":"Is amhránaí Breatnach í Marina Lambrini Diamandis nó Marina and the Diamonds mar is fearr aithne uirthi. Rugadh í ar an 10 Deireadh Fómhair 1985. "},{"question":"ආතාපී සම්පජානෝ  සතිමා  යනු කුමක්ද ?","answer":"මේ පද තුනෙන් කායානුපස්සනාවට උපකාර වන ධර්මයන් ස්වරූප වශයෙන් උදුරා දක්ව යි. රූප සමූහ ය යි කියන ලද කය නිත්‍ය නො වේ. දුක් රැසක් වේ. ආත්මයක් නො වේ. අශුභ වූ වස්තුවකි. මෙසේ මේ රූප කය අනිත්‍ය ය, දුක් ය, අනාත්ම ය, අශුභ ය යි කියා ඇති සැටියෙන් බලන්නා වූ ද ඥානය කායානුපස්සනා ව යි. ඒ භාවනාවෙන් තොර වූ පුද්ගලයා රූපකය කෙරෙහි අතිශයින් ම වරදවා වටහා ගනී. කෙසේද යත්? ජීවිතාන්තය දක්වා පවතින්නේ එක මම රූපයක් ය යි ද, සත්වයෙක් ය යි ද, ඒ රූපය සුවපත් ව පවත්වන්නේ ය යි ද, එය ම ආත්මයක් ය යි ද, වටහා ගනී. ආත්මය වූ තමාට කැමති පරිදි යත හැකි ය. කනු බොනු හැකි ය. කළ හැකි ය, සතුටු විය හැකි ය, මේ රූප කර සෝභන වූ ශරීරයක් ය යි වරදවා වටහා ගනී. මෙසේ තදින් වරදවා වටහා ගෙන, පවත්නා රූප කය කෙරෙහි අනිත්‍ය ය, දුක ය, අනාත්ම ය, අශුභ ය යි කියා ඇත්ත ඇති සැටි වටහා ගැනීම ඉතා දුෂ්කර ය. එහෙයින් ලෝකයෙහි ප්‍රකෘති ඇසින් නොදැකිය හැකි කුඩා දෙයක් වෙයි නම්, ඒ කුඩා දෙය ලොකු කොට පෙන්වන කණ්ණාඩියෙන් බලා හරිහැටි දැකිය හැකි වන්නාක් මෙන්, යෝගී පුද්ගලයාට කයේ තත්වාකාර ය බලා ගැනීම පිණිස උපකාර වන ධර්‍ම කොටසක් ද ඇත. එනම්, විරිය, සති, සමාධි, පඤ්ඤා යන මේවා ය. මෙකී විරිය, සති, ආදියෙන් රූප කයෙහි ඇති සැටි බලන ආකාරය දක්වනු පිණිස “කායේ කායානුපස්සී විහරති. ආතාපී සම්පජානෝ සතිමා” ය යි වදාළ සේක.[1]යෝගියා විසින් රූපකයෙහි ප්‍රකට ව පවත්නා රූප ක්‍රියා සියල්ල නුවණට වැටහෙනු පිණිස නො කඩවා වෑයම් කළ යුතු ය. මේ වෑයම් කිරීම ආතාප ය යි කියන ලද “සම්මප්පධාන වීර්යය”ය යි. මේ තියුණු වීර්යයයෙන් නොකඩවා වෑයම් කළහොත්, යෝගියා තුළ උපදනා තාක් රූප සියල්ල අත් නොහැර සිහි කළ හැකි ය. එසේ සිහිකළ හැකිවීම සති නම් වේ. ඒ සතිය දියුණු තියුණු වූ කල්හි ක්ෂණයක් ක්ෂණයක් පාසා නොයෙක් අරමුණුවල විසිර යමින් පැවති සිත එක ම අරමුණෙක්හි පිහිටු වන සමාධිය පහළ වී එන්නේ ය. මේ සමාධිය වනාහි සිහියගේ ආනුභාවයෙන් හටගන්නා වූ “විපස්සනා ඛණික සමාධිය” මැ යි. මේ සමාධිය වැඩිදියුණු වූ කල්හි රූපක්‍රියා සියල්ල ප්‍රකටව වැටහී එන්නේ ය. කොටස් කොටස් වශයෙන් ද වැටහී එන්නේ ය. රූපයන් ඉපිද නැතිවීම ද දත හැකි වන්නේ ය. ඒ සියල්ල අනිත්‍යය, දුකය, අනාත්මය. අශුභ ය යි කියා දත හැකි වන්නේ ය. මෙසේ දත හැකි වීම “සම්පජඤ්ඤ” නම් අනුපස්සනා ඥානය යි. උපදනා තාක් රූපක්‍රියා සියල්ල නොකඩවා අත් නොහැර මෙනෙහි කරන යෝගියා කෙරෙහි යට දැක් වූ විරිය, සති, සමාධි, අනුපස්සනා ඥාන යන ගුණ ධර්ම සතර ම සම්පූර්ණ වන්නේ ය. මේ රූප කය අනිත්‍ය වූ, දුක් වූ, අනාත්ම වූ, අශුභ වූ රූප කයක් ම ය යි ඇති සැටියෙන් දත හැකි වීම කායානුපස්සනාව සම්පූර්ණ කිරීම ය යි කියනු ලැබේ. එහෙයින් “කායෙ කායානුපස්සී විහරති ආතාපී සම්පජානො සතිමා” යනු වදාරණ ලදී.“විනෙය්‍ය ලොකෙ අභිජ්ඣා දෙමනස්සං” යන වාක්‍යයෙන් භාවනාවගේ ඵලය දක්වන ලදී. කෙසේ ද ය? කය පිළිබඳ රූප ක්‍රියාවන් කෙරෙහි ඉහත දැක් වූ පරිදි මෙනෙහි නොකළ හැකි වුව හොත් ඒ රූප ක්‍රියා සියල්ල නිතර පවත්නා ආත්මයක් ය, මම ය, සුවසේ වාසය කරන සත්වයෙක් ය යි වරදවා වටහා ගැනීමෙන්, අභිජ්ඣා නම් වූ දැඩි ලෝභය හෝ තව ඇතිවිය හැකි ය. රූප කයට පීඩා ඇති වීමෙන් වෙනස සහිත තරහ, ක්‍රෝධ ඇතිවිය හැකිය.සත්වයන් තුළ ලෝහ දොසයන් ඇතිවීම මේ ආකාරයෙන් ම සිදුවන්නේ ය. රූප කය පිළිබඳ ඒ රූප ක්‍රියාවන් කෙරෙහි ලෝභය හා ද්වේෂය ඇති නොවන පරිදි, අනිත්‍යාදී වශයෙන් ඇති සැටියෙන් දැක ගැනීම ම අනුපස්සනා ඤාණයෙන් තදඞ්ග වශයෙන් කෙළෙස් පහ කිරීමය යි කියන ලදී. මේ දැක්වූයේ මෙනෙහි කළ අරමුණෙහි තදඞ්ග වශයෙන් ලෝභ දෝෂයන් පහව යන ආකාර ය යි.තවද ප්‍රකටව පවත්නා රූප ක්‍රියා සියල්ල නොකඩවා මෙනෙහි කිරීමෙන් අනිත්‍යය, දුක්ය, අනාත්මය යි කියා දැන ගන්නා වාරයක් පාසා විරිය, සති, සමාධි යන සමාධිස්කන්ධ ධර්මයෝ දියුණු තියුණු ව පහළ වෙත්. මේ සමථයාගේ බලයෙන් චිත්තය අතිශයින්ම මෘදු මොලොක් වෙයි. කල් යත් යත් ක්‍රම ක්‍රමයෙන් මෘදු මොලොක් බවට පත් වෙයි. එහෙයින් මෙනෙහි නොකරණු ලැබූ අන්‍ය වූ රූප, වේදනා සඤ්ඤා, සංඛාර, විඤ්ඤාණයන් කෙරෙහි ද, සිතා මතා බැලීමෙන් ලෝභය හා දෝෂය බොහෝ සෙයින් ඇති නොවීමෙන් සංසිඳී යන්නට පුළුවන. මෙනෙහි නොකොට වාසය කරන කල්හි ද ඖදාරික ලෝභය හා දෝෂය පෙර මෙන් ඇති නොවී සන්සුන් විය හැකි ය. එවිට ඖදාරික ක්ලේශයන් තමා තුළ පහළ නොවන්නේ ය යි යෝගියාහට වැටහෙන්නේ ය.මේ දැක්වූයේ මෙනෙහි, නොකළ අරමුණෙහි විෂ්කම්භණ වශයෙන් ලෝහ දෝෂයන් පහ ව යන ආකාර ය යි. මෙසෙයින් මෙනෙහි කළ අරමුණහි කෙලෙස් සංසිඳ වීම ය යි කියන ලද තද විනය හා, මෙනෙහි නො කළ අරමුණෙහි කෙලෙස් සංසිඳ වීම යයි කියන ලද විෂ්කම්භණ විනය යන, මේ භාවනා ඵල දෙක යෝගියාහට මෙනෙහි කිරීමක් පාසා ලැබිය හැකි ය. මෙකී ඵල වය ලැබීම සඳහා ප්‍රකට වනතාක් රූපක්‍රියා සියල්ල ම නො කඩ වා මෙනෙහි කිරීමෙන් කායානුපස්සනාව වැඩිය යුතු යයි දත යුතු ය. වෙදනානුපස්සනා ආදියෙහි ද මේ ය ක්‍රමය මැයි.විශේෂය නම් - කයෙහි අශුභ වශයෙන්ද වෙදනා, චිත්ත, ධම්ම යන මොවුන් කෙරෙහි පිළිවෙලින් දුඃඛ අනිත්‍යය, අනාත්ම වශයෙන් ද මෙනෙහි කළ යුතු ය යි වෙසෙසා අටුවාවෙහි කියන ලදී. සාමාන්‍යයෙන් වනාහි කාය, වේදනා, චිත්ත, ධම්ම යන සියල්ල ම අනිත්‍ය, දුක්ඛ, අනාත්ම, අශුභ වශයෙන් මෙනෙහි කළ යුතු ය."},{"question":"Write a philosophical essay on the concepts of free will and determinism, exploring different perspectives on the matter.","answer":"स्वतंत्र इच्छा और नियतता की धाराओं पर एक दार्शनिक निबंध लिखें, जिसमें इस विषय पर विभिन्न परिप्रेक्ष्यों का अन्वेषण किया जाता है।"},{"question":"Durante quantos anos George Washington ocupou a presidência dos Estados Unidos?","answer":"8 anos"},{"question":"Porto-Novo moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"Porto-Novo moy péeyu réwum Bénin"},{"question":"کیا سعودی کلب جانے سے نیمار کا فٹبال کریئر داؤ پر لگ گیا ہے؟","answer":"یہ ایک ایسا اقدام تھا جس نے فٹبال کی دنیا میں ہلچل مچا دی۔چھ سال قبل برازیل کے لیجنڈ فٹبالر نیمار نے بارسیلونا چھوڑ کر فرانسیسی کلب پیرس سینٹ جرمین (پی ایس جی) میں شمولیت کے لیے ریکارڈ 200 ملین پاؤنڈز کا معاہدہ کیا تھا۔مگر اب 31 سالہ نیمار نے یورپی فٹبال کو الوداع کہہ دیا ہے، کم از کم ابھی کے لیے۔ وہ سعودی عرب میں کھیلنے والے بڑے کھلاڑیوں میں سے ایک بن گئے ہیں۔اطلاعات کے مطابق انھیں الہلال فٹبال کلب میں کھیلنے کے لیے سالانہ 150 ملین یوروز ملیں گے۔ انھوں نے دو سال کا معاہدہ کیا ہے لہٰذا یہ پی ایس جی کے مقابلے چھ گنا بڑی رقم ہے۔نیمار نے پی ایس جی کے لیے 173 میچز کھیلے اور انھوں نے 13 ٹرافیاں جیتنے میں نمایاں کردار ادا کیا جس میں پانچ لیگ ون ٹائٹل شامل ہیں۔مگر یہ کلب نیمار کو یورپ کا سب سے بڑا ٹائٹل ’چیمپئنز لیگ‘ جیتنے کے لیے لایا تھا۔ مگر وہ اس میں کامیابی نہ دلا سکے۔ پی ایس جی 2020 میں ان کی موجودگی میں فائنل تک پہنچ سکا تھا۔جنوبی امریکہ میں فٹبال کے ماہر ٹِم وِکری نے بی بی سی کو بتایا کہ ’وہ بہت سے ہم وطنوں کی نظر میں یہ کام نہیں کرسکے۔ وہ اعلیٰ درجے کا یورپی فٹبال چھوڑ کر میدان جنگ سے بھاگ گئے ہیں۔‘’نیمار شاید اسے عارضی الوداع کہیں اور ضروری نہیں کہ وہ دوبارہ پی ایس جی میں شمولیت اختیار کریں۔ وہ شاید دو سال بعد دوبارہ یورپ آئیں کیونکہ اس وقت یہ جاننا مشکل ہے کہ ان کے پاس کیا آپشنز تھے۔‘یہ نیمار کے کریئر کے اتار چڑتاؤ کا نیا باب ہے۔ اس تحریر میں ہم نے ان کے سینٹوس سے سعودی عرب تک کے سفر پر نظر دوڑائی ہے۔2009 میں سینٹوس کے لیے سینیئر ڈیبیونیمار نے اپنے کریئر کا آغاز اپنے آبائی ملک برازیل میں کیا۔ انھوں نے 17 سال کی عمر میں سینٹوس کے ساتھ اپنا پہلا پیشہ ورانہ معاہدہ کیا۔انھوں نے سینیئر ڈیبیو بھی مارچ 2009 میں کیا۔ ایک ہفتے بعد انھوں نے پہلا گول کیا اور ابتدائی طور پر 48 میچوں میں 14 گول کیے۔2010 میں برازیل کے لیے پہلا میچ کھیلےایک سال بعد نیمار کو برازیل نے بلا لیا۔ یہ 10 اگست کو امریکہ کے ساتھ ایک دوستانہ میچ تھا۔ انھوں نے 28 منٹ کے اندر گول کر کے اپنے ڈیبیو کو شاندار بنایا۔نیمار نے برازیل کے لیے 124 میچوں میں 77 گول کیے لیکن ان کا پہلا گول ان کے کریئر کے پسندیدہ ترین گولز میں سے ایک ہے۔2013 میں بارسیلونا اور برازیل کے لیے کامیابیاںلوئس سواریز، لیونل میسی اور نیمار بارسیلونا میں ایک زبردست جوڑی ثابت ہوئی۔سنہ 2011 میں سانتوس کے لیے کوپا لیبرٹادورس جیتنے کے بعد نیمار نے بارسیلونا میں شمولیت اختیار کی۔ انھیں کئی یورپی کلبز نے پیشکش کی تھی۔وہ لیونل میسی اور لوئس سواریز کے ساتھ فرنٹ تھری میں کھیلتے تھے اور اس جوڑی کو ’ایم ایس این‘ کا نام دیا گیا تھا۔نیمار نے بارسیلونا کو لا لیگا، کوپا ڈیل رے اور چیمپئنز لیگ جیتنے میں مدد دی۔بارسیلونا میں شمولیت کے فوراً بعد انھوں نے برازیل کو فیفا کنفیڈریشن کپ جیتنے میں بھی مدد کی اور ٹورنامنٹ کے بہترین کھلاڑی قرار پائے۔2014 میں ورلڈ کپ کا خواب ٹوٹ گیااب تک نیمار کا ستارہ چمک رہا تھا اور برازیل کے 2014 میں ورلڈ کپ کی میزبانی کے ساتھ بہت سے لوگوں نے ان سے امیدیں وابستہ کر لی تھیں۔ٹورنامنٹ سے پہلے اور اس کے دوران ان کی تصاویر ہر جگہ تھیں۔ لیکن لوگوں کو کافی مایوسی ہوئی جب کوارٹر فائنل میں وہ انجرڈ ہوگئے۔ کولمبیا کے جوآن زونیگا کی ٹکر نے انھیں کمر درد میں مبتلا کر دیا۔اس میچ میں تو برازیل نے 2-1 سے کامیابی حاصل کی لیکن اس کی بڑی قیمت ادا کرنا پڑی: نیمار انجری کے ساتھ ورلڈ کپ سے باہر ہوگئے۔سیمی فائنل میں جرمنی کے خلاف برازیل کو ایک سات کی ذلت آمیز شکست کا سامنا کرنا پڑا۔2016 میں اولمپک ریکارڈ اور گولڈ سیزننیمار، میسی اور سواریز کلب فٹ بال میں سب سے خطرناک جوڑیوں میں سے ایک ہے۔ سال 2015-16 میں انھوں نے مل کر 131 گولز کیے، جو ہسپانوی فٹبال تاریخ میں ایک سیزن میں سب سے زیادہ گولز ہیں۔ان گولز نے بارسیلونا کو لا لیگا اور کوپا ڈیل رے کے ڈومیسٹک ڈبل کو مکمل کرنے میں مدد کی۔ اس سے قبل نیمار ریو میں سنہ 2016 کے اولمپک مقابلوں کے لیے دوبارہ برازیل کی ٹیم کا حصہ بنے۔ورلڈ کپ میں چوٹ سے دل ٹوٹنے کے دو سال بعد نیمار نے فیصلہ کن پنالٹی سکور کی۔ انھوں نے برازیل کو پہلا اولمپک گولڈ جتایا۔2017 میں فرانس منتقلیبارسیلونا کے لیے 186 میچوں میں 105 گولز کرنے کے بعد نیمار نے اس ٹیم کو چھوڑ کر پی ایس جی میں شمولیت کا اعلان کیا تو عالمی فٹبال میں ہلچل مچ گئی۔ انھیں 2017 میں اس کے بدلے 200 ملین پاونڈز کی بڑی ڈیل آفر کی گئی تھی۔2017 میں اپنے ڈیبیو پر انھوں نے ایک گول کیا اور دوسرے گول میں اسسٹ کیا۔ وہ کلیان ماپے اور ایڈنسن کوانی کے ساتھ جارحانہ کھیل پیش کرتے تھے۔ نیمار نے لیگ ون، فرنچ کپ اور لیگ کپ میں پی ایس جی کی فتوحات کے دوران 30 میچوں میں 28 گول کیے۔مگر انھیں سیزن چھوڑنا پڑا جب وہ دوبارہ انجری کا شکار ہوئے۔ یہ ان کئی انجریوں میں سے ایک ہے جنھوں نے پیرس میں انھیں خوفزدہ کیے رکھا۔2019 سے 2020: چیمپیئنز لیگ فائنل کے بعد مستقبل غیر یقینیپی ایس جی کے ساتھ دو سال گزارنے کے بعد نیمار کو بارے میں یہ قیاس آرائیاں شروع ہوگئیں کہ وہ دوبارہ بارسیلونا میں شمولیت اختیار کر سکتے ہیں۔جولائی میں وہ سیزن سے قبل ٹریننگ کا حصہ نہ بن سکے جس پر پی ایس جی نے ناراضی ظاہر کی۔ پھر وہ پیرس میں ہی رہے۔یہ سیزن بھی ان کی انجریوں کی وجہ سے متاثر ہوا۔ تاہم انھوں نے ٹیم کو لیگ ون میں فتح دلائی اور چیمپیئنز لیگ کے فائنل تک لے گئے جہاں ٹیم کو بائرن میونخ کے ہاتھوں شکست جھیلنی پڑی۔2012 سے 2023 کے اتار چڑھاؤاگست 2021 کے دوران بارسیلونا میں نیمار کے سابق ساتھی میسی نے بھی پی ایس جی میں شمولیت اختیار کی۔تاہم نیمار کے لیے یہ مایوس کن سال رہا، وہ تمام مقابلوں میں صرف 13 گول کر سکے۔ یہ یورپ آنے کے بعد سے ان کا سب سے بُرا سیزن رہا۔2022 سے 2023 کے سیزن میں میسی اور ماپے کے ساتھ نیمار فارم میں واپس آئے۔ انھوں نے پہلے پانچ لیگ میچوں میں 13 گول اور اسسٹ کیے۔ مگر ماچ میں ٹخنے کی سرجری کے باعث وہ سیزن سے باہر ہوگئے۔فروری کے میچ میں انھوں نے پی ایس جی کے لیے اپنا آخری میچ کھیلا۔کیا نیمار کے کیریئر میں مزید اچھے لمحات آئیں گے؟آج بھی برازیل میں شائقین نیمار کے ساتھ امیدیں جوڑے ہوئے ہیں۔ انھوں نے اب تک ورلڈ کپ میں برازیل کو کامیابی نہیں دلائی ہے۔تو کیا پی ایس جی چھوڑ کر سعودی لیگ کا حصہ بننے سے ان کی کامیابیاں محدود ہوجائیں گی؟وکری کا کہنا ہے کہ ’ان سے بہت سے لوگ مایوس ہیں۔ یہ کوئی اچھا نتیجہ نہیں کیونکہ وہ کافی دیر سے انجرڈ رہے ہیں۔‘’مگر ہمیں یاد رکھنا ہوگا کہ انھوں نے برازیل کی قومی ٹیم کے لیے پیلے جتنے گول کیے ہیں۔ یہ محض ان کی عرفیت نہیں۔ کئی سالوں سے ان سے بہت زیادہ امیدیں وابستہ کی جاتی رہی ہیں۔‘وکری نے کہا کہ اگر وہ دوبارہ فٹبال نہ بھی کھیلیں تو ان کی موجودہ کامیابیوں کو نظر انداز نہیں کیا جاسکتا۔ ’چاہے وہ سعودی عرب میں رہیں، کسی بڑے یورپی کلب میں یا اگلے ورلڈ کپ میں، ان کے لیے کئی عظیم لمحات باقی ہیں۔‘"},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Yaya za a rubuta ɗari ɗaya da arba'in da tara a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 149"},{"question":"Isi tempat kosong dengan jawapan yang paling sesuai.   Emak selalu menegur sikap abang yang __itu. Pilihan:  A) langkah kananB)  rabun ayamC) berat tulangD) berat hati","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah C) berat tulang"},{"question":"Dưới đập Khe Là từng có khu dân cư, giờ là nơi ở của hàng nghìn cá lớn, thu hút đông cần thủ từ khắp nơi đến giăng câu trong 13 năm qua.Đập Khe Là, xã Phú Sơn, huyện Tân Kỳ, dài khoảng 3 km, rộng hơn 500 m, điểm sâu nhất 38 m, dung tích 2 triệu m3. Nhìn từ trên cao, phía tây đập là cánh rừng thoai thoải xen lẫn vài căn nhà. Phía đông là bờ kè bêtông. Phía bắc và nam có nhiều hòn đảo nhỏ, người dân trồng keo và chè. Một số vị trí cây cối rập rạp.Những năm 1970, dưới đập Khe Là là xóm Bắc Sơn, xã Phú Sơn, nơi sinh sống của hơn 15 hộ gia đình. Họ trồng lúa nước và mía mưu sinh nhưng chỉ đủ ăn, không có tích lũy. Giao thông khó khăn, điện chưa đấu nối, mùa hè hạn hán, hoa màu khô héo, mùa mưa thì lũ quét và sạt lở đất.Là cán bộ xã Phú Sơn từ năm 1980, sau này làm Bí thư, Chủ tịch, Phó chủ tịch HĐND xã cho đến khi về hưu năm 2019, ông Nguyễn Hồ Thú nói từ năm 1982 các đoàn của tỉnh và huyện đã về khảo sát xây đập Khe Là để đưa hơn 15 hộ dân ở lòng chảo Bắc Sơn thoát khỏi cảnh sống khổ, đồng thời giải quyết tình trạng hạn hán ở khu vực.Nhưng phải đến năm 2009, khi các hộ dân được di dời, đập Khe Là mới được động thổ. Doanh nghiệp thủy lợi huy động nhân lực đắp bờ, xây kè, tạo độ sâu. Tháng 8/2010, công nhân chuẩn bị giải tỏa hơn 15 ngôi nhà giữa lòng hồ thì một trận lũ lớn ập đến, nhấn chìm cả xóm Bắc Sơn, không thể nạo vét được nữa.Đập Khe Là hoàn thành năm 2010, so với hơn 100 hồ đập tại huyện Tân Kỳ thì diện tích chỉ ở mức trung bình. Tuy nhiên, con đập lại nổi tiếng cả miền Trung do có nhiều loài cá lớn như trắm đen, chép đến cư trú.Anh Đặng Văn Tú, 33 tuổi, đang đấu thầu nuôi cá lăng tại Khe Là, cho biết ước tính cá tự nhiên tại đập hiện vài chục tấn, trong đó có hơn 300 con trắm đen nặng từ 30 kg trở lên, đặc biệt có khoảng 10 con nặng tầm 60-80 kg, nhưng chưa cần thủ nào câu được. Gần đây nhất tối 15/6, nhóm cần thủ ở thị xã Thái Hòa câu được con trắm đen 40 kg, đường kính bụng 40 cm, dài hơn một mét.Hiện mỗi ngày có hàng chục thợ câu đến dựng lán, đặt cần săn cá ở Khe Là. Anh Tú cắm biển cấm đánh bắt tận diệt cá tự nhiên, chỉ cho các cần thủ chinh phục các loài cá lớn, quay video. Nếu bắt được cá lớn, thường gọi là \\"thủy quái\\" thì thợ câu tùy ý xử lý, cá nhỏ sẽ phải thả lại đập để bảo tồn.Trả lời câu hỏi sau dựa vào nội dung của đoạn văn trên: Ai là người đã đề xuất xây đập Khe Là?","answer":"Người đã đề xuất xây đập Khe Là là ông Nguyễn Hồ Thú, một cán bộ xã Phú Sơn từ năm 1980."},{"question":"次の段落にマッチするタイトルをつけてください： もうすぐ夏休みです。子どもたちが外に出ることが多くなります。東京の港区の小学校で、交通のルールを勉強するイベントがありました。950人ぐらいの子どもたちが集まりました。最初に、NHKが子どもたちのために作った交通安全の歌「ててて!とまって!」のアニメーションを見ながら、手をあげる練習をしました。横断歩道では、車が来ていないか右と左をよく見て、運転手に手を見せて渡ることを勉強しました。そしてタレントの2人が、自転車のルールを説明しました。乗るときはヘルメットをかぶること、歩道では歩いている人のために、自転車から降りて歩くことなどです。3年生の女の子は「道を渡るときは、運転手さんに見えるようにしっかり手をあげることを勉強しました」と話していました。","answer":"夏休みを安全に楽しんで　子どもたちが交通のルールを勉強"},{"question":"Nderipi gungwa paNyika harina mahombekombe","answer":"Dead Sea ndiro gungwa repaNyika iro risina mahombekombe. Idziva remvura yemunyu rakaganhurwa neJorodhani kumabvazuva neIsrael nePalestine kumadokero. Kuwanda kwemunyu mumvura kunoita kuti zvisakwanise kuti chero chirimwa kana hupenyu hwemhuka hurarame, saka hapana mahombekombe pamupendeo waro."},{"question":"请用简洁的语言回答以下问题：问题：临床心理学的研究对象是什么？","answer":"答案：临床心理学的研究对象是人们的心理过程、心理问题和心理健康状态。"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన ప్రశ్నకి సమాధానం ఇవ్వండి: నేషనల్ డిఫెన్స్ అకాడమీ ఎక్కడ ఉంది?","answer":"డెహ్రాడూన్"},{"question":"கேள்வி :எந்தத் தட்பவெப்பத்திலும் உறையாத தனிமம் எது?","answer":"பதில்:ஹீலியம்."},{"question":"Vergi borcu ne kadar süre ödenmezse?","answer":"5 yıl içinde ödenmeyen, dolayısıyla tahsil edilmeyen vergi borcu tahsil zamanaşımına uğrar."},{"question":"Pengukuhan perpaduan dalam masyarakat berbilang kaum di negara ini amat pentingdemi keamanan dan keharmonian. Sehubungan dengan itu, anda ingin menulis sebuahrencana yang bertajuk ‘Langkah-Langkah Mengukuhkan Perpaduan DalamKalangan Masyarakat Berbilang Kaum di Negara Ini’.Tulis rencana itu selengkapnya.","answer":"CADANGAN IDEA / ISI1. Mengadakan ceramah atau bengkel tentang perpaduan kaum.2. Meraikan sambutan perayaan kaum-kaum di Malaysia secara bersama-sama.3. Pelaksanaan Konsep 1 Malaysia.4. Penggunaan bahasa Kebangsaan sebagai bahasa rasmi.5. Menganjurkan aktiviti sukan yang melibatkan pelbagai kaum.6. Pihak kerajaan/swasta mengadakan kempen- kempen Budi Bahasa Budaya Kita"},{"question":"ਪਰਿਵਾਰ ਨੇ ਆਂਢ-ਗੁਆਂਢ ਵਿਚ ਪੱਛ-ਗਿੱਛ ਕੀਤੀ। | ਇਸ ਦਾ ਕਾਰਨ ਕੀ ਸੀ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਕੁੱਤਾ ਘਰੋਂ ਭੱਜ ਗਿਆ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਘਰ ਵਿੱਚੋਂ ਕੀਮਤੀ ਗਹਿਣੇ ਗਾਇਬ ਸਨ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦਾ ਕੁੱਤਾ ਘਰੋਂ ਭੱਜ ਗਿਆ।"},{"question":"Cite um subgênero do heavy metal e recomende uma banda.","answer":"O Doom Metal pode ser o que você busca. Sendo considerado um \\"subgênero extremo\\" do Heavy Metal que geralmente usam tempos mais lentos, guitarras em afinações baixas e um som muito mais \\"espesso\\" e \\"pesado\\" do que qualquer outro gênero do Heavy Metal. Os primeiros discos da banda Black Sabbath serviram de fermento para o que o Doom Metal viria a ser. Na década de 90, Anathema se destacou com diversas outras bandas, misturando o Death Metal com o Doom Metal, em harmonias mais melancólicas e ultrarromânticas. Pesquise mais sobre Paradise Lost e My Dying Bride para se familiarizar mais com o gênero."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：问题：人体中负责产生胆汁的器官是什么？","answer":"答案：人体中负责产生胆汁的器官是肝脏。"},{"question":"\\"බෝ පතක් වැටෙන සේ\\" ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. ","answer":"බෝ පතක් වැටෙන සේනුඹ වැටී ලෙඩ ඇඳේනිසොල්මනේ ඇයි අම්මේපෙරහැරක් වගේ සිටිකොඩි වැලක් වගේ නැගිදූ පුතුන් කොහේ අම්මේමුතු පබළු අතේ නැතසවි බලද හිතේ නැතතනිකමද හිතින් දැරුවේකිරි සුවඳ හමා ගියමහ ගෙදර පාළු බවමව් සුවඳ වසා පැතිරේසිල් සුවඳ පිරූ සිතගුණ සුවඳ දැනේ මටපන්සලක් වගේ අම්මේසා දුකින් පෙලෙන සඳකිරි පොවා කඳුළු හෙලුනුඹ නිවන් දකින් අම්මේඅජන්තා නාකන්දලරඹුකන සිද්ධාර්ථ හිමි"},{"question":"රන්වන් පැහැයෙන් බබලන සිරුර නිසා \\"කංචන මානව\\" ලෙස, ගිහි ජීවිතයේදී හැඳින්වූ මහ රහතන්වහන්සේ කවුද ?","answer":"ගිහි ජීවිතයේදී \\"කංචන මානව\\" ලෙස හැඳින්වූ මහ රහතන්වහන්සේ මහා කච්චායන මහ රහතන්වහන්සේය."},{"question":"Thẻ Yikatong là thẻ gì?","answer":"Thẻ Yikatong là một thẻ thanh toán thông minh được chính quyền thành phố Bắc Kinh, Trung Quốc phát hành. Thẻ này được sử dụng để thanh toán cho các dịch vụ giao thông công cộng, bao gồm tàu điện ngầm, xe buýt, taxi, và cũng có thể được sử dụng để mua sắm tại các cửa hàng, siêu thị và các điểm dịch vụ khác trong thành phố. "},{"question":"ఈ పేరాకు కొనసాగింపును వ్రాయండి - 1947-48లో పాకిస్తాన్ దాడి","answer":"సమయంలో, గిల్గిట్ స్కౌట్లు కార్గిల్ ప్రాంతంపై 1948 మే 10 న దాడి చేశారు. కాశ్మీర్ రక్షణ బాధ్యతలు నిర్వర్తిస్తున్న భారత సైన్యం తన బలగాలను పంపింది. అయితే, వారు సమయానికి చేరుకోలేకపోవడంతో, 1948 జూన్ 6 న ద్రాస్ గిల్గిటీల వశమైపోయింది. ఆ తరువాత కార్గిల్, స్కర్దూ కూడా వాళ్ళ వశమైపోయాయి. 1948 నవంబరులో, భారత సైన్యం ట్యాంకుల మద్దతుతో ఆపరేషన్ బైసన్ ను మొదలుపెట్టి, ద్రాస్, కార్గిల్‌లను తిరిగి తన అధీనం లోకి తెచ్చుకుంది. స్కర్దూ అయితే పాకిస్తాన్ నియంత్రణలోనే ఉండిపోయింది. 1949 కాల్పుల విరమణ రేఖ ద్రాస్ నుండి ఉత్తరాన 12 కి.మీ. దూరంలో, పాయింట్ 5353 ద్వారా పోతుంది."},{"question":"Сейтектин чоң атасы?","answer":"Манас"},{"question":"Kirjoita seuraava teksti omin sanoin:Tiedät missä olen, jos tarve vaatii.","answer":"Tiedät mistä minut löytää tarpeen tullen."},{"question":"અહીં ગુજરાતી નાટક ના કલાકારો વચ્ચેની વાતો નીચે મુજબ આપેલી છે:\\"નથ્થુ૦ - તારે મારાથી ચલાય કેમ ? પાસે દીવો હોય છે તોજ આંખે ઝાંખપ વળેછને.હજામ - બીજી તદબીર શોધી કહાડીસું. શેઠ તમારે ગભરાવું નહિ, તમારું કોઈ કામ અડ્યું રહેવાનું નથી.નથ્થુ૦ - વારૂ, આરસી લાવ તો બચ્ચા.હજામ - લ્યો શેઠ આજે તમને એવા બનાવ્યાછ કે બે ઘડી સૌ તમારી તરફ જોઈ રહેસે.નથ્થુ૦ -બચ્ચા, આ પળિયાં તો ટુંપી નાંખ્યા હત, તોજ ઠીક થાત. એતો નઠારૂં દેખાય છે.હજામ - કાકા, સો બસેં હોય તો ટુંપતા પાર પણ આવે. પણ આ તો ખેતરનાં ખેતર છે.નથ્થુ૦ - સાલા, તારા હાડકાં જ આખાંછે તો.હજામ - કાકા, ઘઉંમાંથી વીણામણ નીકળે, પણ વીણામણમાંથીજ ઘઊં કહાડવા તે કેમ થાય?નથ્થુ૦ - અરે તેમ પણ મ્હારી પહેલી વારની કરતીતી જો.હજામ - ત્યારે આવો, આ ચીપિયો, મ્હારે કહાં ના છે? પણ તમરાથી ખમાસે ? કોઈ દહાડો ટુંપાવ્યુંછ?નથ્થુ૦ - બાપ જનમમાં કદી નહિ, પણ લગનનો ડારો ફડી ફડીને આવવાનોછ - (હજામ ટુંપે છે) અરર! ઊંઊં લગાર સમાલીને ટુંપ.હજામ -આટલામાં ઊંઊં કરોછ તો આગળ ટટ્ટુ કેમ ચાલશે ? કહો તો નહિ ટુંપું.નથ્થુ૦ - ટુંપ ટુંપ. (દાંત પીસી સેઠ બોલતા નથી, પણ બે ચાર નીમાળા લીધા એટલામાં બંને આંખમાંથી પાણી વહેવા માંડ્યાં)\\"આ કલાકારો ની આગળની વાતો શું હશે?","answer":"હજામ - સેઠ, મમતે મુસલમાન ન થાઓ. આંખે ઝાંપ તો વળેછ ને પુરું ધબાયનમ: કરવા બેઠાછ ? તમારી નજરમાં એમ હોય, કે જુવાન બૈરીના હેંસી વરસના ઘરડા ધણિયે આંધળા થવું, એમાંજ સુખ છે, તો હું પણ હા કહું છું.નથ્થુ૦ - સાલ્લા, હું તો પક્કા જુવાનને હઠાવું એવોછું. વારું, રાખ. નથી ટુંપવું (આંસુ લુછી નાખે છે.)હજામ - સેઠ, કુલફ લગાવો.નથ્થુ૦ - હા યાર, શાબાસ !ત્હેં અક્કલ ઠીક બતાવી. કમાલખાં ! કમાલખાં ! (કોઈ જવાબ દેતું નથી)હજામ - કમાલખાં !! કમાલખાં !!કમા૦ - મ્હેં આતા હું. હાથમે ચલમ હૈ.નથ્થુ૦ - ચલમકુ જલા દે ! જલદીથી આઓ.કમા૦ - સેઠ, ઈતહીની ડેર હૈ. ચલમકું જલાકર દેખો મ્હે અબી આયા.નથ્થુ૦ - હમણા કે હમણા તુમ આઓ. બહુ જરૂરકા કામ હૈ. યાદ રખો જો વાર લગીતો. (કમાલખાં આવે છે.)કમા૦ - સેઠ, તુમારી નોકરી તો બોત સકત ! ક્યાં હુકમ?નથ્થુ૦ - કમાલ , તેરી પાસ-પેલું-પેલું હજામ સ્હુંતો?હજામ -કુલફ, બાલ રંગનેકા.કમા૦ - મેરી પાસ કુલફ કૈસા ? ઓતો કબરસ્સ્તાન કે મુસાફીરકી પાસ હોવે. નથ્થુ૦ – હેં ! અલ્યા, કબરસ્તાનના મુસાફર તે ક્યા?કમા૦ – જેસા હિંદુસ્તાન, આરબસ્તાન, તુર્કસ્તાન ; તેસા કબરસ્તાનબી બડા મુલુક હૈ. હુંવા તુમેરે જેસે બડે બડે લોક જાતે હૈ.નથ્થુ૦ – વાવા ! ત્યારેતો તું કોઈ ઐસા મુસાફીરકી પાસ આણદે.કમા૦ – ક્યા સાબ, આપને કુલફ લગાને કી મરજી હૈ.નથ્થુ૦ – હાંહાં, મીયાં સાહેબ તું બડા અચ્છા નોકર હૈ. તુમ બોત સમજુ માણસ.કમા૦ – મ્હેં સમજા. કુલફકી જરૂરતો તુમકુ સહી.નથ્થુ૦ – અરે ભાઈ, બડી જરૂર. એતની મહેરબાની તો કરવી પડેગી."},{"question":"शीख राज्याची स्थापना कोणी केली ?","answer":"शीख राज्याची स्थापना महाराजा रणजितसिंगाने णी केली  ."},{"question":"أين يعيش أصغر انواع التماسيح؟","answer":"في نهر الكونغو بأفريقيا ويبلغ طوله 120 سم."},{"question":"கேள்வி :பாண்டியர்களின் ஓவியக்கலை வளர்ச்சியை பறைசாற்றுவதுஅ. மதுரைஆ. தொண்டிஇ. சித்தன்னவாசல்ஈ. மானமாமலை","answer":"பதில் :இ. சித்தன்னவாசல்"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe zavakanto \\"rock prehistoric\\"?","answer":"Ny zavakanto \\"rock prehistoric\\" dia ahitana sary hoso-doko sy sary sokitra vita amin'ny rindrin'ny lava-bato sy trano fialofana nataon'ny mponina taloha."},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండిఒక మోటారు వాహనాన్ని ఏటవాలు రోడ్డుపై దిగువకు స్థిరవడితో ప్రయాణం చేసేటట్లు బ్రేకులకు ఉపయోగిస్తే బ్రేక్ డ్రమ్ములు ఎందుకు వేడెక్కుతాయి? ","answer":"వాహనం వడి స్థిరముగా ఉన్నది కనుక దాని గతిశక్తిలో మార్పు ఉండదు. క్రిందకు వచ్చుచున్నది కనుక అది కొంత స్థితి శక్తిని కోల్పోవును. అది కోల్పోయిన స్థితిశక్తిలో కొంత భాగము ఉష్ణశక్తిగా మారును. అందువలన దాని బ్రేక్ డ్రమ్ వేడెక్కును."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe nosy?","answer":"Ny nosy dia velaran-tany voahodidin'ny rano amin'ny lafiny rehetra."},{"question":"Кандай жаңылмач билесиң ?","answer":"Ат-Башыдан аттын айкелин көрдүм,Ат-Башыдагы аттын айкелине чөгөлөдүм.Аттын айкели башы менен экен,Аттын башына эми кантип жетем,Андан көрө Ат-Башыга кетем."},{"question":"வினா : உலகளவில் 18 வது பெரிய தொலை நோக்கி எது ?","answer":"விடை : தமிழ் நாட்டில் உள்ள வைனிபாப்பு"},{"question":"لدينا الجملة التالية \\"آللهمَ إني أسألك من الخير كله ..عاجله وآجله ، ما علمت منه وما لم أعلم،،وأعوذ بك من الشر كله ..عاجله وآجله، ما علمت منه وما لم أعلم \\" هل المشاعر فيها 1. إيجابية 2. سلبية 3.حيادية","answer":"المشاعر في الجملة السابقة إيجابية."},{"question":"ਵਿਸ਼ਾਃ ਕੋਰੋਨਾਵਾਇਰਸ ਦੇ ਨਵੇਂ ਰੂਪ 'ਤੇ ਵੈਕਸੀਨ ਕਾਰਗਰ ਹੋਣ ਦੀ ਕਿੰਨੀ ਸੰਭਾਵਨਾ ।","answer":"ਮਾਹਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਇਹ ਸਲਾਹ ਅਜਿਹੇ ਸਮੇਂ ਆਈ ਹੈ ਜਦੋਂ ਯੂਕੇ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੋਵਿਡ-19 ਦੇ ਵਾਇਰਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਦਲਾਅ ਦੇਖਣ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਵਜ੍ਹਾ ਨਾਲ ਕੋਰੋਨਾ ਲਾਗ ਦੇ ਫ਼ੈਲਾਅ ਵਿੱਚ ਤੇਜ਼ੀ ਆਈ ਹੈ।ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲ ਕਰਦੇ ਹੋਏ ਮਾਹਰ ਕਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ ਕਿ ਵਾਇਰਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਦਲਾਅ ਬੇਸ਼ੱਕ ਹੋ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਜੋ ਵੈਕਸੀਨ ਬਣ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ ਉਹ ਨਵੇਂ ਵਾਇਰਸ 'ਤੇ ਵੀ ਅਸਰਦਾਰ ਹੋਵੇਗੀ।"},{"question":"కింది ప్రశ్నకు సమాధానం ఇవ్వండి:తరుగుదలను లెక్కించే పద్ధతులను తెలుపుము.","answer":"ఈ క్రింది పద్ధతుల ద్వారా తరుగుదలను లెక్కించవచ్చును:1. సరళరేఖా పద్ధతి.2. తగ్గుతున్న నిల్వల పద్ధతి.3. వార్షిక పద్ధతి.4. తరుగుదల నిధి పద్ధతి.5. భీమా పాలసీ పద్ధతి.6. పునర్మూల్యాంకన పద్దతి.7. తగ్గింపు పద్ధతి.8. గంటకు యంత్రం ఖర్చు రేటు పద్ధతి."},{"question":"Yesu alitabiliwaje?","answer":"Yesu alitabiliwa na manabii wengi sana kutoka katika biblia, ikiwemo musa, mika, isaya, matayo na manabii wengine wengi ambao wao hutupatia amani hii ya yesu kama bwana na mkombozi wa israel ya leo yaani watu wote walio salia katika ulimwengu huu"},{"question":"Àwọn iṣẹ́ wo ní ó pò jù lọ ni ayé àtijọ́ ní ilé Yorùbá?","answer":"Iṣẹ́ Àgbè ati Ìṣe Ọdẹ ní ó pò jù lọ ni ayé àtijọ́ ní ilé Yorùbá. I\\bse Àgbè ní Ìṣe ti o dara ju ati, ni opolopo igba, o ni ere julo."},{"question":"Тумар  бул ...","answer":"Тумар (кыргыз, араб сөздөрүнөн) - Диний ишеним боюнча шайтан, жинден, ар кандай кырсыктардан дуба жазылып, баалуу кездеме же булгары менен үч бурчтук түрүндө тышталып тигилет."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਸੁਣਿਐ ਦੀਪ ਲੋਅ ਪਾਤਾਲ ॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 2 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\"ਜੋ ਸਾਰੇ ਦੀਪਾਂ, ਲੋਕਾਂ, ਪਾਤਾਲਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਵਿਆਪਕ ਹੈ।\\""},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: നെൽകൃഷി കേരളത്തിന്റെ പരിസ്ഥിതിക്ക് എങ്ങനെ സംഭാവന നൽകുന്നു?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: തണ്ണീർത്തടങ്ങൾ സംരക്ഷിച്ചും ജൈവവൈവിധ്യത്തെ പിന്തുണച്ചും കാർബൺ സിങ്കായി പ്രവർത്തിച്ചും നെൽക്കൃഷി കേരളത്തിലെ പാരിസ്ഥിതിക സന്തുലിതാവസ്ഥ നിലനിർത്താൻ സഹായിക്കുന്നു."},{"question":"Awọn aṣofin ọmọ Yoruba fariga, wọn lẹnikẹni ko gbọdọ fiwa janduku ba ilẹ Yoruba jẹ","answer":"Lati fopin si rogbodiyan to n ṣẹlẹ lawọn ibi kan nilẹ Yoruba, lori bi wọn ti ṣe n jo ile, ti wọn n kọlu awọn teṣan ọlọpaa kiri, awọn aṣoju-ṣofin ti sọ pe, iru iwa bẹẹ gbọdọ dopin.Awọn asoju-sofin kan ti wọn je ọmọ Yoruba, eyi ti Ọnarebu Fẹmi Fakẹyẹ, jẹ olori wọn, ni wọn ba awọn oniroyin sọrọ yii niluu Abuja. Ohun ti wọn si sọ ni pe ki awọn to n jo ile, ti wọn n ba dukia jẹ kiri ma sọ ilẹ Yoruba doju ogun.Wọn ni loootọ ni gbogbo wa jẹ ọmọ orilẹ-ede yii, ṣụgbọn  kaluku lo mọ ilu to ti wa, ati pe ko ni i dara ti awọn eeyan kan, paapaa awọn atọhunrinwa ba sọ ipinlẹ Eko doju ogun, ti wọn n ba dukia ijọba ati ti araalu jẹ.Awọn aṣofin yii ti waa rọ awọn ọdọ ki wọn sinmi iwọde ti wọn n ṣe kiri niwọn igba ti ijọba ti gbohun wọn, ti igbesẹ si ti bẹrẹ lori ibeere wọn gbogbo.O ni, ko ni i wu awọn ki ilẹ Yoruba tun la iru ohun to la kọja laye ogun wẹ-tiẹ lọdun 1964 si 65. Fun idi, ki awọn ọdọ sinmi wahala ki alaafia le pada saarin ilu.Fakẹyẹ, tẹ siwaju pe, ki i ṣe pe awọn lodi si iwọde ifẹhonu han si ohun ti awọn ọdọ ko fẹ, ṣugbọn bi wọn ṣe n ba nnkan jẹ, ti ọpọ ẹmi n ṣofo ki i ṣe ohun ti awọn faramọ rara.Bẹẹ gẹgẹ lawọn aṣofin yii tun bu ẹnu atẹ lu bi wọn ti ṣe kọlu Aafin Ṣoun Ogbomọṣọ, Ọba Akiolu, ati bi wọn ṣe ba dukia Aṣiwaju Bọla Tinubu, jẹ atawọn dukia mi-in to jẹ ti ijọba atawọn araalu.O lawọn faramọ ̀ọrọ ti olori ile igbimọ aṣoju-ṣofin, Ọgbẹni Fẹmi Gbajabiamila sọ wi pe eto to yẹ gbọdọ wa fun awọn ti wọn ba dukia wọn jẹ, atawọn eeyan ti wọn padanu ẹmi awọn eeyan wọn ."},{"question":"මෙවර ( 2020 ) බුකර් සාහිත්‍ය සම්මානය හිමිවූ නවකථාව කුමක්ද ? ","answer":"මෙවර ( 2020 ) බුකර් සාහිත්‍ය සම්මානය හිමිවූ නවකථාව වන්නේ ස්කොට්ලන්ත ලේඛක ඩග්ලස් ස්ටුවර්ට් විසින් රචිත ශගී බේන් (Shuggie Bain) නම් නවකථාවයි"},{"question":"வினா: எந்த வெப்ப நிலையில் நீரின் அடர்த்தி அதிகபட்சமாக இருக்கும்?","answer":"விடை: 4 டிகிரி செல்சியஸ்"},{"question":"Escribe la continuación del texto - En 1553 el pirata Barbarroja (Jayr al-Din), intentó apoderarse de la ciudad que fue defendida con la ayuda del genovés Andrea Doria. El 29 de abril de 1587 sufrió el Saqueo... ","answer":"Este ataque fue parte de una serie de incursiones y saqueos realizados por piratas berberiscos en la región del norte de África durante ese período. "},{"question":"Conas a fhaigheann mic léinn deontas chun dul go dtí an ollscoil? ","answer":"Is féidir leat iarratas a dhéanamh ar dheontas ar líne trí shuíomh Gréasáin, agus níl sé ina phróiseas deacair. Tá a fhios agam go dteastaíonn litir glactha ó roinnt coláistí agus ollscoileanna. Ach níor chóir go mbeadh sé ró-deacair litir Glactha a fháil má fhaigheann tú gráid mhaith. Ansin gheobhaidh tú pacáiste cúnaimh airgeadais níos fearr, rud a thabharfaidh níos mó roghanna duit."},{"question":"Iza no nosy kely indrindra eran-tany?","answer":" \\"Eveka Rock Island\\" any Royaume Unis no nosy kely indrindra eran-tany."},{"question":"Maak de volgende zin af: In 1992 schreef Indurain zowel de Giro als de Tour op zijn naam, een prestatie die hij het jaar daarna zou herhalen. Daarmee was hij de eerste renner die \\"La Double\\" (Giro én Tour in één seizoen) tweemaal achter elkaar wist te winnen. Verder werd hij in 1992 kampioen van Spanje op de weg en won hij zilver op het","answer":"WK van 1993 na Lance Armstrong."},{"question":"Ireto misy fanambarana :  \\"Tian'izy ireo ny mijery sarimihetsika amin'ny zoma alina.\\" sy \\"Ny zoma hariva dia tia mijery sarimihetsika izy ireo.\\"Mifanindran-teny ve ireo ?","answer":"Eny, miresaka momban'ny fitiavana mijery sarimihetsika ny zoma hariva ireo."},{"question":"请回答以下问题：谁是墨西哥现任总统？","answer":"答案：墨西哥现任总统是安德烈斯·曼努埃尔·洛佩斯·奥夫拉多尔（Andrés Manuel López Obrador），2018年12月1日就职，任期6年。"},{"question":"செஸ் விளையாட்டு தோன்றிய நாடு?","answer":"இந்தியாவில் சதுரங்கம் முதன்முதலில் கிபி 6 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டில் தோன்றியது"},{"question":"Vraag: Welke zanger scoorde in Nederland hits met 'All Night Long' en 'Hello'? A. Lionel Richie, B. Bruce Springsteen C. Michael Jackson D. James Brown","answer":"Antwoord: A. Lionel Richie"},{"question":"این متن در مورد چه رویداد مهمی صحبت می کند:  ه لحاظ اقتصادی، تمدن غرب و تمدن شرق به شدت از نظر کسب درآمد متفاوت بودند. در چین یکی از عوامل اقتصادی مهم تجارت بود. آنها با جاده ابریشم به اروپا متصل شدند که شامل یک سری مسیرهای تجاری از شرق آسیا به اروپا بود. جاده ابریشم نه تنها برای تجارت کالاها استفاده می‌شد بلکه راهی برای تفکر و مذهب بود. انگلیسی‌ها نوع خاصی از فئودالیسم به نام فئودالیسم خشمگین به کار می‌بردند. این نوع فئودالیسم که در در جنگ رزها خیلی برجسته شده بود، با فئودالیسم منظم متفاوت بود، زیرا پول را در سلسله مراتب اجتماعی وارد کرد.","answer":"این متن درباره جنگ رزها صحبت می‌کند. جنگ‌هایی بودند که در نیمهٔ دوم سدهٔ پانزدهم در فاصلهٔ سال‌های ۱۴۵۵ تا ۱۴۸۵ بین دو خاندان قدرتمند لنکستر با نشان «گل سرخ» و خاندان یورک با نشان «رز سفید» و طرفداران آنها در انگلستان درگرفت. علت این درگیری‌ها تلاش هر یک از دو خاندان برای رساندن یکی از اعضای خود به پادشاهی انگلستان بود"},{"question":"પન્ના નાયકની \\"કોઈની બુદ્ધિના પાંજરામાં\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"કોઈની બુદ્ધિના પાંજરામાં લાગણીનું પંખી થઈ,ટહુક્યા કરવાનું મને મંજૂર નથી;કોઈ પ્રેમને નામે મને ડંખ્યા કરે,અને ઈચ્છા મુજબ મને ઝંખ્યા કરે;જે બોલે તે બોલવાનું ને નાગ જેમ ડોલવાનું,મને આવું અઢેલવાનું મંજૂર નથી.પોતાની આંખ હોય પોતાની પાંખ હોય,પોતાનું આભ હોય પોતાનું ગીત હોય,મનની માલિક હું મારે તે બીક શી?હું તો મૌલિક છું,હા માં હા કહીને ઠીક ઠીક રહીને,મને ઠીક ઠીક રહેવાનું મંજૂર નથી.માપસર બોલવાનું માપસર ચાલવાનું,માપસર પહેરવાનું માપસર પોઢવાનું,માપસર ઓઢવાનું,માપસર હળવાનું માપસર ભળવાનું,આવું હળવાનું ભળવાનું માપસર ઓગળવાનું,મને આવું પીગળવાનું મંજૂર નથી.કોઈની બુદ્ધિના પાંજરામાં લાગણીનું પંખી થઈ,ટહુક્યા કરવાનું મને મંજૂર નથી."},{"question":"Title: ਡੌਨਲਡ ਟਰੰਪ ਲਈ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ 'ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਆਜ਼ਾਦੀ' ਇੱਕ ਅਹਿਮ ਮੁੱਦਾ ਹੈ।","answer":"ਅਮਰੀਕੀ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਉਮੀਦ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਇਹ ਸਵਾਗਤ ਹਾਲ ਦੇ ਸਾਲਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿਸੇ ਵੀ ਵਿਦੇਸ਼ੀ ਆਗੂ ਨੂੰ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਸਨਮਾਨ ਨਾਲੋਂ ਵੱਧ ਹੋਵੇਗਾ।ਟਰੰਪ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਾਸਨ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦਾ ਇਹ ਵੀ ਕਹਿਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਟਰੰਪ ਦੀ ਸੋਮਵਾਰ ਤੋਂ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਹੋਣ ਵਾਲੀ ਭਾਰਤ ਯਾਤਰਾ ਦੋਹਾਂ ਦੇਸਾਂ ਵਿਚਾਲੇ ਵੱਧ ਰਹੇ ਵਪਾਰਕ ਮਤਭੇਦਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਘਟਾਉਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਮਦਦ ਕਰੇਗੀ।ਪਰ ਸ਼ੁੱਕਰਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ  ਦੋਹਾਂ ਦੇਸਾਂ ਦੀ ਪ੍ਰਸਤਾਵਿਤ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਦੇ ਏਜੰਡੇ ਦੇ ਬਾਰੇ ਆਏ ਟਰੰਪ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਾਸਨ ਦੇ ਬਿਆਨ 'ਤੇ ਅਚਾਨਕ ਸਭ ਦੀਆਂ ਨਜ਼ਰਾਂ ਟਿੱਕ ਗਈਆਂ ਹਨ।ਟਰੰਪ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਾਸਨ ਦੇ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, \\"ਮੈਨੂੰ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਪਤੀ ਟਰੰਪ ਆਪਣੇ ਜਨਤਕ ਸੰਬੋਧਨ ਅਤੇ ਫਿਰ ਪੱਕੇ ਤੌਰ 'ਤੇ ਨਿੱਜੀ ਰੂਪ ਵਿੱਚ ਲੋਕਤੰਤਰ ਅਤੇ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਆਜ਼ਾਦੀ ਦੀ ਸਾਡੀ ਸਾਂਝੀ ਪਰੰਪਰਾ ਬਾਰੇ ਗੱਲ ਕਰਨਗੇ। ਉਹ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਮੁੱਦਿਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਚੁੱਕਣਗੇ, ਖ਼ਾਸ ਕਰਕੇ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਆਜ਼ਾਦੀ ਦਾ ਮੁੱਦਾ, ਜੋ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਾਸਨ ਲਈ ਬਹੁਤ ਅਹਿਮ ਹੈ।\\"ਟਰੰਪ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਾਸਨ ਦੇ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀ ਨੇ ਅੱਗੇ ਕਿਹਾ, \\"ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਨਰਿੰਦਰ ਮੋਦੀ ਨਾਲ ਆਪਣੀ ਮੁਲਾਕਾਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਪਤੀ ਟਰੰਪ ਇਸ ਤੱਥ ਵੱਲ ਧਿਆਨ ਦਿਵਾਉਣਗੇ ਕਿ ਲੋਕਤੰਤਰੀ ਪਰੰਪਰਾਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਬਰਕਰਾਰ ਰੱਖਣ ਅਤੇ ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਘੱਟ-ਗਿਣਤੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਸਨਮਾਨ ਲਈ ਬਰਕਰਾਰ ਰੱਖਣ ਲਈ ਦੁਨੀਆਂ ਭਾਰਤ ਵੱਲ ਦੇਖ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ।\\"\\"ਬੇਸ਼ੱਕ ਇਹ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੇ ਸੰਵਿਧਾਨ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਹੈ - ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਆਜ਼ਾਦੀ, ਧਾਰਮਿਕ ਘੱਟ-ਗਿਣਤੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਸਨਮਾਨ ਅਤੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਧਰਮਾਂ ਲਈ ਬਰਾਬਰੀ ਦਾ ਦਰਜਾ।\\"ਵਿਚੋਲਗੀ ਦੇ ਮੁੱਦੇ ਬਾਰੇ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ।ਟਰੰਪ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਾਸਨ ਦੇ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, \\"ਮੈਨੂੰ ਲੱਗਦਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਤੁਸੀਂ ਰਾਸ਼ਟਰਪਤੀ ਤੋਂ ਜੋ ਸੁਣੋਗੇ, ਉਹ ਭਾਰਤ ਅਤੇ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦਰਮਿਆਨ ਤਣਾਅ ਨੂੰ ਘਟਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਬਹੁਤ ਉਤਸ਼ਾਹਜਨਕ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਦੋਹਾਂ ਦੇਸਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਸੀ ਮਤਭੇਦ ਸੁਲਝਾਉਣ ਲਈ ਇੱਕ-ਦੂਜੇ ਨਾਲ ਦੁਵੱਲੀ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹੋਣ ਲਈ ਉਤਸ਼ਾਹਤ ਕਰੇਗਾ।\\"\\"ਸਾਡਾ ਮੰਨਣਾ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਦੋਵਾਂ ਦੇਸਾਂ ਵਿਚਾਲੇ ਸਫ਼ਲ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਦੀ ਮੁੱਢਲੀ ਨੀਂਹ ਆਪਣੇ ਦੇਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਅੱਤਵਾਦੀਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਕੱਟੜਪੰਥੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਨੱਥ ਪਾਉਣ ਦੀਆਂ ਪਾਕਿਸਤਾਨ ਦੀਆਂ ਕੋਸ਼ਿਸ਼ਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਲਗਾਤਾਰ ਗਤੀ ਉੱਤੇ ਅਧਾਰਤ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਲਈ ਅਸੀਂ ਉਸ ਦੀ ਭਾਲ ਜਾਰੀ ਰੱਖਦੇ ਹਾਂ।\\"ਵਪਾਰਕ ਮੁੱਦੇ।ਪ੍ਰਧਾਨ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਮੋਦੀ ਭਾਰਤ ਨੂੰ ਦਿੱਤੀਆਂ ਜਾਣ ਵਾਲੀਆਂ ਕਾਰੋਬਾਰੀ ਰਿਆਇਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਬਹਾਲ ਕਰਨ ਦੀ ਮੰਗ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ ਜਿਸ ਨੂੰ ਟਰੰਪ ਪ੍ਰਸ਼ਾਸਨ ਨੇ 2019 ਵਿੱਚ ਬੰਦ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਸੀ।ਇਸੇ ਬਾਰੇ ਵ੍ਹਾਈਟ ਹਾਊ ਦੇ ਬੁਲਾਰੇ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, \\" ਜਿਸ ਕਾਰਨ ਭਾਰਤ ਦੀ ਜੀਐਸਪੀ ਨੂੰ ਮੁਅੱਤਲ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ, ਉਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਅਸੀਂ ਚਿੰਤਿਤ ਹਾਂ।\\"\\"ਅਸੀਂ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਯਾਦ ਦਿਵਾਉਣਾ ਚਾਹੁੰਦੇ ਹਾਂ ਕਿ ਭਾਰਤ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਕਈ ਖੇਤਰਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਬਾਜ਼ਾਰਾਂ ਲਈ ਢੁੱਕਵੀਂ ਅਤੇ ਵਾਜਬ ਪਹੁੰਚ ਮੁਹੱਈਆ ਕਰਾਉਣ ਵਿੱਚ ਅਸਫ਼ਲ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ।"},{"question":"Baqhubeka-ke nokudla, behlisa ingxoxo ngomculo omnandi owawudlala kulerestoranti. Ngesikade babambana ngezandla futhi, bangena emotweni, baphindelaefulethini likaMahlengi, kwaba yiso leso futhi sokuqabulana nokuxoxa ngokuningiokwakubahlekisa, kubadabukisa, kubajabulisa, kubenza bengaliboni newashi elaselihambile.'Ngeke sthandwa, kufanele ngihambile,' ebuka iwashi ehwaqa, enikina ikhanda.'Eyi, uqinisile, kuyasetshenzwa kusasa,' Bavalelisana kunzima, babambana,baqabulana, bethembisana lona uthando olungapheli, nokuhambisana ezinkingeniokwakufanele babhekane nazo. Wayiklwebha imoto uXolani yadabula idolobha elaselithule lingasaphithizeli, ibheke koDurban North emzini wakhe. Wayehamba eculaejabule lapha emotweni, esanganiswe wuthando olusha olwase lumenza acabangeizinto eziningi ayengakaze acabange ukuthi uyoke azenze empilweni. Njengakhoukudivosa nje. Yebo, kukhona okwakumtshela nje ukuthi usengamane alithethe kubekanye, uma engaqhubeka nokuzwa lolu thando aluzwa manje enhliziyweni ngenxakaMahlengi, hhayi usengalithetha ligcwele, sekungaklebhuka kwancwajana yomshadoleyo.Wayesacabanga ngedivosi ngenkathi eyongena ngesango kwakhe. Ekuqaleniwacabanga ukuthi udukile, wafifiyela. Hhayi, kwakusemzini wakhe lapha. Pho lesisixuku? Laba bantu bezicishamlilo? Wehla sekuxega amadolo.'Kwenzenjani emzini wami?' ebuza ehlahla amehlo.'Yithina okufanele ngabe sibuza wena?' kuhayiza umkakhe owayesingethwe yiphoyisa,lenza umzamo owawubukeka ungaphumeleli wokumduduza nokumthulisa.'Kwenzenjani?' ebuza ediyazela.'Uphumaphi? Izingane zize ziyafa awukho wena?' Ahayize kakhulu.'Izingane zifile?' ebuza ngeliqhaqhazelayo.'Yebo,' kusho iphoyisa eduze kwakhe, lidonsa umoya kakhulu.'Bekwenzenjani?''Kakuqondakali okwamanje. Kusobala ukuthi kusuke umlilo ngaphakathi. Umnyangoubuhluthulelwe. Bahlulekile ukuphuma. Lwephuzile ukufika usizo.' 1. Ngokucabanga kwakho yini inhloso yombhali yokusebenzisa amagamaesiNgisi njengoba enjalo kule noveli? ","answer":"Inoveli eyesikhathi samanje ekhombisa ukuthi abalingiswa bafundile futhi lelizwe seliqhakambisa ubuliminingi/ezinye zezinto okukhulunywa ngazo kulenoveli azinawo amagama esiZulu. "},{"question":"Soạn bài Ông đồ Ngữ văn lớp 7","answer":"- Ngoài bài thơ Đêm nay Bác không ngủ của Minh Huệ (đã học ở lớp 6), em còn biết thêm bài thơ năm chữ là: Mưa đêm, Thăm lại trường xưa, Thao thức, Trở gió…- Tác giả Vũ Đình LiênVũ Đình Liên (12/11/1913- 18/1/1996) sinh tại Hà Nội, nhưng quê gốc ở thôn Châu Khê, xã Thúc Kháng, huyện Bình Giang, tỉnh Hải Dương.Vũ Đình Liên là một trong những nhà thơ lớp đầu tiên của phong trào Thơ mới. Ngoài thơ ông còn hoạt động trong lĩnh vực lý luận, phê bình văn học và dịch thuật. Ông là hội viên sáng lập Hội nhà văn VN. Một số bài thơ: Ông đồ, Lòng ta là những hàng thành quách cũ, Luỹ tre xanh, Người đàn bà điên ga Lưu xá... Sơ thảo lịch sử văn học Việt Nam (cùng Nhóm Lê Quý Đôn – 1957), Nguyễn Đình Chiểu (1957)…- Chữ Nho và nghệ thuật viết chữ Nho (thư pháp).+ Chữ Nho còn gọi là chữ Nôm cũ là hệ thống văn tự ngữ tố dùng để viết tiếng Việt. Chữ Nôm được tạo ra dựa trên cơ sở là chữ Hán (chủ yếu là phồn thể), vận dụng phương thức tạo chữ hình thanh, hội ý, giả tá của chữ Hán để tạo ra các chữ mới bổ sung cho việc viết và biểu đạt các từ thuần Việt không có trong bộ chữ Hán ban đầu. Chữ Nôm bắt đầu hình thành và phát triển từ thế kỷ 10 đến thế kỷ 20.+ Nghệ thuật thư pháp: Thư pháp xuất hiện hầu như đồng thời với sự hình thành văn tự bởi nhu cầu trình bày trang nhã và minh bạch văn bản. Công cụ chính tạo nên thư pháp là bút và chất liệu lưu trữ văn tự, mà sau được hiểu gồm mực và giấy. Thư pháp gia thường không nhất thiết phải là bậc trí giả nhưng ít nhiều được coi trọng nhờ vốn học vấn đủ để biên chép và họ có khả năng đẩy văn tự lên tầm nghệ thuật."},{"question":"ਮੁੰਦਾ ਸੰਤੋਖੁ ਸਰਮੁ ਪਤੁ ਝੋਲੀ ਧਿਆਨ ਕੀ ਕਰਹਿ ਬਿਭੂਤਿ ॥ ਖਿੰਥਾ ਕਾਲੁ ਕੁਆਰੀ ਕਾਇਆ ਜੁਗਤਿ ਡੰਡਾ ਪਰਤੀਤਿ ॥ਆਈ ਪੰਥੀ ਸਗਲ ਜਮਾਤੀ ਮਨਿ ਜੀਤੈ ਜਗੁ ਜੀਤੁ ॥ ਆਦੇਸੁ ਤਿਸੈ ਆਦੇਸੁ ॥ ਆਦਿ ਅਨੀਲੁ ਅਨਾਦਿ ਅਨਾਹਤਿ ਜੁਗੁ ਜੁਗੁ ਏਕੋ ਵੇਸੁ ॥੨੮॥","answer":"(ਹੇ ਜੋਗੀ!) ਜੇ ਤੂੰ ਸੰਤੋਖ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੀਆਂ ਮੁੰਦਰਾਂ ਬਣਾਵੇ, ਮਿਹਨਤ ਨੂੰ ਖੱਪਰ ਤੇ ਝੋਲੀ, ਅਤੇ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੇ ਧਿਆਨ ਦੀ ਸੁਆਹ (ਪਿੰਡੇ ਤੇ ਮਲੇਂ) , ਮੌਤ (ਦਾ ਭਉ) ਤੇਰੀ ਗੋਦੜੀ ਹੋਵੇ, ਸਰੀਰ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਾ ਕੇ ਰੱਖਣਾ ਤੇਰੇ ਲਈ ਜੋਗ ਦੀ ਰਹਿਤ ਹੋਵੇ ਅਤੇ ਸ਼ਰਧਾ ਨੂੰ ਡੰਡਾ ਬਣਾਵੇਂ (ਤਾਂ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਕੂੜ ਦੀ ਕੰਧ ਟੁੱਟ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ) ।ਜੋ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਸਾਰੀ ਸ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਟੀ ਦੇ ਜੀਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਆਪਣੇ ਸੱਜਣ ਮਿੱਤਰ ਸਮਝਦਾ ਹੈ (ਅਸਲ ਵਿਚ) ਉਹੀ ਆਈ ਪੰਥ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੈ। ਜੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਮਨ ਜਿੱਤਿਆ ਜਾਏ, ਤਾਂ ਸਾਰਾ ਜਗਤ ਹੀ ਜਿੱਤਿਆ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ (ਭਾਵ, ਤਾਂ ਜਗਤ ਦੀ ਮਾਇਆ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਤੋਂ ਵਿਛੋੜ ਨਹੀਂ ਸਕਦੀ) । (ਸੋ, ਕੂੜ ਦੀ ਕੰਧ ਦੂਰ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ) ਕੇਵਲ ਉਸ (ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ) ਨੂੰ ਪ੍ਰਣਾਮ ਕਰੋ, ਜੋ (ਸਭ ਦਾ) ਮੁੱਢ ਹੈ, ਜੋ ਸੁੱਧ ਸਰੂਪ ਹੈ, ਜਿਸ ਦਾ ਕੋਈ ਮੁੱਢ ਨਹੀਂ (ਲੱਭ ਸਕਦਾ) , ਜੋ ਨਾਸ-ਰਹਿਤ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਜੋ ਸਦਾ ਹੀ ਇਕੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹੈ। 28।"},{"question":"Mubvunzo: Grand Canyon yakava paki yenyika rini Mhinduro:","answer":"Kukadzi 26, 1919"},{"question":"Completa la siguiente frase:  Paola Félix (23 de marzo de 1983) es una deportista mexicana que compitió en taekwondo. Ganó una medalla en el","answer":"Campeonato Mundial de Taekwondo de 2001, y tres medallas en el Campeonato Panamericano de Taekwondo entre los años 2000 y 2004."},{"question":"Inona no anjara asan'ny fankasitrahana amin'ny fahatsapana tsara?","answer":"Ny fampiharana ny fankasitrahana dia midika hoe mahafantatra sy mankasitraka ireo lafiny tsara amin'ny fiainana. Nampifandraisina tamin'ny fitomboan'ny fahasambarana sy ny fahasalamana ankapobeny izany."},{"question":"Awọn janduku ya bo ile Tẹslim Fọlarin n’Ibadan, ọkada, ẹrọ ata, maṣinni iranṣọ, jẹneretọ ni wọn ko nibẹ","answer":"O jọ pe pupọ ninu awọn araalu ni ko fẹẹ duro de ijọba tabi oloṣelu kankan mọ lori ohun iranwọ ti wọn maa n ṣe fun wọn, niṣe ni wọn lọọ n fọle, ti wọn si n fọwọ ara wọn ko ohun ti wọn ba fẹ.Idi ni pe awọn kan ti ya lọ sile ọkan ninu awọn sẹnetọ to n ṣoju awọn eeyan Ibadan, Teslim Fọlarin. Gbogbo awọn ẹru bii ọkada, maṣinni atawọn nnkan mi-in ti ọkunrin oloṣelu naa ko pamọ tawọn kan gbagbọ pe o feẹ fi ṣe eto ironilagbara fawọn araalu ni wọn n ko kẹtikẹti bayii.Ọkada bii igba, (200), firisa bii ọgọrun-un (100), ẹrọ ilọta bii igba (200) ati ẹrọ amunawa bii igba (200) ni awọn eeyan yii lọọ ko nile ọkunrin naa to wa ni Oluyọle, niluu Ibadan.Ni kete ti wahala a n sun ile, a n sun teṣan ọlọpaa ti lọ silẹ lawọn eeyan orilẹ-ede yii tun ti jagbọn ohun mi-in, paapaa lawọn ilẹ Yoruba.Nipinlẹ Eko gan-an ni wahala ọhun ti bẹrẹ, ile ounjẹ kan lawọn eeyan lọọ ja ni Mazamaza atawọn ibomi-in kaakiri Eko. Bẹẹ gẹgẹ nirufẹ iṣẹlẹ yii waye l’Ọṣun, Kwara atawọn ilu nla nla mi-in.Ni bayii, ọna ara ti araalu tun gba yọ si awọn oloṣelu, paapaa awọn ti wọn ko ohun iranwọ rẹpẹtẹ sile, niṣe lawọn eeyan n lọọ ja ibi ti wọn ko wọn si, ti wọn si n fọwọ ara wọn ran awọn lọwọ.Fidio kan lawọn eeyan tun n wo bayii, ilu Ibadan lo ti ṣẹlẹ, niṣe lawọn eeyan ya lọ si ile nla ti oloṣelu kan ko ọkada rẹpẹtẹ si, bi wọn ti ṣe n gbe e ni wọn n lọọ pera wọn wa, ti wọn si n ko o kẹtikẹti.Ki i ṣe iyẹn nikan o, bẹẹ gẹgẹ lọrọ ri ni Ikirun, bi wọn ṣe n ko maṣinni ilọta, ni wọn n gbe ọkada ati ẹrọ amomitutu.  ALAROYE gbọ pe awọn oloṣelu kan lo ko o pamọ, ti wọn fẹẹ fi ṣeto iranwọ, ṣugbọn tawọn araalu lọọ n gbe e funra wọn bayii.Ẹnikan to ba ALAROYE sọrọ sọ pe ohun ti awọn eeyan naa n ṣe yoo lẹyin, nitori pupọ ninu awọn eeyan ti fidio gbe oju wọn yii, lo ṣee ṣe ki ọrọ ọhun di ẹjọ si lọrun nigba to ba ya."},{"question":"ਯੁੱਧ ਕਾਰਨ ਮਰਨ ਵਾਲੇ ਨਾਗਰਿਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਦੀ ਗਿਣਤੀ ਵੱਧ ਗਈ। | ਨਤੀਜੇ ਵਜੋਂ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ? ਚੋਣ 1 : ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀਵਾਦੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਵਿਰੋਧ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਕੀਤਾ। ਚੋਣ 2 : ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀਵਾਦੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਪਰੇਡ ਕੱਢੀ। ","answer":"ਚੋਣ 1 : ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀਵਾਦੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਵਿਰੋਧ ਪ੍ਰਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਕੀਤਾ।"},{"question":"பெருஞ்சித்திரனாரை ஆதரித்தவன் யார்?","answer":"பெருஞ்சித்திரனாரை ஆதரித்தவன் குமணன்.குமணன் சங்ககால மன்னர். முதிரம் இவர் நாடு. இவர் சிறந்த கொடையாளி. பெருஞ்சித்திரனார், பெருந்தலைச்சாத்தனார் ஆகிய புலவர்கள் இவரைப் பாடியுள்ளனர். இவர் கடையெழு வள்ளல்கள் காலத்துக்குப் பின்னர் வாழ்ந்தவர். இவரது தம்பி இளங்குமணன்.யானைப்பரிசில்குமணன் அரசனாக விளங்கியபோது பெருஞ்சித்திரனார் தன் வறுமை நிலையைக் கூறிக் குமணனிடம் தான் யானைமீது செல்லும் வகையில் பரிசில் தருமாறு வேண்டினார். அவனும் அவ்வாறே கொடுத்தான். தன் இல்லம் திரும்பும் வழியில் இளவெளிமான் நாட்டுக்கு வந்து தன் பெருமிதம் தோன்றத் தன் யானையை அவனது காவல்மரத்தில் கட்டிவிட்டு, அவனிடமே சென்று தன் பெருமிதத்தை வெளிப்படுத்தினார்.வாள் தந்தனன்குமணனை அவன் தம்பி இளங்குமணன் நாடுகடத்திவிட்டான். குமணன் காட்டில் தலைமறைவாக வாழ்ந்துவந்தான். குமணனிடம் பரிசில் பெறச் சென்ற புலவர் பெருந்தலைச்சாத்தனார் நிலைமையைத் தெரிந்துகொண்டு காட்டிற்குச் சென்று குமணனைப் பாடினார். புலவருக்குத் தரக் குமணனுக்குத் தன்னைத் தவிர வேறொன்றும் இல்லை. குமணன் தன் வாளைப் புலவர்க்குக் கொடுத்தான். குமணன் தலையைக் கொண்டுவருவோருக்குத் தக்க பரிசில் வழங்கப்படும் என்று இளங்குமணன் அறிவித்திருந்தான். குமணன் தன் வாளைப் புலவருக்குக் கொடுத்தது, தன் தலையையே வெட்டியெடுத்து எடுத்துச் செல்வதற்காகவே. குமணன் தந்த வாளே தனக்குப் போதும் என்று வாளைமட்டும் எடுத்துக்கொண்டு புலவர் இளங்குமணனிடம் வந்து வாளைக் காட்டி நிகழ்ந்ததைக் கூறினார். இளங்குமணன் புலவர்க்குப் பரிசில் நல்கியிருக்கலாம். அதைக்கொண்டு புலவர் தன் வறுமையைப் போக்கிக்கொண்டிருக்க வேண்டும்."},{"question":"Iza no anaran'ilay mpanjaka nampianatra ny vahoaka malagasy hihinana hen'omby?","answer":"I Ralambo no mpanjaka nampianatra ny vahoaka malagasy hihinana hen'omby."},{"question":"භූමි ප්‍රමාණය අනුව ලෝකයේ විශාලතම රට කුමක්ද?","answer":" රුසියාව"},{"question":" \\"УКК\\" - кыскартылган сөздүн түшүндүрмөсү кандай  ?","answer":"УКК—Улуттук коопсуздук кызматы;"},{"question":"මිනිස් වාසයක් සහිත ලොව ශීතලම ප්‍රදේශය කුමක්ද?","answer":"මිනිස් වාසයක් සහිත ලොව ශීතලම ප්‍රදේශය  \\"ඔයිම්යකොන්\\" වේ."},{"question":"සිංහල ජන කතාවක් කියන්න","answer":"හා හාමිගේ කතාවඔන්න එක කැලයක ලස්සන හාවෙක් ජිවත් වුණා. මේ හාවාට තිබුණා ලස්සන දිග රැවුලක්. දවසක් මේ හාවාට හිතුණා උගේ රැවුල කපන්න. ඉතින් හාවා බාබර් සාප්පුවට ගියා රැවුල කපාගන්න.''කරුණාකරලා මගේ මේ රැවුල කපනවද?'' හාවා බාබර් උන්නැහේට කිව්වා.බාබර් උන්නැහේත් හාවාගේ රැවුල කැපුවා.හාවා හරි සතුටින් ගෙදර ගියා. ටික වෙලාවක් යනකොට හාවාට හිතුණා ''අනේ මගේ රැවුල තිබුණන් කොච්චර හොදද'' කියලා. හාවා ආපහු බාබර් සාප්පුවට ගිහින් එයාගෙ රැවුල ඉල්ලුවා.''මම කොහොමද ඔයාගේ රැවුල දෙන්නෙ. මෙච්චර වෙලා කපපු රැවුල්, කොණ්ඩ ඔක්කොම අතුගාලා දැම්මනේ. දැන් ඔයාගේ රැවුල ආපහු හොයන්න බෑ.'' බාබර් උන්නැහේ කිව්වා.හාවාට හරිම දුකයි. ''මගේ රැවුල ආපහු මට දෙන්න කියලා'' හාවා කරදර කරන්න පටන් ගත්තා.බේරෙන්නම බැරි තැන බාබර් උන්නැහේ කිව්වා,''මට ඔයාගේ රැවුල දෙන්න නම් බැහැ. කැමතිනම් මගේ මේ දැලි පිහිය දෙන්නම් කියලා''.හාවා කමක්නැහැ කියලා පිහියත් අරගෙන ගෙදර යන්න පිටත් වුණා. මෙහෙම යනකොට හාවාට හමුවුණා අඹ ගොඩක් අරගෙන එන මනුස්සයෙක්. එයා ළග ඉදුණු අඹ ගොඩක් තිබුණා. හාවා ඒ මනුස්සයගෙන් අඹ ඉල්ලුවා. එයා බැහැ කිව්වා.''මං ලග පිහියක් තියෙනවා. ඔය අඹ වෙනුවට මම ඔයාට පිහිය දෙන්නම්.'' හාවා කිව්වා. මනුස්සයා කැමති වෙලා පිහිය අරගෙන හාවාට අඹ දුන්නා.හාවා අඹත් අරගෙන යනවා. මගදි හාවාට හම්බවුණා තෙල් අරගෙන යන මනුස්සයෙක්.''අනේ හාවො, මට ඔය අඹ දෙනවාද?'' අර මනුස්සයා ඉල්ලුවා. හාවා කැමති වුණේ නැහැ.'' මම ඔයාට මේ තෙල් දෙන්නම්. ඒ වෙනුවට මට අඹ දෙන්න.''  හාවා ඒකට කැමති වෙලා තෙල් අරගෙන අඹ දුන්නා.හාවා දැන් තෙල් අරගෙන ගෙදර යනවා. මෙහෙම යනකොට හාවාට කැවුම් සුවදක් ආවා. වටපිට බලනකොට දැක්කා එක ගෙදරක කැවුම් උයනවා. හාවා ඒ ගෙදරට ගියා. ගෙදර හිටිය නැන්ද කෙනෙක් කැවුම් උයනවා. හරිම සුවදයි.''අනේ නැන්දෙ, මට කැවුම් දෙනවාද? මම මේ තෙල් ටික ඔයාට දෙන්නම්'' හාවා කිව්වා. ඒ නැන්දත් කැමති වෙලා හාවාගෙන් තෙල් අරගෙන ඌට කැවුම් මල්ලක් දුන්නා.හාවා දැන් කැවුම් මල්ලත් අරගෙන ගෙදර යනවා. කැලේ මැදින් යනකොට හාවාට හම්බවුණා තවත් මනුස්සයෙක්. ඒ මනුස්සයා ලග තිබුණා බෙරයක්. හාවාට දැන් බෙරය ඕන වුණා.''මම ළග කැවුම් ගොඩක් තියනවා. මම මේ කැවුම් ඔක්කොම ඔයාට දෙනවා. මට ඔය බෙරේ දෙනවද?'' හාවා ඇහුවා. ඒ මනුස්සයත් කැමති වෙලා කැවුම් අරගෙන හාවාට බෙරය දුන්නා.හාවා බෙරයත් අරගෙන කැලේ මැදින් යනවා. හාවාට මහන්සියි. ඌ ගං ඉවුරෙ ඉදගත්තා. බෙරේ අතට ගත්ත හාවා බෙරේ ගහන්න පටන් ගත්තා.''රැවුල දීලා පිහිය ගත්තා ඩුං ඩුං ඩුංපිහිය දීලා අඹ ගත්තා ඩුං ඩුං ඩුංඅඹ දීලා තෙල් ගත්තා ඩුං ඩුං ඩුංතෙල් දීලා කැවුම් ගත්තා ඩුං ඩුං ඩුංකැවුම් දීලා බෙරේ ගත්තා ඩුං ඩුං ඩුං''"},{"question":"Ano ang ibig sabihin kapag ang isang tao ay \\"balat-sibuyas\\"?","answer":"Sensitibo at madaling masaktan ang isang taong tinawag na \\"balat-sibuyas\\". Inihahalintulad ang ganitong tao na madaling naapektuhan sa balat ng sibuyas na manipis at madaling masira kapag hindi iningatan."},{"question":"为以下的原文给译文：滕文公问曰：“滕，小国也，间于齐、楚。事齐乎？事楚乎？”孟子对曰：“是谋非吾所能及也。无已，则有一焉：凿斯池也，筑斯城也，与民守之，效死而民弗去，则是可为也。”","answer":"滕文公问道：“滕国是个小国，夹在齐国和楚国的中间，侍奉齐国呢，还是侍奉楚国呢？”孟子回答道：“谋划这个问题不是我力所能及的。一定要我说，就只有一个办法：深挖护城河，筑牢城墙，与百姓共同守卫，百姓宁可献出生命也不逃离，这样就好办了。”"},{"question":" iye ọjọ́ mélòó ni ó ṣeéṣe kí omíyalé àgbàrá ya ṣọ́ọ̀bù ṣọṣẹ́ láwọn ìpínlẹ̀ kọ̀ọ̀kan ló rílẹ̀dè Nìájiria ","answer":"jọba àpapọ̀ ti kéde pé ó ṣeéṣe kí àwọn ìpínlẹ̀ tí odò River Benue gba ọ̀dọ̀ wọn kọjá bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ní omíyalé àgbàrá ya ṣọ́ọ̀bù ní ọ̀sẹ̀ kan sí àsìkò yìí bí orílẹ̀èdè Cameroon ṣe ṣí odò Ladgo.Mínísítà fún ìbojú àánú woni àti pípa òṣì rẹ́, Dókítà Betta Edu ní ìgbìmọ̀ kan tí ààrẹ Bola Tinubu gbé dìde láti wá ojútùú sí ìṣòro náà yóò bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ní gbé àwọn ètò kalẹ̀ láti rii dájú ìpalára tí ìjàmbá náà yóò fà kò ní kọjá bó ṣe yẹ.Betta Edu rọ àwọn gómínà àwọn ìpínlẹ̀ yìí láti tètè gbé ìgbésẹ̀, kí wọ́n kó àwọn ènìyàn ìpínlẹ̀ wọn tọ wà ní àwọn agbègbè tí ẹ̀kúnwọ́ omi yìí le ṣe àkóbá fún lọ sí òkè odò, níbi tí ààbò tó péye ti wà fún wọn.Ó ní ààrẹ Tinubu níbi ìpàdé ìgbìmọ̀ aláṣẹ Nàìjíríà tó wáyé lọ́jọ́ Ajé ti pa á láṣẹ fún gbogbo àwọn ilé iṣẹ́ tí ọ̀rọ̀ náà kàn láti foríkorí, kí wọ́n wá ọ̀nà àbáyọ sí ìṣòro ọ̀hún.Ó ṣàlàyé pé pẹ̀lú bí Cameroom ṣe sí odò Lagdo, kò ní pẹ́ tí àwọn ìpínlẹ̀ tí wọ́n wà ní àwọn bèbè omi yìí yóò bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí ní rí ìpalára rẹ̀ àti pé omíyalé jẹ́ ìṣòro kan gbòógì ní orílẹ̀ èdè Nàìjíríà èyí tó ti fá ìpàdánù ẹ̀mí àti dúkìá.“Ààrẹ ti fún wa níṣẹ́ láti ri dájú pé a gbáradì bó ṣe yẹ fún ìpalára ṣíṣí odò Lagdo.”“Lára àwọn nǹkan tí àwọn ìjọba ìpínlẹ̀ yìí gbọ́dọ̀ kọ́kọ́ mójútó ni pé gbogbo àwọn ojúṣàn àgbàrá àti kòtò ìdominù ló wà ní mímọ́.”Bákan náà ló ní àwọn ìjọba ìpínlẹ̀ yìí gbọ́dọ̀ ṣe ètò ìlanilọ́yẹ̀ tó péye fún àwọn ará ìlú lórí ìpalára omíyalé àgbàrá ya ṣọ́ọ̀bù.”“Gbogbo àwọn ará ìlú tó bá kọ̀, tí wọn kò bá fẹ́ kó kúrò níbi tí omíyalé ti le ṣe ìjàmbá fún wọn ni ìjọba níl]o láti mójútó nítorí orílẹ̀ èdè yìí k]o tún gbọdọ̀ fijú winá ìpàdánù ẹ̀mí àti dúkìá sọ́wọ́ omíyalé àgbàrá ya ṣọ́ọ̀bù bíi ti ọdún tó kọjá.”Bẹ́ẹ̀ náà ni Mínísítà fétò àyíká Iziaq Salako àti Mínísítà fọ́rọ̀ omi àti ìmọ́tótó, Ọ̀jọ̀gbọ́n Joseph Utsez tí wọ́n wà níbi ìpàdé náà ṣèlérí láti gbé ìgbésẹ̀ akin láti mójútó omíyalé àgbàrá ya ṣọ́ọ̀bù náà."},{"question":"Viết tiếp đoạn văn sau: Iulian, người đàn ông Romania chăn cừu bên bờ sông Danube, cho biết ông đã nhìn thấy UAV bay dọc sông để tấn công lãnh thổ Ukraine, nhưng bị lực lượng phòng không của Kiev ngăn chặn. \\"Tôi thấy chúng bị bắn hạ ngay tại đó, rồi khói lửa bốc lên\\", ông kể.","answer":"Danube, con sông rộng vài trăm mét chảy dọc biên giới Ukraine - Romania trước khi đổ ra Biển Đen, là khoảng cách ngăn một cuộc tập kích vào Ukraine trở thành đòn tấn công vào toàn bộ liên minh NATO. Nếu UAV Nga bay chệch mục tiêu và lao vào lãnh thổ Romania, xung đột quy mô lớn có thể bùng nổ, bởi NATO có trách nhiệm bảo vệ đồng minh theo điều khoản phòng thủ chung của khối."},{"question":"O que estava escrito na lápide do homem que não saía da internet?","answer":"Enfim, offline."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : తుగ్లక్ ల కాలంలో రాగి, ఇత్తడి నాణేలను ప్రవేశపెట్టడంపై మీ అభిప్రాయం ఏమిటి?","answer":"తుగ్లక్ యొక్క అతిసాహసిక పరిపాలనా చర్యలలో రాగి నాణెములు ప్రవేశపెట్టడం అత్యంత ప్రధానమైన చర్య.సైనిక ఖర్చు పెరుగుట, రాజధాని మార్పిడి ఖర్చు, కరువుకాటకాల కారణంగా ఈ సంస్కరణను అమలు జరిపెను.అయితే ఆనాటి పరిస్థితులకు అనగా వెండి కొరతగా ఉండటం వలన ఈ చర్య సమంజసమైనదే.చైనా కుబ్లయి ఖాన్, మంగోలు పాలకుడు గైఖాతులు అప్పటికే ఈ నామమాత్రపు కరెన్సీని అమలు చేయటంలో విజయం సాధించారు.తుగ్లక్ విఫలమవ్వటానికి కారణం, తన మంత్రులను సంప్రదించక అధికార దాహంతో ఈ సంస్కరణను అమలు చేయాలని తాపత్రయపడుట, ప్రజలు స్వార్థపరులగుట, ప్రభుత్వము నాణెముల ముద్రణను గుత్తాధికారముగ అమలు జరపకపోవుట."},{"question":"Como é chamado o arremesso em que o jogador salta e arremessa a bola no aro enquanto está no ar?","answer":"Esse tipo de arremesso é chamado de \\"enterrada\\" ou \\"dunk.\\" É uma jogada espetacular em que o jogador salta alto o suficiente para colocar a bola diretamente no aro."},{"question":"තම මංගල ටෙස්ට් තරඟය තුළ ද්විත්ව ශතකයක් වාර්තා කළ එකම ශ්‍රීලාංකික පිතිකරුවා කවුද?","answer":"බ්‍රෙන්ඩන් කුරුප්පු"},{"question":"पुरानो थकान सिन्ड्रोम (CFS) भएका व्यक्तिहरूमा लक्षणहरूको कमीमा ध्यानको प्रभाव अन्वेषण गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"ध्यानले ऊर्जा स्तर सुधार गरेर, तनाव कम गरेर, र राम्रो निद्रालाई बढावा दिएर क्रोनिक थकान सिन्ड्रोमका लक्षणहरू व्यवस्थापन गर्न प्रतिज्ञा देखाएको छ। यसले व्यक्तिहरूलाई CFS सँग सम्बन्धित चुनौतीहरू व्यवस्थापन गर्न उपकरणहरू प्रदान गर्दछ।"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"abu dajal\\"? Berikan ayat contoh untuk peribahasa tersebut.","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang jahat yang suka menggangu orang lain. Contoh ayat: Selagi ada Abu Dajal di tepi jalan itu, tiada seorang gadis pun yang berani lalu di situ."},{"question":"다음 문장 뒤에 올 문단을 완성시키시오. 제2차 세계대전 기간인 1943년에 연합군과 독일 양측의 폭격으로 막대한 피해를 입었다.","answer":"연합군의 시칠리아 침공의 암호명 \\"허스키 작전\\"이 영국군의 시칠리아섬 남동쪽 공격과 함께 1943년 7월 9-10일 사이 밤에 이뤄졌다. 작전 계획은 버나드 로 몽고메리의 제8군 휘하 부대인 영국 제5 보병 사단이 침공 첫 날에 시라쿠사를 점령하는 것이었다. 이 작전은 계획에 따라 성공적으로 이뤄졌고, 영국군은 작전 첫 번째 밤에 시라쿠사를 점령해낸다. 시라쿠사의 항구는 영국 왕립 해군의 기지로 쓰였다. 도시 서쪽에는 대략 1천명이 묻혀있는 영연방전쟁묘소가 있다. 종전후, 시라쿠사 북쪽 지구는 빠른 산업화의 과정으로 크고, 잦은 혼란스러움을 겪었다."},{"question":"Af-soomaliga muxuu hodan ku yahey?","answer":"Afsoomaaliga wuxuu hodan Ku yahey Maansada."},{"question":"በአፍሪካ በሕዝብ ብዛት አንደኛ ሀገር ማን ነች?","answer":"ናይጄሪያ"},{"question":"Ndàx man ngaa jubbanti mbind mii?Éy yéen way-gëm yi! Buleen di wax [sàmmoonteel ak nun], deeleen wax: \\"Xool nu\\" ; te deeleen dégg [ndigal] ! Mbugal mu metti mooy dal ca kaw way-weddi ña.","answer":"Waaw! Mi ngii:Éy yéen waygëm yi! Buléen di wàx [sàmmoonteel ak nun], deeléen wàx: \\"Xool nu\\"; te deeléen dégg [ndigal]! Mbugal mu metti moo'y dàl ca kaw wayweddi ña."},{"question":"સરળ રીતે સમજાવો કે શા માટે ૨૧૬ એ સાચો જવાબ છેઃ લેગોલેન્ડમાં દરેક કોઆલા માટે  કેંગારુ છે. જો લેગોલેન્ડમાં ૧૮૦ કંગારૂ છે, તો કુલ કેટલા કોઆલા અને કંગારૂ છે? સમજૂતીઃ","answer":"દરેક ૫ કાંગારૂ માટે, એક કોઆલા છે, જેનો અર્થ છે કે ૧૮૦ કાંગારૂ માટે, ૧૮૦/ ૫  = ૩૬  કોઆલા છે. કુલ મળીને, ૩૬  + ૧૮૦  = ૨૧૬  કોઆલા અને કાંગારૂ છે."},{"question":"Awọn agbebọn tu ijokoo igbimọ alaṣẹ Kwara Poly ka n’Ilọrin ","answer":"Ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, ni awọn janduku agbebọn ti wọn fura si gẹgẹ bii ọmọ ẹlẹgbẹ okunkun, ya bo ijokoo igbimọ alaṣẹ to n gbẹjọ lori awọn akẹkọọ to ṣe magomago lakooko idanwo, ti wọn si tu ijokoo naa ka, ninu ọgba ile ẹkọ ọhun to wa niluu Ilọrin, nipinlẹ Kwara.ALAROYE gbọ pe akọlu naa waye lasiko ti igbimọ naa jokoo, ti wọn ni ki awọn akẹkọọ ti wọn ṣe magomago lakooko idanwo waa sọ ohun ti wọn ri ti wọn fi gbeegun lakooko idanwo naa, sugbọn awọn agbebọn dabaru eto naa, ti erongba wọn si fori sanpọn.Ẹni tọrọ naa ṣoju rẹ to ba akọroyin wa sọrọ sọ pe lojiiji lawọn agbebọn naa ya bo inu ọgba ile-ẹkọ naa, ti wọn si n yinbọn soke, eyi lo da ibẹru-bojo silẹ, ti gbogbo awọn akẹkọọ at’olukọ si sa asala fun ẹmi wọn.Gbogbo ẹrọ ibanisọrọ awọn igbimọ naa ni wọn gba patapata. Ṣa o, ohun gbogbo ti pada bọ sipo ni akoko ti a n ko iroyin yii jọ."},{"question":"එස්‌. මහින්ද හිමි ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න. ","answer":"ඇස්. මහින්ද හිමි හෝ ටිබෙට් ජාතික ඇස්. මහින්ද හිමි ලෙසින් සාමාන්‍යයෙන් හැඳින්වෙන, සිකිම් මහින්ද හිමි යනු, සිකිම් රාජ්‍යයේ උපත ලබා බ්‍රිතාන්‍ය ලංකාවට සංක්‍රමණය වී මහණවූ බෞද්ධ භික්ෂුවකි. උන්වහන්සේ, කවියෙකු සහ ගත් කතු වරයෙකු වන අතර, සිංහල ජාතික වයාපාරයට සම්බන්ධ වී කටයුතු කර ඇත. උන්වහන්සේ පැමිණ ඇත්තේ සිකිම් වෙතින් වුවද, තමන් ටිබෙට් ජාතික යැයි එතුමන් විසින් පවසන්නට ඇත්තේ, බොහෝ විට ලංකාවේ ටිබෙටය බෙහෙවින් ජනප්‍රියව පැවති නිසා වන්නට ඇත.තරුණ වියෙහි ලංකාවට (වර්තමානයෙහි ශ්‍රී ලංකාව) පැමිණි මහින්ද හිමි බෞද්ධ භික්ෂුවක් ලෙසින් පැවිදි බව ලැබීය. සිංහල භාෂාව ඉගෙනගත් උන්වහන්සේ, කවියෙකු වී, ඔවුන්ගේ නිදහස වෙනුවෙන් සටන් කරන මෙන් ලාංකිකයන් පොළඹවමින්, ස්වදේශාලය ඔවුන් සිත් වල කාවද්දමින් සාහිත්‍ය කෘතීන් කිහිපයක් බිහි කලේය. උන්වහන්සේ වර්තමානයෙහි ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ ජාතික වීරයෙක් ලෙසින් සැලකෙයි.මධ්‍යම ආසියාවේ හිමාලය කදු වැටියේ සීකිම් (SIKKIM) දේශයට උතුරු සීමාවේ ටිබෙටය නම් බෞද්ධ දේශයේ 1901 ජන්ම ලාභය ලද මහින්ද හිමියන්ට දෙමාපියන් විසින් එස්‌. කේ. තෂිනම්ගල් ලෙස නම් තබන ලදී. එතුමාගේ පවුල ජීවත්වූයේ සිකිම් හී අගනුවර වන ගංටොක් නුවරය . කුඩා අවධියේම දෙමාපියන් අහිමි වූ තෂිනම්ගසල්ට සොහොයුරන් තිදෙනකු වූ බවට තොරතුරු හමු වේ. ඒ අතර තුන්වන සොයුරු සීකිම් පුණ්‌නජි හිමි නමින් පැවිදිව සිටි අතර කුඩා තෂිනම්ගසල් හට රැකවරණ සැපයූයේ උන්වහන්සේය. වැඩිමල් සොහොයුරා කල්කටා විශ්වවිද්‍යාලයෙහි ටිබෙට්‌ භාෂාව පිළිබඳව කථිකාචාර්යවරයකු ලෙස කීර්තිමත් සේවයක්‌ කළ අයෙකි. දෙවැනි සොයුරා ටිබෙට්‌ රජුගේ අගමැති ලෙස රාජ්‍ය පාලනයට සම්බන්ධ වී තිබේ.සීකිම් පූණ්‌නජි හිමිගේ මිත්‍රයෙකු වූ ජර්මන් ජාතික ඥනාතිලෝක හිමිගේ අවශ්‍යතාව මත සීකිම් පූණ්‌නජි හිමියන්ට ද ලංකාවට වැඩම කිරීමට සිදුවිය. එසේ සීකිම් පුණ්‌නජි හිමියන් හා ජර්මන් ජාතික ඥනාතිලෝක හිමියන් සමගින් කුඩා තෂිනම්ගසල්ට ද ලංකාවට පැමිණීමට සිදුවිය. ඒ 1912 වර්ෂයේය. කුඩා තෂිනම්ගසල් ලංකාවට පැමිණීම සිදුවූයේ ඒ අයුරිනි. දොඩම්දූවේ පොල්ගස්‌දූව ආරාමය මෙම තිදෙනාගේම වාසස්‌ථානය විය. පසුව අධ්‍යාපනය ලැබීමට පුණ්‌නජි හිමියන් සමගින් මරදාන මාලිගාකන්ද විෙද්‍යාදය පිරිවෙනට ගිය තෂිනම්ගසල් එහිදී සිංහල, පාලි, සංස්‌කෘත ආදි භාෂාද බුදුදහම හා නක්‍ෂත්‍රය වැනි විෂයන් ද ඉගෙන ගත්තේය. පසුව දොඩංදූව ශෛලබිම්බාරාමයේදී තෂිනම්ගසල් පැවිදි භාවයට පත්වන්නේ ටිබෙට්‌ එස්‌. මහින්ද හිමි නමිනි. ශ්‍රී ලංකා අමරපුර මහා නිකායට අයත් රත්ගම සිරි චූලසුමන හිමියන්ගේ ශිෂ්‍යයෙකු ලෙස උන්වහන්සේ එදා පැවිදිව දොඩංදූවේ වාසය කරන අතර තම සද්ධිවිහාරික දොඩංදූවේ ජිනරතන හිමියන්ගේ ඇසුරින් තම සහජ කවිත්වය ඔප්නංවා ගත්තේය. ටිබෙට්‌ එස්‌. මහින්ද හිමියන් මහා කවියකු බවට පත්කරන ලද්දේ දොඩංදූවේ ජිනරතන හිමියන්ගේ ගුරු හරුකම් මගිනි. ජිනරතන හිමියන් අප්‍රකට වුවත් දක්‍ෂ කවියෙකි"},{"question":"உங்கள் பகுதியில் உற்பத்தி செய்யப்படும் பொருட்களை சந்தையில் கிடைக்கும் பொருட்களுடன் ஒப்பிடுங்கள்.","answer":"ஆரம்பத்தில், மனிதர்கள் ஒரு நாடோடி வாழ்க்கை முறையை வழிநடத்தினர், வேட்டையாடுவதையும், உணவு தேடுவதையும் நம்பியிருந்தனர். இருப்பினும், காலப்போக்கில், விவசாய உற்பத்தி நான்கு வெவ்வேறு வகையான நிலங்களில் விரிவடைந்தது, காய்கறிகள், கீரை மற்றும் தானியங்கள் போன்ற பல்வேறு பயிர்களை பயிரிட உதவியது. சந்தையில் கிடைக்கும் பொருட்கள், விவசாயிகள் உற்பத்தி செய்யும் பொருட்களை விற்கவும், மாற்று பொருட்களை வாங்கவும் பயன்படுகிறது. இந்த வியாபாரத்தை நடத்துவதற்காக, மூன்று வழி மற்றும் நான்கு வழி சந்திப்புகள் போன்ற மக்கள் அதிகம் கூடும் பகுதிகளில் கடைகளை நிறுவினர்."},{"question":"Quantas palavras tem a frase a seguir: \\"O signo de Peixes é o décimo segundo signo, portanto, o último do Zodíaco. Esse é o signo mais elevado e representa o último estágio de aprendizado da Escola da Vida.\\"","answer":"A frase contém 31 palavras"},{"question":"Escribe un email en donde justifiques el que estoy enfermo a mi profesor de deportes.","answer":"Hola estimad@ [nombre del profesor de deportes],Me comunico a través del presente para informarle que no estoy en un buen estado físico. Me sucedió [enfermedad o lesión que ha sucedido]. Es por eso que no podré ir a clases de deportes. Espero su comprensión.Saludos, [tu nombre]."},{"question":"¿Qué película ganó el Oscar de 1943 como mejor película?","answer":"La película ganadora del Óscar a mejor película fue Casablanca, y es una de las películas mejor valoradas de la cinematografía estadounidense y ganadora de otros dos premios Óscar: Mejor guion adaptado y Mejor director "},{"question":"Sự kiện quan trọng nào được nói tới trong văn bản này? - Sau khi được trang bị và chạy thử, \\"Lexington\\" gia nhập Hạm đội Tàu chiến tại San Pedro, California vào ngày 7 tháng 4 năm 1928. Đặt căn cứ tại đây, nó hoạt động tại vùng bờ tây trong các nhiệm vụ huấn luyện bay, diễn tập chiến thuật và các cuộc tập trận. Hằng năm nó tham gia vào các cuộc tập trận cơ động hạm đội ở Hawaii, trong vùng biển Caribe, ngoài khơi Vùng kênh đào Panama, và tại Đông Thái Bình Dương. Trong các chuyến đi thử, chiếc \\"Lexington\\" đạt được vận tốc trung bình 30,7 knot (hải lý mỗi giờ), và duy trì được vận tốc 34,5 knot trong một giờ.","answer":"Sự kiện quan trọng được nói tới trong văn bản là việc tàu \\"Lexington\\" gia nhập Hạm đội Tàu chiến tại San Pedro, California vào ngày 7 tháng 4 năm 1928 và các hoạt động, nhiệm vụ huấn luyện bay, diễn tập chiến thuật và các cuộc tập trận mà nó tham gia tại các khu vực khác nhau."},{"question":"질문: 개그맨이 되려면 어떻게 해야해요? 답:","answer":"이제는 공채시험이 개콘까지도 다 없어졌습니다. 그러니 다양한 곳에서 활동하는 분들과 접촉이 이루어지는데요, 흔하게는 대학로에서 개그무대를 하는 분들을 예로 드릴 수가 있을 것이고, 추가로는 유튜브나 그런 곳에서 활동하는 분들에게 방송국 PD가 접촉을 하거나, 지인연결 형식으로 데뷔를 하게 됩니다."},{"question":"நெகிழி + அற்ற என்பதைச் சேர்த்து எழுதக் கிடைக்கும் சொல் ………………………………நெகிழிஅற்றநெகிழியற்றநெகிழ்அற்றநெகிழ்யற்ற","answer":"விடை : நெகிழி + அற்ற என்பதைச் சேர்த்து எழுதக் கிடைக்கும் சொல் …………நெகிழியற்ற"},{"question":"フランス語で「のりづけ」という意味がある、紙や写真の切り抜きなどを貼り付ける絵画の技法を何というでしょう？","answer":"コラージュです。"},{"question":"Ko sohun to n jẹ ‘Yahoo-plus’, awọn to n ṣe e n tẹ ẹ nidii ni- Ọlalekan","answer":"Ọmọkunrin kan, Ayọọla Ọlalekan, lo ti jẹwọ bayii pe iṣẹ jibiti ori ẹrọ ayelujara ti oun n ṣe ko ni oogun ninu rara, aanu ati igbagbọ ninu Ọlọrun nikan loun maa n beere fun ti gbogbo nnkan fi maa n lọ geere fun oun.Lasiko ti Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa l’Ọṣun, Wale Ọlọkọde, n ṣafihan Ọlalekan ati aburo rẹ, Tunde, pẹlu awọn ikọ adigunjale marun-un mi-in niluu Oṣogbo llọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, lọmọkunrin naa sọ pe nigba ti ileewe su oun, ti iṣẹ-kikọ naa si nira ju foun, loun bẹrẹ iṣẹ ‘yahoo-yahoo’.Ọlalekan ṣalaye fun ALAROYE pe oun ki i jale, bẹẹ ni toun yatọ si eyi ti wọn n pe ni ‘Yahoo-plus’, ti wọn maa n tẹ nidii pẹlu oogun owo, o ni oun ko tẹ ẹ nidii ni toun, ṣugbọn ohun kan ṣoṣo ti oun maa n beere ninu adura nigbakuugba ti anfaani rẹ ba yọ ni aanu Ọlọrun, oun si nigbagbọ ninu Ọlọrun pe iṣẹ naa yoo yọwo fun oun.Ọlalekan, ọmọ bibi ilu Ibadan, ti inagijẹ rẹ n jẹ Wire Lord sọ pe ko si inu akanti ti oun ko ti le ko owo jade niwọn igba toun ba ti ri siimu ti ẹni naa fi n gba alaati, nitori gbogbo boun ṣe le mọ nipa ẹni to ni siimu loun ti kọṣẹ rẹ ni Mushin, niluu Eko.O fi kun ọrọ rẹ pe oun maa n ri owo daadaa ninu iṣẹ naa, o si jawo fun oun ju iṣẹ ‘yahoo’ gan-an ti ọpọlọpọ ọdọ n ranju mọ lasiko yii lọ.Yatọ si iṣẹ waya-waya ti Ọlalekan n ṣe, o ni oun tun ni talẹnti orin, ti oun si ti ṣe orin kan sori ẹrọ-ayelujara laipẹ yii to pe orukọ rẹ ni Wire 999.Ninu ọrọ kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa, o ni loootọ ni Ọlalekan ko ba wọn digunjale, ṣugbọn oun lo n ba wọn ko owo to ba wa lori siimu foonu ti wọn ba gba lọwọ awọn ti wọn ba lọọ digun ja lole.Ni ti Tunde, aburo Ọlalekan, Ọlọkọde ṣalaye pe ọmọ ẹkọṣẹ lọmọ naa jẹ labẹ ẹgbọn rẹ, ṣe loun naa n kọ bi wọn ṣe le ko owo lakanti lai jẹ pe ẹnikẹni fura si wọn.Lara awọn ti wọn ṣafihan papọ mọ Ọlalekan ni Adewusi Iṣọla, Moshood Yusuf, Taye Fala, Azeez Dauda ati Abdullahi Adeṣọkan.Ọlọkọde sọ pe iwadii n tẹ siwaju, ati pe ni kete  tiwadii ba ti pari ni wọn yoo foju bale-ẹjọ."},{"question":"ਵਿਸ਼ਾ: ਪੱਛਮੀ ਬੰਗਾਲ ਕਿਉਂ ਨਹੀਂ ਗਏ ਉਗਰਾਹਾਂ ਤੇ ਮਮਤਾ ਬੈਨਰਜੀ ਨੇ ਕਥਿਤ ਹਮਲੇ ਤੋਂ ਬਾਅਦ ਕੀ ਕਿਹਾ ?","answer":"ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਪੱਤਰਕਾਰ ਸਰਬਜੀਤ ਸਿੰਘ ਧਾਲੀਵਾਲ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਉਗਰਾਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਜਥੇਬੰਦੀ ਵੋਟ ਰਾਜਨੀਤੀ ਤੋਂ ਦੂਰ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ, ਇਸੇ ਲਈ ਉਹ ਪੱਛਮੀ ਬੰਗਾਲ ਦੀਆਂ ਕਿਸਾਨ ਰੈਲੀਆਂ ਵਿਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਜਾ ਰਹੇ ।ਜੋਗਿੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਉਗਰਾਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਅਜੇ ਚੁੱਪ ਹੈ ਅਤੇ ਹੰਕਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਹੋਣ ਕਾਰਨ ਅਜੇ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਰੱਦ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਤਿਆਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਹੈ ਪਰ ਕਿਸਾਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਇਕਜੁੱਟਤਾ ਬਣੀ ਰਹਿਣੀ ਵੀ ਅੰਦੋਲਨ ਦੀ ਵੀ ਇੱਕ ਵੱਡੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤੀ ਹੈ।ਜੋਗਿੰਦਰ ਸਿੰਘ ਉਗਰਾਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਨਾਲ ਗੱਲਬਾਤ ਵਿਚ ਜੋ ਕੁਝ ਕਿਹਾ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਕੁਝ ਅੰਸ਼ ਇਹ ਹਨ।ਮਮਤਾ ਬੈਨਰਜੀ ਉੱਤੇ ਕਥਿਤ ਹਮਲੇ ਦੀ ਜਾਂਚ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ :ਪੱਛਮੀ ਬੰਗਾਲ ਦੀ ਮੁੱਖ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਮਮਤਾ ਬੈਨਰਜੀ ਨੇ ਨੰਦੀਗ੍ਰਾਮ ਵਿੱਚ ਬੁੱਧਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਹੋਏ ਕਥਿਤ ਹਮਲੇ ਦੀ ਜਾਂਚ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਹੈ। ਪੂਰਬੀ ਮੋਦਿਨੀਪੁਰ ਦੇ ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹਾ ਅਧਿਕਾਰੀ ਅਤੇ ਪੁਲਿਸ ਸੁਪਰੀਡੈਂਟ ਨੇ ਨੰਦੀਗ੍ਰਾਮ ਦੇ ਬਿਰੂਲੀਆ ਬਾਜ਼ਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਸ ਥਾਂ ਦਾ ਦੌਰਾ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਕਥਿਤ ਤੌਰ 'ਤੇ ਕੁਝ ਅਣਜਾਣ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਧੱਕਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ। ਮਮਤਾ ਬੈਨਰਜੀ ਨੇ ਹਸਪਤਾਲ ਤੋਂ ਇੱਕ ਬਿਆਨ ਜਾਰੀ ਕੀਤਾ ਹੈ। ਜਿਸ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸ਼ਾਂਤੀ ਕਾਇਮ ਰੱਖਣ ਦੀ ਅਪੀਲ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ। ਏਐੱਨਆਈ ਨਿਊਜ਼ ਏਜੰਸੀ ਨੇ ਮਮਤਾ ਬੈਨਰਜੀ ਦੇ ਹਵਾਲੇ ਨਾਲ ਲਿਖਿਆ ਹੈ, \\"ਮੈਨੂੰ ਹੱਥ, ਪੈਰ ਅਤੇ ਲਿਗਾਮੈਂਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਸੱਟਾਂ ਲੱਗੀਆਂ ਹਨ। ਮੈਂ ਕਾਰ ਕੋਲ ਖੜ੍ਹੀ ਸੀ ਜਦੋਂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਧੱਕਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਗਿਆ ਸੀ। ਮੈਂ ਛੇਤੀ ਹੀ ਕੋਲਕਾਤਾ ਲਈ ਰਵਾਨਾ ਹੋ ਜਾਵਾਂਗੀ।\\"ਇਸ ਵਿਚਾਲੇ ਤ੍ਰਿਣਮੂਲ ਕਾਂਗਰਸ ਨੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਨੇਤਾ 'ਤੇ ਹਮਲੇ ਕਾਰਨ ਵੀਰਵਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਚੋਣ ਮਨੋਰਥ ਪੱਤਰ ਦੇ ਐਲਾਨ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰੋਗਰਾਮ ਟਾਲ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਹੈ। (ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਪੰਜਾਬੀ ।)"},{"question":"Àjẹsára rotavirus","answer":"Àjẹsára rotavirus jẹ́ àjẹsára tí a fi ń dáàbò bo ara ẹni lọ́wọ́ àkóràn kòkòrò àìlèfojúrí afàìsàn kan tí à ń pè ní rotavirus. Àwọn kòkòrò àìlèfojúrí afàìsàn wọ̀nyí ló má a ń sábà ṣe òkùnfà ìgbẹ́ gbuuru tó lágbára púpọ̀ láàárín àwọn ọmọdé. Àjẹsára náà a má a dènà ìwọ̀n 15 sí 34% ìṣẹ̀lẹ̀ ìgbẹ́ gbuuru tó lágbára púpọ̀ náà ní àwọn orílẹ̀-èdè tó ṣì ń tẹ̀síwájú, àti ìwọ̀n 37 sí 96% ìṣẹ̀lẹ̀ ìgbẹ́ gbuuru tó lágbára púpọ̀ náà ní àwọn orílẹ̀-èdè tó ti ní ìtẹ̀síwájú. Àjẹsára náà dàbí èyí tó má a ń dín ewu ikú tó ti ipasẹ̀ ìgbẹ́ gbuuru wáyé kù láàárín àwọn ọmọdé. Fífún àwọn ọmọ-ọwọ́ ní àjẹsára náà dàbí ohun tó má a ń dín ìṣẹ̀lẹ̀ àrùn náà kù láàárìn àwọn àgbàlagbà àti láàárín àwọn tí kò tíì gba àjẹsára náà tẹ́lẹ̀ rí.Àjọ Ìlera Àgbáyé (WHO) gbani nímọ̀ràn pé kí àjẹsára rotavirus jẹ́ ara àwọn àjẹsára tí à ń gbà lóòrèkóòrè, pàápàá júlọ ní àwọn agbègbè ibi tí àrùn náà ti wọ́pọ̀. A gbọ́dọ̀ ṣe èyí ní ìdàpọ̀ pẹ̀lú gbígbé àwọn ohun bíi fífún ọmọ lọ́yàn, fífọ ọwọ́ ẹni, àti lílo omi tó mọ́ àti ìmọ́tótó lárugẹ. Ẹnu ni a ń gbà fúnni ní àjẹsára náà, ènìyàn sì nílò ìwọ̀n egbògi náà méjì sí mẹta. A gbọ́dọ̀ bẹ̀rẹ̀ sí fúnni láti ìgbà tí ènìyàn bá ti tó ọmọ ọ̀sẹ̀ mẹ́fà.Lílò àjẹsára náà kò léwu. Èyí kan lílò fún àwọn tó ní àrùn kògbóògùn HIV/AIDS pàápàá. Ẹ̀yà ìṣáájú àjẹsára náà níí ṣe pẹ̀lú lílọ́pọ̀ ìfun, ṣùgbọ́n ẹ̀yà titun rẹ̀ ní báyìí kò tíì ní ohunkóhun ṣe pẹ̀lú èyí dájúdájú. Nítorí ewu tó lè wáyé, a kò gbani nímọ̀ràn láti lòó fún àwọn ọmọ-ọwọ́ tí ìfun wọn ti lọ́ pọ̀ rí. A ṣe àgbéjáde àwọn àjẹsára náà nípasẹ̀ kòkòrò àìlèfojúrí afàìsàn rotavirus tí a ti sọ di aláìlágbára.Àjẹsára náà di èyí tó wà fún lílò ní ilẹ̀ Amẹ́ríkà fún ìgbà àkọ́kọ́ ní ọdún 2006. Ó wà lórí Àkójọ Àwọn Egbògi Kòṣeémáàní ti Àjọ Ìlera Àgbáyé, àwọn òògùn tó ṣe pàtàkì jùlọ tí a nílò fún ètò ìlera ìbẹ̀rẹ̀pẹ̀pẹ̀ yòówù. Iye owó rẹ̀ lójú pálí jẹ́ bíi 6.96 sí 20.66 USD fún ìwọ̀n egbògi náà kanṣoṣo ní ọdún 2014. Ní ilẹ̀ Amẹ́ríkà iye owó rẹ̀ ju 200 USD lọ. Dí ọdún 2013 oríṣi àjẹsára náà méjì ni ó wà káàkiri àgbáyé, Rotarix àti RotaTeq, pẹ̀lú àwọn oríṣi díẹ̀ mìíràn tó tún wà ní àwọn orílẹ̀-èdè kọ̀ọ̀kan."},{"question":"Imagine a futuristic society where robots and humans coexist. Write a scene depicting their interactions.","answer":" एक भविष्यवाणी भविष्यवाणी करें जहां रोबोट और मानव सहजीवन हैं। उनके बीच इंटरएक्शन को दर्शाता सीन लिखें।"},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Programmet formulerades av Roland Perrot, före detta desertör från","answer":"Algeriet-kriget och aktiv under maj 68, som personligen kände Giono och hans erfarenheter av en frikommun i Contadour på 1930-talet. Det var inspirerat av Fouriers idéer men lade också till antimilitarism, pacifism, antikapitalism, frånvaro av politisk representation samt jämställdhet mellan män och kvinnor."},{"question":"السؤال: ما اسم السورة التي اُفتتحت باسمٍ من أسماء الله الحسنى؟","answer":" الجواب: سورة الرّحمن."},{"question":"வினா:இந்தியாவின் ஏவுகணைப் பெண் என்று அழைக்கப்படுபவர் யார்?","answer":"விடை: இந்தியாவின் ஏவுகணைப் பெண் டெஸ்ஸி தாமஸ் ஆவார். முனைவர் டெஸ்ஸி தாமஸ் அல்லது டெசி தாமசு ஐதராபாத்தில் உள்ள பாதுகாப்பு ஆராய்ச்சி மற்றும் வளர்ச்சி அமைப்பில் அக்னி-5 ஏவுகணைக்கான திட்டப்பணி இயக்குனர். இந்தியாவில் ஏவுகணை திட்டப்பணி ஒன்றிற்கு தலைமை தாங்கும் முதல் பெண் அறிவியலாளர் என்ற பெருமை கொண்டவர்."},{"question":"刑事ドラマの舞台となる警察署で、「踊る大捜査線」は湾岸署ですが、「はぐれ刑事純情派」の舞台となっている警察署は何でしょう？","answer":"山手中央署です。"},{"question":"What is the purpose of continuous integration (CI) in the context of MLOps?","answer":"Continuous integration in MLOps ensures that code changes and model updates are automatically tested and integrated into the shared repository, promoting collaboration and reducing integration issues."},{"question":" Waxaad Sheegtaa magaca qoraalka ay Isticmaalaan Indhoolayaasha?","answer":" Waxaa loo-Yaqaanaa Pareel."},{"question":"Quel est le 55ème élément du tableau périodique ?","answer":"Le 55ème élément du tableau périodique est le Césium (Cs). Avec un numéro atomique de 55, le césium est un métal alcalin qui possède des propriétés et des applications distinctives. C'est un métal mou, argenté-doré, très réactif en raison de son électron de valence unique. Le césium est réputé pour sa réactivité exceptionnelle avec l’eau, conduisant à des réactions vigoureuses qui libèrent de l’hydrogène gazeux et de la chaleur. Cette propriété rend le césium utile dans diverses applications, notamment dans des types spécialisés d'horloges atomiques appelées horloges atomiques au césium, qui sont des dispositifs de chronométrage très précis utilisés dans les systèmes de positionnement global (SPG), les télécommunications et la recherche scientifique. Les composés du césium sont également utilisés dans les fluides de forage pour les puits de pétrole et de gaz et comme catalyseurs dans les processus chimiques. Malgré son utilisation commerciale limitée, la réactivité et les propriétés uniques du césium soulignent son importance dans le chronométrage précis et les processus industriels."},{"question":"\\"ගම හාමිනේ කොණ්ඩේ කප්පවා  ගත්තා  වගේ\\" යනුවෙන් ප්‍රස්ථා පිරුලක් තිබේද? තිබේ නම් එහි අදහස පහදන්න.","answer":"ඒක ජන කතාවක්. භාණ්ඩ හා  සේවා හුවමාරු ක්‍රමයට ජීවත් වූ අතීතයේ කරණවෑමියාගේ සේවය ලබා ගත්තේ යම් යම් දේ ලබා දීමෙන්. ගම ගෙදරින් වී වැනි බෝග ලබා දීම අනිවාර්ය වුණා. කරණවෑමියා  පැමිණි දින ගමරාල නිවසේ නොසිටියත් අදාල බෝග ලබා දීම තමන්ගේ පාර්ශවයට පාඩුවක් බව සිතන ගම හාමිනේ තමාගේ දිගු කෙස් වැටිය කපා  දමන්නැයි කරණවෑමියාගෙන් ඉල්ලා  සිටිනවා.⚫ තමන්ට පාඩුවක් වේ යැයි සිතා ඊට විශාල පාඩුවක්වන දෙයක් තෝරා ගන්නා අවස්තාවකදී මෙවැනි ප්‍රස්ථා  පිරුළු පාවිච්චි වෙනවා."},{"question":"1 litre mazot vergisi ne kadar?","answer":"Karara göre kurşunsuz benzinin litre fiyatı üzerinden alınan ÖTV tutarı 2,52 liradan 7,52 liraya, motorinin litre fiyatı üzerinden alınan vergi tutarı ise 2,05 liradan 7,05 liraya yükseldi."},{"question":"السؤال: ماذا يسبب حدوث التبخر بالخرسانة ؟","answer":"الإجابة: التبخر یسبب شروخ في الخرسانة خصوصًا في الوقت المبكر بعد الصب حیث تكون قوة تماسك الاسمنت مازالت غیر كافیة لمقاومة تلك الشروخ"},{"question":"‘విద్య గొప్పతనం’ నాలుగు వాక్యాల్లో రాయండి.","answer":"విద్య చాలా గొప్పదని నార్ల చిరంజీవిగారు చెప్పారు. విద్యను దొంగలెత్తుకు పోలేరు. ఎవ్వరూ దోచుకోలేరు. అన్నదమ్ములు విద్యను పంచుకోలేరు. విద్య వలననే ప్రపంచం అభివృద్ధి చెందుతుంది."},{"question":"Qual é o nome artístico da cantora Larissa de Macedo Machado?","answer":"Resposta: Anitta."},{"question":"МАНАС эпосундагы ыйык туткан сандар кайсылар?","answer":"Кырк уруу кыргыз, кырк чоро, кырк күн, кырк кыз ж.б. түшүнүктөр менен коштолот. Андан сырткары 3, 5, 7, 9, 12 сакралдык сандар катары эсептелет. "},{"question":"Tarjamahkeun kalimah ieu tina basa Sunda kana basa Indonésia:Partisipasi politik masyarakat penting untuk menjaga keseimbangan kekuasaan.","answer":"Partisipasi pulitik masarakat penting pikeun ngajaga kasaimbangan kakawasaan."},{"question":"Content: కశ్మీర్‌ ప్రత్యేక ప్రతిపత్తికి సంబంధించిన ఆర్టికల్ 370ని భారత రద్దు చేయడం గురించి మేక్రాన్‌ను అప్పుడు ఓ జర్నలిస్టు ప్రశ్న అడిగారు.''నియంత్రణ రేఖకు రెండు వైపులా ఉన్న సాధారణ పౌరుల హక్కుల విస్మరణకు గురవ్వకూడదన్న విషయాన్ని ఫ్రాన్స్ పరిశీలిస్తోంది'' అని మేక్రాన్ దానికి బదులిచ్చారు.ఈ విషయమై ప్రధాని మోదీతోనూ తాను మాట్లాడానని... భారత్, పాకిస్తాన్ రెండూ ఈ బాధ్యతను అర్థం చేసుకోవాల్సిన అవసరం ఉందని ఆయన అన్నారు.భారత్, పాక్ తమ మధ్య ఉన్న విభేదాలను చర్చల ద్వారా పరిష్కరించుకోవాలని విజ్ఞప్తి చేస్తున్నామని, పాక్‌కు కూడా తాము ఇదే సూచిస్తామని మేక్రాన్ చెప్పారు.అంటే, ఆర్టికల్ 370 రద్దు విషయంలో ఆయన బహిరంగంగా భారత్‌కు మద్దతు తెలిపేందుకు ముందుకు రాలేదు.అయితే, తాజాగా ఫ్రాన్స్‌లో ఇస్లాం విషయమై వివాదం రేగుతోంది. ఈ వ్యవహారంలో ఫ్రాన్స్ అధ్యక్షుడు మేక్రాన్‌ను భారత విదేశాంగ మంత్రిత్వశాఖ గట్టిగా సమర్థించింది.''ఎమ్మాన్యుయేల్ మేక్రాన్‌పై అభ్యంతరకర భాషలో జరుగుతున్న వ్యక్తిగత దాడులను మేం ఖండిస్తున్నాం. ఫ్రాన్స్‌లో తీవ్రవాద దాడి చేసి టీచర్ ప్రాణాలు తీయడాన్ని కూడా మేం ఖండిస్తున్నాం. ఆ టీచర్ కుటుంబానికి, ఫ్రాన్స్ ప్రజలకు సానూభూతి తెలియజేస్తున్నాం. ఎలాంటి పరిస్థితుల్లోనైనా తీవ్రవాదాన్ని సమర్థించడం సరికాదు'' అని భారత విదేశాంగ శాఖ ఓ ప్రకటన విడుదల చేసింది.భారత్ కన్నా ముందు జర్మనీ, ఇటలీ, నెదర్లాండ్స్ లాంటి యురోపియన్ దేశాలు కూడా ఫ్రాన్స్‌కు ఈ విషయంలో మద్దతు ప్రకటించాయి.గురువారం ఫ్రాన్స్‌లోని నీస్ పట్టణంలో ఓ ఆగంతకుడు ముగ్గురిని హత్య చేశాడు. ఈ హత్యలను ఖండిస్తూ భారత ప్రధాని మోదీ ట్వీట్ చేశారు. అమెరికా, బ్రిటన్, రష్యా లాంటి దేశాలు కూడా ఆ తర్వాత స్పందించాయి.మరోవైపు భారత్‌లోని భోపాల్‌లో ఫ్రాన్స్‌కు వ్యతిరేకంగా ప్రదర్శన జరిగింది.భారత విదేశాంగ కార్యాలయం ఫ్రాన్స్‌కు మద్దతుగా చేసిన ప్రకటనను ఆ దేశ రాయబారి ఎమ్మాన్యుయేల్ లీనైన్ ట్వీట్ చేశారు.భారత విదేశాంగ మంత్రిత్వశాఖకు ధన్యవాదాలు తెలియజేశారు. తీవ్రవాద వ్యతిరేక పోరాటంలో భారత్, ఫ్రాన్స్ పరస్పర నమ్మకంతో ముందుకు వెళ్తాయని అన్నారు.కానీ, కశ్మీర్‌లో మానవహక్కుల ఉల్లంఘనల ఆరోపణలతో విమర్శలు వచ్చినప్పుడు అండగా నిలవని ఫ్రాన్స్‌ను... భారత్ ఇప్పుడు ఇంతలా ఎందుకు సమర్థిస్తోంది?భారత్ తాజా స్పందనకు ఫ్రాన్స్‌తో ఉన్న స్నేహం ఒక్కటే కారణమా? ఇతర అంశాల పాత్ర ఇందులో ఉందా?ఈ విషయంపై భారత్-ఫ్రాన్స్ వ్యవహారాలను...","answer":"భారత ప్రధాని నరేంద్ర మోదీ గత ఏడాది ఆగస్టులో ఫ్రాన్స్‌లో పర్యటించారు. అప్పుడు ఫ్రాన్స్ అధ్యక్షుడు ఎమ్మాన్యుయేల్ మేక్రాన్‌తో కలిసి ఆయన ఓ ప్రెస్ కాన్ఫరెన్స్ ఏర్పాటు చేశారు."},{"question":"ఒక వృత్త వ్యాసార్ధం 8√2 సెం.మీ. ఆ వృత్తంలో – అంతర్లిఖించబడిన చతురస్ర భుజం పొడవు ఎంత ?","answer":"వృత్త వ్యాసార్ధం r = 8√2 సెం.మీ.∴ వ్యాసం = చతురస్ర కర్ణం d = 16√2∴ చతురస్ర భుజం = 16 సెం.మీ.(చతురస్ర కర్ణం d = √2 × భుజం)"},{"question":"Microsoft භාවිතා කරන්නේ කුමක් සඳහාද?","answer":"Microsoft යනු ලොව විශාලතම පරිගණක මෘදුකාංග වෙළෙන්දා වේ. එය ක්ලවුඩ් පරිගණක සේවා, වීඩියෝ ක්‍රීඩා, පරිගණක සහ ක්‍රීඩා දෘඩාංග, සෙවුම් සහ වෙනත් සබැඳි සේවා සපයන ප්‍රමුඛ සැපයුම්කරුවෙකි. මයික්‍රොසොෆ්ට් හි ආයතනික මූලස්ථානය වොෂ් හි රෙඩ්මන්ඩ් හි පිහිටා ඇති අතර එයට රටවල් 60කට වැඩි ගණනක කාර්යාල ඇත."},{"question":"Qui est la cinéaste Sarah Polley ?","answer":"Sarah Polley est connue pour sa polyvalence en tant qu'actrice et réalisatrice. Son documentaire « Stories We Tell » et ses films narratifs comme « Away from Her » et « Take This Waltz » explorent les relations et les histoires personnelles avec sensibilité et authenticité."},{"question":"یک سؤال طرح کنید که جواب آن متن زیر باشد:با اندازه گیری میزان دما و بارش یک مکان، در طی ماه و سال می توان پی برد که آب و هوای آنجا چگونه است.","answer":"این سؤال می‌تواند برای پاسخ موردنظر، مناسب باشد: آب و هوای یک منطقه چگونه مشخص می‌شود؟"},{"question":"請回答這個問題：什麼是心理學中的「反射作用」？","answer":"答案：心理學中的反射作用是指在感知或刺激下，個體自動產生的無意識或自發性的心理或生理反應，如閃躲、抓取反射等。它們是簡單而直接的自動反應，無需意識參與。"},{"question":"Quel est le 50ème élément du tableau périodique ?","answer":"Le 50ème élément du tableau périodique est l'étain (Sn). Son numéro atomique est de 50, ce qui signifie qu’il possède 50 protons dans son noyau. L'étain est un métal de post-transition et est couramment utilisé pour diverses applications industrielles."},{"question":"Samsung နဲ့ Apple က ဘယ်ဟာပိုကောင်းလဲ။","answer":"Apple ၏ iPhone နှင့် Samsung ၏ Galaxy တို့တွင် မတူညီသော အားသာချက်များနှင့် အားနည်းချက်များ ရှိသည်၊ Samsung ဖုန်းများသည် ဘတ်ဂျက်မော်ဒယ်များတွင်ပင် ပိုမိုကောင်းမွန်သော ကင်မရာများ၊ ဘက်ထရီ သက်တမ်းနှင့် မျက်နှာပြင် အရည်အသွေးတို့ ရှိကြပါသည်။ သို့သော်လည်း iPhone များသည် ပိုမိုကောင်းမွန်သော ဆော့ဖ်ဝဲလ်ပံ့ပိုးမှုနှင့် ဒေတာလုံခြုံရေးကို ပေးဆောင်သည်။"},{"question":"এই লেখাটি কোন গুরুত্বপূর্ণ ঘটনা সম্পর্কে?বাংলাদেশের নবীন কবি-লেখকদের সাহিত্যচর্চা গতিময় এবং সৃজনধারাকে সজীব করার লক্ষ্যে কালি ও কলম তরুণ কবি ও লেখক পুরস্কার ২০০৮ সাল থেকে চালু হয়েছে। সাধারণত কবিতা, কথাসাহিত্য, প্রবন্ধ গবেষণা এবং মুক্তিযুদ্ধভিত্তিক সাহিত্য— এই চারটি বিভাগে এই পুরস্কার প্রদান করা হয়। এই পুরস্কারের অর্থমূল্য প্রতিটি বিভাগের জন্যে ১০,০০০ টাকা।","answer":"মুক্তিযুদ্ধভিত্তিক |"},{"question":"คุณกำลังทำอะไรอยู่","answer":"เล่นเกม"},{"question":"薫製にした大根を塩やヌカで漬けた、秋田県の郷土料理は何でしょう？","answer":"いぶりがっこ"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga: \\"Ny iray amin'ireo sakafo nasionaly eto Madagasikara dia _.\\"","answer":"Valiny: Iray amin'ireo sakafo nasionaly eto Madagasikara ny romazava."},{"question":"坐立姿勢怎樣好？","answer":"　　正確的坐立姿勢應該是„坐像鍾，立像松‟。　　也就是坐得要端正，立得要直，不能扭腰、彎腿的。因為小孩正在發育長身體，骨骼比較軟，坐得不正，立得不直，時間長了，會使脊柱和大腿骨彎曲變形。"},{"question":"السؤال: من هو الصحابي الذي أرسله النبي رسولا إلى كسرى؟","answer":"الجواب: الصحابي الجليل عبد الله بن حذافة السهمي"},{"question":"Berikan contoh ayat untuk peribahasa \\"babi buta\\".","answer":"Serangan yang membabi buta itu telah menyebabkan ramai orang awam terkorban."},{"question":"文中の主な言葉を見つけて、その内容を説明しなさい。 20日、厚生労働省で新型コロナウイルスの専門家が会議を開きました。ウイルスがうつった人は、8月から減り続けていました。しかし19日までの1週間は、前の1週間より多くなりました。専門家は、お年寄りでもウイルスがうつる人が増えて、心配だと言いました。そして、「これからウイルスが広がって、8回目の波になる可能性がとても高いです」と言いました。お年寄りなど病気がひどくなりそうな人を十分に治療できるように準備することや、新型コロナとインフルエンザのワクチンを注射することが大切だと説明しました。毎日の生活では、必要なときにマスクをして、部屋に新しい空気を入れて、少ない人数で食事をしてほしいと言っています。","answer":"文にある主な言葉とその内容はこちらです。"},{"question":"Dê um exemplo de curiosidade nesta categoria: cinema.","answer":"Que ator ou atriz de Hollywood estrelou em mais filmes e shows de TV, até 2020? James Hong estrelou em mais de 600 produçōes de TV e cinema."},{"question":"O ma ṣe o, tankan epo re sinu odo Soka, n’Ibadan, dẹrẹba to wa a ti jade laye","answer":"Awakọ tanka epo bẹtiroolu kan ti j’Ọlọrun nipe ninu ijanba ọkọ to waye lori biriiji Soka, n’Ibadan, l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii. Niṣe ni ọkọ nla ọhun gbokiti sinu omi Soka lati ori biriiji odo naa.Gẹgẹ b’awọn tiṣẹlẹ ọhun ṣoju wọn ṣe sọ, ṣadeede lọkọ ọhun to n ti ọna Iwo Road, n’Ibadan, lọ sọna Eko, ya bara kuro loju titi, to si re sinu odo jínjìn naa.Awọn eeyan sare sọ kalẹ sinu odo ọhun lati ran awọn to wa ninu mọto naa lọwọ, nigba naa ni wọn ri i pe awakọ yii nikan ṣoṣo lo wa ninu mọto, loju ẹsẹ lo si ti ku.Awọn to sọrọ lori iṣẹlẹ yii sọ pe bireeki ọkọ ọhun to daṣẹ silẹ lojiji lo ṣee ṣe ko ṣokunfa ijanba naa. Ṣugbọn Ọgbẹni Shehu Umar, alamoojuto ẹka to n ri si ajalu buburu fun ajọ alaabo ilu ta a mọ si Sifu Difẹnsi nipinlẹ Ọyọ sọ pe o le jẹ oorun to n kun awakọ naa nitori àárẹ̀ to ti mu un latari ọna jinjin to ti n bọ lo mu ki ọwọ ọkọ naa ya bara sinu odo, ti ko si ri ara dù pada mọ titi to fi bọ sinu omi.O ni ni kete ti ijanba ọhun ti waye ni wọn ti tẹ ileeṣẹ oun laago, tawọn oṣiṣẹ Sifu Difẹnsi si sare lọ sibẹ lati doola ẹmi awọn eeyan.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe sọ, “Awa atawọn panapana la jọ wa nibẹ lati doola ẹmi awọn eeyan, paapaa lati dena ki awọn eeyan ma baa maa ji bẹtiroolu to n ṣẹ jade latinu tanka epo yẹn bu, ki iyẹn naa ma tun lọọ fa ijanba to ṣee ṣe ko tun la ẹmi lọ”.Ileewosan ijọba ipinlẹ Ọyọ ta a mọ si Adeọyọ ni wọn gbe oku awakọ epo naa pamọ si gẹgẹ bi ọga awọn Sifu Difẹnsi yii ṣe fidi ẹ mulẹ."},{"question":"Pourquoi voit-on toujours la même face de la Lune ?","answer":"La Lune nous montre toujours la même face. Si bien que l’on pourrait croire qu’elle cache quelque chose (certains l’affirment encore aujourd’hui). Mais le mystère de sa face cachée a disparu le jour où Luna 3, une sonde soviétique lancée en 1959, transmit vers la Terre les premières images d’un sol cratérisé et désolé. La raison pour laquelle la Lune « regarde » toujours la Terre est tout simplement gravitationnelle. La Lune tourne sur elle-même en un peu plus de 27 jours, soit le même temps que pour effectuer un tour de Terre. Sa rotation est dite synchronisée avec sa révolution. Ce sont les forces de marées entre la Terre et son satellite qui ont ralenti sa course jusqu’à l’obtention de ce synchronisme. C’est le cas pour de nombreux objets dans le système solaire. Mercure effectue une rotation et demie par révolution. Io, Europe, Ganymède et Callisto, satellites de Jupiter, sont, comme la Lune, en rotation synchrone. C’est aussi le cas de Titan, satellite de Saturne, que l’on connaît aujourd’hui un peu mieux, depuis que la sonde européenne Huygens a exploré sa surface en 2005."},{"question":"د قرارداد اجزا څه شی دي ؟","answer":"ځواب – د قرارداد ډول (شفاهي او تحريري) ، د قرارداد د طرفينو ظرفیت ، د نظر توافق ، مشروعيت ، د خسارې د جبران غوښتلو حق ، او د طرفينو مکلفیتونه ."},{"question":"كيف أرتدي الكمامة الطبية وكيف أحملها وأخلعها؟","answer":"كيفية ارتداء الكمامة الطبية وخلعها:قبل لمس الكمامة، نظف يديك بفركهما بمطهّر كحولي أو بغسلهما بالماء والصابون.تفحّص الكمامة للتأكد من أنها غير ممزقة أو مثقوبة؛ ولا تستعمل كمامة سبق ارتداؤها أو تعرّضت للتلف.حدّد الطرف العلوي للكمامة - وهو الموضع الذي عادة ما يوجد فيه الشريط المعدني.حدّد بعد ذلك الطرف الداخلي للكمامة، وهو الجهة البيضاء في العادة.ضع الكمامة على وجهك بحيث تغطي أنفك وفمك وذقنك، وتأكد من عدم ترك أي فراغات بين وجهك والكمامة. ثبّت شريطيْ الكمامة خلف الرأس أو الأذنين. وتجنّب تقاطع الشريطين لأن ذلك قد يؤدي إلى ظهور فراغات على جوانب الكمامة.اضغط على الشريط المعدني لتثبيته كي يأخذ شكل أنفك.تذكّر ألاّ تلمس الطرف الأمامي من الكمامة أثناء استخدامها لتجنب التلوث. وإذا لمستها خطأً، نظف يديك.كيفية خلع الكمامة الطبية:قبل لمس الكمامة، نظف يديك بفركهما بمطهّر كحولي أو بغسلهما بالماء والصابون.انزع الشريطين من خلف الرأس أو الأذنين، دون لمس الجهة الأمامية من الكمامة.عند إزالة الكمامة، انحنِ إلى الأمام واسحب الكمامة بعيدًا عن وجهك.تُستعمل الكمامات الطبية مرة واحدة فقط؛ تخلّص من الكمامة بعد خلعها على الفور، ويفضل رميها في صندوق نفايات مغلق.نظّف يديك بعد لمس الكمامة.انتبه لحالة الكمامة؛ استبدلها إذا اتّسخت أو تبللت."},{"question":"次のタイトルに基づいて、最大500語の段落を書いてください： 栃木県で新しいLRTの運転が始まる","answer":"LRTと呼ばれる新しいタイプの路面電車は、電気で動いて環境にいいと言われています。26日、栃木県で新しいLRTの運転が始まりました。宇都宮駅と芳賀町の間の14.6kmを50分ぐらいで走ります。全部の線路を新しく作った日本で初めてのLRTです。28日は運転が始まってから初めての平日でした。宇都宮駅では午前7時ごろから、大勢の人が並んで、電車を待っていました。高校生は「前はバスを使っていました。LRTはあまり遅れないと思うので、早く学校に着くことができると思います」と話しました。仕事に行くために乗った男性は「駅に止まるときも揺れなくてよかったです」と話しました。日本では、75年前から新しい路面電車ができていませんでした。"},{"question":"Ƙirƙiri labarin don kanun labarai mai zuwa: Bidiyon Ku San Malamanku tare da Shiekh Lawan Hassan Abubakar","answer":"Ku latsa hoton da ke sama don kallon bidiyon: A wannan makon filin Ku San Malamanku ya tattauna ne da Shiekh Lawan Hassan Abubakar dafa jihar Bauchi."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Semua raja memerlukan saya, saya kelihatan besar dan cantik. Saya selalunya dijaga pegawai keselamatan, siapa saya?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah istana kerana semua raja hidup dalamnya dan ia sering dikawal untuk mengelakkan pencerobohan."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధాలు మరియు తాత్పర్యం రాయండి:క. క్షత్రవరుఁడైన విశ్వా ,మిత్రునకుఁ బవిత్రయైన మేనకకున్ సత్పుత్తినయి బొంకువలుకఁగధాత్రీతల నాథ ! యంత ధర్మేతరనే ?","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్థం :ధాత్రీతలనాథ ! = భూమిని పాలించే ఓ రాజా !క్షత్రవరుఁడు + ఐన = క్షత్రియులలో ఉత్తముడైనవిశ్వామిత్రునకున్ = విశ్వామిత్రుడికేపవిత్ర + ఐన = పవిత్రురాలు అయినమేనకకున్ = మేనకకూసత్ + పుతిన్ + అయి = యోగ్యురాలైన కుమార్తెనైన నేనుబొంకు + పలుకఁగన్ = అబద్దమాడటానికిఅంత = అంతధర్మ+ఇతరను+ఏ = అధర్మపరురాలనా ? (కాదని భావం)తాత్పర్యం :భూమిని పాలించే ఓ రాజా ! క్షత్రియులలో ఉత్తముడైన విశ్వామిత్రుడికీ, పవిత్రురాలైన మేనకకూ యోగ్యురాలైన కుమార్తెనైన నేను అబద్ధమాడటానికి అంత అధర్మపరురాలను కాను అని తాత్పర్యం."},{"question":"வினா: இரு சொற்களையும் ஒரே தொடரில் அமைத்து எழுதுக: மடு – மாடு","answer":"விடை : மடு – மாடு: மடுவில் (குட்டையில்) மாடு நீர்க் குடித்தது."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：地球上最古老的數學記錄是哪一個？","answer":"答案：巴比倫的錐形文字數表"},{"question":"السؤال: من الذي اخترع الفستان الأسود الصغير الأيقوني؟","answer":"الإجابة: كوكو شانيل ، عشرينيات القرن الماضي"},{"question":"Булуң деген эмне ?","answer":"Булуң-океан,деңиз же көлдүн кургактыкка кирип турган бөлүгү."},{"question":"Por que a mobilidade urbana é um tema fundamental quando se discute desenvolvimento urbano e qualidade de vida da população?","answer":"Porque as condições de deslocamentos das pessoas e das mercadorias nos centros urbanos impactam toda a sociedade."},{"question":"Cabiraadda Heerka Nafaqada.","answer":"Qiimaynta nafaqadu waa habka laguogaado heerka tayada nafaqada ee qofka.Afar hab ayaa loo siticmaalaa kuwaas oolagu naanayso ABCDda qiimayntanafaqada: Qiimaynta cabiraada jirka(anthropometric assessment) Qiimaynta iyadoo la isticmaalayoShaybaar (biochemical)Qiimaynta calaamadaha muuqda (clinical assessment)Qiimaynta cunto qaadashada (dietry assessment)"},{"question":"Con trai tôi 6 tuổi, còi xương, ăn trứng mỗi ngày có cải thiện sức khỏe không?","answer":"Còi xương là một dạng rối loạn ở trẻ em, khiến xương nhỏ, yếu và dễ gãy hơn bình thường. Tình trạng này xảy ra chủ yếu do thiếu hụt vitamin D, canxi hoặc phospho trong cơ thể. Trong một số trường hợp hiếm gặp, bệnh xảy ra do rối loạn di truyền khiến trẻ gặp các vấn đề về chuyển hóa canxi, phospho. Từ đó, nồng độ phospho trong xương thấp, dẫn đến còi xương.Dinh dưỡng đóng vai trò quan trọng trong ngăn ngừa và hỗ trợ điều trị còi xương. Phần lớn các trường hợp còi xương tập trung vào bổ sung dưỡng chất còn thiếu như vitamin D, canxi, phospho thông qua chế độ ăn hàng ngày và thuốc uống bổ sung.Trứng là thực phẩm lành mạnh với trẻ. 100 g trứng gà cung cấp 166 kcal, protein 14,8 g, chất béo 11,6 g, glucid 0,5 g, 0,88 mcg vitamin D, 0,3 mcg vitamin K, 55 mg canxi, 2,7 mg sắt, 176 mg kali, 0,9 mg kẽm, 11 mg magie...Ăn trứng gà hàng ngày góp phần cung cấp dưỡng chất, vi chất cần thiết giúp trẻ cải thiện còi xương. Tuy nhiên, ăn mỗi trứng chưa đáp ứng đủ nhu cầu canxi, vitamin D. Bé cần ăn đa dạng thực phẩm, bổ sung thêm các vi chất, uống sữa, ăn cua, tôm, cá, trứng... theo tư vấn của bác sĩ.Dấu hiệu còi xương sớm là trẻ hay quấy khóc, nôn trớ, ra mồ hôi trộm, ngủ không yên giấc, rụng tóc phía sau đầu (vành khăn). Trẻ bị còi xương cấp có biểu hiện tiếng thở rít thanh quản, hay nôn, nấc khi ăn, có thể co giật do hạ canxi máu, chân cong (chân vòng kiềng), vòng cổ chân, cổ tay.Dấu hiệu còi xương thể bụ bẫm tương tự với còi xương thông thường. Tình trạng thường xảy ra ở trẻ thừa cân, béo phì nhưng thiếu vitamin D. Nếu không kịp thời điều trị, sau khoảng vài tuần, trẻ xuất hiện triệu chứng ở xương, dấu hiệu khác nhau tùy vào độ tuổi."},{"question":"Sanaa moy péeyu ban réw?","answer":"Sanaa moy péeyu réwum Yémen"},{"question":"ධර්ම චක්‍ර මුද්‍රාව  ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"බුදු හිමියනගේ ධර්ම දේශනා විලාසය සංකේතවත් කරනු ලබන මුද්‍රාවයි.දකුණු අත්ල පිටතට හරවා පපුවේ මට්ටමට තබාගෙන,එහි දබර ඇඟිල්ලෙන් හා මහපට ඇඟිල්ලේ තුඩු දෙක කවයක් සෑදෙන සේ එකට තබා ඇතුළට හැරැණු වම් අතේ ඇඟිල්ලක් ස්පර්ශ කරන අයුරින් පැවතීම ධර්ම චක්‍ර මුද්‍රාවේ ලක්ෂණයයි."},{"question":"ప్రపంచీకరణ అంటే ఏమిటి ? దాని ఆవశ్యకతను వివరించండి.","answer":"ప్రపంచము స్వయం పోషక జాతీయ ఆర్థిక వ్యవస్థల నుంచి క్రమముగా పరస్పరం ఆధారపడిన సమీకృత ప్రపంచ ఆర్థిక వ్యవస్థ దిశగా కదులుతున్నది. దీనినే ప్రపంచీకరణగా వ్యవహరించడం జరుగుతుంది. ఒక దేశ ఆర్థిక వ్యవస్థ కార్యకలాపాల పరిధిని విదేశాలకు కూడా విస్తరించే విధానమే ప్రపంచీకరణ. ఉత్పత్తి కారకాలకు ప్రపంచవ్యాప్తముగా సంపూర్ణమైన గమనశీలతను ఏర్పరచడమే ప్రపంచీకరణ. ఒకదేశ ఆర్థిక వ్యవస్థను ప్రపంచ ఆర్థికవ్యవస్థలలో అనుసంధానము చేసి ప్రపంచాన్ని ఏకైక అంతర్జాతీయ మార్కెట్గా రూపొందించడమే ప్రపంచీకరణ లక్ష్యము. దీనివలన ప్రపంచ దేశాల మధ్య దూరము తగ్గి ప్రపంచమంతా ఒక గ్రామముగా మారే అవకాశము ఉన్నది.అభివృద్ధి చెందిన దేశాల ఆర్థిక శాస్త్రవేత్తలు ప్రపంచీకరణను ఈ విధముగా నిర్వచించినారు. “స్వేచ్ఛా వాణిజ్య విధానము, పెట్టుబడి, సాంకేతిక పరిజ్ఞానము, శ్రామికుల గమనశీలత”. ప్రపంచీకరణలో నాలుగు లక్షణాలు ఉన్నవి. అవి:ఆటంకాలు లేని వర్తక ప్రవాహాలు: దేశ సరిహద్దులు దాటి వస్తువుల ప్రవాహాలు స్వేచ్ఛగా జరగడానికి అనుమతులు తేలికగా లభించేటట్లుగా వర్తక అవరోధాలను తగ్గించుట.మూలధన ప్రవాహాలు: వివిధ దేశాల మధ్య మూలధనము స్వేచ్ఛగా ప్రవేశించడానికి వీలుగా వాతావరణాన్ని సృష్టించడం.సాంకేతిక విజ్ఞానాల ప్రవాహము: సాంకేతిక విద్య, విజ్ఞానము ఒక ప్రాంతము నుంచి మరొక ప్రాంతానికి, ఒక దేశము నుంచి మరొక దేశానికి స్వేచ్ఛగా ప్రవేశించడానికి అనువైన వాతావరణము.ఆటంకములేని శ్రామికుల గమనము: ప్రపంచములోని వివిధ దేశాలమధ్య శ్రామికుల స్వేచ్ఛాగమనాన్ని ప్రోత్సహించే విధముగా వాతావరణమును సృష్టించడము.ప్రపంచీకరణలో రెండు రూపాలున్నవి. 1) మార్కెట్ను ప్రపంచీకరించడం, 2) ఉత్పత్తిని ప్రపంచీకరించడం.మార్కెట్ను ప్రపంచీకరించడం అంటే జాతీయ మార్కెట్లను ఒక ప్రపంచ మార్కెట్ కలిపివేయడం ద్వారా వ్యాపార ఆటంకాలు తగ్గి, అంతర్జాతీయ విక్రయాలు సులభతరము అవుతాయి. వినియోగదారుల అభిరుచులు, ఇష్టాలు ఒక ప్రపంచక్రమానుసారము ఐక్యం అవుతుంది. సంస్థలు సారూప్యత గల ప్రధాన వస్తువులను ప్రపంచవ్యాప్తముగా అందిస్తూ ప్రపంచమార్కెట్కు దోహదపడతాయి.ఉత్పత్తిని ప్రపంచీకరించడం అంటే వస్తుసేవల ఉత్పత్తి కేంద్రాలను ఉత్పత్తికారకములైన శ్రమ, భూమి, మూలధనమును ప్రపంచములోని వివిధ ప్రాంతాలకు వ్యాపింపచేయడం. కంపెనీలు వ్యయమును తగ్గించుట ద్వారా, నాణ్యతను పెంచడంద్వారా వస్తు సేవలను అందించడములో వాటి పనితీరును మెరుగుపరుచుకుంటాయి.ప్రపంచీకరణకు రెండు కారకాలు ఉంటాయి. 1) తక్కువ వర్తక ఆటంకాలు. 2) సాంకేతికపరమైన మార్పులు. సాంకేతిక మార్పులు టెలీకమ్యూనికేషన్స్ మరియు మైక్రోప్రాసెసర్స్, ప్రపంచవ్యాప్త వెబ్, రవాణాలో పురోగతులు సంభవించినవి. రవాణా వ్యయాలను తగ్గించి, సంస్థలు తమకు ఆర్థికముగా భౌగోళికముగా, అనుకూలముగా ఉన్న ప్రాంతాలకు వ్యాప్తిచెందేలా చేశాయి. సమాచారాన్ని సేకరించడానికి, విశ్లేషించడానికి, అందించడానికి అయ్యే వ్యయాలను తగ్గించడం ద్వారా ప్రపంచవ్యాప్తమైన ఉత్పత్తి సంవిధానాన్ని సంస్థలు సమర్థవంతముగా నిర్వహించేలా చేశాయి."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau -  Lâu đài của Sobieski ở Oława là một lâu đài theo phong cách Phục hưng - Baroque nằm trong khu vực của một lâu đài gothic trước đây. Lâu đài ban đầu được xây dựng bởi Công tước Ludwik I vào nửa sau của thế kỷ mười bốn. Đó là cấu trúc lâu đài thứ ba ở Olawa. Ban đầu nó là chỗ của người cai quản thành trì, và nằm ở phía đông nam của thị trấn. Nó vẫn là một phần không thể thiếu trong hệ thống phòng thủ của thị trấn cho đến các cuộc chiến","answer":"với người Hussite. Với vị trí chiến lược này, nó đã đóng góp quan trọng vào hệ thống phòng thủ và quản lý an ninh của thị trấn trong nhiều thế kỷ, vượt qua các cuộc chiến và biến đổi thời kỳ."},{"question":"கம்பராமாயணக் கதைமாந்தர்களுள் எவரேனும் ஒருவர் குறித்து வகுப்பில் உரையாற்றுக.","answer":"கதைமாந்தர்: குகன்தன் மனைவி சீதையுடனும், தம்பி இலக்குவனுடனும் இராமன் காட்டிற்குச் சென்றான். செல்லும் வழியில் கங்கைக் கரையை அடைந்தான். அங்கே அன்பே வடிவான வேட்டுவத்தலைவன் குகன் இராமனைச் சந்தித்தான்.போர்க்குணமிக்க குகனானவன் ஆயிரம் படகுகளுக்குத் தலைவன்; கங்கையாற்றுத் தோணித் துறைக்குத் தொன்றுதொட்டு உரிமையுடையவன்; பகைவர்களை அழிக்கும் வில்லாற்றல் பெற்றவன்; மலை போன்ற திரண்ட தோள்களை உடையவன்; துடி என்னும் பறையை உடையவன்; வேட்டை நாய்களைக் கொண்டிருப்பவன்; தோல் செருப்பு அணிந்த பெருங்கால்களை உடையவன் ; கரிய நிறத்தவன். கரிய மேகக் கூட்டம் திரண்டு வந்தாற்போல் மிகுதியான படைபலம் உடையவன்.இத்தகைய குகன் கங்கைக் கரையின் பக்கத்திலுள்ள சிருங்கிபேரம் என்னும் நகரில் வாழ்பவன். அவன் முனிவர் தவச்சாலையில் உள்ள இராமனைக் காண தேனும் மீனும் கொண்டு சென்றான் (அரசன், குரு, தெய்வம் ஆகியோரைக் காணச் செல்லும் போது வெறுங்கையோடு செல்லலாகாது என்பது தமிழ் மரபு).இராமனைக் கண்டதும் இருள் போன்ற நீண்ட முடியுடைய தலை மண்ணில் படியக் கீழே விழுந்து வணங்கினான். பின், எழுந்து வாயை கையால் பொத்தி, உடலை வளைத்து அடக்கமாய் நின்றான். இராமன் அவனை தன் அருகில் அமருமாறு கூறியும் மரியாதை நிமித்தமாக அவன் அமரவில்லை .குகனின் அன்பு மற்றும் மரியாதையைக் கண்ட இராமன் குகனிடம், உள்ளத்து அன்பு முதிர்வினால் நீ கொண்டு வந்த இந்தப் பொருட்கள் எத்தன்மையதாய் இருந்தாலும் அமுதத்தைவிட சிறந்தனவே. அன்பு கலந்ததனால் தூயனவே. நான் இதை ஏற்றுக் கொண்டதே விரும்பி உண்டதற்குச் சமம் என்றான்.மேலும் குகனிடம், முன்னர் நாங்கள் உடன்பிறந்தோர் நால்வராய் இருந்தோம் ; விரிந்த அன்பினால் உன்னோடு ஐவரானோம் என்றான் இராமன்."},{"question":"Дотримуючись тексту, напиши відповідь на питання: Речення 1: Брюс працював інженером у Саутгемптоні і помер 3 жовтня 1940 року в свій 73-й день народження в доках Саутгемптона. Речення 2: Брюс працював інженером у Саутгемптоні. Він помер у Саутгемптонських доках у свій 73-й день народження, 3 жовтня 1940 року. Питання: Чи перше і друге речення розповідають тих самих фактах? Так чи ні?","answer":"Так."},{"question":"Sallar azahar raka'a nawa ce ?(a) hudu(b)uku(C) biyar","answer":"(a)"},{"question":"What category is this question from: ¿En qué ciudad se ubica la Gran Pirámide de Giza?.","answer":"La categoría a la que pertenece esta pregunta es geografía."},{"question":"Inona no  atao hoe  ankohonana?","answer":"Ny atao hoe  ankohonana dia Ray sy reny ary zanaka"},{"question":" sheeg waxyabaha laxiriira wegluhu? ","answer":" Waxyabaha laxiriira wegluhu waxaa kamid ah 1.Caqiidada 2.Barashada quraanka3.Barashada Higgaada iwm"},{"question":"参考下面的段落,然后以相同的语言回答后面的问题:  过道:在20世纪90年代初,海湾航天公司和苏霍伊设计局开始共同努力开发超音速小型商务喷气机,代号为S-21. 由于市场对商业超音速飞机的需求值得怀疑,对该项目的承诺减弱,延误增加.湾流最终解散了合作伙伴关系,尽管苏霍伊继续在S-21上工作.  问题:这两家公司共同制造的飞机是什么?","answer":"超音速小型商务喷气机,代号为S-21"},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe lahatra?","answer":"Ny lahatra dia fandaminan’Andriamanitra tsy azo ovana sy tsy azo ihodiviran’ny zavaboaary tsirairay hatrany am-piandohana na dia miezaka mandamina ny fiainany aza ny olona."},{"question":"* مارمز وكالة أنباء الإمارات ؟","answer":"وام"},{"question":"السؤال: كم تبلغ مساحة روسيا؟","answer":"الإجابة: 17,130,000 كم²"},{"question":"චීනයේ නිෂ්පාදිත \\" සිනොවැක් බයෝටෙක් \\" කොවිඩ් එන්නත මිලදීගත් , පළමුවැනි ආසියානු රට කුමක්ද ?","answer":"චීනයේ නිෂ්පාදිත \\" සිනොවැක් බයෝටෙක් \\" කොවිඩ් එන්නත මිලදීගත් , පළමුවැනි ආසියානු රට වන්නේ ඉන්දුනීසියාව යි."},{"question":"வினா: நிதி ஆணையத்தின் பதவிக்காலம்?","answer":"விடை: 5 ஆண்டுகள் "},{"question":"ක්‍රිකට් ක්‍රීඩාවේ කඩුළු දෙකක් අතර දුර කීයද?","answer":"යාර 22"},{"question":"Maak een functiebeschrijving voor de volgende rol: Data Analytics Consultant.","answer":"We zijn op zoek naar een Data Analytics Consultant om onze activiteiten te ondersteunen. De consultant zal strategieën ontwikkelen om inzichten uit data te begrijpen, interpreteren en de resultaten gebruiken. De consultant moet ervaring hebben in data visualisatie en dashboard ontwikkeling, machine learning en communicatie van data inzichten naar interne en externe belanghebbenden. De ideale kandidaat heeft uitstekende probleemoplossende vaardigheden, is detailgericht en kan zelfverzekerd werken met belanghebbenden van verschillende niveaus."},{"question":"Vraag: Welk element is het meest voorkomende in het universum? A. Waterstof, B. Zuurstof, C. Stikstof, D. Koolstof","answer":"Antwoord: A. Waterstof"},{"question":"வினா:அமிலம் காரம் பற்றிய புதிய கொள்கை","answer":"விடை: பிரான்ஸ்டெட்–லவ்ரி கொள்கை"},{"question":"Ano ang pinakadulong estayon ng MRT-3?","answer":"Ang North Avenue Station sa Quezon City ang dulong estasyon ng MRT-3 sa hiwaga, at ang Taft Avenue Station sa Manila ang dulong estasyon sa timog."},{"question":"બાજીરાવ મસ્તની ફિલ્મ સમીક્ષાઓ લખો .","answer":"બાજીરાવ મસ્તની ફિલ્મ સમીક્ષાઓબાજીરાવ મસ્તની બોલિવૂડની એક ઐતિહાસિક રોમાંટિક ફિલ્મ છે જે 2015 માં રિલીઝ થઈ હતી. આ ફિલ્મને વિવેદકો અને પ્રેક્ષકો બંને પાસેથી ખૂબ સારી સમીક્ષાઓ મળી હતી. ફિલ્મે ઘણા ખ્યાતનામ ઇનામો પણ જીત્યા હતા, જેમાં 12 ફિલ્મફેર એવોર્ડ્સનો સમાવેશ થાય છે.ફિલ્મ તેના શાનપૂર્ણ સંગીત, અદભૂત ફોટોગ્રાફી, શક્તિશાળી પાત્રો અને ઐતિહાસિક સાચવણીને કારણે પ્રશંસા મેળવી હતી. ફિલ્મના કલાકારોએ પણ તેમના અભિનય માટે ખૂબ પ્રશંસા મેળવી હતી, ખાસ કરીને શાહરૂખ ખાને તેમના પ્રદર્શન માટે.બાજીરાવ મસ્તની ભારતના ઇતિહાસમાંથી એક મહાન યુગની વાર્તા છે. તે પ્રેમ, સંઘર્ષ અને સ્વપ્નો વિશે વાત કરે છે. તે એક સાહસિક અને રોમાંચક ફિલ્મ છે જે દરેકને ગમશે."},{"question":"Qual o significado de \\"Matar a cobra e mostrar o pau?\\"","answer":"\\"Matar a cobra e mostrar o pau\\" é um ditado popular de alguém que está trazendo evidências de que alcançou um objetivo. Em outras palavras, não está apenas dizendo que fez (matar a cobra), mas trazendo também a prova (mostrar o pau). Não há informações sobre a origem da expressão, mas se sabe que o objetivo dela é alertar que alguém não está fazendo afirmações vazias."},{"question":"මිනිසාගේ ඉළ ඇට ගණන කොපමණද?","answer":"12යි"},{"question":"Jubbantil mbind mii:Jàngoroo nekk ci seeni xol (gog sikki-sàkk ak ug naaféq), faf Yàlla yokk leen jàngoro. Mbugal mu metti dana leen dal ngir seenug weddi.","answer":"Mbind mi jub a ngi nii:Jàngoroo nekk ci séen i xol (gog sikki-sàkka ak ug naaféq), faf Yàlla yokk léen jàngoro. Mbugal mu metti da na léen dàl ngìr séenug weddi."},{"question":"Kung ang lalake ay may titi, ano naman ang mayroon sa babae?","answer":"Ang babae ay may kiki. Ang pinag-uusapan ng analogo ay ang sekswal na parte ng katawan ng mga tao, o ang bahagi ng katawan na ginagamit para sa pag-aanak at iba pang reproductive functions."},{"question":"Про яку важливу подію йде мова: під час Голодомору 1932-33 рр., проведеного урядом тодішнього СРСР, у Копилах загинуло 2 людини. На жаль, імена загиблих не встановлено.","answer":"Голодомор 1932-33 рр."},{"question":"வினா:அசோக சக்கரத்தை வென்ற முதல் இந்திய பெண் யார்?","answer":"விடை: நீர்ஜா பான்ட்"},{"question":"De qual categoria é essa pergunta: Qual monumento nacional localizado nas Montanhas Robledo no Novo México foi escolhido pelo Congresso em 2009?.","answer":"Geografia"},{"question":"In what year was the internet opened to the public?","answer":"1993"},{"question":"සජීවී සෛල, එනම් සජීව පදාර්ථය නිර්මාණය වී ඇති රසායනික සංයෝග, කාණ්ඩ දෙකකට බෙදිය හැක. ඒවා නම් කරන්න.","answer":"1. කාබනික සංයෝග2. අකාබනික සංයෝග"},{"question":"ध्यानले कसरी आन्तरिक शान्ति र शान्तिको भावनामा योगदान गर्छ?","answer":"ध्यानले आन्तरिक प्रतिबिम्ब र शान्तिको लागि ठाउँ सिर्जना गर्दछ। दिमागलाई शान्त गरेर र मानसिकताको अवस्थालाई बढावा दिएर, व्यक्तिहरूले आफ्नो दैनिक जीवनमा विस्तारित आन्तरिक शान्तिको गहिरो भावना अनुभव गर्न सक्छन्।"},{"question":"Sinds de zomer van 2021 vind je op de autosnelwegen in Frankrijk een witte ruit op een blauwe of zwarte achtergrond terug. Om op deze rijstroken te mogen rijden moet je aan één van drie voorwaarden voldoen. Deze rijstroken zijn ten eerste voorbehouden voor taxi’s en ten tweede voor groene auto’s (dat wil zeggen: elektrische, hybride of klasse 0-voertuigen). Wat is de derde voorwaarde om op deze rijstrook te mogen rijden?","answer":"Carpoolen "},{"question":"manao  ahoana Ireo karazana gidro/varika misy eto Madagasikara?","answer":"Tsy mitsahatra mitombo ny karazan’ireo gidro/varika fantatra fa misy eto Madagasikara  hatramin’izay nisian’ny fikarohana momba azy ireny. Tamin’ny fanisana farany dia fantatra fa misy 5 ny fianakaviam-be ny varika eto Madagasikara ka mitsinjara ho 15 ny “genre” , 99 karazany ary  110 taxa.Betsaka ihany koa anefa ireo karazana gidro/varika lehibe izay mahatratra hatrany amin’ny 200 kg ny halehibeny no fantatra fa lany tamingana noho ny fahasimban’ny tontolo iainan’izy ireo nisy eto ambon'ny tany sy teto Madagasikara."},{"question":"Mfihloni len' engaka,Zinyanya zakithi nonkana sitsheleni,Izinyanga nezanusi ziwachitha ziwaqoqe,Kanti kufihlweni?Nonesifuba ugcina esemchathazela umngani,Le mfihlo ayinamngani nasihlobo,Othuke wakwelamela okufihliwe uyihlab' inhlaliNabantabakhe uthi bayozibonela kuhle kwabenyoka.Abalele bayabuya ngamaphupho,Balethe izinhlanhla nemikhokha,Noma kunjalo sebeze baqumbelana,Bengayithi vu ngenhlalo yabo,Kukhulu esafihlelwa khona,Yonke imithetho iyeqiwa, ujeze,Munye vo ongasoze weqiwaLowo uthi, 'Ngamunye ngamunye wozibonela azizwele'Nesichwensi asichwenseli ngakuwo.Liba izindaba zakho ziyaxaka azixoxeki,Akukho namunye onyonyobayo,Azosihlebela ngenhlalo yangale,Kukhulu okufihlwe ngale kwempilo yomhlaba,Abanye bawuthumela igundane kepha kuwe lingelokothwe. 1. Phawula ngekhono lembongi ekusebenziseni isenzukuthi emgqeni we-15. ","answer":"Ikhono lembongi lokusebenzisa isenzukuthi u’vo’ lisetshenziswe ukugcizelelaumthetho owodwa kuphela ongasoze weqiwa muntu ngisho noma ngabeumuntu udelela kanjani."},{"question":"(Asukume ame eshashalazini lapho kukhombe khona uSalimani.)(Uthatha isihlalo ebesihleli uNodwengu usisa kuyena.)Esikhambeni esingakwesokudla sikaSinkampunkampu singamanzikampompi, abathi abaweli uMngeni abaphonse ubhontshisiomnyama.(Bangenisa amasaka kabhontshisi. Elinomnyama balibekangakwesokudla, elimhlophe lona ngakwesobunxele.)(Kungena zimbili zithwele izikhamba. Enye esinye isibeka ngaphanenye ngalena kukaNodwengu.)Laba abavuma ukuphanisa kuhle kwempahla yakobelungukubona umuntu ngamunye acoshe uhlamvu olumhlophe esakenilwalo bhontshisi aluphonse esitsheni esingakwesokunxele.1. Ucabanga ukuthi wawuzoba njani umphumela empilweni kaSalimani ukubealimthethanga icala laseMgungundlovu? Sekela umbono wakho ngamaphuzuAMATHATHU. ","answer":"Wawuzoba mubi, wayengeke esaba nezwi ebantwini bakhe njengobaabelungu babezobe sebemkhinyabeze amandla okuphatha. Imfuyoyayingathathwa ngabelungu, kube nokuchitheka kwegazi. Wayengagcinaehlukumezekile ebuswa ngabelungu ."},{"question":"Що таке \\"мікроскоп\\"?","answer":"Мікроскоп - це прилад для розглядання дрібних, невидимих для неозброєного ока, предметів у збільшеному зображенні."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"berbuat muka\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud berpura-pura menunjukkan sifat mesra dan hormat."},{"question":"Quem é Abel Ferreira?","answer":"Abel Ferreira é um técnico de futebol português que atualmente comanda o Palmeiras. Ele é conhecido por seu trabalho tático e já conquistou títulos importantes com o clube, como a Copa Libertadores."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਪ੍ਰਭ ਕੀ ਦ੍ਰਿਸਟਿ ਮਹਾ ਸੁਖੁ ਹੋਇ ॥ਹਰਿ ਰਸੁ ਪਾਵੈ ਬਿਰਲਾ ਕੋਇ ॥ਜਿਨ ਚਾਖਿਆ ਸੇ ਜਨ ਤ੍ਰਿਪਤਾਨੇ ॥ਪੂਰਨ ਪੁਰਖ ਨਹੀ ਡੋਲਾਨੇ ॥ਸੁਭਰ ਭਰੇ ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਰਸ ਰੰਗਿ ॥ਉਪਜੈ ਚਾਉ ਸਾਧ ਕੈ ਸੰਗਿ ॥ਪਰੇ ਸਰਨਿ ਆਨ ਸਭ ਤਿਆਗਿ ॥ਅੰਤਰਿ ਪ੍ਰਗਾਸ ਅਨਦਿਨੁ ਲਿਵ ਲਾਗਿ ॥ਬਡਭਾਗੀ ਜਪਿਆ ਪ੍ਰਭੁ ਸੋਇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਾਮਿ ਰਤੇ ਸੁਖੁ ਹੋਇ ॥੨॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 289 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ (ਮੇਹਰ ਦੀ) ਨਜ਼ਰ ਨਾਲ ਬੜਾ ਸੁਖ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ, (ਪਰ) ਕੋਈ ਵਿਰਲਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਦਾ ਸੁਆਦ ਚੱਖਦਾ ਹੈ । ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ (ਨਾਮ-ਰਸ) ਚੱਖਿਆ ਹੈ, ਉਹ ਮਨੁੱਖ (ਮਾਇਆ ਵਲੋਂ) ਰੱਜ ਗਏ ਹਨ, ਉਹ ਪੂਰਨ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਬਣ ਗਏ ਹਨ, ਕਦੇ (ਮਾਇਆ ਦੇ ਲਾਹੇ ਘਾਟੇ ਵਿਚ) ਡੋਲਦੇ ਨਹੀਂ; ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਪਿਆਰ ਦੇ ਸੁਆਦ ਦੀ ਮੌਜ ਵਿਚ ਉਹ ਨਕਾ-ਨਕ ਭਰੇ ਰਹਿੰਦੇ ਹਨ, ਸਾਧ ਜਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਗਤਿ ਵਿਚ ਰਹਿ ਕੇ (ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ) (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਮਿਲਾਪ ਦਾ) ਚਾਉ ਪੈਦਾ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ;ਹੋਰ ਸਾਰੇ (ਆਸਰੇ) ਛੱਡ ਕੇ ਉਹ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਸਰਨ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ, ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਚਾਨਣ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ ਹੈ, ਤੇ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਲਿਵ (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ) ਲੱਗੀ ਰਹਿੰਦੀ ਹੈ । ਵੱਡੇ ਭਾਗਾਂ ਵਾਲੇ ਬੰਦਿਆਂ ਨੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਨੂੰ ਸਿਮਰਿਆ ਹੈ । ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਵਿਚ ਰੱਤਿਆਂ ਸੁਖ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ ।੨।\\""},{"question":"Qual é a capital dos Emirados Árabes Unidos?","answer":"Abu Dabi."},{"question":"எந்த வைட்டமின் குறைபாட்டால் இரவு குருட்டுத்தன்மை ஏற்படுகிறது?","answer":"வைட்டமின் ஏ குறைபாடு காரணமாக இரவு குருட்டுத்தன்மை ஏற்படுகிறது. வைட்டமின் ஏ குறைபாடு அல்லது ஹைபோவைட்டமினோசிஸ் ஏ என்பது இரத்தம் மற்றும் திசுக்களில் வைட்டமின் ஏ இல்லாதது . இது ஏழ்மையான நாடுகளில், குறிப்பாக குழந்தைகள் மற்றும் இனப்பெருக்க வயதுடைய பெண்களிடையே பொதுவானது, ஆனால் மிகவும் வளர்ந்த நாடுகளில் அரிதாகவே காணப்படுகிறது. நிக்டலோபியா (இரவு குருட்டுத்தன்மை) இன் முதல் அறிகுறிகளில் ஒன்றாகும், ஏனெனில் வைட்டமின் ஒளி கடத்தலில் முக்கிய பங்கு வகிக்கிறது . செரோஃப்தால்மியா , கெரடோமலாசியா , மற்றும் முழுமையான குருட்டுத்தன்மை குறைபாடு அதிகமாக இருந்தால் பின் தொடரலாம்.வைட்டமின் ஏ குறைபாடு தடுக்கக்கூடிய குழந்தை பருவ குருட்டுத்தன்மைக்கு உலகின் முக்கிய காரணமாகும் , மேலும் குழந்தை இறப்பைக் குறைப்பதற்கான மில்லினியம் டெவலப்மெண்ட் இலக்கு நான்கை அடைவதில் முக்கியமானது . வளரும் நாடுகளில் சுமார் 250,000 முதல் 500,000 ஊட்டச்சத்து குறைபாடுள்ள குழந்தைகள் ஒவ்வொரு ஆண்டும் வைட்டமின் ஏ குறைபாட்டால் பார்வையற்றவர்களாக மாறுகிறார்கள், அவர்களில் பாதி பேர் பார்வையற்றவர்களாகி ஒரு வருடத்திற்குள் இறக்கின்றனர். "},{"question":"Seleccione la respuesta correcta: El escorbuto es una enfermedad que los marineros suelen contraer en largos viajes. Se descubrió que el escorbuto se podía prevenir comiendo naranjas y limones. Esto sugiere que el escorbuto es una enfermedad causada por... - exposición al aire marino; - una deficiencia nutricional; - un microorganismo; - falta de ejercicio. Respuesta: ","answer":"una deficiencia nutricional."},{"question":"¿De qué evento importante trata este texto? El réis es una deformación de la palabra portuguesa \\"reais\\", plural de la moneda real (que significa lo mismo que en castellano: \\"perteneciente al rey\\" o \\"propio de un rey\\"). Fue la moneda de Portugal desde 1500 hasta 1911. El real reemplazó al \\"dinheiro\\" (dinero) al cambio de 1 real = 840 dinheiros y en 1911 fue reemplazada por el \\"escudo\\", a causa de la Revolución del 5 de octubre de 1910, al tipo de 1 escudo = 1000 réis.","answer":"Este texto trata sobre la moneda portuguesa llamada \\"réis\\". Habla sobre su origen, su significado, su duración como moneda de Portugal desde 1500 hasta 1911, y su posterior reemplazo por el \\"escudo\\" debido a la Revolución del 5 de octubre de 1910."},{"question":"පාරු  කවියක්  සඳහා   උදහරණයක් දෙන්න ","answer":"මාතර ගඟේ ඉන්නා කිඹුලිගේ පැටියාතල්ල සුදයි බෙල්ලේ ගෝමර කැටියායන එන ඔරු පාරු නවතා ගෙන සිටියාමිනී නොකයි මාතර කිඹුලිගේ පැටියා"},{"question":"السؤال: من هو بطل العالم في التنس لعام ٢٠٢٠ من الرجال؟","answer":"الإجابة:  الصربي نوفاك ديوكوفيتش"},{"question":"Háblame sobre la segunda guerra mundial y el holocausto, máximo 2000 caracteres.","answer":"La Segunda Guerra Mundial, que tuvo lugar entre 1939 y 1945, fue un conflicto global que involucró a la mayoría de las naciones del mundo. Fue desencadenada por la invasión de Polonia por parte de Alemania en 1939 y resultó en una serie de alianzas militares y enfrentamientos en diferentes frentes.Uno de los aspectos más oscuros de la Segunda Guerra Mundial fue el Holocausto, que fue el genocidio sistemático llevado a cabo por el régimen nazi liderado por Adolf Hitler. Durante este período, aproximadamente seis millones de judíos, junto con otros grupos como gitanos, discapacitados y minorías étnicas, fueron perseguidos y asesinados en campos de concentración y exterminio.El Holocausto fue un evento sin precedentes en la historia, donde la maquinaria del Estado se utilizó para llevar a cabo el exterminio sistemático de millones de personas. Los campos de concentración como Auschwitz, Treblinka y Sobibor se convirtieron en símbolos de este horror inimaginable.La Segunda Guerra Mundial y el Holocausto dejaron una profunda marca en la historia y en la conciencia global. Sirven como recordatorio de los horrores extremos que puede llevar a cabo el odio y la intolerancia, y han motivado esfuerzos para prevenir futuros conflictos y genocidios a través de la promoción de la paz, la tolerancia y los derechos humanos. "},{"question":"Diniho ity fanambarana manaraka ity: “Mpampihorohoro avokoa ny fivavahana eny amin'ny fiangonana sekta ka tokony ho voarara!” Misy resaka fankahalana ve ity fanambarana ity?","answer":"Eny, maneho fankahalana amin'ny vondrom-pivavahana sekta ity fanambarana ity."},{"question":"Euskal mitologiako Mari nola irudikatzen da?","answer":"Mari Euskal mitologiako jainkosa nagusia da. Normalean emakume eder batekin irudikatzen da, ile luze eta gorriarekin. Batzuetan, sugearen itxura hartzen du. Anboto mendian bizi dela esaten da, baina beste mendi batzuetan ere agertzen da."},{"question":"في أي قارة تقع تشاد؟","answer":"تقع التشاد في قارة إفريقيا."},{"question":"Ṣọọṣi Ridiimu pese aaye itọju aisan kindirin si ọsibitu OOUTH, wọn tun ra irinṣẹ si i","answer":"Ninu akitiyan wọn lati lọwọ si alaafia araalu, ki wọn si ran ijọba lọwọ, ijọ Onirapada ti wọn n pe ni Ridiimu, ti pese aaye itọju aisan kindinrin si ọsibitu Ọlabisi Ọnabanjọ to wa ni Ṣagamu, nipinlẹ Ogun, bẹẹ ni wọn si ra irinṣẹ ti wọn yoo maa lo nibẹ si i.Ọjọbọ, ọjọ karun-un oṣu kẹjọ ọdun 2021 ni Gomina Dapọ Abiọdun, ṣi ileetọju naa ti wọn pe orukọ ẹ ni ‘Enoch and Folu Adeboye Dialisis Centre’, pẹlu ọrọ iwuri to ti ẹnu Igbakeji ẹ, Onimọ-ẹrọ Nọimọt Salakọ-Oyedele, to ṣoju rẹ wa.Gomina Abiọdun sọ pe agbekalẹ bii eyi yoo ran ijọba lọwọ lati wa alaafia faraalu si i. O ni nigba ti awọn ileejọsin atawọn olufẹ idagbasoke mi-in ba n kun ijọba lọwọ bii eyi lati pese itọju, ko si bi ẹka ilera ko ṣe ni i gbera sọ. O dupẹ lọwọ ijọ Onirapada fun ohun ti wọn ṣe yii, bẹẹ lo ni ijọba oun ko ni i da iṣẹ naa da awọn oluranlọwọ bii eyi, awọn yoo maa ṣe aṣekun mọ eyi tawọn n ṣe lọ ni.Irinṣẹ itọju aisan kindinrin ti wọn ko saaye naa ni ẹrọ kan to n tọju omi ti wọn yoo lo fun alaisan, eyi to n fọ omi naa mọ gaara ati ẹrọ amunawa jẹnẹretọ ti wọn yoo maa fi lo o bi ina ọba ba lọ.(30kva generator)Lara awọn to tun wa nibẹ lọjọ naa ti wọn fi idunnu wọn han si eto yii ni Dokita Tomi Coker, iyẹn kọmiṣanna eto ilera nipinlẹ Ogun, pẹlu Akarigbo ilẹ Rẹmọ, Ọba Babatunde Ajayi.Gbogbo wọn ni wọn fi atilẹyin wọn han si igbesẹ yii, ti wọn dupẹ lọwọ ijọ Ridiimu fun iranlọwọ naa, pẹlu ileri pe ijọba yoo maa fọwọsowọpọ pẹlu awọn ẹka aladaani to ba fẹẹ ṣe iru eyi, wọn si gba a laduura pe oke ti ọwọ afunni n gbe lọwọ wọn yoo maa lọ.Akarigbo rọ awọn oninu-dundu ọlọrẹ lati dide, ati awọn ẹka aladaani naa, ki wọn ran ijọba Gomina Dapọ Abiọdun lọwọ lati pese ọjọ iwaju rere to pilẹ rẹ lati mu wa fun ipinlẹ Ogun.Adele ọga pata ni OOUTH, Dokita Oluwabunmi Fatungaṣe, sọ ninu ọrọ tiẹ pe ile itọju aisan kindinrin yii yoo jẹ ibi iranlọwọ fawọn araalu ti aisan naa ba n da laamu, ti wọn ko si lowo gidi ti wọn yoo fi tọju ara wọn lawọn ọsibitu olowo gegere."},{"question":"イギリスではなぜか「ヨコハマ」と呼ばれている、高知県原産の特別天然記念物の鳥は何でしょう？","answer":"尾長鳥です。"},{"question":"தாவர வகைப்பாட்டியலின் தந்தை' என்று அழைக்கப்படுபவர் யார்?","answer":"கரோலஸ் லின்னேயஸ் வகைபிரிப்பின் தந்தை (உயிரினங்களை வகைப்படுத்தி பெயரிடும் அமைப்பு) ஆவார். கரோலஸ் லின்னேயஸ் (கரோலசு இலின்னேயசு) சுவீடன் நாட்டைச் சேர்ந்த, உயிரினங்களைப் பற்றி ஆய்வு செய்த முன்னோடி அறிவியலாளர். இவர் தாவரவியலாளராகவும், விலங்கியலாளராகவும், மருத்துவராகவும் திகழ்ந்தார். புதிய, தற்கால அறிவியல் வகைப்பாட்டு முறைக்கும், பெயர்முறைக்கும் அடிப்படையை உருவாக்கியவர் இவரே. தற்கால சூழிணக்கவியல் அல்லது சூழிசைவு இயலின் முன்னோடிகளில் ஒருவராக இவர் கருதப்படுகிறார். எனவே இவர் நவீன வகைப்பாட்டியலின் தந்தையென அழைக்கப்படுகிறார்."},{"question":" Qual é a capital da Austrália?","answer":"A capital da Austrália é Canberra. Localizada no Território da Capital Australiana (Australian Capital Territory - ACT), Canberra foi escolhida como capital em 1908 devido à sua localização entre as duas maiores cidades do país, Sydney e Melbourne, que eram as principais candidatas a capital. A cidade foi planejada especificamente para ser a sede do governo australiano."},{"question":"ચાલો જાણીએ ચોળાફળી વિશે","answer":"ચોળાફળીએ ચણાનો લોટ, મગનો લોટ, અડદનો લોટ, મઠનો લોટ જેવા લોટને મિશ્ર કરીને બનાવાતું એક તળેલું [૧] ફરસાણ છે. તેનો દેખાવ કઠોળ આદિની ફળી જેવો હોવાથી તેને ફળી કહેવાતી હશે. જોકે તેમાં ચોળાનો લોટ વપરાતો નથી. આ ફરસાણ પર મરચું અને સંચળ ભભરાવીને પણ ખવાય છે.ગુજરાતભરમાં આ ફરસાણ દિવાળીના તહેવારમાં વિશેષ બનાવાય છે. અમદાવાદમાં આ ફરસાણ ચણાના લોટ અને ફુદિનાની ચટણી સાથે ખવાય છે. અમદાવાદીઓ માટે આ બપોરના નાસ્તા તરીકે મશહુર છે."},{"question":"Berikan jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut:  Mee apa yang ramai dan tak boleh isi perut?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah meeting. Ini adalah teka-teki yang bermain dengan perkataan dalam Bahasa Melayu, di mana kata \\"mee\\" yang biasanya merujuk kepada jenis makanan, digunakan di sini untuk merujuk kepada \\"meeting,\\" yang merupakan perkataan bahasa Inggeris untuk mesyuarat atau pertemuan."},{"question":"ద్విగు సమాసము గురించి వివరించి ఉదాహరణలు ఇవ్వండి.","answer":"ద్విగు సమాసము :సంఖ్యా వాచక శబ్దము పూర్వ పదము గాను, నామవాచకము ఉత్తరపదముగాను కలది.ఉదా :నాల్గులోకములు – నాల్గు సంఖ్యగల లోకములుపంచపాండవులు – పంచసంఖ్యగల పాండవులుసప్త సముద్రములు – సప్త సంఖ్యగల సముద్రములుదశ దిక్కులు – దశ సంఖ్య గల దిక్కులుమూడుతరాలు – మూడైన తరాలునాలుగు కాళ్ళు – నాలుగు సంఖ్య గల కాళ్ళురెండేళ్లు – రెండైన ఏళ్లుపన్నెండు ద్వారములు – పన్నెండు సంఖ్య గల ద్వారములు"},{"question":"س147- من الذي وضع علم النحو؟","answer":"ج147- أبو الأسود الدؤلي"},{"question":"\\" લોભિયા ભાઈ લટકી ગયા! \\" બાળવાર્તા લખો.","answer":"એક હતો લોભિયો. અસલી, પાકો ને ખરેખરનો લોભિયો.આ લોભિયા ભાઈને લીલું કોપરું ખાવાનું મન થયું. કહે: ‘લાવ, બજારમાં જાઉં ને ભાવ તો પૂછું?’‘અલ્યા નાળિયેરવાળા! આ નાળિયેરનું શું લઈશ?’‘કાકા! બે રૂપિયા.’‘બે રૂપિયા? એ આપણું કામ નહિ. રૂપિયાનું નાળિયેર ક્યાંય મળે કે?’‘કાકા! જરા આગળ જાઓ તો મોટી બજારમાં મળશે.’‘ચાલને મોટી બજાર સુધી જાઉં! એક રૂપિયો બચતો હોય તો પગ છૂટો થશે ને સસ્તું નાળિયેર પણ મળશે.’‘અલ્યા ભાઈ ! નાળિયેરનું શું લે છે?’‘કાકા ! એક રૂપિયો. જૂઓ આ પડ્યાં નાળિયેર. જોઈએ એટલાં લઈ જાઓ!’‘અરે! હું આટલે સુધી ચાલીને આવ્યો ને તું એક રૂપિયો માંગે છે? પચાસ પૈસે આપ, પચાસ પૈસે.’‘તો કાકા ! જરા વધુ આગળ જાઓ; ગામ બહારની વખારમાંથી તમને પચાસ પૈસે મળશે.’‘પચાસ પૈસા ક્યાં રેઢા પડ્યા છે? એટલું ચાલી નાખશું. લાવને, વખાર સુધી જાઉં!’‘અલ્યા વખારવાળા! આ નાળિયેર કેમ આપ્યાં? આ તો સારાં લાગે છે!’‘કાકા! એમાં શું ભાવ કરવાનો હોય? લઈ જાવ પચાસ પૈસે નાળિયેર.’‘અરે રામ! આટલું ચાલ્યો એ પાણીમાં ગયું? એમ કર, પાવલીમાં આપીશ? આ લે રોકડા પૈસા.’‘કાકા! પાવલી પણ શું કામ ખરચવી ? એક કામ કરો. જૂઓ અહીંથી બે કલાક આગળ ચાલીને જશો તો દરિયા કિનારો આવશે. ત્યાં નાળિયેરીના હારબંધ ઝાડ છે. ઝાડ ઉપર ચડી તમતમારે નાળિયેર તોડી લેજોને. એક પૈસો પણ ખરચવો નહિ અને જોઈએ એટલા નાળિયેર મળશે!’લોભિયા ભાઈ તો લલચાઈ ગયા. કહે :‘હવે આટલા ભેગું આટલું. ચાલને ઝાડ ઉપરથી જ નાળિયેર ઉતારી લઉં! પાવલી બચતી હોય તો એક ટંક દૂધ આવશે. પાવલી ક્યાં મફત આવે છે?’લોભિયા ભાઈ તો ઉપડ્યા દરિયા કિનારે અને નાળિયેરી ઉપર ચડ્યા. મનમાં એમ કે ‘આટલાં બધાં મોટાં મોટાં નાળિયેર અબઘડી ઉતારી ને ફાંટ બાંધીને લઈ જાઉં ! એક પૈસો યે દેવાનો નહિ ને સાવ તાજાં નાળિયેર! આ વાત તો બહુ સારી કહેવાય.’લોભિયા ભાઈ ઝાડની છેક ઉપર પહોંચ્યા. લાંબો હાથ કરીને નાળિયેર લેવા ગયા પણ નાળિયેર તોડવાની આવડત કે અનુભવ નહિ એટલે નાળિયેરનું ઝૂંડ પકડીને જ લટકી પડ્યાં. ન નાળિયેર તૂટે ને ન પોતે નીચે ઉતરી શકે. એવી તો હાલત ખરાબ થઈ ગઈ કે વાત ન પૂછો. બૂમાબૂમ કરી માણસો ભેગા કર્યાં પણ કોઈ એમને નીચે ઉતારવા તૈયાર નહિ. છેવટે એક મજૂર તૈયાર થયો પણ કહે કે શેઠ! તમને નીચે ઉતારવાના દશ રૂપિયા થશે. ખૂબ રકઝક પછી પણ એ ન માન્યો એટલે લોભિયા ભાઈ થાકી-હારીને દશ રૂપિયા આપી નીચે ઉતર્યા પણ નીચે ઉતરતાં ઉતરતાં એક નાળિયેર તો પોતાની સાથે લઈ જ આવ્યા.આમ લોભિયા ભાઈને બે રૂપિયાનું એક નાળિયેર છેવટે દશ રૂપિયામાં પડ્યું!"},{"question":"రాజ్యం, సమాజం మధ్యగల సంబంధం, వ్యత్యాసాలను వివరించండి.","answer":"పరిచయం: రాజ్యం, సమాజం అనేవి ప్రముఖమైన మానవసంస్థలు. మేకైవర్ అభిప్రాయంలో రక్త సంబంధం సమాజ అవతరణకు దారితీస్తే, సమాజం రాజ్య ఆవిర్భావానికి నాంది పలికింది.రాజ్యం: “ఒక నిర్ణీత భూభాగంలో రాజకీయంగా వ్యవస్థాపితమైన ప్రజలే రాజ్యం” – బ్లంటి సమాజం: “కొన్ని ఉమ్మడి లక్ష్యాలను సాధించేందుకై సమైక్యం చెందిన వ్యక్తుల సమూహం”.రాజ్యానికి, సమాజానికి మధ్యగల సంబంధం:1) ఒకే రకమైన లక్షణాలు: రాజ్యం, సమాజం రెండింటికి ఒకే తరహా లక్షణాలు ఉంటాయి. సాధారణంగా రాజ్యం, సమాజాలలో ప్రజలే ఉంటారు. సమాజంలోని సభ్యులే రాజ్యంలో సభ్యులుగా కొనసాగుతారు.2) పరస్పర పూరకాలు: రాజ్యం, సమాజం రెండూ పరస్పర పూరకాలు. ఒకదానికొకటి సహకరించుకొంటాయి. సమాజ ప్రగతి రాజ్య ప్రగతిపై ఆధారపడి ఉంటుంది. రాజ్య కార్యకలాపాలు లేదా పనితీరు సమాజంలోని ఆచారాలు, సంప్రదాయాలపై ఆధారపడి ఉంటాయి.3) పర్యాయపదాలు: రాజ్యం, సమాజం అనే పదాలను అనేక సందర్భాలలో పర్యాయపదాలుగా వినియోగించడమైంది. గ్రీకు రాజనీతితత్త్వవేత్తలైన ప్లేటో, అరిస్టాటిల్లు, తరువాతి కాలంలో హెగెల్, బొసాంకేలు రాజ్యం, సమాజం రెండూ ఒకటే అని భావించారు. గ్రీకు రాజనీతి పండితులు నగర రాజ్యాలను, సమాజాన్ని పర్యాయపదాలుగా ఉపయోగించడం జరిగింది.4) పరస్పర సంబంధం: రాజ్యం, సమాజం మధ్యగల సంబంధాన్ని ఎవ్వరూ విస్మరించలేరు. రాజ్యం తాను రూపొందించిన చట్టాల ద్వారా సమాజంలో వ్యక్తుల బాహ్య ప్రవర్తనను నియంత్రిస్తుంది. సామాజిక వ్యవస్థకు విస్తృత పునాదిని ఏర్పరుస్తుంది. అందుచేత రాజ్యం సమాజాలను రెండు విభిన్న వ్యవస్థలలో విడదీయలేం. సమాజ ఆర్థిక, సాంస్కృతిక, మత, మానవతాపరమైన కార్యకలాపాల ద్వారా రాజ్యాన్ని పరిపుష్టంగావిస్తుంది.రాజ్యం, సమాజం మధ్య వ్యత్యాసాలు: రాజ్యం, సమాజాల మధ్య సన్నిహిత సంబంధం ఉన్నప్పటికీ, ఈ రెండూ ఒకదానికొకటి వ్యత్యాసాలను కలిగి ఉన్నాయి. వాటిని కింది పట్టిక ద్వారా తెలపవచ్చు.రాజ్యంరాజ్యం అనేది రాజకీయ సంస్థ.రాజ్యం వ్యక్తుల బాహ్య ప్రవర్తనను మాత్రమే నియంత్రిస్తుంది. ఈ విషయంలో అది కొన్ని నిబంధనలను రూపొందిస్తుంది.రాజ్యానికి దండనాధికారం ఉంది. రాజ్యశాసనాన్ని అతిక్రమించినవారు శిక్షార్హులుగా పరిగణించ బడతారు.రాజ్యం చేసే చట్టాలు రాజ్యానికి బలం చేకూరుస్తాయి.రాజ్యం అనేది ప్రాదేశిక సంస్థ. దానికి స్వీయ నిర్దిష్ట భూభాగం ఉంటుంది. ప్రాదేశికత అనేది రాజ్యానికి చెందిన ప్రధాన లక్షణంగా పేర్కొనవచ్చు.రాజ్యం ఒక్కటే సార్వభౌమాధికారాన్ని కలిగి ఉంటుంది. తన సార్వభౌమాధికారాన్ని వినియోగించి ప్రజల సంబంధాలను నిర్దేశించే అనేక చట్టాలను రూపొందించి, అమలు పరుస్తుంది.రాజ్యం సహజంగా ఏర్పడిన సంస్థ కాదు. అది మానవనిర్మితమైంది. దానిలో సభ్యత్వం వ్యక్తులకు నిర్బంధమైంది.రాజ్యం సమాజంలోని అతి ముఖ్యభాగం. సమాజంలోని రాజకీయంగా వ్యవస్థీకృతమైన భాగాన్ని అది సూచిస్తుంది.సాంఘిక వ్యవస్థ అభివృద్ధి చెందిన రూపమే రాజ్యం. అది సమాజం నుంచి ఆవిర్భవించింది.రాజ్యం శాశ్వతమైంది కాకపోవచ్చు. అది అంతరించి పోయే అవకాశం ఉంది. వేరొక రాజ్యం దానిని బలవంతంగా ఆక్రమించుకోవచ్చు.రాజ్య చట్టాలు, విధి, విధానాలు ఖచ్చితంగాను, స్పష్టంగాను ఉంటాయి.రాజ్యంలోని చట్టాలు ఒకే విధంగా ఉంటాయి. ఒకే చట్టాన్ని అతిక్రమించిన వ్యక్తులందరూ తారతమ్యం లేకుండా శిక్షకు గురవుతారు.రాజ్యానికి ప్రభుత్వం అనే రాజకీయ వ్యవస్థ ఉంటుంది. అది రాజ్యం తరపున చట్టాలను రూపొందించి, అమలుచేస్తుంది.సమాజంసమాజం అనేది సాంఘిక వ్యవస్థ.సమాజం మానవుల బాహ్య, అంతర్గత ప్రవర్తనలు రెండింటిని నియంత్రిస్తుంది. వ్యక్తుల సామాజిక జీవనాన్ని ఇది క్రమబద్దం చేస్తుంది.సమాజానికి దండనాధికారం లేదు. సాంఘిక ఆచారాలను అతిక్రమిస్తే వారిని సమాజం శిక్షించ లేదు.సమాజంలోని ఆచారాలు, సంప్రదాయాలు, కట్టుబాట్లు సమాజానికి బలం చేకూరుస్తాయి.సమాజానికి నిర్దిష్టమైన భౌగోళిక హద్దులు లేవు. అది రాజ్యం కంటే విశాలమైంది కావచ్చు లేదా చిన్నదైనా కావచ్చు. సమాజం విశ్వమంతా విస్తరించి ఉంటుంది.సమాజానికి నిర్బంధ అధికారాలు అంటూ ఏవీ లేవు. సమాజం మానవ సామాజిక ప్రవర్తనను క్రమబద్దం చేసే నియమాలను రూపొందించి నప్పటికీ వాటికి చట్టబద్ధత ఉండదు.సమాజం సహజంగా, స్వతఃసిద్ధంగా ఏర్పడిన సంస్థ. వ్యక్తులు తమ విచక్షణను అనుసరించి దీనిలో సభ్యులుగా కొనసాగుతారు.రాజ్యం కంటే సమాజం విస్తృతమైంది. అనేక సంఘాలు, సంస్థలు, వ్యవస్థల ద్వారా అది ఏర్పడి అభివృద్ధి చెందుతుంది.సమాజం పెద్దది. రాజ్యం దానిలో అంతర్భాగం మాత్రమే. సమాజం రాజ్యం కంటే ముందు అవతరించింది. మానవుడు స్వభావరీత్యా సంఘ జీవి.సమాజం శాశ్వతమయింది. ఇది నిరంతరం కొనసాగుతుంది.సమాజ సూత్రాలు అస్పష్టమైనవి. అవి సాధారణంగా అనిర్దిష్టంగా ఉంటాయి. అవి సంప్రదాయాలు, కట్టుబాట్లపై ఆధారపడి ఉంటాయి.సమాజం నియమాలు ఒకే విధంగా ఉండవు. ఒక వర్గ నియమాలకు, వేరొక వర్గ నియమాలకు మధ్య వ్యత్యాసం ఉంటుంది. వివిధ సామాజిక వర్గాలు ఒకే రకమైన నేరానికి పాల్పడితే విధించే శిక్షలు వేరువేరుగా ఉంటాయి.సమాజ నియమాలను అమలుపరచడానికి ఒక ప్రత్యేకమైన యంత్రాంగమంటూ ఏదీ లేదు. ఆచారాలు, సంప్రదాయాలు, కట్టుబాట్ల ద్వారా అది మానవ ప్రవర్తనను నియంత్రిస్తుంది."},{"question":"ما عاصمة مالي ؟","answer":"تمبكتو"},{"question":"Karazana fifanarahana asa inona no tsy manana fe-potoana voafaritra?1-Ny CDI (Fifanarahana maharitra tsy voafetra)2-Ny CDD (fifanarahana maharitra)3-Ny fifanarahana vonjimaika","answer":"Valiny: 1. Ny CDI (Fifanarahana maharitra maharitra)"},{"question":"Фразеологиялык айкаш дегенде кандай түшүнөсүз?","answer":"Фразеологиялык айкаш дегенге мисал келтиребиз:Жалгыз эле мага  керекпи, чындап эле акыр заман келгенсип, эмне мынча сары  санаага батам?Ошентип дароо эле ток этер жеринен баштайын."},{"question":"Apakah air belanda?","answer":" Air yang bergas"},{"question":"Кыргызтан кайсы өлкөлөр менен чектешет?","answer":"Кыргызстан 4 өлкө менен чектешет.Алар:1-Казакстан🇰🇿2-Өзбекстан🇺🇿3-Таджикистан🇹🇯4-Кытай🇨🇳"},{"question":"Bán átt la senegaal njëkk diël raya wu football ci Afrique","answer":"2022 la senegaal njëkk diël raya wu football ci Afrique "},{"question":"Dựa trên tiêu đề sau, hãy viết một bài báo nói về chủ đề này: Dự báo điểm chuẩn cao nhất sẽ ở khối ngành Công nghệ thông tin và Kinh tế Theo GS.TS Nguyễn Trung Việt, Phó Hiệu trưởng trường ĐH Thủy lợi, năm nay, nhà trường vẫn tuyển sinh theo 4 phương thức. Thứ nhất, xét tuyển theo hình thức tuyển thẳng (5 đối tượng gồm học sinh đạt giải quốc tế, quốc gia; học sinh đạt giải cấp tỉnh; học sinh trường chuyên; học sinh đạt Học sinh giỏi 3 năm liên tục và học sinh có chứng chỉ tiếng Anh quốc tế). Thứ hai, xét tuyển theo kết quả 3 năm học THPT. Thứ ba, xét tuyển theo kết quả kỳ thi đánh giá năng lực tư duy phối hợp với trường Đại học Bách khoa Hà Nội. Thứ tư, xét tuyển theo kết quả kỳ thi tốt nghiệp THPT năm 2022. Với riêng hai hình thức xét tuyển theo kết quả kỳ thi đánh giá năng lực tư duy và kết quả thi tốt nghiệp THPT, chỉ tiêu sẽ không quá 50% so với tổng chỉ tiêu nhà trường đã công bố. Về dự báo điểm chuẩn trúng tuyển phương thức xét tuyển kết quả thi tốt nghiệp THPT, GS Việt cho biết trường ĐH Thủy lợi năm nay tuyển sinh tổng cộng 37 ngành, mỗi ngành có mức điểm chuẩn cao/thấp khác nhau. Trong đó, riêng khối kỹ thuật, GS Việt dự báo điểm chuẩn có thể tăng nhẹ so với mặt bằng chung điểm chuẩn năm 2021 và những năm trước đây, phạm vi khoảng 0,5 đến 1 điểm. Những ngành có điểm chuẩn cao nhất tại trường Đại học Thủy lợi vẫn là khối Công nghệ thông tin và khối ngành Kinh tế, đặc biệt là các chương trình đào tạo có liên kết với nước ngoài như Nhật Bản, Hàn Quốc. Tại buổi Tọa đàm trực tuyến do báo Dân trí vừa tổ chức, trả lời câu hỏi của một thí sinh về vấn đề \\"18 điểm khối A00 có cơ hội nào trúng tuyển vào ngành kỹ thuật của trường ĐH Thủy lợi?\\", GS Việt cho hay, với mức điểm thi này, thí sinh cũng có cơ hội trúng tuyển và có thể đăng ký vào các ngành kỹ thuật như Kỹ thuật công trình thủy, Kỹ thuật xây dựng công trình biển, Kỹ thuật tài nguyên nước, Thủy văn học, Kỹ thuật cơ sở hạ tầng,… Tuy nhiên, GS cũng đưa ra lời khuyên, các em cần phân tích kỹ các số liệu năm nay để đưa ra lựa chọn phù hợp nhất. Trả lời câu hỏi của một phụ huynh có con đạt 25.05 điểm khối D, xin tư vấn cơ hội trúng tuyển, GS.TS Nguyễn Trung Việt chia sẻ, đây là mức điểm tương đối cao với khối D. Nhà trường năm nay có tổng số 37 ngành tuyển sinh và em có thể cân nhắc, lựa chọn đặt hồ sơ vào các ngành nói trên. Dự kiến miễn học phí cho sinh viên một số ngành kỹ thuật Trả lời thắc mắc về cơ hội việc làm của các ngành mới tại trường như Trí tuệ nhân tạo và Khoa học dữ liệu; Kỹ thuật robot và Điều khiển thông minh, theo GS Việt, đây là những ngành có sức hấp dẫn rất cao trong xã hội hiện nay, điều kiện đầu ra rất tốt. \\"Ở trường ĐH Thủy lợi, ngành này chưa phải là ngành có truyền thống lâu năm như Thủy lợi, Thủy điện, Tài nguyên môi trường, Phòng chống giảm nhẹ thiên tai. Tuy nhiên, điểm đặc sắc của các ngành mới nói trên là chúng tôi có sự hợp tác chặt chẽ với các nước tiên tiến như Nhật Bản, Pháp, ứng dụng trí tuệ nhân tạo vào lĩnh vực mà trường ĐH Thủy lợi có thế mạnh\\", GS Việt cho hay. Về cơ sở vật chất đào tạo các ngành này, nhà trường đáp ứng các tiêu chuẩn cao, khắt khe của Nhật Bản. Sinh viên vừa học lý thuyết, vừa được thực hành, học chuyên môn bằng cả ngôn ngữ tiếng Nhật, tiếng Hàn, bởi vậy đáp ứng đầu ra ngay trong quá trình học tập ở trường. Bên cạnh các ngành mới trong khối Kỹ thuật và Công nghệ, GS Việt chia sẻ, trường ĐH thủy lợi cũng đào tạo thêm rất nhiều ngành học mới thuộc khối Kinh tế như Thương mại điện tử, Logistics và Quản lý chuỗi cung ứng, Quản trị du lịch và Lữ hành, Kinh tế số, Tài chính ngân hàng, Kiểm toán,…","answer":"Dự báo điểm chuẩn vào đại học Thủy lợi 2022: Khối kỹ thuật tăng nhẹ"},{"question":"Firy ny faritra eto Madagasikara?","answer":"Mizara ho faritra 22 i Madagasikara."},{"question":"पंडित जवाहरलाल नेहरू पर एक छोटा निबन्ध लिखिए।","answer":"पंडित जवाहरलाल नेहरू, जिन्हें पंडितजी के नाम से भी जाना जाता है, एक भारतीय राजनेता, एक दूरदर्शी नेता और एक स्वतंत्रता सेनानी थे जिन्होंने भारतीय स्वतंत्रता आंदोलन में एक महत्वपूर्ण भूमिका निभाई थी। वह स्वतंत्र भारत के पहले प्रधान मंत्री थे और १९४७ से १९६४ में उनकी मृत्यु तक सेवा की। उन्हें व्यापक रूप से आधुनिक भारत के वास्तुकार के रूप में माना जाता है और राष्ट्र के लिए उनका योगदान बहुत बड़ा है।१४ नवंबर, १८८९ को इलाहाबाद, उत्तर प्रदेश में जन्मे, नेहरू एक सफल वकील और राजनीतिज्ञ मोतीलाल नेहरू के सबसे बड़े पुत्र थे। उन्होंने अपनी शिक्षा हैरो स्कूल, ट्रिनिटी कॉलेज, कैम्ब्रिज और लंदन के इनर टेंपल में प्राप्त की, जहाँ उन्होंने कानून का अध्ययन किया।हालाँकि, भारतीय राजनीति और स्वतंत्रता के लिए उनके जुनून ने उन्हें अपना कानूनी करियर छोड़ने और 1919 में भारतीय राष्ट्रीय कांग्रेस में शामिल होने के लिए प्रेरित किया।नेहरू धर्मनिरपेक्षता, लोकतंत्र और समाजवाद में दृढ़ विश्वास रखते थे। वे महात्मा गांधी की शिक्षाओं से बहुत प्रभावित थे, और वे भारतीय राष्ट्रीय कांग्रेस में महात्मा के सबसे करीबी सहयोगियों में से एक थे। उन्होंने भारतीय स्वतंत्रता संग्राम में एक महत्वपूर्ण भूमिका निभाई, और उन्हें विभिन्न सविनय अवज्ञा आंदोलनों में शामिल होने के लिए कई बार कैद किया गया।१९४७ में भारत को ब्रिटिश औपनिवेशिक शासन से स्वतंत्रता मिलने के बाद, नेहरू भारत के पहले प्रधान मंत्री बने। उन्होंने भारत की घरेलू और विदेश नीतियों को आकार देने में महत्वपूर्ण भूमिका निभाई। उनकी सबसे उल्लेखनीय उपलब्धियों में से एक पंचवर्षीय योजनाओं की शुरूआत थी, जिसका उद्देश्य भारत की अर्थव्यवस्था और बुनियादी ढांचे का विकास करना था। औद्योगीकरण, शिक्षा और सामाजिक कल्याण पर नेहरू के ध्यान ने भारत को एक कृषि अर्थव्यवस्था से एक आधुनिक औद्योगिक राष्ट्र में बदलने में मदद की।नेहरू अंतर्राष्ट्रीय शांति और सहयोग के भी चैंपियन थे। उन्होंने शीत युद्ध के दौरान तटस्थता बनाए रखने की मांग करने वाले राष्ट्रों के समूह गुटनिरपेक्ष आंदोलन के गठन में महत्वपूर्ण भूमिका निभाई। उन्होंने संयुक्त राज्य अमेरिका, सोवियत संघ और चीन सहित अन्य देशों के साथ भारत के संबंधों को मजबूत करने के लिए भी काम किया।अपनी कई उपलब्धियों के बावजूद, नेहरू को प्रधान मंत्री के रूप में अपने कार्यकाल के दौरान कई चुनौतियों का सामना करना पड़ा। उन्हें सांप्रदायिक तनाव, आर्थिक संकट और क्षेत्रीय अलगाववादी आंदोलनों से निपटना पड़ा। विशेषकर कश्मीर और चीन के क्षेत्रों में उनकी नीतियों और निर्णयों के लिए उनकी आलोचना की गई।नेहरू की विरासत आज भी भारत में महसूस की जाती है। उन्हें एक दूरदर्शी नेता के रूप में याद किया जाता है जिन्होंने एक आधुनिक, लोकतांत्रिक और धर्मनिरपेक्ष राष्ट्र के निर्माण के लिए अथक प्रयास किया।शिक्षा और सामाजिक कल्याण के प्रति उनकी प्रतिबद्धता ने लाखों भारतीयों के जीवन को बेहतर बनाने में मदद की। भारत की विदेश नीति और अंतर्राष्ट्रीय संबंधों में उनके योगदान का अध्ययन और सराहना जारी है।निष्कर्ष:- पंडित जवाहरलाल नेहरू एक उल्लेखनीय नेता थे जिन्होंने अपना जीवन अपने देश की सेवा के लिए समर्पित कर दिया। भारत की प्रगति के प्रति उनकी दृष्टि, नेतृत्व और प्रतिबद्धता भारतीयों की पीढ़ियों को प्रेरित करती रहेगी। वह भारतीय इतिहास में एक महान व्यक्तित्व बने हुए हैं, और उनकी विरासत आने वाले वर्षों में देश के भविष्य को आकार देती रहेगी।"},{"question":"請回答這個問題：地球上最古老的戰爭是哪一場？","answer":"答案：古埃及的「卡德西戰役」"},{"question":"*أين يقع سهل البقاع ؟","answer":"لبنان"},{"question":"How to make an outdoor pillow? You have two possible solutions:Solution 1: Blow into a tin can and tie with rubber band Solution 2: Blow into a trash bag and tie with rubber band ","answer":"Solution 2 is more reasonable. It is much easier to blow into a trash bag compared to a tin can. "},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи ?","answer":"Албетте , мына сизге кызыктуу факты :Тамеки кутучасына 1966-жылдан бери  тамекинин зыяндуулугу жөнүндө эскерүүлөр жазыла баштаган. "},{"question":"இந்தப் பத்தியின் தொடர்ச்சியை எழுதுங்கள் - கஸ்தூரிபா ஆசிரமம் என்று அழைக்கப்படும் பங்களாதேஷ் விடுதலைப் போரின்போது","answer":", காலனி வங்காள விதவைகளுக்கான அகதி முகாமையும் இந்த பகுதி வைத்திருந்தது. 1960 ஆம் ஆண்டில், இந்தியப் பிரிவினைக்குப் பிறகு, பல ஆண்டுகளாக செயல்பட்ட பின்னர் மக்கள் சங்கத்தின் ஊழியர்கள் (1921 இல் லாகூரில் லாலா லஜ்பத் ராய் அவர்களால் நிறுவப்பட்டது) எம்.பி. லாலா அச்சிந்த் ராமின் இல்லத்திலிருந்து லஜ்பத் பவன் என்ற புதிய கட்டிடத்திற்கு மாற்றப்பட்டது."},{"question":"Ölen babasının maaşının kızı yüzde kaçını alır?","answer":"Yani vefat eden baba 1000 TL alıyorsa, yetim kalan çocuk da tek başına emekli maaşına başvuru yaptıysa bu durumda 500 TL olarak bağlanır. Eğer başka maaş alan çocuk varsa ya da eş de alıyorsa bu durumda ölen babadan kalan maaş için çocuğun hissesi %25 olur ve alınacak maaş 250 TL olur."},{"question":"ጥያቄ፦ በአማካይ የሰው ምላስ ምን ያህል ጣዕም አለው? መልስ፦ ","answer":"10,000"},{"question":":الكوكب الذي طول العام فيه11,86 سنة أرضية… هو كوكب..؟","answer":"المشتري"},{"question":"கேள்வி : தீயணைப்பு நிலைய அவசர உதவி எண்   எது? ","answer":"பதில் :  101"},{"question":"Descreva a bandeira da Suécia.","answer":"A bandeira da Suécia é composta por um campo azul com uma cruz amarela que se estende até as bordas da bandeira, formando um design simples e icônico."},{"question":"أعط معلومة عشوائية من الفئة التالية: الروايات","answer":"بالتأكيد، يسعدنى ذلك. عدد أشقاء بريدجيرتون في سلسلة كتب جوليا كوين هو ثمانية أشقاء."},{"question":"संयुक्त राष्ट्र संघ के शांति स्थापना मिशन और इनकी भूमिका। ","answer":"संयुक्त राष्ट्र संघ के शांति स्थापना मिशन विश्व के उन क्षेत्रों में काम करते हैं जहाँ संघर्ष या युद्ध हुआ है। इनका मुख्य उद्देश्य संघर्ष को समाप्त करना, स्थायी शांति स्थापित करना, और स्थानीय समुदायों के पुनर्निर्माण में मदद करना है। ये मिशन सैन्य और पुलिस बलों के साथ-साथ नागरिक कर्मचारियों को भी शामिल करते हैं। वे संघर्ष के बाद की स्थितियों में सुरक्षा, मानवाधिकारों की रक्षा, और राजनीतिक प्रक्रियाओं के समर्थन में महत्वपूर्ण भूमिका निभाते हैं।"},{"question":"No contexto do futebol, defina, de maneira concisa, a expressão \\"Bola Parada\\".","answer":"O expressão \\"Bola Parada\\" se refere à situações, em que o jogo é retomado, após uma interrupção, como falta, escanteio, ou tiro livre."},{"question":"inona ny zavatara masaka nefa tsy andrahoina ?","answer":"Ny voankazo no masaka nefa tsy andrahoina"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය රචනා  කලේ කව්ද ?තොටමුණ බද සිටි රුවන්මලීගඟ බිලිගත් මගෙ රුවන්මලීගමට සිටිය එක රුවන්මලීගඟට වරෙන් අද රුවන්මලීඉර අවරට යන හැන්දෑ යාමේදුම්බර කඳු වැටි මුදුන් වලින්සිහින් වළාවක් සෙමින් නැගීලාමේ තොටමුණ බද රැඳී සිටීසුදු ඔසරිය හැඳ වළා රොදින් බැසරුවන්මලී තොටමුණට ඇදේකළය පුරා දිය උකුලෙ තබා ගෙනහෙමින් හෙමින් පා නගනු පෙනේ","answer":"උදයසිරි පතිරණ"},{"question":"Ibinu Alaaji bii ibinu Abija, Ọlọrun ma jẹ n ri i","answer":"Ka ṣa maa ṣe rere. Ṣe ẹ mọ pe gbogbo igba ni mo maa n wi bẹẹ. Ka ṣa maa ṣe rere o. Ani n ko mọ ohun ti mo fẹẹ fun awọn ọmọ ti mo ba ni ṣọọbu wa yẹn. Mo mọ pe ni gbogbo igba ti wahala wa yẹn, ti wọn ko ba si nibẹ loootọ, ti awọn ẹlẹgbẹ wọn mi-in ba kọja nibẹ ti wọn ri ṣọọbu ni ṣiṣi, wọn maa maa ko gbogbo ẹru nibẹ ni. Ṣe irẹsi ti wọn ba gbe ni ka ka iye ẹ ni abi apo ẹwa, abi awọn nnkan mi-in ni ṣọọbu keji, tabi owo ta a tiẹ ni nibẹ. Ṣugbọn emi ti gba kamu o, mo ti mọ pe gbogbo iyẹn ti lọ niyẹn, ba o ku iṣe o tan, bi ẹmi wa ba wa, ireti n bẹ.Mo mo pe bi a ba wa laye ti a wa laaye, a oo ni ọja to ju eleyii lọ. O maa dun mi o, o maa dun mi pe mo sọ iru awọn nnkan bẹẹ nu, paapaa fun awọn ọmọọta ati awọn ole, ṣugbọn mo maa dupẹ lọwọ Olorun naa ni pe ẹmi eeyan kan o bọ si i. Mo ti mọkan, mo si ti gba pe ko sohun ti a le ri ninu ṣọọbu naa, paapaa nigba ti wọn ni ka ma jade, ta a tun n ri i bi wọn ṣe n fọ ṣọọbu, ti wọn n ko gbogbo ohun to wa nibẹ lọ, ati bi wọn ṣe n dana sun awọn mi-in. Iyẹn lo ṣe ya mi lẹnu nigba ti mo de ṣọọbu ti mo ba awọn ẹruuku, ti ṣọọbu wa digbi ti ko ṣẹni to debẹ.Ko si iye ti wọn beere ti n ko ni i fun wọn. Ṣugbọn wọn o beere nnkan kan. Mo tun ni ki wọn jẹ ki n wọle ki n ko owo fun wọn, wọn ni irọ ni. Nigba ti mo ta ku ni wọn ni owo ounjẹ aarọ ọjọ naa nikan lawọn le gba lọwọ mi. Ani ọkan ninu wọn ni ṣe emi o mọ pe emi ti ran oun lọwọ nijọ kan to ṣoro foun ri ni. Ọlọrun si mọ pe emi o ranti rara, koda n ko da ọmọ naa mọ, igba to n sọ ọ yii naa ni mo too gbọ. Bi wọn ṣe gba iwọnba owo ti mo fun wọn ree, ni wọn ba lọ, la ba wọ sọọbu. Emi ati Safu. A ko gburoo Abbey ati Raṣida, awọn ọlẹ meji!A o le pẹ ni ṣọọbu nijọ ta a kọkọ lọ naa, gbogbo adugbo lo da paroparo, nigba ti a si ti duro diẹ la ti tilẹkun, ẹni to ba fẹẹ raja ko pada wa nigba ti gbogbo nnkan ba rọlẹ. A si dupẹ bayii, gbogbo ẹ ti rọlẹ, onikaluku ti bẹrẹ iṣẹ ẹ pada, o kan jẹ oju apa ko jọ oju ara ni. Ki Ọlọrun ṣa maa fi iṣọ ẹ ṣọ wa, ohun to n da wahala silẹ ko to nnkan rara, bi wahala kekere bayii ba si bẹrẹ, bi wọn ko ba tete mura si i, yoo sare di nla ni. Ohun ti emi ri si gbogbo ọrọ to wa nilẹ yii niyẹn. Akin gan-an royin o fi ti, o ni diẹ lo ku ki wọn ṣa oun ladaa.Mo beere pe awọn wo ni wọn fẹẹ ṣa a ladaa, o ni awọn ọmọọta kan ti wọn waa ya ba awọn nibi ti awọn duro si ni sẹkiteeria ni. Niṣe ni mo pariwo, ‘Akin! O lọ si sẹkiteeria, ki lo wa lọ!’ Bi mo ba n sọrọ, ẹyin naa yoo ri i pe ki i ṣe pe mo kan n deede pariwo, awọn kan yoo si maa bu mi pe emi ti le jaya ku, pe Akin ki i ṣe ọmọde mọ. Ṣe iru ere egele to waa lọọ ṣe yii daa ni, abi kin ni ka ti pe e. Emi wa ni Oṣodi, oun ti kọja s’Ikẹja, bi wọn ba waa ṣe e lẹṣe lọhun-un nkọ! Kin ni mo fẹẹ maa wi. Ọlọrun ṣa ma jẹ kọmọ naa fi tiẹ ko ba mi.Niwọnba igba ti a fi wa nile yẹn, a gbadun ara wa, emi ati Safu. Niṣe ni inu ọrẹ yin naa n dun ṣinkin, Aunti Sikira. Ọjọ meji ni wọn fun un pe ki Alaaji fi maa lọ sọdọ ẹ, ṣugbọn gbogbo igba ni yoo maa yọ wa, ti yoo maa waa mu Alaaji lọ. Mo ni ki Safu fi i silẹ, nitori mo mọ ohun to n ṣe e. Ohun to n ṣe e naa ni pe o fẹ ki Alaaji tun fẹran oun pada bii ti tẹlẹ, ki wọn tun jọ maa ṣe bi wọn ti n ṣe. Ṣugbọn mo mọ pe iyẹn o ni i ṣee ṣe. Mo mọ ẹni ti mo ni, bi ọrọ ba ti ri bo ṣe ri yii, iru ọrọ bẹẹ ki i tete tan ninu Alaaji. Ọkọ mi buru bo ba jẹ tiyẹn ni.Bobinrin ba ti ṣe iru ohun ti Aunti yii ṣe yii, bi ko ba ṣọra, bọya ni Alaaji yoo tun gori ẹ mọ, yoo kan maa yi i sori ebe, ti yoo maa yi i si poro ni, nigba naa ni yoo ni ara oun ko ya, ti yoo maa wa oriṣiiriṣii alaye ti ko kun ajọ ṣe. Nigba ti Safu si fẹẹ maa binu pe ṣe lojoojumọ ni wọn tun n ri ara wọn bayii ni, mo ni ko jokoo ẹ jẹẹ,ko maa woran, mo waa sọ ohun to n ṣẹlẹ fun un. O ni ṣe Alaaji lo sọ bẹẹ femi ni, mo ni Alaaji ko ni i sọ fun mi, ṣugbọn ṣe ko mọ iye ọdun ti emi pẹlu ẹ ti jọ wa ni, bawo ni n ko ṣe ni i mọ bi nnkan kan ba n ṣe e, tabi iru iwa to le hu.Safu si sọ fun mi nijọ kẹta pe ti mo ba n woṣẹ, mo maa jẹun. Mo ni ki lo de to fi wi bẹẹ. O ni Aunti Sikira lo waa ba oun ninu ile nigba to ri i pe Alaaji lọ sọdọ iyaale wa agba, lo ba sọ foun pe ki oun ba oun bẹ ọkọ oun, pe ko ma binu, ko gbagbe ọrọ to ti lọ, nitori ko sun mọ oun lati ọjọ ti a ti lọọ mu oun bẹbẹ yẹn o, to ba ti wa to ti jẹun, o maa gba yara ẹ lọ pada ni. Ọjọ to ba si sun toun naa, o maa sun kaaka, ti yoo maa han-an-run ni o, bi oun si fọwọ pa a lara titi, ara ẹ ko ni i dide o. Niṣe ni mo miri titi, nigba ti n ko sinmi ni Safu ni ki lo de.Mo ni bawo ni agbalagba ṣe n ya alailojuti bayii. Ṣe oun lo tun yẹ ki Aunti Sikira maa fi iru ọrọ bẹẹ lọ. Ṣebi oun naa yoo ni suuru ki inu ọkọ ẹ fi rọ, ti inu ẹ ba si ti rọ, ṣebi yoo mọ bi yoo ṣe tubọ bẹ ẹ ni. Ọkunrin meloo lo le gba iru iyẹn, ki wọn ni wọn ka ẹ mọ ile ale, nibi ti ẹ ti n ba ara yin sun, ki iyawo onitọhun ka yin mọ, ko o sare jade debii pe o gbagbe pata, ko o waa ni ki ọkọ ẹ ti tun maa sare gori ẹ. Mo tiẹ jẹrii ọkọ temi o, gbogbo nnkan lọmọ ọba o ni, bii ti dansaki kọ. Bo ṣe wa yẹn, ko ma jẹ ohun ti yoo ba kuro nile Alaaji niyẹn. Alaaji ti inu ẹ le buruku.Bo ba tiẹ wa jẹ iru ọrọ bayii ni, yoo ko agidi bori ni, bẹẹ ni yoo maa rẹrin-in, ti ko ni i sọ ohun to fẹẹ ṣe gan-an. Ṣugbọn ẹnu temi kọ leeyan yoo ti gbọ iru ẹ, eyi to fẹ ki n ṣe ni mo ti ṣe yẹn, mo ti ba a bẹ ọkọ ẹ, mo si ti le awọn famili kuro nidii ọrọ ẹ, oun lo ku ko yanju ara ẹ. Ohun ti oun ko ti i mọ ni pe iru ọrọ bẹẹ yẹn le lọkan Alaaji ju keeyan pa a lọmọ lọ, ibinu Alaaji to jẹ bii ibinu Abija ni, Ọlọrun ma jẹ n ri i."},{"question":"# ජාතක කථාවලින් අනර්ඝතම උපදේශ ලැබේ.මෙම වාක්‍යයේ ''ජාතක කථාවලින්''යන පදය කරණ විභක්ති පදයක් ද? අවධි විභක්ති පදයක් ද?","answer":"මෙහි ඇත්තේ කරුණාදාස රූපසිංහ මහතා දක්වා ඇති පරිදි අවධි විභක්තිය යි.ගින්නෙන් දුම් නගි. කිව්වත් අවධි විභක්තිය තමයි."},{"question":"全天８８星座のうち、最も面積が広い星座は何座でしょう？","answer":"うみへび座"},{"question":"අවසන්කළා යන වචනයට අදහසක් ගෙන දෙන වචනය ලියා  දක්වන්න.","answer":"අවසන්කළා යන්නට විරුද්ධ අර්ථයක් ඇති පදය පටන්ගත්තා වේ.  "},{"question":"Hãy viết tiếp nội dung cho đoạn văn sau: Quân đội Trung Quốc chuẩn bị kỷ niệm 95 năm ngày thành lập (ảnh: Hoàn cầu) Hôm 30.7, thời báo Hoàn cầu của Trung Quốc đưa tin, bài viết \\"chuẩn bị cho chiến tranh\\" của Tập đoàn quân số 80 đã nhận được hơn 300.000 lượt thích chỉ sau 12 giờ đăng tải. Bình luận bên dưới bài viết, Tập đoàn quân số 80 của Trung Quốc tuyên bố: \\"Chúng ta phải ghi nhớ trách nhiệm cơ bản là chuẩn bị cho chiến tranh và tấn công, trong quá trình trở thành một đội quân hùng mạnh\\". Bên dưới bài viết, một số cư dân mạng Trung Quốc bày tỏ sự ủng hộ với Tập đoàn quân số 80 và mong muốn 2 bờ eo biển Đài Loan sớm thống nhất. ","answer":"Một số cựu chiến binh cũng bình luận dưới bài viết của Tập đoàn quân số 80, thể hiện rằng họ sẵn sàng quay trở lại phục vụ trong quân đội bất cứ lúc nào. Bình luận của Tập đoàn quân số 80 được đưa ra trong bối cảnh tinh thần các binh sĩ Trung Quốc lên cao trước lễ kỷ nhiệm 95 năm ngày thành lập Quân Giải phóng nhân dân Trung Quốc (PLA) – ngày 1.8. Theo Hoàn cầu, Chủ tịch Trung Quốc Tập Cận Bình từng tuyên bố, chỉ những người có khả năng chiến đấu mới có thể ngăn chặn một cuộc chiến và chỉ những người luôn chuẩn bị cho chiến tranh mới có thể ngăn chặn chiến tranh. "},{"question":"问：关羽的生平经历是怎样的？","answer":"答：关羽在东汉末年跟随刘备云游四方，后来成为刘备的重要将领，参与了许多重大战役。他在建兴二年（公元220年）的麦城之战中被孙权所杀。"},{"question":"Nintendo သည် Switch 2 ကို ဖန်တီးနေပါသလား။","answer":"အစီရင်ခံစာတစ်ခုတွင် Nintendo Switch 2 ကို 2024 အစောပိုင်းတွင်ဖြန့်ချိရန်ထပ်မံစီစဉ်ထားသည်။ Nintendo သည် Nintendo အကောင့်များကို Switch 2 သို့လွှဲပြောင်းပေးမည်ဟု အတည်ပြုထားပြီး မျိုးဆက်သစ် console သည် နောက်ပြန်လိုက်ဖက်မှုကိုပေးစွမ်းနိုင်မည်ဟု အရိပ်အမြွက်ပြောကြားခဲ့သည်။"},{"question":"Binatang apakah yang ada pada Jata Negara Malaysia? Pilih jawapan yang betul dari pilihan berikut.  A. Singa B. Tikus C. Harimau D. Helang","answer":"Jawapannya ialah C. Harimau."},{"question":" Sheeg xagee buu ku aasan yahay Rasuulkeena (NNKH) ?","answer":" Wuxuu ku aasan yahay magaalada Madiina (Madina)"},{"question":"પાછા ફરતા મોસમી પવનોની ઋતુ ભારતમાં ક્યારે હોય છે?A). જુલાઇ-ઓગષ્ટB). ઓક્ટોબર-નવેમ્બરC). જાન્યુઆરી-ફેબ્રુઆરીD). માર્ચ-મે","answer":"B). ઓક્ટોબર-નવેમ્બરઆ ઋતુમાં, દક્ષિણ-પશ્ચિમથી ફૂંકાતા મોસમી પવનો સમુદ્ર પરથી ભેજ લઈને આવે છે અને ભારતમાં વરસાદ લાવે છે. આ ઋતુને ભારતમાં \\"શરદ ઋતુ\\" પણ કહેવાય છે. પાછા ફરતા મોસમી પવનોની ઋતુ શરૂ થાય છે જ્યારે હિમાલયની પર્વતમાળાઓ પરનું શિયાળાનું બરફ ઓગળવા લાગે છે. આનાથી હિમાલયની પર્વતમાળાઓ પરનું દબાણ ઘટે છે અને દક્ષિણ-પશ્ચિમથી ફૂંકાતા મોસમી પવનોને આગળ વધવા માટે પ્રોત્સાહન મળે છે. પાછા ફરતા મોસમી પવનોની ઋતુ દરમિયાન, ભારતમાં વરસાદનું પ્રમાણ ખૂબ જ વધારે હોય છે. આ વરસાદ ભારતીય ખેતી માટે ખૂબ જ મહત્વપૂર્ણ છે."},{"question":"Inona no tena loharanon-karena ara-toekarena ao Madagasikara?","answer":"Ny loharanon-karena ara-toe-karena lehibe eto Madagasikara dia ny fambolena, ny jono, ny harena an-kibon’ny tany (toy ny grafita) ary ny fizahan-tany."},{"question":"Quem dos Weasley morreu na batalha de Hogwarts no último livro da saga \\"Harry Potter\\"? ","answer":"Os Weasley são uma família de personagens fictícios no universo da série de livros \\"Harry Porter\\". No decorrer dos eventos do último livro da série, Fred Weasley é morto devido a uma explosão."},{"question":"= विद्युतीय ईन्जिनियरहरूले इलेक्ट्रोनिक उपकरणहरूको विकासमा कसरी योगदान गर्छन्?","answer":"विद्युत ईन्जिनियरहरूले यी यन्त्रहरूको आधार बन्ने कम्पोनेन्टहरू, सर्किटहरू र प्रणालीहरूमा काम गरेर इलेक्ट्रोनिक उपकरणहरू डिजाइन र विकास गर्छन्। तिनीहरू सर्किट डिजाइन, सिग्नल प्रशोधन, र इलेक्ट्रोनिक प्रणालीहरूको विश्वसनीयता सुनिश्चित गर्ने जस्ता कार्यहरूमा संलग्न छन्।"},{"question":"පහත  නාම පදයට අදාළ ස්ත්‍රී ලිංග නාම පාදක කුමක්ද?බමුණා ","answer":"බැමිණි "},{"question":"「児童福祉法」でいう「児童」は１８歳までですが、「老人福祉法」でいう「老人」とは何歳からでしょう？","answer":"６５歳"},{"question":"世界上最大的宫殿是？","answer":"故宫"},{"question":"కంప్యూటర్ మీద వ్యాసం రాయండి.","answer":"కంప్యూటర్ అనేది ఒక ఎలక్ట్రానిక్ పరికరం. కంప్యూటర్ లో ‘డేటా’ ను నిల్వచేయవచ్చు. దాన్ని మళ్ళీ ఎప్పుడైనా వెనక్కి తీసుకోవచ్చు. అంతేకాకుండా కంప్యూటర్ చాలా కచ్చితంగా, త్వరగా ఫలితాన్ని ఇస్తుంది. ఇటువంటి అద్భుత సాధనమైన కంప్యూటర్‌ను కనిపెట్టినవాడు ఛార్లెస్ బాబ్బేజి.కంప్యూటర్ వల్ల చాలా లాభాలున్నాయి. కూడికలు, తీసివేతలు, గుణకారాలు (హెచ్చవేతలు), భాగహారాలు వంటి లెక్కలు చాలా వేగంగా చేయడానికి కంప్యూటర్ బాగా పనికివస్తుంది. కంప్యూటర్ల ద్వారా వాతావరణ పరిస్థితిని తెలుసుకోవచ్చు.విమానాలు, బస్సులు, రైళ్ళు మొదలైన వాటి టెక్కెట్ల రిజర్వేషన్లకు కంప్యూటర్లను ఉపయోగిస్తారు. పెద్ద పెద్ద కర్మాగారాల్లో, కార్యాలయాల్లో, బ్యాంకుల్లో ఇవి ఎంతగానో ఉపయోగపడుతున్నాయి. విద్యా, వైద్య, వ్యాపార, వ్యవసాయ, సమాచార, శాస్త్ర సాంకేతిక రంగాలలో ఈ కంప్యూటర్లు ప్రముఖపాత్ర వహిస్తున్నాయి.కంప్యూటర్‌ను ఉపయోగించి ఇంటర్నెట్ అనే సౌకర్యం ద్వారా ప్రపంచంలో జరుగుతున్న విషయాలన్నింటిని మన ఇంట్లోని కంప్యూటర్ ముందు కూర్చొని తెలుసుకోవచ్చు. ఆధునిక విజ్ఞాన ప్రగతికి నిదర్శనం కంప్యూటర్."},{"question":"O que é o fair play no futebol?","answer":"O fair play, ou jogo limpo, no futebol refere-se ao respeito pelas regras, adversários, árbitros e espírito esportivo. Isso inclui jogar com ética, sem simulações ou condutas antidesportivas. O fair play promove a honestidade e a integridade no esporte e é celebrado por meio de prêmios, como o Troféu Fair Play da FIFA, concedido à equipe que demonstra os mais altos padrões de fair play em um torneio."},{"question":"Qual é a capital da Líbia?","answer":"Trípoli."},{"question":"Bhala okuqhubekayo kwalesi sigaba - Izikhathi eziningi ezisheshayo zabekwa kumathayi e-C5 athambile. I-Pirelli ilinganisela ngonyaka odlule ukuthi igebe lokusebenza phakathi kwenhlanganisela ngayinye yamathayi lalicishe libe ngu-0,6-0,7 s, yize lokhu kwahlukahluka ngokuya ngezici eziningi. Isikhathi esisheshayo sikaBottas sasicishe sibe yizingxenye ezintathu kwezingu-10 kunesikhathi sakhe sokuthatha indawo yokuqala ku-2019 Spanish Grand Prix.","answer":"emjikelezweni ofanayo. Kusukela ngoFebhuwari 2020, i-Q2 ne-Q3 yakhe evela ku-2019 Grand Prix kanye ne-lap yakhe esheshayo ekuhlolweni kuka-2020 yizindawo ezintathu ezisheshayo ezake zaba khona esifundeni ekucushweni kwaso kwamanje, kanye nezindawo ezintathu kuphela ezingaphansi kuka-1: 16.0."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau với nội dung có liên quan tới đoạn văn dưới đây: Đọc đoạn văn sau và đưa ra một tiêu đề phụ hợp với nội dung: ","answer":"Chuyện showbiz: Á hậu Mâu Thủy khoe ảnh bạn trai cầu hôn"},{"question":"इलेक्ट्रॉन मायक्रोस्कोप कसे कार्य करते?","answer":"इलेक्ट्रॉन मायक्रोस्कोप हे एक शक्तिशाली इमेजिंग साधन आहे जे पारंपारिक प्रकाश सूक्ष्मदर्शकापेक्षा खूपच जास्त रिझोल्यूशन असलेल्या अत्यंत लहान वस्तूंचे विस्तार आणि दृश्यमान करण्यासाठी दृश्यमान प्रकाशाऐवजी इलेक्ट्रॉनच्या बीमचा वापर करते. इलेक्ट्रॉन मायक्रोस्कोपचे दोन मुख्य प्रकार आहेत: ट्रान्समिशन इलेक्ट्रॉन मायक्रोस्कोप (TEM) आणि स्कॅनिंग इलेक्ट्रॉन मायक्रोस्कोप (SEM). प्रत्येक प्रकार कसा कार्य करतो याचे विहंगावलोकन येथे आहे:1. ट्रांसमिशन इलेक्ट्रॉन मायक्रोस्कोप (TEM):TEM मध्ये, इलेक्ट्रॉन गनमधून इलेक्ट्रॉनचा बीम तयार केला जातो. ही इलेक्ट्रॉन गन इलेक्ट्रिक फील्ड वापरून इलेक्ट्रॉन्सचा वेग वाढवते आणि त्यांना पातळ, सुसंगत बीममध्ये केंद्रित करते. इलेक्ट्रॉन बीम नंतर अत्यंत पातळ नमुन्यातून जातो, जो पूर्वी अति-पातळ भागांमध्ये कापून आणि कॉन्ट्रास्ट वाढवण्यासाठी हेवी मेटल सोल्यूशन्सने डाग करून तयार केला गेला होता.इलेक्ट्रॉन बीम नमुन्यातून जाताना त्याच्याशी संवाद साधतो. काही इलेक्ट्रॉन परस्परसंवाद न करता नमुन्याद्वारे प्रसारित केले जातात, तर इतर विखुरलेले किंवा शोषले जातात, एक प्रतिमा तयार करतात जी नमुन्यातील घनतेच्या भिन्नतेशी संबंधित असतात. प्रसारित इलेक्ट्रॉन नमुन्याच्या दुसऱ्या बाजूला गोळा केले जातात आणि फ्लोरोसेंट स्क्रीन किंवा डिजिटल डिटेक्टरवर प्रतिमा तयार करण्यासाठी वापरले जातात.संशोधकांना नॅनोमीटर स्केलवर संरचना पाहण्याची परवानगी देऊन, TEMs अत्यंत उच्च वाढ साध्य करण्यात सक्षम आहेत. तथापि, TEM साठी नमुने तयार करणे जटिल आणि वेळ घेणारे असू शकते.2. स्कॅनिंग इलेक्ट्रॉन मायक्रोस्कोप (SEM):SEM मध्ये, इलेक्ट्रॉन बीम नमुन्यातून जात नाही. त्याऐवजी, ते रास्टर पॅटर्नमध्ये नमुन्याची पृष्ठभाग स्कॅन करते. केंद्रित इलेक्ट्रॉन बीम आणि नमुन्याची पृष्ठभाग यांच्यातील परस्परसंवादामुळे दुय्यम इलेक्ट्रॉन, बॅकस्कॅटर्ड इलेक्ट्रॉन आणि क्ष-किरणांसह विविध सिग्नल तयार होतात. हे सिग्नल नमुन्याच्या पृष्ठभागाच्या स्थलाकृति, रचना आणि इतर गुणधर्मांबद्दल माहिती देतात.उत्सर्जित दुय्यम इलेक्ट्रॉन आणि बॅकस्कॅटर्ड इलेक्ट्रॉन डिटेक्टरद्वारे गोळा केले जातात आणि नमुन्याच्या पृष्ठभागाची तपशीलवार त्रिमितीय प्रतिमा तयार करण्यासाठी सिग्नलचा वापर केला जातो. एसईएम विशेषतः वस्तूंच्या पृष्ठभागाच्या आकारविज्ञानाचा अभ्यास करण्यासाठी उपयुक्त आहेत आणि सामग्रीच्या सूक्ष्म संरचनामध्ये मौल्यवान अंतर्दृष्टी प्रदान करू शकतात.टीईएमच्या तुलनेत, एसईएम वापरणे सोपे असते आणि त्यांना कमी जटिल नमुना तयार करण्याची आवश्यकता असते. तथापि, जेव्हा नमुन्यांच्या अंतर्गत रचनांचा विचार केला जातो तेव्हा त्यांचे रिझोल्यूशन कमी असते.दोन्ही प्रकारच्या इलेक्ट्रॉन मायक्रोस्कोपमध्ये, इलेक्ट्रॉन बीम इलेक्ट्रोमॅग्नेटिक लेन्स वापरून नियंत्रित केले जातात जे बीमला नमुन्यावर केंद्रित करतात आणि निर्देशित करतात. परिणामी सिग्नल्सवर प्रतिमा तयार करण्यासाठी प्रक्रिया केली जाते जी प्रकाश सूक्ष्मदर्शकाच्या क्षमतेपेक्षा जास्त स्केलवर नमुन्याच्या संरचनेचे गुंतागुंतीचे तपशील प्रकट करतात."},{"question":"\\"કમલેશ સોનાવાલા ની\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"સાંભળું તો તને ખાલી પડઘા સંભળાયતને શોધું સિતારના વનમાંટમકીને કો’ક વાર ઈશારાવાત છાની રાખીશ મારા મનમાં.આ ગુલમહોર મહેક્યાં વરસી વાદલડીધુંધળી સંધ્યા રંગ લાલમડીઅને તમે યાદ આવ્યા..પેલાં આંખ્યુંનાં અંજન, શાંત રાતલડીએક અનેરી પ્રેમ વાતલડીઅને તમે યાદ આવ્યા..ભૂલવા ચહું હું સુની રે તલાવડીસરકે સરિતા અશ્રુ આંખલડીઅને તમે યાદ આવ્યા..આ ઝંઝાવત પલ એકલડીદિલના દરિયામાં નહીં આ નાનકડીઅને તમે યાદ આવ્યા.."},{"question":"ਭੁਪਾਲ/ਸਿਹੋਰ: ਮੱਧ ਪ੍ਰਦੇਸ਼ ਦੇ ਕਾਂਗਰਸੀ ਵਿਧਾਇਕ ਨੇ ਅੱਜ ਇਸਲਾਮੀ ਸ਼ਰੀਅਤ ਕਾਨੂੰਨ ਦਾ ਹਵਾਲਾ ਦਿੰਦਿਆਂ ਵੰਦੇ ਮਾਤਰਮ ਬੋਲਣ ਤੋਂ ਨਾਂਹ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੀ। ਭੋਪਾਲ (ਕੇਂਦਰੀ) ਤੋਂ ਵਿਧਾਇਕ ਆਰਿਫ਼ ਮਸੂਦ ਨੇ ਇਕ ਸਮਾਗਮ ਦੌਰਾਨ ਜਦੋਂ ਮਾਈਕ ਫੜਿਆ ਤਾਂ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਉਹ ਵੰਦੇ ਮਾਤਰਮ ਦਾ ਨਾਅਰਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਲਾਉਣਗੇ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਸ਼ਰੀਅਤ ਇਸ ਦੀ ਇਜਾਜ਼ਤ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੰਦਾ। ਵਿਧਾਇਕ ਨੇ ਆਪਣਾ ਬਚਾਅ ਕਰਦਿਆਂ ਕਿਹਾ, ‘ਮੇਵ ਭਾਈਚਾਰੇ ਦੀਆਂ ਕਿਤਾਬਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਈ ਸੂਰਬੀਰਾਂ ਦਾ ਜ਼ਿਕਰ ਹੈ, ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇਸ਼ ਲਈ ਜਾਨਾਂ ਵਾਰ ਦਿੱਤੀਆਂ। ਪਰ ਅਫ਼ਸੋਸਨਾਕ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਦੇਸ਼ ਪ੍ਰਤੀ ਆਪਣੀ ਵਚਨਬੱਧਤਾ ਸਾਬਤ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਸਾਨੂੰ ਵੰਦੇ ਮਾਤਰਮ ਦੇ ਨਾਅਰੇ ਲਾਉਣੇ ਪੈਂਦੇ ਹਨ।’'ਵੰਦੇ ਮਾਤਰਮ' ਦਾ ਨਾਅਰਾ ਕੌਣ ਨਹੀਂ ਲਵੇਗਾ?","answer":"ਵਿਧਾਇਕ ਆਰਿਫ਼ ਮਸੂਦ 'ਵੰਦੇ ਮਾਤਰਮ' ਦਾ ਨਾਅਰਾ ਕੌਣ ਨਹੀਂ ਲਵੇਗਾ।"},{"question":"வினா: புத்தரால் பேசப்பட்ட மொழி எது?","answer":"விடை: பாலி"},{"question":"Munyaya dzaWinnie the Pooh, mwana waKanga anonzi ani?","answer":"Munyaya dzaWinnie the Pooh naA.A. Milne, mwana waKanga anonzi Roo. Roo idiki kangaroo joey anowanzoonekwa achisvetuka-svetuka neHundred Acre Wood naamai vake, Kanga. Roo anozivikanwa nekuda kwesimba rake risingaperi uye kuda kuziva, uye ndiye mumwe wevadiwa mavara muWinnie the Pooh akatevedzana."},{"question":"*من هي والدة السيدة مريم ؟","answer":"حنا"},{"question":"Terjemahkanlah penggalan teks Bahasa Inggris yang disadur dari kumpulan cerita anak dunia berikut ke dalam teks Bahasa Indonesia.Cheekoo never littered again. Secretly, she liked living in a clean village. But she was also scared that the trash cloud would come back, some day. Who knew!Terjemahan:","answer":"Cheeko tidak akan pernah membuang sampah sembarangan lagi. Diam-diam dia senang tinggal di kota yang bersih. Tapi, dia takut awan sampah akan muncul kembali suatu hari nanti. Siapa yang tahu!"},{"question":"Ìtàn Iyàwó Ti Ó Fi Ẹ̀mi Òkùnkùn Pa Iyá-Ọkọ: Ẹni A Fẹ́ La Mọ̀, A Ò Mọ Ẹni Tó Fẹni","answer":"Ìtàn ti ó wọ́pọ̀ ni, bi iyá-ọkọ ti burú lai ri ìtàn iyá-ọkọ ti ó dára sọ.  Eyi dákún àṣà burúkú ti ó gbòde láyé òde òni, nipa àwọn ọmọge ti ó ti tó wọ ilé-ọkọ tàbi obinrin àfẹ́sọ́nà ma a sọ pé àwọn ò fẹ́ ri iyá-ọkọ tàbi ki iyá-ọkọ ti kú ki àwọn tó délé.Ni ayé àtijọ́, agbègbè kan na a ni ẹbi má ngbé – bàbá-àgbà, iyá-àgbà, bàbá, iyá, ẹ̀gbọ́n, àbúrò, iyàwó àgbà, iyàwó kékeré, ìyàwó-ọmọ, àwọn ọmọ àti ọmọ-mọ.  Ṣùgbọ́n ni ayé òde òni, ọ̀pọ̀ kò fẹ́ ṣe iṣẹ́ àgbẹ̀ mọ, ẹbi ti fúnká si ilú nlá àti òkè-òkun nitori iṣẹ́ ajé àti iṣẹ́-ijọba.Ni ọ̀pọ̀ ọdún sẹhin, iyá kan wà ti a o pe orúkọ rẹ ni Tanimọ̀la ninú ìtàn yi.  Ó bi ọmọ ọkùnrin meje lai bi obinrin. Kékeré ni àwọn ọmọ rẹ wà nigbati ọkọ rẹ kú.  Tanimọ̀la fi ìṣẹ́ àti ìyà tọ́ àwọn ọmọ rẹ, gbogbo àwọn ọkùnrin na a si yàn wọn yanjú.  Nigbati wọn bẹ̀rẹ̀ si fẹ́ ìyàwó, inú rẹ dùn púpọ̀ pé Ọlọrun ti bẹ̀rẹ̀ si dá obinrin ti ohun kò bi padà fún ohun.   Ó fẹ́ràn àwọn ìyàwó ọmọ rẹ gidigidi ṣùgbọ́n ọ̀pọ̀ ọmọ rẹ  kó lọ si ilú miran pẹ̀lú ìyàwó wọn nitori iṣẹ́.  Àbi-gbẹhin rẹ nikan ni kò kúrò ni ilé nitori ohun ló bójú tó oko àti ilé ti bàbá wọn fi silẹ.  Nigbati ó fẹ ìyàwó wálé, inú iyá dùn pé ohun yio ri ẹni bá gbé.  Ìyàwó yi lẹ́wà, o si ni ọ̀yàyà, eyi tún jẹ́ ki iyá-ọkọ rẹ fẹ́ràn si gidigidi.Yorùbá ni “Ẹni a fẹ́ la mọ̀, a ò mọ ẹni tó fẹni”.  Tanimọ̀la kò mọ̀ pé àjẹ́ ni ìyàwó-ọmọ ti ohun fẹ́ràn, ti wọn jọ ngbé yi.  Bi Tanimọ̀la bá se oúnjẹ, ohun pẹ̀lú ọmọ àti ìyàwó-ọmọ rẹ ni wọn jọ njẹ ẹ.  Bi ìyàwó bá se oúnjẹ, á bu ti iyá-ọkọ rẹ.  Kò si ìjá tàbi asọ̀ laarin wọn ti ó lè jẹ ki iyá funra.Yorùbá gbà pé ohun burúkú ni ki enia jẹun lójú orun.  Ni ọjọ́ kan, iyá ké lati ojú orun ni bi agogo mẹrin ìdájí òwúrọ̀, pe ìyàwó-ọmọ ohun ti fún ohun ni oúnjẹ jẹ ni ojú orun.  Ìyàwó-ọmọ rẹ kò sẹ́, bẹni kò sọ nkan kan.  Ọkọ rẹ kò gba iyá rẹ gbọ.  Lati igbà ti iyá ti ké pé ohun jẹ àsáró-iṣu ti ìyàwó-ọmọ ohun gbé fún òhun jẹ lójú orun ni inú rirun ti bẹ̀rẹ̀ fún iyá.  Inú rirun yi pọ̀ tó bẹ gẹ ẹ ti wọn fi gbé Tanimọ̀la kúrò ni ilé fún ìtọ́jú.  Wọn gbiyànjú titi, kò rọrùn, nitori eyi, Tanimọ̀la ni ki wọn gbé ohun padà lọ si ilé ki ohun lọ kú.Ki Tanimọ̀la tó kú, ó pe gbogbo ilé lati ge ẹgun fún ìyàwó-ọmọ rẹ pé “Òhun jẹ ìyá lóri ọmọ, nigbati àsikò àti jẹun ọmọ tó, ìyàwó-ọmọ ṣe ikú pa ohun.  Nitori eyi, ìyàwó-ọmọ yi ko ni jèrè ọmọ rẹ, ẹlòmiràn ni yio wo ọmọ rẹ dàgbà. Ó ni à fi ti ó bá jẹ ẹ̀ṣẹ̀ ni lati ni ifẹ́ ìyàwó-ọmọ”.  Bi ó ti ge ẹ̀gún tán ni o mi imi ikẹhin ti ó si kú.Yorùbá ni “Ọlọrun àtijọ́, ló npẹ́ dájọ́”, oṣù meje lẹhin ikú Tanimọ̀la (iyá-ọkọ), ìyàwó bẹ̀rẹ̀ si rù nitori kò lè jẹun, kò pẹ́, ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ àisàn.  Ó ni ohun kò lè sùn bẹni ohun kò lè jẹun nitori iyá-ọkọ kò jẹ́ ki ohun gbádùn. Lóri àisàn ni ó ti bẹ̀rẹ̀ si jẹ́wọ́ pé tòótọ́ ni ohun gbé oúnjẹ ti ohun gbà ninú ẹgbẹ́ àjẹ́ fún iyá-ọkọ ohun.  Ó pariwo titi ó fi kú.Ìtàn yi fihàn pé ẹ̀san mbọ̀ fún oniṣẹ́ ibi.  Ẹ̀kọ́ ni fún àwon ọmọge òde òni pé, ki ṣe gbogbo iyá-ọkọ ló burú, bó pẹ́ bóyá, ẹ̀san mbọ̀ fún ìyàwó ti ó ni ohun kò fẹ́ ri iya-oko, tàbi ki iyá-ọkọ kú ki ohun tó délé."},{"question":"අගුන් ගිනි කන්ද පිහිටා තිබෙන්නේ","answer":"ඉන්දුනීසියාවේ"},{"question":"ද්‍රාවණය සෑදීමට මිශ්‍ර කළ සංඝටක අතුරින් වැඩිපුර ඇති සංඝටකය හඳුන්වන නම කුමක්ද?","answer":"ද්‍රාවණය සෑදීමට මිශ්‍ර කළ සංඝටක අතුරින් වැඩිපුර ඇති සංඝටකය දාවකය ලෙස හඳින්වේ."},{"question":"தமிழ்நாட்டின் விவசாயம் எந்த வகையில் முன்னேற்றம் அடைந்துள்ளது  என்பதை விளக்குக.","answer":"தமிழ்நாட்டில் விவசாயம் மிகவும் முன்னேற்றம் அடைந்துள்ளது. தமிழ்நாட்டில் நெல், கரும்பு, பருத்தி, காய்கறிகள், பழங்கள் என பல்வேறு விளைபொருட்கள் விளைவிக்கப்படுகின்றன. தமிழ்நாட்டில் விவசாயம் மாநிலத்தின் பொருளாதாரத்திற்கு பெரும் பங்களிப்பு செய்கிறது.20 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டின் முற்பகுதியில் வேளாண்மையில் கலப்பு நைட்ரஜனுடன், வெட்டியெடுக்கப்பட்ட பாறை பாஸ்பேட், பூச்சிக்கொல்லிகளைப் பயன்படுத்துதல் மற்றும் இயந்திரமயமாக்கல் ஆகியவை பயிர் உற்பத்தியைப் பெருமளவில் அதிகரித்தன. தானியங்கள் வழங்கலின் அதிகரிப்பால் கால்நடைகள் மலிவடைவதற்கும் இது வழிவகுத்தது. மேலும், அரிசி, கோதுமை, மற்றும் மக்காச்சோளம் போன்ற தானிய விளைபொருள்களின் உயர் விளைச்சல் வகைகள் பசுமைப் புரட்சியின் ஒரு பகுதியாக அறிமுகப்படுத்தப்பட்டன. இதன் காரணமாக 20 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டு பிற்பாதியில் உலகளாவிய தானிய உற்பத்தி அதிகரித்தது. பசுமைப் புரட்சியானது தொழில்நுட்பங்களை வளர்ந்த நாடுகளிடமிருந்து வளரும் நாடுகளுக்கு அளிக்க வழிசெய்தது.இந்தியாவில் மக்களின் பஞ்சத்தை போக்க இந்திய வேளாண் ஆராய்ச்சி குழுமம், வேளாண் பல்கலைக்கழகங்கள் ஆகியவை சர்வதேச ஆராய்ச்சி நிறுவனங்களுடன் இணைந்து ஆராய்ச்சி செய்தன, அதன் மூலம் நாம் பயிர் விளைச்சலில் தன்னிறைவு ஏற்பட்டது. ஆனால் பாரம்பரிய முறைகளை கைவிட்டு ரசாயன உரங்களையும், வேதியியல் பூச்சிக்கொல்லிகளையும், களைக்கொல்லிகளையும் மானியம் கிடைக்கிறது என்ற காரணத்திற்காகவும், அதனை பயன்படுத்துவதால் மகசூல் கூடுகிறது என்ற எண்ணத்தினாலும் நவீன கால வேளாண்மையான ரசாயனங்களை மையமாக கொண்ட வேளாண்மை நம்மை நன்கு ஆக்கிரமித்துக் கொண்டது."},{"question":"Fisikan, nola aztertzen du kuantika mekanikak partikula subatomikoen ?","answer":"Kuantika mekanikak partikula subatomikoen portaera probabilistikotzat hartzen du, superposizioaren eta entrelazamenduaren "},{"question":"ప్రత్యేక ఆర్థిక మండళ్ళకు నీవు మద్దతిస్తావా? వ్యతిరేకిస్తావా? ఎందువలన?","answer":"నేను ప్రత్యేక ఆర్థిక మండళ్ళను సమర్థిస్తాను. కారణాలు:ప్రత్యేక ఆర్థిక మండళ్ళు పెద్ద యెత్తున ఉద్యోగ అవకాశాలు కల్పిస్తాయి.అవి ప్రపంచస్థాయి అవస్థాపనా సౌకర్యాలను ఒకే ప్రదేశంలో అందిస్తాయి.విదేశీ పెట్టుబడులను ఆకర్షించి పరిశ్రమల స్థాపనకు దోహదపడతాయి."},{"question":"Iza no manamboatra ny Pringles ? ","answer":"Ny orinasa Proctor and Gamble no manamboatra ny Pringles. "},{"question":"Waaa maxay faaidooyinka caanaha la karkariyay?","answer":"U dulqaadashada barootiinta caanaha:Marka caanaha la karkariyo, barootiinta caanaha ku jirta way isbedeshaa taas oo u fududaynaysaa dadka xasaasiyada ku qaba barootiinta in calooshoodu ay shiiddo caanaha.U dulqaadashada la’aanta laktoos:Si la mid ah barootiinta, caanaha marka la karkariyo waxaa yaraada sonkorta laktoos ee ku jirta caanaha. Karkarintu waxay sonkorta laktoos u bedeshaa aasidhyo iyo “lactulose” oo ah nooc sonkorta ka mid ah jirka u bini-aadanku uusan nuugin.Digniin: inkastoo caanaha oo la karkariyo ay yareyso sonkorta laktoos iyo barootiinta ku jira, waxaa dhici karta inaysan wax wayn ka beddelin oo aysan cabin karin dadka qaba xasaasiyadda barootiinta caanaha iyo cillada u dulqaadasho la’aanta laktoos (lactose intolerance).Dufanno faaido leh:Caanaha la karkariyay waxaa dufanno faaido u leh caafimaadka..Dufannadaani waxay wanaajiyaan caafimaadka caloosha waxayna hoos u dhigaan halista kansarka ku dhaca mindhicirrada waa wayn.Sidoo kale, dufannada caanaha la karkariyay ku jira waxay yareeyaan baruurta jirka, waxayna kordhiyaan dheregta sidaas darteed waxay caawiyaan miisaan dhimista."},{"question":"වියට්නාමයේ අගනුවර කුමක්ද?","answer":"වියට්නාමයේ අගනුවර ලෙස සැලකෙන්නේ හැනෝයි නගරයයි."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'mandi keringat'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud bekerja dengan sepenuh tenaga. Contoh ayat: Penduduk di kampung itu bermandi keringat untuk membina sebuah sekolah agama."},{"question":"කොකෝවා  භෝගය ගැන විස්තරයක් කරන්න. ","answer":"Theobroma cacaoකුලය: Sterculiaceaeඇමේසන් ද්‍රෝණියේ සම්භවය වූයේ යැයි උපකල්පනය කෙරෙන කොකෝවා ගස විශේෂයෙන් මෙක්සිකෝව ද ඇතුලත්ව මධ්‍යම ඇමරිකාවට ව්‍යාප්ත වී ඇතැයි සැලකේ. ඔල්මෙක් සහ මායාස් වැනි එම කලාපයේ ස්වදේශිකයන් විසින් කෙකෝවා පිළිබඳව දැනුවත්ව එය භාවිතා කරන ලද අතර ඔවුහු එය “දෙවිවරුන්ගේ ආහාර” ලෙස සැලකූහ. කොකෝවා බීජ මුදල් ලෙස භාවිතා කළ ඇස්ටෙක්වරු කොකෝවා වලින් සාදන ලද තිත්ත චොකලට් බීම වර්ගයක්ද රස වින්දෝය. ක්‍රිස්ටෝපර් කොලම්බස් ඇමරිකාවේ දී කොකෝවා ඇට සොයාගත් අතර එය ඔහු සිදුකලේ වසර 20 කට පසුවය. හර්නන්ඩෝ කෝර්ටස් ඇස්ටෙක්වරු භාවිතා කළ තිත්ත පානය සොයාගෙන කොකෝවා ඇට සහ වට්ටෝරුව ස්පාඤ්ඤයේ පස්වන චාල්ස් රජු වෙත යවා ඇත. ස්පාඤ්ඤ ජාතිකයින් විසින් වට්ටෝරුව නැවත සකස් කළේ සීනි එකතු කිරීම සහ රසය වැඩි දියුණු කිරීම සඳහා අමුද්‍රව්‍ය රත් කිරීමෙනි. 1828 වන විට කොකෝවා බටර් නිස්සාරණය කිරීමට කොකෝවා මිරිකන යන්ත්‍රයක් නිර්මාණය විය. පසුව 1879 දී ස්විට්සර්ලන්ත ජාතිකයෝ මිල්ක් චොකලට් සහ ඝන චොකලට් නිෂ්පාදනය කළෝය. එක්දහස් අටසිය ගණන් වලදී විට යුරෝපීය යටත් විජිත පාලකයෝ ඔවුන්ගේ යටත් විජිතවලට කොකෝවා හඳුන්වා දුන් අතර ඉන් පසුව එය අප්‍රිකාවේ සහ ආසියාවේ වාණිජ වගාවන් ලෙස සංවර්ධනය කරන ලදී."},{"question":"Inona avy ny karazana gazety nivoaka tamin'ny VANIM-POTOANA KRISTIANINA 1818 - 1896 ?","answer":"Ireo karazana gazety nivoaka tamin'ny VANIM-POTOANA KRISTIANINA 1818 - 1896 dia :1) Teny soa (1861: Gazety voalohany)2) Ny Sakaizan’ny tanora3) Mpanolo-tsaina"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai api dalam sekam\\"?","answer":"Perbuatan jahat atau rindu dendam yang tersembunyi."},{"question":"Escreva uma continuação para este parágrafo - Butron fez parte do elenco da Seleção Peruana de Futebol da Copa América de 1997","answer":", 1999, 2004, 2007 e 2011."},{"question":"வினா : மெசபடோமியாவில் வாழ்ந்தவர்கள் எவ்வாறு அழைகப்படுகிறார்கள்?","answer":"விடை :  சுமேரியர்"},{"question":"Dáhùn ìbéèrè tó tẹ̀ lée yìí. Ta ni ẹni tó ṣe michael jackson nínú fíìmù jackson 5?","answer":"Alex Burrall ni."},{"question":"Se ìtumò ‘I am at my wits’ end on this issue","answer":"N ò mò ohun tí mo lè se mo lórí òrò yìí"},{"question":"Rozwiąż zagadkę. Chcę przejechać pociągiem z Ostravy do Pragi. Na terenie jakiego kraju się znajduję?","answer":"To prosta zagadka. Zarówno Ostrava, jak i Praga znajdują się na terenie Czech. Zatem znajdujesz się w Czechach."},{"question":"Wie was DuBose Heyward en waar staat hij bekend voor?","answer":"Edwin DuBose Heyward was een Amerikaans schrijver die vooral bekendheid verwierf met zijn boek uit 1925 Porgy dat weer de basis vormde voor het gelijknamige toneelstuk (met zijn vrouw Dorothy als co-auteur) dat weer het fundament leverde voor de opera Porgy and Bess waarvoor George Gershwin de muziek schreef. "},{"question":"フランス語で「虹」という意味のyukihiro、ken、tetsuya、hydeの4人からなるロックバンドは?","answer":"L'Arc～en～Ciel(ラルク アン シエル)です。"},{"question":"Ijọba apapọ yan ipinlẹ Ogun lati janfaani oriṣii mẹta labala ọgbin","answer":"Wọn ti yan ipinlẹ Ogun gẹgẹ bii ilu ti yoo jẹ anfaani ọna mẹta tijọba apapọ n ṣeto labala eto ọgbin ati ipesẹ ounjẹ.Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọjọ karun-un, oṣu karun-un yii, ni akọwe to n ri si iṣẹ ọgbin lẹka ijọba apapọ, ‘NALDA’(National Agricultural Land Development  Authority) Ọgbẹni Paul Ikonne, sọ eyi di mimọ lọfisii Gomina Dapọ Abiọdun, l’Oke-Mosan.O ni eto mẹta ti wọn darukọ ipinlẹ Ogun fun naa ni Ẹsiteeti ọgbin rẹpẹtẹ, aaye ti wọn ti n ṣe gaari ati kikọ awọn akẹkọọ jade igba (200) lẹkọ lori ilẹ ọgbin. Awọn to ba kẹkọọ yii yoo lanfaani ati maa ri ounjẹ oojọ wọn pẹlu iṣẹ ti wọn ba n ṣe.Ẹkun mẹtẹẹta ti ipinlẹ Ogun pin si, iyẹn Abẹokuta, Ijẹbu ati Yewa ni Akọwe NALDA sọ pe ijọba apapọ yoo gbe ẹsiteeti oko nla naa si, o ni wọn ki yoo si da iṣẹ ibẹ da awọn eeyan, lati ibẹrẹ ọgbin titi dori gbigbe awọn ere oko lọ sọja lo ni ijọba apapọ yoo lọwọ si.Bakan naa lo ni sare ilẹ ẹẹdẹgbẹrin (700 hectares) to wa ni Jọga Orile, yoo gba agbara ijọba laipẹ, o ni igbedide ilẹ naa yoo mu kounjẹ tun pọ si i nipinlẹ Ogun ni.Nigba to n fesi, Gomina Dapọ Abiọdun sọ pe koko kan pataki ni iṣẹ agbẹ ninu iṣẹjọba oun, o loun ko fọwọ yẹpẹre mu un rara. O ni nitori ẹ loun ṣe bẹrẹ papakọ ofurufu akẹru ti yoo ran iṣẹ ọgbin lọwọ. O waa dupẹ lọwọ Aarẹ Buhari fun atilẹyin rẹ, o ni idasi ijọba apapọ labala ọgbin ko ṣee fọwọ rọ sẹyin ninu ijọba oun."},{"question":"మహిళల పట్ల చూపుతున్న వివక్షలను, వారి మీద జరుగుతున్న దాడులను ఖండిస్తూ, మహిళలందరూ ధైర్యంగా మెలగాలని తెలియజేసేలా ఒక కరపత్రాన్ని తయారు చేయండి.","answer":"“ధైర్యే సాహసే లక్ష్మీ”మహిళామణులారా! ‘పదండి ముందుకు, పదండి తోసుకు పోదాం పోదాం, పైపైకి’ అన్న శ్రీశ్రీ మాట మరచిపోకండి. ఈనాడు మనపట్ల సంఘం ఎంతో వివక్షత చూపిస్తోంది. ఆడపిల్ల గర్భాన పడిందని తెలిస్తే, తల్లిదండ్రులు విలవిల లాడుతున్నారు. కొందరు భ్రూణహత్యలకు దిగుతున్నారు.తండ్రి ఆస్తిలో స్త్రీలకు మగవారితో సమాన వాటాలు ఇవ్వడం లేదు. పేపరు తిరగవేస్తే, స్త్రీల మానభంగాల వార్తలు, టి.వి. పెడితే స్త్రీలకు జరిగిన అన్యాయాలు, అత్తవారింట స్త్రీల కష్టాలు, వరకట్నాల చావులు కనబడతాయి. వినబడతాయి. — పసిపిల్లల నుండి పండు ముదుసళ్ళు వరకు అత్యాచారాలకు గురి అవుతున్నారు.స్త్రీలంతా కరాటే నేర్చుకోవాలి. అల్లరి చేసే మగవారి చెంపలు పగుల కొట్టాలి. నిర్భయంగా పోలీసు వారికి రిపోర్టు చెయ్యాలి. మీరు పొరపాటున అన్యాయానికి గురి అయితే, సిగ్గుతో చితికిపోవద్దు. ధైర్యంగా నిలవండి. అన్యాయాన్ని ఎదిరించి పోరాడండి. బాగా చదవండి. ఉద్యోగాలు చేయండి. మనం ఈ దురాచారాల్ని ఖండిద్దాం.అన్యాయం జరిగిన తోటి స్త్రీలకు, మనం అండగా నిలవాలి. ఆడపిల్ల ఇంటికి మహాలక్ష్మి అని, ఆనందించే రోజు రావాలి. అందుకు మనమంతా చేయి చేయి కలిపి పోరాడుదాం. ఝాన్సీ లక్ష్మీబాయిలా, సరోజినీ దేవిలా దుర్గాబాయమ్మలా తలలెత్తి నిలుద్దాం. ధైర్యమే మనకు శ్రీరామరక్ష.ఇట్లు,వనితా సంఘం."},{"question":"Apat na oras ang biyahe namin ng kaibigan ko mula Manila papuntang Pampanga. Pagkarating namin doon, nagmeryenda kami nang isang oras at namasyal sa Clark nang limang oras. Umabot lang ng dalawa't kalahating oras ang biyahe namin pauwi. 11:30 PM na nang nakabalik kami sa Manila.Anong oras kami umalis kanina mula Manila?","answer":"Umalis kayo nang 11 AM mula Manila."},{"question":"Inona no fitaovana ara-pitsaboana novolavolain'i Sanctorius tamin'ny 1612 ? ","answer":"Ny thermometatra no fitaovana ara-pitsaboana novolavolain'i Sanctorius tamin'ny 1612 ."},{"question":"أريد إنشاء قصيدة رومنسيه من بحر الخفيف. هل يمكنك مساعدتي؟","answer":"إليك هذه القصيدة من البحر الخفيف:لي حَبيب فِداهُ كُل حَبيبلَيسَ إِلّا بِهِ الحَياة تَطيبقَد دَعاني مُتَيماً وَكَئيبمَدداً يا أَنيس كُل غَريبقَمر دُون حُسنِهِ الأَقمارساقَني نَحوَ حُبِهِ الأَقدارهُوَ في القَلب إِن دَنا أَو سارمَدداً يا أَنيس كُل غَريبمال بِالنَوم قَدهُ المَيّالعَن جُفوني وَزادَني بلبالوَرَماني بِقسوة وَدَلالمَدداً يا أَنيس كُل غَريبما لِمِثلي عَلى هَواهُ نَصيرلا وَلا مُسعف يَرى وَظَهيررَب هَون عَلَيَّ كُل عَسيرمَدداً يا أَنيس كُل غَريبوَأَجرني بِالمُصطَفى الهاديمِن عَدوي وَشَر حُساديوَاِجعَل الخَير وَالتُقا زاديمَدداً يا أَنيس كُل غَريب"},{"question":"Indil péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Da noo demoon seeti Usmaan Sónko ndàxte yoon aayewu nu ko te benn dogalub yoon manut làyal ni ñu gawe këram.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Da noo demoon seeti Usmaan Sónko ndàxte yoon aayewu nu ko te benn dogalub yoon manut làyal ni ñu gawe këram.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Da: AUXnu: PRONa: PARTdemoon: VERBseeti: VERBUsmaan: PROPNSónko: PROPNndàxte: SCONJyoon: NOUNaayewu: VERBnu: PRONko: PRONte: CCONJbenn: DETdogalub: NOUNyoon: NOUNmanut: VERBlàyal: VERBni: ADPñu: PRONgawe: VERBkëram: NOUN.: PUNCT"},{"question":"සිංහරාජ වනාන්තරය මායිව ඇති දිස්ත්‍රික්ක තුන ?","answer":"රත්නපුරය, ගාල්ල, සහ මාතර"},{"question":"Rispondi alla seguente domanda:\\"Dove si trova il Pozzo di San Patrizio?\\"","answer":"Il Pozzo di San Patrizio si trova nella città di Orvieto, in Umbria (Italia).Il pozzo è una struttura costruita da Antonio da Sangallo il Giovane tra il 1527 e il 1537 per volere del papa Clemente VII, reduce dal Sacco di Roma e desideroso di tutelarsi nell'eventualità che la città in cui si era ritirato fosse assediata. Pertanto fu progettato proprio per fornire acqua in caso di calamità o assedio. I lavori furono conclusi durante il papato di Paolo III Farnese (1534-1549).L'accesso al pozzo, capolavoro di ingegneria, è garantito da due rampe elicoidali a senso unico, completamente autonome e servite da due diverse porte, che consentivano di trasportare con i muli l'acqua estratta senza ostacolarsi e senza dover ricorrere all'unica via che saliva al paese dal fondovalle."},{"question":"Manana ity teny nakorontana ity ianao:viaanmaVinavinao ilay teny rehefa voalamina.","answer":"Ilay teny rehefa voalamina dia \\"maivana\\"."},{"question":"این جمله را کامل کن.طرح نجات دریاچه ارومیه، گران‌ترین و پرمخاطب‌ترین پروژه","answer":"زیست‌محیطی ایران است. این طرح تا سال ۱۴۰۰ بیش از ۱۵ هزار میلیارد تومان هزینه داشته‌است."},{"question":"Maxay kala yihiin tiirarka uu iimaanku ku taaganyahay (arkaan-ul-iimaan)?","answer":"MAYA; sababtoo ah wuxuu qofku muslim buuxa noqonayaa marka uu arkaanul-iimaanka wada qiro, kuna dhaqmo arkaanul-islaamka."},{"question":"യുണൈറ്റഡ് സ്റ്റേറ്റ്സിലെ ന്യൂയോർക്ക് ഹാർബറിൽ സ്ഥിതി ചെയ്യുന്ന സ്വാതന്ത്ര്യത്തിന്റെയും ജനാധിപത്യത്തിന്റെയും പ്രതീകമാണ് സ്റ്റാച്യു ഓഫ് ലിബർട്ടി. ഫ്രാൻസിൽ നിന്ന് യുണൈറ്റഡ് സ്റ്റേറ്റ്സിന് ലഭിച്ച സമ്മാനമായിരുന്നു ഇത്, 1886-ൽ സമർപ്പിക്കപ്പെട്ടു. ഫ്രെഡറിക് അഗസ്റ്റെ ബാർത്തോൾഡി രൂപകൽപ്പന ചെയ്ത ഈ പ്രതിമ റോമൻ സ്വാതന്ത്ര്യത്തിന്റെ ദേവതയായ ലിബർട്ടസിനെ പ്രതിനിധീകരിക്കുന്നു. 305 അടി ഉയരത്തിൽ നിൽക്കുന്ന ഇത് കടൽമാർഗം അമേരിക്കയിലേക്ക് വരുന്ന സന്ദർശകരെയും കുടിയേറ്റക്കാരെയും സ്വാഗതം ചെയ്യുന്നു. സ്വാതന്ത്ര്യത്തിന്റെയും ജനാധിപത്യത്തിന്റെയും ആശയങ്ങൾ ഉൾക്കൊള്ളുന്ന, പ്രത്യാശയുടെയും അവസരങ്ങളുടെയും സാർവത്രിക പ്രതീകമായി ലിബർട്ടി പ്രതിമ മാറിയിരിക്കുന്നു.ചോദ്യം: ഈ ഭാഗം എന്തിനെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ഈ ഖണ്ഡിക സ്വാതന്ത്ര്യത്തിന്റെയും ജനാധിപത്യത്തിന്റെയും പ്രതീകമാണ് സ്റ്റാച്യു ഓഫ് ലിബർട്ടിയെക്കുറിച്ചാണ്. കൂടാതെ ഈ ഭാഗം സ്വാതന്ത്ര്യത്തിന്റെയും ജനാധിപത്യത്തിന്റെയും പ്രതീകമെന്ന നിലയിൽ അതിന്റെ പ്രാധാന്യം, ഫ്രെഡറിക് അഗസ്റ്റെ ബാർത്തോൾഡിയുടെ രൂപകൽപ്പന, 1886-ൽ അതിന്റെ സമർപ്പണം, കുടിയേറ്റക്കാർക്കുള്ള പ്രതീക്ഷയുടെയും അവസരത്തിന്റെയും പ്രതിനിധാനം എന്നിവയെക്കുറിച്ചും സംസാരിക്കുന്നു."},{"question":"Geef me de lijst van de laatste vijf winnaars van de Europese Gouden Schoen en vertel me hoeveel doelpunten ze hebben gescoord.","answer":"Dit zijn de laatste vijf winnaars met de hoeveelheid doelpunten:1. Robert Lewandowski, 2022-2021, 35 doelpunten 2. Robert Lewandowski, 2021-2020, 41 doelpunten 3. Ciro Immobile, 2020-2019, 36 doelpunten 4. Lionel Messi, 2019-2018, 36 doelpunten 5. Lionel Messi, 2018-2017, 34 doelpunten"},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ചില സാധാരണ പച്ചക്കറികൾ എന്തൊക്കെയാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: കാരറ്റ്, ബ്രോക്കോളി, തക്കാളി, ഉരുളക്കിഴങ്ങ്, കുക്കുമ്പർ, ചീര, ഉള്ളി, കുരുമുളക്, കാബേജ്, കോളിഫ്ലവർ"},{"question":"Iza no anaran'ilay mpahay siansa poloney malaza ary hany olona nahazo loka Nobel roa tamin'ny taranja roa samy hafa: ny fizika sy ny simia?","answer":"Ny mpahay siansa poloney malaza dia Marie Curie."},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਅਸੰਖ ਭਗਤ ਗੁਣ ਗਿਆਨ ਵੀਚਾਰ ॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 3 ਤੋਂ ਲਈ ਗਈ ਇੱਕ ਤੁਕ ਦਾ ਵਾਕ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਨਾਨਕ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਸ ਬਾਣੀ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸਦਾ ਮਤਲਬ ਇਹ ਹੈ,\\"ਅਣਗਿਣਤ ਭਗਤ ਹਨ, ਜੋ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੇ ਗੁਣਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਗਿਆਨ ਦੀ ਵਿਚਾਰ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ, \\""},{"question":"¿Cuáles fueron las causas de la Primera Guerra Mundial?","answer":"Las causas principales incluyeron tensiones políticas, alianzas militares, nacionalismo, imperialismo y el asesinato del Archiduque Francisco Fernando de Austria-Hungría."},{"question":"Apakah nama lagu kebangsaan Malaysia?","answer":"Nama lagu kebangsaan Malaysia ialah Negaraku."},{"question":"« Amin’izao fotoana ahazoany indray ny fahaleovantenany manolona ny siansa izao, dia ilain’ny Filôzôfia ny mahatsapa  fa miavaka amin’ny Siansa izy, tsy eo amin’ny fomba entiny mandinika ihany, tsy eo amin’ny foto-dresaka fotsiny ihany koa, izany hoe ny votoaty manokan’ireo olany, fa eo ihany koa ny zavatra hafa mbola mialha izany, dia ny toetran’ny olany araka ny maha-olana azy… Mitoetra ho olana tsy manam-petra ny olana sahanin’ny fikarohana filôzôfika. Misy ny Siansa raha misy ny vahaolana, tsy maintsy ilaina io. Tsy mba toy izany kosa ny Filôzôfia. Tsy noho izy hoe mandroso vahaolana azo ekena no manamarina ny fisiany fa noho ireo olana asehony tsy azo ihodivirana . Mametraka olana siantifika ny olona rehefa tiany izany. Ny olana filôzôfika kosa mipetraka ho azy amin’ny olona, mipetraka avy hatrany na tiany na tsy tiany. »Inona ny lohahevitr’io lahatsoratra ambony io ?","answer":"Ny lohahevitr’io lahatsoratra io dia ny mahasamihafa ny siansa sy ny filôzôfia."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：在數學中，什麼是黎曼積分？","answer":"答案：黎曼積分是一種對函數在一個區間上的定積分，通常用來計算曲線下的面積。"},{"question":"问题：三星耳机在市场上的竞争对手有哪些？","answer":"答案：三星耳机在市场上的竞争对手包括苹果的AirPods、索尼的WF系列等。"},{"question":"\\"Ny Paska dia fety ara-pivavahana jiosy izay ahatsiarovana ny nanafahana ny Isiraelita tamin'ny fanandevozana tany Egypta teo ambany fitarihan'i Mosesy.\\"\\"Inona ny fanontaniana azo tsongaina amin'io andian-teny io?","answer":"Fanontaniana: Inona no fety jiosy ahatsiarovana ny nanafahana ny Israelita tamin'ny fanandevozana tany Egypta?"},{"question":" மு.வரதராசனின் திரைப்படமான கதைகள் என்னென்ன?","answer":"பெற்ற மனம் திரைப்படத்தின் கதையை மு. வரதராசன் எழுதினார். பெற்ற மனம் 1960 ஆம் ஆண்டில் வெளிவந்த இந்தியத் தமிழ்த் திரைப்படம் ஆகும். ஏ. பீம்சிங் இயக்கத்தில் நேசனல் பிக்சர்சு நிறுவனத்தினர் இதனைத் தயாரித்திருந்தனர். சிவாஜி கணேசன், புஷ்பவல்லி, எஸ். எஸ். ராஜேந்திரன், பத்மினி ஆகியோர் முக்கிய பாத்திரங்களில் நடித்தனர். இது 1953 இல் வெளிவந்த பெம்புடு கொடுக்கு என்ற தெலுங்குத் திரைப்படத்தின் தழுவல் ஆகும்.நடனங்களை கே. என். தண்டாயுதபாணி, பிள்ளை தங்கப்பன், முத்துசாமிப் பிள்ளை ஆகியோர் அமைத்திருந்தனர். பெற்ற மனமும், பெம்புடு கொடுக்கு என்ற தெலுங்குத் திரைப்படமும் ஒரே நேரத்தில் தயாரிக்கப்பட்டிருந்தாலும், தெலுங்குத் திரைப்படம் 1953 இலேயே வெளியிடப்பட்டு விட்டது. ஏழாண்டுகளின் பின்னரேயே தமிழ்த் திரைப்படம் வெளியானது."},{"question":"Tamin'ny taona firy no nandimby an-dRanavalona I i Radama II ? ","answer":"Tamin'ny taona 1861 ny mpanjaka Radama II no nandimby an-dRanavalona I ."},{"question":"Кудай жалгасын","answer":" Көбүнчө бирөөгө ыраазы болуу же келиндерди алкоо маанисинде колдонулат. Өмүрүң узун болсун! Кудай жалгасын! Сооп иш кылдың, ишиң оңолсун! (Медетов). Балам, кудай жалгасын! – деген сөздөр таятасынын оозунан чыкканын бала ишене албай укту (Айтматов) В.: теңир жалгасын! – а-а, айланайын балам: Сага чоң рахмат! Сени теңир жалгасын! Эми биз кайталы, келе колуңду бер, азаматым! («Ала-Тоо»). Кудай жалгагыр! Ай, кудай жалгагыр, уулуңду таап келчи (Тойбаев). – Ой, – деди жалынгандай күбүрөй, – энеми капа кылбай, деги эле эчтеме болбогондой кашкайып, барчы, кудай жалгагыр, ай… (Касымбеков). Кудай тилегиңди бергир! Кудай тилегиңди бергир, жаныңда ишенимдүү жигиттериң бар тура! (Медетов)"},{"question":"Complete o seguinte trecho: Collado ganhou os prêmios de jornalismo Varona e Víctor Muñoz. No final da","answer":"Revolução Cubana, María Collado se aposentou do jornalismo, mas ela ainda se juntou à Federação das Mulheres Cubanas (; FMC), fundada em 1960 como parte do Partido Comunista de Cuba, onde testemunhou a plena incorporação das mulheres à sociedade pela qual lutou por toda a vida."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa qaaraddaha loo-yaqaano qaaradaha Da’da Yar Ama Cusub?","answer":"1- Qaaradda America 2- Qaaradda Australia."},{"question":"Have you been subject to any disciplinary proceedings against you for misconduct which resulted in a disciplinary sanction from any organization? ","answer":"Yes, I have been."},{"question":"Nor izan zen Isaac Newton?","answer":"Isaac Newton XVII. mendeko fisikari, matematikari eta astronomo ingelesa izan zen. Haren grabitazio-legeak eta optikari buruzko lanak fisika modernoaren oinarriak ezarri zituzten."},{"question":"Hãy chọn đáp án đúng cho câu hỏi sau:Điều gì giúp cho chúng ta có thể nghe thấy?A. MắtB. TaiC. MũiD. Miệng","answer":"Đáp án: B"},{"question":"Korona mu oṣiṣẹ DSTV n’Ibadan, wọn ba ni kawọn onibaara wọn lọọ fira wọn pamọ sile","answer":"Oṣiṣẹ ileeṣẹ Multichoice, iyẹn ileeṣẹ to ni ẹrọ amohunmaworan alatagba ti wọn n pe ni DSTV n’Ibadan ti lugbadi arun Korona.Eyi lo mu ki awọn alaṣẹ ileeṣẹ ọhun sọ fawọn onibaara wọn to ti ni nnkan kan tabi omi-in i ṣe lọfiisi wọn lẹnu ọjọ mẹta yii lati lọọ fi ara pamọ sile wọn fun asiko diẹ naa.Ninu atẹjade ti Abilekọ Caroline Oghuma fi sita lorukọ igbimọ awọn alaṣẹ ileeṣẹ DSTV nirọlẹ ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ana, lo ti sọ ojú abẹ níkòó pe ọkan ninu awọn oṣiṣẹ awọn ti ṣayẹwo Korona, abajade ayẹwo ọhun si fi han pe kokoro arun naa ti wa ninu ẹjẹ rẹ.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe sọ, “Laipẹ yii la ri i pe ọkan ninu awọn oṣiṣẹ wa, ni ẹka ọfiisi wa kẹrinla to wa l’Onireke, n’Ibadan, ti ni kokoro arun Korona lara. O si ti n gba itọju nileewosan lọwọ bayii.“Gbogbo ẹyin tẹ ẹ ba wa si ẹka ọfiisi wa yii laarin ọsẹ meji sẹyin, bẹrẹ lati ọjọ kẹtadinlọgbọn, oṣu kẹfa, si ọjọ kọkanla, oṣu keje ọdun 2020 yii, o ṣee ṣe kẹ ẹ ti ni ifarakinra pẹlu ẹni to ni kokoro Korona lara yii. Nitori naa, a rọ yin lati sé ara yin mọ́lé fun asiko diẹ nitori.”"},{"question":" Avy amin’ny Zanahary na Andriamanitra ny vintana satria izy no mpamorona ny Zavaboaary rehetra. Toy izao ny filazan’i RAHAJARIZAFY izany: “Anjara avy amin’ Andriamanitra nahary tongotra aman-tanana ny vintana.”     Mety ho avy amin’ny Ray aman-dreny sy ny Razana ihany koa ny vintan’ny taranaka. Ny todin’ny nataon’izy ireo na tsara na ratsy dia hamantarana ny toetry ny vintana araka ny hevitr’i Joseph RAKOTONIRAINY hoe: “Ny vintana dia lalàn’ny todin’ny natao.” Miresaka momban'ny inona ity lahatsoratra eo ambony ity?","answer":"Miresaka momban'ny loharano nipoiran’ny vintana ity lahatsoratra izay hita teo ambony ity ."},{"question":"*ما السورة التي سميت سورة المؤمن؟","answer":"غافر"},{"question":"तलको प्रश्नको सहि उत्तर छान्नुहोस ।यदि गोठलाई घर भनिन्छ भने गाई कहाँ बस्छ ?(क) वन(ख) गोठ(ग) खोर(घ) घर","answer":"यदि गोठलाई घर भनिन्छ भने गाई \\"(घ) घर\\"मा बस्छ । "},{"question":"નીચેના ગુજરાતી ઉખાણાં નો જવાબ આપો:ઊંચું છે એક પ્રાણી, એની પીઠ છે ત્રિકોણી, છે રણનું જહાજ-ગાડી, એને જોઈએ થોડુંક પાણી.","answer":"ઊંટ"},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'cuci mata'? Berilah satu contoh ayat untuknya.","answer":"Ia bermaksud 1. Melihat pemandangan yang cantik. 2. Melihat perempuan yang cantik-cantik. Contoh ayat: 1. Semasa bercuti di Air Terjun Lasir dapatlah kami mencuci mata melihat keindahan alam semula jadi di sekitarnya. 2. Kasim suka duduk-duduk di serambi rumahnya sambil mencuci mata melihat gadis yang lalu di hadapan rumahnya."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa  qiimaynta cabbiraadda jirka ee nafaqo daridda?","answer":"Jir cabbirku waa hab lagu cabiro xajmiga jirka waxaana loo isticmaalaa in lagu fahmo heerka nafaqo ee qofka. Cabiraadahan soo socda ayaa badanaaba la isticmaalaa. Culays: Isbeddelka ku yimaada culayska ilmaha wuxuu tilmaan muhiim ah u yahay caafimaadka guud iyo ladnaanta bulshada. Si kastaba ha ahaatee xilliyada duruufaha gaarka ah waxaa muhiim noqon kara in la cabiro da’aha kale. Jiif ama Joog: Dhererka ilmuhu wuxuu isla beddelaa wakhtiga isagoo ku xiran nafaqeeyayaalka la qaatay iyo sida jirku uga faa’iidaystay.Dhexroorka bartamaha cududda sare (MUAC): kani waa cabbir deg-deg ah waxtarna u leh in la saadaaliyo carruurta dhimashada khatarta ugujirata da’dooduna u dhexayso 12 – 59 bilood. MUAC waa aalad baaritaan oo muhiima u ah go’aaminta ilmaha khatarta ku jira xilliga masiibooyinku jiraan. Tusaha cufnaanta jirka(BMI): waa aalad muhiim ah marka la cabirayo heerka nafaqada dadka waaweyn. Cabbirka culayska iyo dhererka ayaa la qaadaa ka dibna waxaa lagu xisaabiyaa tusaha. Isticmaalka BMI ee dadka waaweyn waa mid aan lagu kalsoonaan karin waayo saxnaanta dhererka ayaa waxaacarqaladeeya arrimo da’da la xiriira sida soo godashada lafta dhabarka (spinal curvature).Sidaas awgeed MUAC-gu waa cabbiraadda ugu haboon maadaama ilaa xad aanu ku xirnayn da’da. Barar(oedama): Ururitaanka dheecaanadaaan caadiga ahayn unugyada dhexdooda wuxuu tilmaamaa nafaqo-darro halis ah."},{"question":"قم بالإجابة على السؤال التالي كم عدد أعين الذبابة ؟","answer":"تملك الذبابة 5 عيون؛ عينين كبيرتين يُمكن رؤيتهما ويُطلق عليهما اسم \\"العيون المركبة\\"، و3 عيون أخرى بسيطة التركيب موجودة في الجزء العلوي من الرأس وهي مخصّصة لرصد الحركات،[١] وتُعتبر الذبابة المنزلية واسمها العملي (Musca Domestica) من أكثر أنواع الذباب شيوعاً، وتُمثّل 90% من أنواع الذباب الذي يعيش في المنازل، وتنتمي لفصيلة الذباب المنزلي، من رتبة الحشرات ذات الجناحين."},{"question":"বসন্তকাল নিয়ে অনুচ্ছেদ লিখুন।","answer":"বাংলার ঋতুপরিক্রমায় ছয়টি ঋতু আসে ধারাবাহিকভাবে। সেই ধারাবাহিকতায় শীতের পরে আসে বসন্ত। কুয়াশা মাখা পাতা ঝরার দিন শেষ হয়। প্রকৃতি নতুন রূপে সেজে বরণ করে নেয় ঋতুরাজ বসন্তকে। বাংলার ঋতুর হিসেবে ফাল্গুন ও চৈত্র এ দুই মাস বসন্তকাল। কিন্তু মাঘের শেষে শীত কমতে শুরু করলেই শুরু হয় শীতের যাই যাই ভাব। তখন থেকেই প্রকৃতিতে বসন্তের আগমন-লক্ষণ দেখা দেয়। অন্যদিকে চৈত্রের মধ্যভাগে অনুভূত হতে থাকে গ্রীষ্মের তাপ। এদিক থেকে মাঝের এই নাতিশীতোষ্ণ আবহাওয়াই বসন্তের নিজস্ব পরিচয়। প্রকৃতিতে এ আবহাওয়া এক নতুন সৌন্দর্যের সম্ভার সৃষ্টি করে। বসন্তের আগমনে বাংলার প্রকৃতিতে মন-মাতানো দখিনা বাতাসের মৃদুমন্দ আনাগোনা শুরু হয়। সে বাতাসে নিষ্পত্র গাছে গাছে নতুন পাতা গজায় । আমগাছ নব মঞ্জরীতে সেজে ওঠে। অশোক, পলাশ, শিমুল, ডালিম আর কৃষ্ণচূড়ার ফুলে ছেয়ে যায় চারদিক। ফুলে ফুলে নীল আকাশে তৈরি হয় লাল রঙের আলপনা। ফুলে ফুলে নেচে বেড়ায় মৌমাছি ও প্রজাপতিরা। কোকিলের কুহুতান মানবমনকে আনন্দে ভরিয়ে তোলে। ফুলের গন্ধে আমোদিত বাতাসের ঢেউ খেলে যায় দিক-দিগন্তে। যব, গম, সরিষা ইত্যাদি শস্যের রঙিন আবেশে গ্রামবাংলার খেতগুলো হয়ে ওঠে অপরূপ। প্রকৃতি ও জনজীবনে বয়ে যায় আনন্দের শিহরণ। ঋতু পরিবর্তন সবসময়ই মানবমনের পরিবর্তনে বিশেষ ভূমিকা পালন করে। বসন্ত ঋতুতেও মানবমনে পরিবর্তন সাধিত হয়। চারদিকে প্রকৃতির বিচিত্র রূপ দেখে মানবমনে আনন্দের ছোঁয়া লাগে। সেই আনন্দ আমরা প্রকাশ করি নানাভাবে। ছড়িয়ে দিতে চাই সবার মাঝে। বাংলা সাহিত্যে বসন্ত ঋতুকে ঘিরে তৈরি হয়েছে নানা গল্প, গান ও কবিতা । এসব সাহিত্যপাঠের মধ্য দিয়ে আমরা বসন্ত ঋতুকে আরও বেশি করে অনুভব করি। বসন্তের আগমনে বাঙালির জীবনে লাগে উৎসবের ছোঁয়া। বাঙালি আয়োজন করে বসন্ত বরণ উৎসবের। তরুণ-তরুণীরা বাসন্তী রঙের পোশাকে সাজে।"},{"question":"في أي عام اكتشف كريستوف كولمبس أمريكا ؟","answer":"1492"},{"question":"धार्मिक प्रतिमामा रञ्जना लिपिको प्रतीकात्मकता अन्वेषण गर्नुहोस्, विशेष गरी देवताहरू र दैवी व्यक्तित्वहरूको चित्रणमा। यसले कसरी पवित्र छविलाई बढाउँछ?","answer":"रञ्जना लिपिले धार्मिक मूर्तिकलामा प्रतीकात्मकता राख्छ, देवताहरू र दैवी व्यक्तित्वहरूको चित्रण बढाउँछ। पवित्र इमेजरीमा यसको प्रयोगले धार्मिक प्रतिनिधित्वहरूमा पवित्रता र सांस्कृतिक समृद्धिको भावना थप्छ।"},{"question":"Ogbenye ","answer":"Olundi - mgbei"},{"question":"Акция деген эмне ?","answer":"Акция - голландиянын аktic деген сөзүнөн - баалуу кагаз; базар экономикасы - жеке менчиктин жана товардык-акча мамилелеринин негизинде өнүккөн, эркин ишкердүүлүктүн жана тандоонун принциптерине таянган социалдык-экономикалык система"},{"question":"No contexto de Aprendizado de Máquina, o que significa \\"Feature Engineering\\"?","answer":"Feature Engineering é o processo de seleção, transformação e criação de características (ou atributos) a partir dos dados brutos para melhorar o desempenho de um modelo de ML."},{"question":"නිඛිල ලෙස හැඳින්වෙන්නේ කුමන සංඛ්‍යා  ද?","answer":"නිඛිල ලෙස හැඳින්වෙන්නේ ධන නිඛිල, ශුන්‍යය හා  ඍණ නිඛිල යන සියලු සංඛ්‍යා ය."},{"question":"नाप्राप्यमभिवाञ्छन्ति नष्टं नेच्छन्ति शोचितुम् |आपत्स्वपि न मुह्यन्ति नराः पण्डितबुद्धयः ||","answer":"अर्थ : विद्वान् माणसे न मिळण्याजोग्या [अशक्य] गोष्टीची इच्छा करीत नाहीत, नाश पावलेल्या गोष्टीबद्दल दुःख करीत नाहीत आणि संकटकाळी डगमगत नाहीत."},{"question":"文章から主要な単語を特定し、それを定義しなさい。 三菱商事のグループの会社は7月、東京の世田谷区に電気自動車を200台ぐらい貸す計画を始めました。車を新しく買うよりもかかるお金を少なくすることができます。そして、車から出る二酸化炭素をどのくらい少なくすることができたかデータを出します。世田谷区では、2027年度までに役所の車の半分が電気自動車などになる予定です。東京ガスは、役所や会社などに、電気自動車の充電の機械や管理のシステムを一緒にして売るサービスを始めています。たくさんの車を電気自動車にうまく変えていく計画も作ります。住友商事のグループの会社は、使って古くなった電気自動車を役所に貸す実験を始めています。","answer":"この文章の中での主要な単語とその定義は以下のようになっています。- グループ: 1）仲間。集団。- 二酸化炭素: 1）炭素と酸素の化合物で、色もにおいもない気体。炭火の燃えるときなどに発生し、人のはく息の中にもふくまれている。ドライアイス・ソーダ水などに使われる。炭酸ガス。記号は「CO₂」。- データ: 1）考えるもとになる材料や事実。2）コンピューターで使えるように、数字や記号に置きかえられた資料。- 年度: 1）仕事の都合で決めた一年の期間。ふつう四月一日に始まり、翌年の三月三十一日に終わる。- 役所: 1）国や地方公共団体の仕事をする所。官庁。役場。- 充電: 1）蓄電池に電気をたくわえること。2）活力をたくわえること。- 管理: 1）ものごとを取りしきること。2）よい状態に保つこと。- システム: 1）仕組み。組織。2）ひとまとまりの組み合わせ。- サービス: 1）人のために尽くすこと。奉仕。2）客をもてなすこと。3）直接物を作る以外の仕事。- 実験: 1）実際にためしてみること。"},{"question":"Me diga as seleções nacionais que já ganharam a Copa, quantos troféus e em quais anos elas venceram?","answer":"Claro, aqui está uma lista de seleções que já ganharam copa até o ano de 2023:Brasil - 5 troféus (1958, 1962, 1970, 1994, 2002).Alemanha - 4 troféus (1954, 1974, 1990 como Alemanha Ocidental, 2014 como Alemanha unificada).Itália - 4 troféus (1934, 1938, 1982, 2006).Argentina - 3 troféus (1978, 1986, 2022).Uruguai - 2 troféus (1930, 1950).França - 2 troféus (1998, 2018).Inglaterra - 1 troféu (1966).Espanha - 1 troféu (2010)."},{"question":"வீட்டில் மாட்டிக்கொள்வதை விட ________ காட்டில் அலைவதே மேல்.","answer":"விடை : வீட்டில் மாட்டிக்கொள்வதை விட __சுதந்திரமாக__ காட்டில் அலைவதே மேல்."},{"question":"ماهو تشكيل النص التالي: مكان من وطئه أو استدخال منيه ولدا لحقه وإن لم يعترف به بأن سكت عن استلحاقه لأنه صلى الله عليه وسلم ألحق الولد بزمعة بمجرد الفراش أي بعد علمه الوطء بوحي أو إخبار لما مر من الإجماع وإن أقر بوطء ونفى الولد وادعى استبراء بحيضة مثلا بعد الوطء وقبل الوضع بستة أشهر فأكثر وحلف على ذلك وإن وافقت.","answer":"ِمْكَانِ مِنْ وَطْئِهِ أَوْ اسْتِدْخَالِ مَنِيِهِ وَلَدًا لَحِقَهُ وَإِنْ لَمْ يَعْتَرِفْ بِهِ بِأَنْ سَكَتَ عَنْ اسْتِلْحَاقِهِ لِأَنَهُ صَلَى اللَهُ عَلَيْهِ وَسَلَمَ أَلْحَقَ الْوَلَدَ بِزَمْعَةَ بِمُجَرَدِ الْفِرَاشِ أَيْ بَعْدَ عِلْمِهِ الْوَطْءَ بِوَحْيٍ أَوْ إخْبَارٍ لِمَا مَرَ مِنْ الْإِجْمَاعِ وَإِنْ أَقَرَ بِوَطْءٍ وَنَفَى الْوَلَدَ وَادَعَى اسْتِبْرَاءً بِحَيْضَةٍ مَثَلًا بَعْدَ الْوَطْءِ وَقَبْلَ الْوَضْعِ بِسِتَةِ أَشْهُرٍ فَأَكْثَرَ وَحَلَفَ عَلَى ذَلِكَ وَإِنْ وَافَقَت."},{"question":"இச்சமயம் தென்னாப்பிரிக்காவில் ஆங்கிலேயர் ஆட்சியில் நிறவெறியும் இனப்பாகுபாடும் மிகுந்து இருந்தது. இதுவரை அரசியல் ஈடுபாடில்லாது தன்னையும் தன் குடும்பத்தையும் மட்டுமே கவனித்து வந்த இளைஞராயிருந்தார் காந்தி.","answer":"தென்னாப்பிரிக்காவில் அவருக்கேற்பட்ட அனுபவங்கள், பின்னாளில் அவரை ஒரு மாபெரும் அரசியல் சக்தியாக உருவாக்க உதவியது."},{"question":"Запропонойте назву для цієї статті:Печерський районний суд Києва мав обрати запобіжний захід народному депутату Олександру Дубінському, якого підозрюють у державній зраді.Але адвокати нардепа заявили про відвід судді, - пише Суспільне.Засідання відбулося у закритому режимі.Також захист Дубінського заявив про відвід судді, бо не встиг ознайомитися з матеріалами справи. Адвокати подали клопотання, щоб перенести засідання на завтра, 14 листопада. Суд його відхилив і надав пів години для ознайомлення. Тепер має відбутись авторозподіл судді і той або прийме відвід колеги, або ні.\\"Має відбутися авторозподіл справи на іншого суддю, який розглядає відвід, який надали мої адвокати, прийме рішення відводити чи не відводити. І після цього, якщо відвід відхилено, то ми маємо повертатися знову на судове засідання. Нас повідомлять, ми приїдемо\\", — зауважив нардеп.13 листопада ЗМІ повідомили, що ДБР та СБУ прийшли з повторними обшуками до Дубінського, а саме – в межах справи про злочинну організацію, створену задля дискредитації іміджу України на міжнародній арені.Нагадаємо, 3 листопада Дубінському було оголошено підозру в організації схеми для незаконного виїзду чоловіків за кордон.","answer":"Суд наразі не обрав запобіжний захід Дубінському: адвокати заявили про відвід судді"},{"question":"Shin gaskiya ne cewa: A da an san Zimbabwe da sunan Rhodesia. (a) Gaskiya (b) Ƙarya","answer":"Amsa: Gaskiya"},{"question":"Эртеси эрте туруп, көптөн күткөн Эйфел мунарасын көрүүгө жөнөп калдык.  Негизи Париж өзү туристке бай, туристтик жайларга, көрө турган жайларга бай, тарыхий мыкты жер экен. Бирок негедир Францияга келе жатканда эле Кыргызстанга кирип жаткандай сезимдер болуп жатты.Эгерде бул контексттен суроо жаратсак, ал суроого жооп \\"Эйфел мунарасын\\" болсо, анда суроо кандай болмок? ","answer":"Эртеси эрте туруп, биз эмнени  көрүүгө жөнөдүк?"},{"question":"కింది వానిలో ప్రకృతి వికృతులను జతపరచండి.1. పుత్రుడు\\tఅ) పసువు2. రాక్షసుడు\\tఆ) పుడమి3. పృథ్వి\\tఇ) బొట్టె4. పశువు\\tఈ) రక్కసుడు","answer":"1. పుత్రుడు\\tఇ) బొట్టె2. రాక్షసుడు\\tఈ) రక్కసుడు3. పృథ్వి\\tఆ) పుడమి4. పశువు\\tఅ) పసువు"},{"question":"Fantaro raha maneho fifaliana, alahelo, hatezerana, na tahotra ity fanambarana manaraka ity: \\"Tsy masiaka be ve io alika io?\\"","answer":"Ity fanambarana ity maneho tahotra. Matahotra ianao satria manahy ny mety hasiaka an'ilay alika. "},{"question":"\\"Nitombo ny fampianarana an-tserasera sy lavitra tato anatin'ny taona vitsivitsy, manome fahafaham-po ny mpianatra hanohy ny fianarany amin'ny hafainganam-pandehany. Nanjary zava-dehibe indrindra ny fampianarana an-tserasera nandritra ny areti-mifindra COVID-19.\\". Inona ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io?","answer":"Ny lohahevitr'io lahatsoratra eo ambony io dia ny fanabeazana."},{"question":"A wace shekara Gambia ta fara shiga gasar cin kofin duniya?","answer":"A shekarar 2021."},{"question":"Балдарга кантип чет тилди тез үйрөтсө болот?","answer":"Чет тилдердин пайдасы тууралуу айтып берүүдөн тажабаңыз. Көп тил билсе көп дос табарын айтып, шартыңыз болсо атайын тил үйрөнүү боюнча уюшулган лагерлерге жөнөтүңүз."},{"question":"Apakah maksud 'air di tulang bumbungan, turunnya ke cucur atap'?","answer":"Maksud 'air di tulang bumbungan, turunnya ke cucur atap' ialah sesuatu itu, meskipun sedikit, akan menurut asalnya juga"},{"question":"ගෞතම බුදුසසුනේ \\" මනෝමය කාය නිර්මාණය කරන්නවුන් අතරින් අග්‍ර \\" වූ , මහ රහතන් වහන්සේ කවුද ?","answer":"චුල්ල පන්ථක තෙරුන්වහන්සේ "},{"question":"1 sakinys: \\" Pravda \\" skaitytojams puikiai žinomi ypač populiarūs unikalūs pėsčiųjų, mokyklų ir kelių žemėlapiai, \\" Pravda \\" kišeniniai gidai, naudingos memorandumo kortelės ar kalendoriai. 2 sakinys: \\" Pravda \\" skaitytojams puikiai žinomi ypač populiarūs ir naudingi pėsčiųjų žemėlapiai, mokyklos kortelės ir gatvių žemėlapiai, \\" Pravda \\" kišeniniai gidai, unikalūs memorandumo žemėlapiai ar kalendoriai. Klausimas: Ar 1 ir 2 sakiniai reiškia tą pačią reikšmę? Taip ar ne?","answer":"Ne"},{"question":"Kung aduna kay 5 ka pares sa tsinelas ug gikuhaan ka og duha, pila ang nabilin?","answer":"Ang nabilin kay 3 nalang ka pares sa tsinelas."},{"question":"इंग्रज व मराठे यांच्यात एकूण किती युध्द झाले?","answer":"इंग्रज व मराठे यांच्यात एकूण तीन युध्द झाले."},{"question":" வினா : தங்கள்   நூலுக்குத் தாங்களே  உரை எழுதியவர்கள் யார் ?","answer":"விடை : பல ஆண்டுகளுக்கு முன் பாடல் வடிவில் எழுதப்பட்ட தமிழ் நூல்களின் பொருளை உரைவடிவில் விரித்து எழுதியவர்கள் தமிழ் உரைநூல் ஆசிரியர்கள் ஆவர்.வைத்தியநாத தேசிகர் -இலக்கண விளக்கம்சாமிநாத தேசிகர் –  இலக்கணக்கொத்துபுலவர் குழந்தை – யாப்பதிகாரம்"},{"question":"GACAL DOORASHADA!","answer":"GACAL DOORASHADA!Diinteenna Islaamku waxay ina baraysaa in haweeney afar waxyaabood lagu guursado, kuwaasi oo kala ah: qurux, qoys sharaf leh ooy ka dhalatay, maal iyo diin. Haddaba haddaynu mid mid u kala qaadno:1-Qurux: Quruxdu inkastoo ay tahay shabagga ugu horreeya ee ay dumarku ragga u daadiyaan, misana diin iyo akhlaaq haddaanay dugsanayn, intay halleyso ayaa ka badan waxay hagaajiso, waxana weeye wax da' ku xiranoo qofka aan ku daahin. Waxaa la yiri quruxda keligeed ahi waa sida bal cagaaran oo intaad u bogto aa xoolaha ku deysatid, kolkeyse daaqaan ay ku banaan (shubmaan) oo bushi uun ka qaadaan.2-Qoys sharaf leh: Waa wax loo baahan yahay in dad la garanayo 00 magac iyo maamuus leh laga guursado, waana kii uu Rasuulku (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) yiri: U doorta xawadiinna, cirqigu waa uu dusaaye\\". Xadiiska oo uu soo saaray ibnu Maajah, micnihiisu waxa weeye dadnimo wanaagga waa la'iska dhaxlaaye, hubiya qofka aad guursaneysaan amaba u guurineysaan inuu qoys wanaagsan ka dhashay. Ha yeeshee, illayn qoyska dhan guursan maysido0 qof baad ka guursanaysaaye, sideed ku dammaanad qaadaysaa inay qoftaasi noqon doonto tii lagu nastoo lagu nagaado, haddaanad akhlaaq iyo diin ka cegin?.3-Maal: Ninkii gabar maalkeed oo qura\\" u guursadaa, ma uu doonayo gabadhee maalkeeduu doonayaa, ayada lafteeduna waxayu aragtaa nin ay iibsatay. Waxaa hore loo yiri: Ninka waxa wanaagsan inuu gabadha uu guursanayo saddex dheer yahay: da' iyo nasab iyo duunyo, Si aysan u yasin. Gabadhana waxa wanaagsan ninka ay guursanayso inay saddex dheer tahay: samir iyo edeb iyo suurad wanaag, si uusan u yasin.4-Diin: Rasuulku (Sallallaahu calayhi wasallam) waxa uu xadiis saxiix ah ku yiri: (Naag waxa loo guursadaa maalkeeda, quruxdeeda, sharafteeda iyo dinteeda, ee ta diinta leh gaar gacmaha ciid gashee). Gabadha diinta lihi waa tan garanaysa siday u gudan lahayd xaqa uu ninkeedu ku leeyahay, siday u dhawri lahayd asraarta gurigeeda iyo nafteeda, siday isaga ilaalin lahayd masayr, carruurtana ugu barbaarin lahayd tubta toosan.Haddaba, maadaama ay adagtahay sidii lagu heli lahaa haweeney afarta sifoee aannu soo sheegnay isku darsatay, waxaa habboon in XOogga la saaro qof diin leh, hadday markaasi qurux iyo qoys wanaag ku darsato waa Alxamdu Lil Laahi, hadday maalkeeda sidatana waa Rabbil Caalamiin.Si kastaba arrintu ha ahaatee, waxaad mooddaa in dabeecadda raggu dalkay doonaanba ha u dhasheene tahay inay gabadha bilicsanaanteeda iyo muugaalkabedenkeeda ku daba galaan, intaanay u daadegin diin iyo dabeecad kale.Hadday markaasi diin iyo dabeecadi u dheer yihin, ninka daa'in ka baqayaa waa tuu doonayey, kii kalee damackatiir ahe xoolo daneeyaase quruxda wuxuu ku daraa inay dad magac iyo deeq leh ka dhalatay. "},{"question":"س186- كم مرة احتلت القدس منذ فجر التاريخ ؟","answer":"ج186- 24 مرة"},{"question":"வினா:பெருமுத்தரையர்கள் பற்றிய குறிப்புகள் அமைந்துள்ள நூல் யாது?                          (1)  இன்னா நாற்பது                                (2) நான்மணிக்கடிகை                          (3) நாலடியார்                                                                      (4) சிறுபஞ்சமூலம்","answer":"விடை:நாலடியார்நாலடியார் பதினெண் கீழ்க்கணக்கு நூல் தொகுப்பைச் சேர்ந்த ஒரு தமிழ் நீதி நூல். இது நான்கு அடிகளைக் கொண்ட வெண்பாக்களால் ஆனது. இது சமண முனிவர்களால் இயற்றப்பட்ட நானூறு தனிப்பாடல்களின் தொகுப்பாகக் கருதப்படுகிறது. இதனால் இது நாலடி நானூறு எனவும் பெயர் பெறும். 'வேளாண் வேதம்' என்ற பெயரும் உண்டு. பல நேரங்களில் இது புகழ் பெற்ற தமிழ் நீதி நூலான திருக்குறளுக்கு இணையாகப் பேசப்படும் சிறப்பைப் பெற்றுள்ளது.ஆலும் வேலும் பல்லுக்குறுதி; நாலும் இரண்டும் சொல்லுக்குறுதி என்னும் பழமொழியில் நாலு என்பது நாலடியாரையும், இரண்டு என்பது திருக்குறளையும் குறிக்கும். பதினெண்கீழ்க்கணக்கு நூல்களில் உள்ள ஒரே தொகை நூல் நாலடியார் ஆகும்."},{"question":"۵ برند برای خرید وسایل برقی که در ایران پرفروش هستند را معرفی کن.","answer":"از برندهای پرفروش لوازم برقی  که ساخت ایران هستند می‌توان به پارس خزر، پاکشوما، اسنوا، الکترواستیل و ارج اشاره کرد. "},{"question":"அம்பேத்கரின் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"பீம்ராவ் ராம்ஜி அம்பேத்கர் (14 ஏப்ரல் 1891 – 6 திசம்பர் 1956) என்றும் பாபாசாகேப் அம்பேத்கர் (பொருள்: தந்தை) என்றும் அழைக்கப்படுபவர் இந்திய விடுதலைக்குப் பின்னர் நாட்டின் முதலாவது சட்ட அமைச்சராக பதவியேற்றவர் ஆவார். உயர் கல்வி பெறுவதற்காக அமெரிக்கா சென்ற முதல் இந்தியர் ஆவார். பட்டியல் சாதி மக்களுக்கென கழகம் ஒன்றைத் தொடங்கியவர். பரோடா மன்னருடன் இணைந்து தீண்டாமை ஒழியப் போராடியவர். பொருளாதாரம், அரசியல், வரலாறு, தத்துவம், சட்டம் ஆகிய துறைகளில் தேர்ந்தவர்; ஆசிரியராகவும், இதழாளராகவும், எழுத்தாளராகவும் சமூகநீதிப் புரட்சியாளராகவும் விளங்கியவர். 'நவ புத்தம்' என்ற பெயரில் பல ஆயிரக்கணக்கான பட்டியல் சாதி மக்களை புத்தசமயத்தைத் தழுவச்செய்தவர்; இவை யாவற்றுக்கும் மேலாக இந்திய அரசியலமைப்புச் சாசனத்தை வரைவதற்கான குழுவின் தலைவராகவும் பொறுப்பேற்றவர். 2012 ஆம் ஆண்டில் வரலாற்றுத் தொலைக்காட்சியும், சி.என்.என்- ஐ.பி.என் தொலைக்காட்சியும் நடத்திய வாக்கெடுப்பில் மிகச்சிறந்த இந்தியராகத் தேர்ந்தெடுக்கப்பட்டார். இந்தியாவின் மிகச்சிறந்த உயரிய விருதான 'பாரத ரத்னா' விருது இவரது இறப்புக்குப் பின் 1990இல் இவருக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டது.இந்தியப் புரட்சியின் இரு பெரும் தடைகள் பார்ப்பனீயமும் முதலாளியமும்தான்-அம்பேத்கர்"},{"question":"“பொருப்பிலே பிறந்து தென்னன் புகழிலே கிழந்து சங்கத்து“ – என்ற பாடலடி வருகின்ற நூல் எது?","answer":"வில்லி பாரதம்."},{"question":"Inona ny fomba atao mba tsy handosiran'ny tantely?","answer":"Ny fomba atao mba tsy handosiran'ny tantely. Io fandosirana voajanahary io dia mametraka olana eo amin'ny mpiompy tantely. Ireo famantarana ho an'ny mpiompy fa handeha ireo tantely- rehefa mandrafitra tranon'ny mpanjaka eo amin'ny papiny ny tantely- feno zana-tantely ny tohotra- mimonomonona be ireo lahitantely- tsy ahitana mpiasa intsony eo amin'ilay malalaka kely fanidinanyNy fomba fanakanana ny tantely tsy hamoaka andiany- tsidihana ny tohotra aloha kely sy mandritra ny fotoana isian'ny sakafon-tantelyTorolalana fiompiana tantely amin’ny fomba nohatsarainaRecyclage des apiculteurs relais Boeny – novembre 201814 INSIGHT in development- potehina ny trano-panjaka narafiny- asiana rivotra ny tohotra amin'ny fanabeazana ny fidirana- omena tohotra lehibe ireo tantely- apetraka ara-potoana ny tovana- manao fizarana andian-tantely enti-tanana.Ny fomba fanaovana andian-tantely enti-tànana- Ny andian-tantely enti-tànana dia ataon'ny mpiompy amin'ny alalan'ny tohotra efa nampiasainy.- Izany dia fitsinjarana ny tohotra iray efa hipoka atao hoe tohotra fototra.- Apetraka eo amin'ny toerana misy ilay tohotra fototra ny tohotra vaovao fa ilay tohotra fototrakosa atao eny amin'ny toeran-kafa izany hoe fandrihina ilay tantely;Ny fizarana ny andiany efa tena feno hipoka- ialana ny fanaovana andian-tantely tsy niriana- manome andian-tantely ho an'ny tohotra vaovao- voatery mamorona mpanjaka vaovao ireo tantely amin'izay ary mitahiry solom-panjakaNy andian-tantely enti-tànana azo avy amin'io fizarana io dia ahitana- kadira iray na papina tantely misokatra misy atody sy olitra- kadira iray na 2 na papiny mihidy (tapony)- kadira 2 na papiny misy tahirin-tsakafo, misy vovombony (sakafon'ny mpitaiza) ary misymamintantely- tantely maro be no mipetraka amin'ilay kadra sy papiny nafindra- Ny fizarana tohotra fototra dia manome :• andian-tantely A (voalohany) tsy misy mpanjaka ka voatery mamorona mpanjaka• andian-tantely B (faharoa) efa misy mpanjaka.Toro-lalana :• Apetraka eo amin'ilay toeran'ilay tohotra fototra ilay tohotra A: ny ankamaroan'ireotantely avy miasa avy any ivelany dia mivantana avy hatrany ao amin'io tohotra Aio.• Apetraka lavidavitr'ilay tohotra A ilay tohotra B no tohotra fototra: mamoronaandiany vaovao indray ilay mpanjaka. Hitondrana mamintantely na sakafo aoanatin'ny andro vitsivitsy izy ireo mba ho fanohanana azy.• Azo atao ny mizara ireo andian-tantely eo anelanelan'ny amin'ny 10 ora ka hatramin'ny 2 ora hariva : ny ankamaroan'ireo mpitsetsitra dia miasa ivelan'nytohotra."},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధాలు మరియు తాత్పర్యం రాయండి:ఉ. తమ్ముని గూడి పుణ్య గుణ ధాముఁడు, రాముఁడు వచ్చి మాల్యవం.తమ్మున సైన్య సంఘము ముదంబునఁ గొల్వఁగ నుండి, భూమిపైమిమ్ములఁజూచి రండనుచు మేటి కపీంద్రులఁ బుచ్చి, యందు మొతమ్ముగ మమ్ముఁ గొందఱను దక్షిణ భాగము చూడఁ బంపుచున్.","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్థము :తమ్ముని = సోదరుడైన లక్ష్మణునితోకూడి = కలిసిపుణ్యగుణధాముడు = పుణ్యగుణములకు నిలయమైనరాముడు = శ్రీరాముడువచ్చి = చేరిమాల్యవంతమ్మున = మాల్యవంతము అను పర్వతముపైసైన్య సంఘము = భటుల సమూహంముదంబునన్ = ఆనందంతోకొల్వఁగన్ = సేవిస్తూఉండి = ఉండగాభూమిపై = భూభాగముపైమిమ్ములన్ = మిమ్మల్నిచూచి = వెదకిరండ + అనుచు = రమ్మనిమేటి = వీరులైనకపీంద్రులన్ = వానర శ్రేష్ఠులనుపుచ్చి = పంపిఅందు = ఆ వానరములమొత్తమ్ముగ = సమూహము లోనిమమ్మున్ = మా వంటి వారినికొందఱును = కొందరినిదక్షిణ భాగము = దక్షిణ దిక్కు వెంబడిచూడన్ = వెదకుటకుపంపుచున్ = పంపుతూ (ఇలా పలికాడు)తాత్పర్యము :ఓ సీతాదేవీ ! సోదరుడైన లక్ష్మణునితో కలిసి పుణ్యగుణములు కలిగిన శ్రీరాముడు, మాల్యవంతము అనే పర్వతంపై తనను, సైన్యము సంతోషంతో సేవిస్తూ ఉండగా, నిన్ను ఇక్కడి భూభాగములో వెదికి చూచి రండని, శ్రేష్ఠులైన వానరములలో కొందరిని మావంటి వారిని ఈ దక్షిణ దిక్కు వైపు పంపుతూ ఇలా పలికాడు."},{"question":"Ndiani akatengesa Louisiana kuUSA muna 1803?","answer":"Nharaunda yeLouisiana yakatengeswa kuUnited States neFrance muna 1803. Ichi chikuru chekutengeserana, chinozivikanwa seLouisiana Purchase, chakakurukurwa naNapoleon Bonaparte, panguva iyoyo Mumiriri Wokutanga weFrance, naRobert Livingston, gurukota reAmerica kuFrance. Kutenga kwacho kwakawedzera nekaviri ukuru hweUnited States, kusanganisa nzvimbo yakakura kubva kuRwizi rweMississippi kusvika kuMakomo eRocky. The Louisiana Purchase yakave nemhedzisiro yakakura mukuwedzera nekusimudzira kweUnited States, ichivhura mikana mitsva yekugara nekuongorora kumadokero."},{"question":"सन् २०१४ को नोबेल शान्ति पुरस्कार बिजेता भारतका बाल अधिकारकर्मी एवं सामाजिक अभियन्ता कैलाश सत्यार्थी नेपालको ३ दिनेभ्रमणका क्रममा कहिले काठमाडौं आउनुभएको थियो ?","answer":" वि ।सं २०७१ पुष ४ गते"},{"question":"”Адамды жаратылыш жаратат, бирок аны коом өстүрүп,өнүктүрөт”-деген сөз кимге таандык?а)Тольстой б)Ушинский в)Беменскийг)Доброльюбов","answer":"Тураа жообу:в)Беменский"},{"question":"Kodi wodwala malungo adye chiyani?","answer":"Zakudya zopatsa thanzi, monga chimanga, masamba, zipatso, ndi mkaka, nsomba (za msuzi), nkhuku (ya msuzi, mphodza), shuga, uchi, ndi zina zomwe zimapereka chakudya chokwanira komanso kusunga madzi okwanira ndizomwe zimafunika kwa odwala malungo"},{"question":"السؤال: شكون هي أغنى امرأة فالعالم ؟","answer":"الإجابة: هي ما كاينزي سكوت طليقة جيف بيزوس."},{"question":"ঢাকায় চলাচলের ক্ষেত্রে অ্যাপ-ভিত্তিক মোটরসাইকেলের জনপ্রিয়তা পেয়েছে।মোটরসাইকেল চালকেরা আজ (বৃহস্পতিবার) ঢাকায় সড়ক অবরোধ করে বিক্ষোভ করেছে। এছাড়া বিধি-নিষেধ উপেক্ষা করে অনেকে যাত্রী পরিবহন করছে। রাজধানী ঢাকার অন্তত পাঁচটি জায়গায় - ধানমন্ডি ২৭ নম্বর সড়ক, প্রেসক্লাবের সামনের সড়ক, আগারগাঁও, শাহবাগ এবং বাড্ডায় মোটরসাইকেল চালকরা রাস্তায় দাঁড়িয়ে যানবাহন চলাচলে প্রতিবন্ধকতা সৃষ্টি করেছে।মোটরসাইকেল চালকরা রাস্তায় বিক্ষোভে নামলে শহরজুড়ে তীব্র যানজটের সৃষ্টি হয়। সরকারের সিদ্ধান্তকে অযৌক্তিক বলে বর্ণনা করছেন চালকরা। করোনাভাইরাস ভ্যাকসিন টিকাদানে আপনার দেশের অবস্থান কোথায়?নিজেকে আক্রান্ত মনে হলে কী করবেন, কোথায় যাবেন?একজন মোটরসাইকেল চালক নূরে আলম বলেন, সরকারের বিধি-নিষেধ অনুযায়ী তাদের যাত্রী পরিবহন বন্ধ হলে তারা চরম আর্থিক সংকটে পড়বেন। তিনি প্রশ্ন তোলেন, \\"সব যানবাহন চলতেছে, তাহলে মোটরসাইকেলে যাত্রী পরিবহন করতে অসুবিধা কোথায়?\\"এছাড়া সকাল থেকে হাজার-হাজার অফিস-মুখো মানুষ যানবাহন সংকটের কারণে বিড়ম্বনায় পড়েছে। ঢাকায় চলাচলের জন্য মোটর সাইকেল খুবই জনপ্রিয়।সরকারের নতুন বিধি-নিষেধ অনুযায়ী গণ-পরিবহনে ধারণক্ষমতার অর্ধেক যাত্রী বহন করতে পারবে। ফলে যানবাহন সংকটে পড়েছে হাজারো মানুষ। অনেকে রাস্তায় দাঁড়িয়ে তীব্র ক্ষোভ প্রকাশ করেছে। কর্মক্ষেত্রে যোগ দিতে প্রতিদিন ঢাকার মিরপুর এক নম্বর থেকে আজিমপুর পর্যন্ত যাতায়াত করেন রবিউল ইসলাম।তিনি জানান, পরিবহন সংকটের কারণে অফিসে যাতায়াত করা এখন দুর্বিসহ হয়ে উঠেছে।  বাসে উঠতে না পেরে অফিস-মুখো যাত্রীরা সকালে ঢাকার খিলক্ষেত সড়ক অবরোধ করেছে। এ সময় ঢাকা-ময়মনসিংহ সড়ক বন্ধ হয়ে যায়। পরে পুলিশের হস্তক্ষেপে বিক্ষুব্ধ যাত্রীরা রাস্তা থেকে ছেড়ে যায়।  এদিকে বৃহস্পতিবার সংসদে প্রধানমন্ত্রী শেখ হাসিনা বলেছেন, ভ্যাকসিন নেবার পরে অনেকে ঢিলেঢালা-ভাব দেখানোর কারণে করোনাভাইরাসের সংক্রমণ বেড়েছে। করোনাভাইরাসের সংক্রমণ ঠেকাতে দেশের মানুষের সহযোগিতা চেয়েছেন প্রধানমন্ত্রী শেখ হাসিনা।তিনি বলেন, পরিস্থিতি নিয়ন্ত্রণের জন্য আবারো বিধি-নিষেধ আরোপ করা হচ্ছে এবং এজন্য জনগণের সহযোগিতা প্রয়োজন। দেশের মানুষকে স্বাস্থ্যবিধি মেনে দায়িত্বশীল আচরণের অনুরোধ জানান প্রধানমন্ত্রী শেখ হাসিনা। এই অনুচ্ছেদের জন্য একটি উপযুক্ত শিরোনাম প্রস্তাব করুন |","answer":"করোনা ভাইরাস: সরকারি বিধি-নিষেধের প্রতিবাদে রাইড-শেয়ারিং মোটরসাইকেল চালকরা"},{"question":"Escribe la continuación de este texto : Holly Beatie es una deportista estadounidense que compitió en biatlón. Ganó una medalla de bronce en el Campeonato Mundial de Biatlón de 1984... ","answer":"En la prueba de relevos."},{"question":"Apakah resipi untuk bahulu goreng yang merupakan kuih-muih tradisional Melayu? Tunjukkan langkah-langkah terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan-bahan: 600g tepung gandum (digoreng dan diayak dahulu), 300 g gula halus (boleh kurangkan jika tak mahu manis), 1 sudu jintan manis (disangai dan dikisar halus), 6 biji telur gred A (dipukul), 1 tin kecil minyak sapi (dicairkan), esen vanila opsyenal.Cara-cara:1. Pukul telur sehingga kembang.2. Gaul tepung, gula dan jintan manis dengan sebati.3. Campur telur dan minyak sapi. Uli secara erselang-seli dengan tepung. Uli sebati.4. Perap selama 2 – 3 jam.5. Uli doh sedikit demi sedikit minyak sapi sehingga kurang melekat di tangan dan terbentuk elok.6. Gorengkan.7. Sedia untuk dihidang."},{"question":"スピーカーの音をマイクが拾ってアンプで増幅。この繰り返しからキーンと音が出ることを何という？","answer":"ハウリング（フィードバック）です。"},{"question":"Tamin'ny oviana ny Repoblika fahatelo teto Madagasikara ? ","answer":"1991-2014 ny repoblika faharoa teto Madagasikara "},{"question":"बन्धनानि खलु सन्ति बहूनि प्रेमरज्जुदृढ़बन्धनमन्यत्।दारुभेदनिपुणोSपि षंडध्रिर्निष्क्रियो भवति पङ्कजकोशे ।।","answer":"अनेक प्रकारचे बंध असतात, पण प्रेमाचा मजबूत बंध वेगळाच असतो. लाकडालासुद्धा भोक पाडण्यात प्रवीण असलेला भुंगा कमळाच्या पाकळ्यांत अडकला तर मात्र काही करू शकत नाही."},{"question":"Ukuxabana kwezinsizwa ngasemakhaya ngoKhisimuzi kwenza ukuba impi ingapheleliemakhaya ngoba uxolo lwalungenzekanga. Ziphindela nje izinsizwa emsebenzini,izinhliziyo zibomvu akukhulunyiswana. Kufihlelwene induku emqubeni. Olunyeuhlangothi lwalwehla lwenyuka luthenga izibhamu zomgunyathi ngoba befunaukuziphindiselela ingcabha ingagcini kubona. Akutshelwana uma kukhonaabazohlasela, ngakho-ke abanye babona ngoba sebembozwa impi. Ngalelo langabehlaselwa, uManyoba wayesebenza ebusuku. Wafika ekuseni sekukhona ababesebefile, sekugcwele ezikadalawane emagcekeni ehostela. Uma ebuza ukuthikwenzenjani, bamtshela ngokwenzekile, washaqeka wacishe wawa phansi uvalolokuthi ngabe naye ungomunye mhlawumbe walaba abafile. Kwake kwaba muncuisikhathi eside kunohlevana kubahlali basehostela. Ngenhlanhla nje kwakungabangwaizwe, kwakungamagqubu nje ezinsizweni. Ezinye zezizathu ezamenza wafunaukushiya umsebenzi eGoli ayosebenza ePitoli. EGoli izinsizwa zokuhamba zazivamiseukuhamba ngambili noma ngantathu ngoba zazikhuthuzwa noma zigetshengweotsotsi. Ngesikhathi sabo kwakukhona amaqembu otsotsi anjengoMsomi namanyeayedume ngokubulala, umuntu atholakale edindilizile esefile emgwaqweni. Isikhaliesikhulu sokubulala kuqala, kwakuwummese noma kube untshumentshu. Into embikakhulu eyayenzeka emadolobheni, ukuthola umuntu enqunywe intamo kungaziwaukuthi ubulawe ubani.Lichazani leli gama elibhalwe ngokugqamile kulo musho olandelayo njengobalisetshenzisiwe kulesi siqeshana?","answer":"Izibhamu ezingekho emthethweni."},{"question":"ස්පාඤ්ඤයේ අගනුවර කුමක්ද?","answer":"මැඩ්රිඩ් යනු ස්පාඤ්ඤයේ අගනුවර සහ විශාලතම නගරයයි. එය ආසන්න වශයෙන් මිලියන 3.4 ක ජනගහනයක් සහ අගනගරයේ මිලියන 6.7 ක් පමණ වාසය කරයි. එය යුරෝපීය සංගමයේ (EU) දෙවන විශාලතම නගරය වන අතර, එහි පරිපාලන සීමාවන් තුළ බර්ලිනය පමණක් අභිබවා යයි. යුරෝපා සංගමයේ ඒකකේන්ද්‍රීය නාගරික ප්‍රදේශය දෙවන ස්ථානය වන අතර පැරිස් ඊට පිටුපසින් පමනි. එය භූමි ප්‍රමාණයෙන් 604.3 km2 (වර්ග සැතපුම් 233.3) ආවරණය කරයි.මැඩ්රිඩ් පිහිටා ඇත්තේ මධ්‍යම අයිබීරියානු අර්ධද්වීපයේ Manzanares ගඟේ ය. එය ස්පාඤ්ඤයේ සහ මැඩ්රිඩ්හි අගනුවර වන අතර එය 1561 සිට අඛණ්ඩව පාහේ රටේ අගනුවර වේ. නගරය ආසන්නතම මුහුදු වෙරළේ සිට කිලෝමීටර් 300 (සැතපුම් 190) දුරින් උස් තැනිතලාවක පිහිටා ඇත. Iberian සෘතු විචලනයන් උණුසුම් ගිම්හාන (සහ සිසිල් ශීත) දෙකම සමග විශාල වේ. මහජන පක්ෂයෙන් ජෝස් ලුයිස් මාර්ටිනස් අල්මේදා නගරාධිපති වේ.මැඩ්රිඩ් යනු යුරෝපා සංගමයේ දෙවන විශාලතම නාගරික සමුච්චය වේ. දේශපාලනය, අධ්‍යාපනය සහ විනෝදාස්වාදය, මාධ්‍ය, මාධ්‍ය, මාධ්‍ය, විද්‍යාව, සංස්කෘතිය සහ කලාව කෙරෙහි එහි බලපෑම වඩාත් වැදගත් ගෝලීය නගරවලින් එකක් ලෙස එහි ස්ථානයට දායක වේ. මැඩ්රිඩ් ස්පාඤ්ඤයේ අගනුවර වන අතර අයිබීරියානු අර්ධද්වීපයේ ප්රමුඛතම ආර්ථික මධ්යස්ථානය වේ. Telefonica, Iberia සහ BBVA වැනි ප්‍රධාන ස්පාඤ්ඤ සමාගම් මෙට්‍රොපොලිටන් ප්‍රදේශයේ පිහිටා ඇත. එය රටේ බැංකු මෙහෙයුම්වලින් බහුතරයකට සහ වැඩිම වෙබ් පිටු ජනනය කරන ස්පාඤ්ඤ භාෂාව කතා කරන ප්‍රාග්ධනයට නිවහන වේ."},{"question":"Su’aal: Sheg Kumuu ahaa Safiirkii ugu horeeyey ee uu rasuulka (Nnkh) uu Madiina I diro Si uu u Baro Quraanka?","answer":"Jawaab: Wuxu ahaa wuxu ahaa Muscab Bin Cumeyr (RC)."},{"question":"Sheeg imisa ayee ahayeen tirada cidamada musliminta badar?","answer":"Waxay ahayen tirada cidmada musliminta 313Io 70 gel io labo  faras ."},{"question":" مقدار ولتاژ باتری در خودروهای معمول سواری چند ولت است؟ ","answer":"مقدار ولتاژ باتری در خودروهای معمول سواری ۱۲ ولت است."},{"question":"\\"Баш\\" - устуканы  жөнүндө эмне билесиң ?","answer":"Баш – койдун башы. Ал коноктордун арасынан эң сыйлуусуна тартылат. Башка каржилик же дагы башка жилик кошумчаланат. Башкы устуканды алганына ыраазы болгон конок үйдүн кожоюндарына урмат көрсөтүүнүн белгиси катары бир кесип алып ооз тиет да, калганын эң жаш мейманга же кожоюндун уулуна өткөрүп берет. Ал башты бузат да, этин төмөндөгү эрежелерди сактоо менен отурган конокторго бөлүштүрүп берет: кулакты – атасынын сөзүн угуп жүрүү үчүн кожоюндун уулуна; көздү – тез-тезден көрүшүп тургусу келген кишисине; таңдай жана анын кесимдерин – чебердик менен сайма сая билүүлөрү үчүн кыздарга (таңдайдын үстү саймаланганга окшоп турат). Андан соң баштын этин майдалап кесип, шорпо куюлган идишке салат да, аны калган конокторго айлантып узатат."},{"question":"ทำไมเราถึงมีฤดูกาลต่าง ๆ บนโลก?","answer":"เป็นเพราะแกนโลกเอียง ณ ตอนนี้ โลกเอียงประมาณ 23.5 องศาบนแกนของมันในวงโคจรรอบดวงอาทิตย์ ด้านของโลกที่อยู่ใกล้กับดวงอาทิตย์จะได้รับความร้อนจากดวงอาทิตย์มากขึ้น นั่นคือเหตุผลที่ซีกโลกเหนือเป็นฤดูร้อน ในทางกลับกัน ซีกโลกใต้เป็นฤดูหนาว"},{"question":"දිව්‍යමය දේවාරක්ෂාව යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"දිව්‍යමය දේවාරක්ෂාව යනු දෙවියන් වහන්සේ විශ්වයේ සියළු දේ පිළිබඳව ආණ්ඩු කරන බවය. එනම් දෙවියන් වහන්සේ සියළු දේ තම පාලනය යටතේ සිදුකරන බවයි. මේ යටතට මුලු විශ්වයම සමස්තයක් ලෙස දැක්වීම (ගීතාවලිය 103:19), භෞතික (බාහිර) ලෝකය (මතෙව් 5:45), ජාතීන් අතර සබඳතා (ගීතාවලිය 67:7), මනුෂ්‍ය උපත හා ඉරණම (ගලාති 1:15), මනුෂ්‍ය දියුණුව හා අසමත්වීම (ලූක් 1:52), එමෙන්ම එතුමන්ගේ ජනතාවගේ ආරක්‍ෂාව (ගීතාවලිය 4:8) යනාදිය ඇතුලත් වේ. මෙම මතය විශ්වය පාලනය වන්නේ අහඬු සිදුවීම් හා අවස්ථාවන් යන මතයට විරුද්ධ මතයක් වේ.දිව්‍යමය දේවාරක්ෂාවේ මූලික අරමුණ හා අපේක්ෂාව වන්නේ දේව කැමැත්ත ඉටු කිරීමයි. දෙවියන් වහන්සේ මනුෂ්‍යයාගේ සියලු ක්‍රියාකාරකම් උදෙසා අධිපතිකම් කරන බවත්, ස්වභාව ධර්මයට කිසිදු අයුරකින් බලයක් හෝ ඒ සෑම දෙයක්ම දෙවියන් වහන්සේගේ කැමැත්ත අනුව සිදුවන බවට මෙය සහතික කරයි. මෙය තව දුරටත් විග්‍රහ කලහොත් දෙවියන් වහන්සේ සියළු දේ ගැන පාලනයක් නොමැති නම් එවිට උන් වහන්සේ සර්වබලධාරි තැනැන්වහන්සේ නොවේ. එතුමන් සර්වබලධාරි නොවේ නම් එවිට උන් වහන්සේ දෙවියන් වහන්සේ විය නොහැක. දෙවියන් වහන්සේගේ කැමැත්ත හා පාලනයට පිටත් සිදුවන දේ තිබේද? එය පාලනය කරන්නේ දෙවියන් වහන්සේ නොවේ නම් කවුද? පුද්ගලයෙකුගේ ස්වාධීන කැමැත් හා නිදහස් තීරණ මගින් දේවාරක්ෂාව පාලනයට යටත් කිරීමට හැකිය ආදිය පිළිබඳව ගත් විට අවසානයේ දෙවියන් යනුවෙන් අවසන් නිගමනය වන්නේ කවුද? ඒ අපිමය. කිතුනුවන් හා බයිබලීය දැනුම ඇති ඕනෑම අයෙකුට මෙම තීරණය කිසිසේත්ම පිළිගත නොහැකිය. දෙවියන් වහන්සේ විසින් ලබා දෙන්නාවූ දිව්‍යමය දේවාරක්ෂාව පවතින්නේ පුද්ගලයෙකුගේ නිදහස හෝ කැමැත්ත විනාශ කිරීමට නොව, පුද්ගලයෙකුගේ නිදහස හා කැමැත්ත නිවැරදි ලෙස යොදා ගැනීමට උපකාරි වන අංශයක් ලෙසට දිව්‍යමය දේවාරක්ෂාව ශක්තියක් දෙන බවට අප වටහා ගත යුතු කරුණකි."},{"question":"จีบได้มั้ย?","answer":"ไม่ได้ มีแฟนแล้ว"},{"question":"අමු කැවිලද? මෙහි අමු යනු මොනවද?","answer":"පැරණි ලංකාවේ හේන් වගාවේ දී යොදාගත් ධාන්‍ය වර්ගයක්. අඩියක්, එකහමාරක් පමණ උසට වැඩෙන තෘණ වර්ගයේ ශාකයේ, දුඹුරු පැහැති ඇට ස්වල්පයක් සහිත කරල් හටගනී. ( වී කරල් මෙන් නො වේ )අමු ආහාරයට ගත් කල ඇතැම් විට මත් ගතියක් ඇති වන්නේ ලු. ඒ අනුව ඉහත සඳහන් සාම්ප්‍රදායික යෙදුම විවහාරයට පැමිණ ඇත."},{"question":"O que é um mochilão?","answer":"Um mochilão é uma forma de viagem que consiste em carregar uma mochila com o essencial para se aventurar por diferentes lugares, geralmente com um baixo orçamento e sem um roteiro definido."},{"question":"Tirela elepo ṣubu ni Badagry, lawọn eeyan ba n fi koroba gbọn epo bẹntiroolu","answer":"Bi onikoroba ṣe n gbe e, bẹẹ lawọn to yọ ike lọwọ paapaa n sare lẹlẹlẹ lọ sibi ti mọto tanka epo bẹtiroolu kan ṣubu si lowurọ kutu oni Tusidee yii lagbegbe Igborosun, ni Aso Odo, niluu Badagry l’Ekoo.Ohun ti ALAROYE gbọ ni pe, lojiji ni tanka epo to gbe lita bii ẹgbẹrun mẹtalelọgbọn yii ṣubu lulẹ, ti awọn eeyan si berẹ si gbọn ọn laibikita ijamba ina to le ṣẹlẹ nibẹ.Ọgbẹni Olufẹmi Oke Ọsanyitolu to jẹ ọga agba fun iṣẹlẹ pajawiri l’Ekoo ti sọ pe lojuẹsẹni wọn ti fi iṣẹlẹ ọhun to awọn leti lawọn ti sare debẹ.Bakan naa lo ti bu ẹnu atẹ lu bi awọn eeyan kan ṣe n gbọn epo to n jo danu, o ni ọpọlọpọ igba ni irufẹ iwa bẹẹ ti ṣe ẹmi ọpọ eeyan lofo, ati pe awọn to n gbọn epo to n jo danu yii, bii ẹni pe wọn ko nifẹẹ ara wọn rara ni.Ohun ta a gbọ ni pe, ọkọ tanka agbepo mi-in ti debẹ, ti wọn si ti n fa epo sinu ẹ, bẹẹ lawọn oṣiṣẹ ileeṣẹ to n mojuto awọn iṣẹlẹ pajawiri naa ti duro wamuwamu lati le tete mojuto ijanba to le ṣeeṣi waye."},{"question":"یک مکان تفریحی برای کودکان و یا نوجوانان در تهران معرفی کن.","answer":"یکی از محل های تفریح برای کودکان در شهر تهران، دنیای بولینگ است. البته این محیط بیشتر به درد نوجوانان و افرادی می خورد که برای تفریح خانوادگی به دنبال یک محیط جذاب هستند. کودکان شما می‌توانند در این مجموعه به تفریح بپردازند و از محیط شاد و دلنشین آن نهایت لذت را ببرند. از مهم ترین وسایل بازی این منطقه می توان به ترن هوایی، سینما ۷ بعدی، فایر بال، سیمیلاتور فراری، تایگر بولینگ، اسپیس شاتل، هلو کیتی، مجیک شوتر، تمپل ران و… اشاره کرد. بازی‌هایی مانند فریزبی، ماشین کوبنده، فرمول ۱، ایر هاکی و فوتبال دستی هم از مهم ترین وسایل بازی هستند که برای بزرگ سالان در این مجموعه وجود دارد."},{"question":"Wọn ti ko ọlọpaa kuro lẹyin Fẹmi Fani-Kayọde atawọn olowo-aye kan","answer":"Awọn olowo-aye ati onipo nla bii ọgọta ọmọ orilẹ-ede yii ni ọga ọlọpaa patapata, Muhammed Adamu, ti paṣẹ ki awọn ọlọpaa to n ṣọ wọn kuro lẹyin wọn kia bayii, ki kaluku si pada si ọfiisi rẹ.Ṣaaju asiko yii, nigba ti wahala rogbodiyan SARS n gbona girigiri, ni ikede ọhun ti kọkọ waye pe ki awọn ọlọpaa to n ṣọ awọn olowo atawọn eeyan nla nla mi-in kiri pada si teṣan wọn, iyẹn lọjọ kọkanlelogun, oṣu kẹwaa, ọdun yii.ALAROYE gbọ pe nigba ti ọga ọlọpaa ri i pe wọn ko tẹle aṣẹ ọhun bo ti yẹ lo tun mu un kede orukọ awọn olowo ati ọlọrọ ti wọn n ko awọn ọlọpaa kiri gẹgẹ bii ẹṣọ bayii. Ohun to si sọ ni pe ti a ba ri ọga ọlọpaa ti awọn ọmọ ẹyin ẹ ba ṣi n ṣọ olowo kan kiri, niṣe niru wọn yoo fẹnu fẹra bii abẹbẹ.Lara awọn eeyan pataki ti wọn ti ja ọlọpaa kuro lẹyin wọn bayii ni Fẹmi Fani-Kayọde, minisita feto ọkọ ofurufu tẹlẹ atawọn wọnyi;  akọwe agba fun ijọba apapọ tẹlẹ, Babachir Lawal; Sẹnetọ Lado Yakubu, Yuguda Bashir, Uche Chukwu, Boroface Ajayi, Mutiu Nicholas, Tokunbọ Afikuyọmi, Edozie Madu, Emeka Ofor, David Adesanya, Chris Giwa, Oloye Godwin Ekpo, Pius Akinyẹlurẹ atawọn mi-in.Ni bayii, ọga ọlọpaa Muhammed Adamu ti sọ pe gbogbo awọn ọga ọlọpaa ni ẹka kọọkan ni wọn gbọdọ kan si oun pada wi pe awọn ti ko gbogbo ọlọpaa to n sare tẹle awọn olowo-aye pada si ọfiisi wọn titi ọjọ kẹwaa, oṣu kọkanla yii.Ṣaaju asiko yii ni igbakeji ọga ọlọpaa patapata tẹlẹ lorilẹ-ede yii, Adedayọ Adeoye, to ti fẹyinti lẹnu iṣẹ ti tako aṣa ki awọn ọlọpaa maa tẹle awọn olowo kiri. O ni, awọn to nilo ọlọpaa ko yẹ ko ju Aarẹ, igbakeji ẹ, gomina, igbakeji ẹ, olori ile igbimọ aṣofin agba ati kekere ati adajọ agba lorilẹ ede yii.O ni bi wọn ti ṣe n ṣọ awọn olowo yẹn bii ẹni lo wọn si ibi ti ko yẹ ni, nitori araalu gan an ni wọn lẹtọọ lati maa ṣọ. Bakan naa lo fi kun un pe pupọ ninu awọn olowo yẹn ni wọn lanfaani lati gba ẹṣọ alaabo funra wọn lai lo awọn ọlọpaa ti wọn ko ti i to fun aabo ilu."},{"question":"こんぼう、ボール、リボン、ロープを使う屋内競技といえば何？","answer":"新体操です。"},{"question":"नेपालमा के कस्ता कल्याणकारी गतिविधिहरु सञ्चालित छन् ?","answer":"ध्यान, आयुर्वेद, विश्वास उपचार, पञ्चकर्म, ध्वनि ध्यान, प्राकृतिक तातो पानी,, तीर्थयात्रा आदि नेपालमा सञ्चालन हुने कल्याणकारी गतिविधिहरू हुन्।"},{"question":"Descreva a bandeira da Bulgária.","answer":"A bandeira da Bulgária é composta por três faixas horizontais de cores branca (superior), verde (no meio) e vermelha (inferior)."},{"question":"Wanene Sanata mafi karancin shekaru a Najeriya a 2021?","answer":"Sanata Elisha Abba (an haife shi a Mubi North, Nigeria) ɗan siyasan Najeriya ne. Shi ne Sanata mai wakiltar Adamawa ta Arewa a jihar Adamawa ."},{"question":"सचिन तेंदुलकर को किन-किन पुरस्कारों से सम्मानित किया गया है और उनका महत्व क्या है?","answer":"सचिन तेंदुलकर को उनके असाधारण क्रिकेट करियर के लिए कई प्रतिष्ठित पुरस्कारों से सम्मानित किया गया है। इनमें भारत रत्न, पद्म विभूषण, पद्म श्री, और अर्जुन पुरस्कार शामिल हैं। भारत रत्न से सम्मानित होने वाले वे पहले खिलाड़ी हैं, जो उनके खेल के प्रति असाधारण योगदान को दर्शाता है। ये पुरस्कार उनकी प्रतिभा, समर्पण, और खेल के प्रति उनके योगदान का सम्मान हैं।"},{"question":"Akọbi Awolọwọ, Rẹfurẹndi Tọla Oyediran, ti ku o","answer":"Ọkan lara awọn ọmọ Oloogbe Ọbafẹmi Awolọwọ, Rẹfurẹndi Tọla Oyediran, ti ku o.Oni, Fraide, ọjọ Ẹti, ni oloogbe yii jade laye lẹni ọdun mọkandinlọgọrin. Ohun ti ALAROYE gbọ ni pe, ọjọ kin-in-ni oṣu kejila ọdun yii gan an ni iya agbalagba yii, ẹni ti ṣe akọbi Awolọwọ iba pe ẹni ọgọrin ọdun laye.Titi di asiko to fi jade laye, wọn ni Mama naa ni Alaga fun awọn oludari African Newspapers of Nigeria, iyen ileeṣẹ to n tẹ iwe iroyin Tribune.Ṣaaju ki ọlọjọ too de, wọn ni obinrin Ojiṣẹ Ọlọrun yii ko ṣaisan kankan, paapaa ni gbogbo alẹ ana ko too dagbere faye wi pe o digbooṣe."},{"question":"Cuba jawab teka-teki berikut: Dalam diri kita, anggota badan manakah yang paling manis?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah jari. Ia dikatakan manis kerana kadang-kala kita mempunyai tabiat menjilat jari, terutamanya selepas memegang makanan yang enak."},{"question":"شنو كايتسمى الوليد ديال الفيل؟","answer":"هو : دغفل."},{"question":"Inona avy ireo teknika mandrisika mba hihazonana toe-tsaina tsara mandritra ny fotoan-tsarotra?","answer":"Ny teknika dia ahitana ny firesahana momba ny tena tsara, ny fijerena ny fahombiazana, ny manodidina anao amin'ny olona manohana, ary ny fampiharana fankasitrahana."},{"question":"Est-ce que tu peux me raconter une blague ?","answer":"D'accord, voici une blague :Question: Qu’a dit le requin après avoir mangé le poisson-clown ?Réponse: Ça goûte drôle."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هى سورة المضاجع؟","answer":"الإجابة:  سورة السجدة"},{"question":"በ1977 የእንግሊዝ ብሄራዊ ቡድንን በኃላፊነት ያገለገሉትን አሰልጣኝ ስም ጥቀስ ?","answer":"ሮን ግሪንዉድ"},{"question":"मृत्युंजयाय रुद्राय नीलकण्ठाय शम्भवे ।अमृतेशाय शर्वाय महादेवाय ते नम: ॥वरील संस्कृत श्लोकाचा अर्थ काय आहे ?उत्तर:","answer":"अर्थ : मृत्युंजय (मृत्यूवर ज्याने विजय मिळवलेला आहे असा), रुद्र (असुरांना ज्याची भीती वाटते असा), नीलकण्ठ (ज्याचा कंठ निळा आहे असा), शम्भु (कल्याणकारी), अमृतेश (अमृताचा स्वामी), शर्व (मंगलमय), महादेव (देवांमध्ये श्रेष्ठ) अशी विविध नावे असलेल्या भगवान शंकराला मी वंदन करतो."},{"question":"ከጣና ሐይቅ በዓመት ምን ያል የዓሳ ምርት ይገኛል?","answer":"1,454 ቶን"},{"question":"aiza no misy ny \\"Tour Eiffel\\"?","answer":"any Paris no misy ny \\"Tour Eiffel\\""},{"question":"Jawablah soalan yang rumit ini: Warna bulu apakah adalah sama antara anjing Colorpoint Shorthair dan Siam?","answer":"Warna titik"},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Saya biasanya di atas, duduk di sebelah kiri, kanan atau tengah, bercorak dan boleh menutup, siapa saya?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah topi."},{"question":" من بين المآسي اللي وقعات للمسلمين فحياه الرسول صلى عليه وسلم واحد المأساه وقعات فشهر صفر سنه 4ه تقتل فيها حوالي 70 من الصحابه, شنو هي هذا المأساه؟","answer":"مآساة بئر معونة"},{"question":"يعني أيه نوع فى علم الأحياء؟ قول باختصار","answer":"سؤال مهم و يسعدنى أجاوبك عليه.باختصار كده، النوع فى علم الاحياء هوا واحد من وحدات التصنيف الحيوى الاساسيه, و هوا مرتبه تصنيفيه اساسيه فى علم التصنيف. فى الغالب بيعرف النوع انه مجموعه من الكائنات الحيه اللى قادرة على التزاوج و انتاج نسل خصب. و مع ان التعريف داه كافى فى كتير من الحالات, بس فيه صعوبه فى تعريف مفهوم النوع, و دا معروف بمشكلة النوع, بتستخدم تدابير تانيه مختلفه لتعريفه, زى تشابه الدنا, المورفولوجيا, او النيش البيئي.أتمنى أكون جاوبت على سؤالك. فى حاجة تانية أقدر أساعدك بيها؟"},{"question":"A wane birni ne manyan dala-dalar firamid na Masar suke?","answer":"A babban birnin Alƙahira."},{"question":"‘மனிதனுடைய மனத்தில் உணர்ச்சிகளை எழுப்பி அழகையும் இன்பத்தையும் அளிக்கின்ற பண்பு அழகுக்கலைகளுக்கே உண்டு ’ என்று கூறியவர் ?","answer":"விடை – மயிலை . சீனி . வேங்கடசாமி"},{"question":"س254- في أي مدينة يوجد المسجد النبوي الشريف ؟","answer":"ج254- في المدينة المنورة"},{"question":"અહીં મીરાંબાઈ રચિત કૃતિ  \\"અબ મોહે ક્યું તરસાવૌ\\" ના શરૂઆતની પંકતિઓ આપેલ છે:\\"તુમરે કારણ સબ સુખ છોડ્યા,અબ મોહે ક્યું તરસાવૌ હૌ.\\"આ કૃતિની આગળની પંકતિઓ લખો.","answer":"તુમરે કારણ સબ સુખ છોડ્યા,અબ મોહે ક્યું તરસાવૌ હૌ. વિરહ-વ્યથા લાગી ઉર અંતર,સો તુમ આય બુઝાવૌ હૌ. અબ છોડત નહીં બનહિ પ્રભુજી,હંસકર તુરત બુલાવૌ હૌ. મીરાં દાસી જનમ-જનમ કી,અંગ સે અંગ લગાવૌ હૌ."},{"question":"Iza no mpanjaka nitondra an'i Madagasikara ny taona 1861 hatramin'ny taona 1863?","answer":"I Radama II no mpanjaka nitondra an'i Madagasikara ny taona 1861 hatramin'ny taona 1863. Izy io no mpanjaka nanjaka tamin'ny fe-potoana fohy indrina teto Madagasikara , na manjaka tapany noho izy nitondra nandritra ny roa taona monja raha mihoatra ny mpanjaka rehetra izay efa nitondra teo alohany."},{"question":"\\"Акта чилен, чилен куш,Акырегин таңган куш.Көктө чилен, чилен куш,Көкүрөгүн таңган куш\\".-табышмактын жандырмагы кандай?","answer":"Табышмактын жандырмагы -\\"БЕШИКТЕГИ БАЛА\\"."},{"question":"Những đối tượng nào không được tham quan tháp nghiêng?","answer":"Trẻ em dưới 8 tuổi không được tham quan tháp, còn dưới 18 tuổi cần đi kèm với một người lớn. Mỗi lần tham quan, khách du lịch phải chia thành từng nhóm 30 người. Lối vào ở tầng cuối cùng khá hẹp, có thể gây khó khăn với những người cao lớn.Chuyến tham quan kéo dài 30 phút và không có thời gian nghỉ. Các hướng dẫn viên đưa ra bài tập thể dục khởi động nhằm chuẩn bị cho du khách để có thể leo liên tục gần 300 bậc thang nghiêng mà không bị chóng mặt."},{"question":"Ndàx mbind mii jub na?Axakay! Ku def jëf ju bon ba ay ñaawtéefam mëdd ko, ñooña ñooy ñay dëkk Safara te dañu fay béel.","answer":"Déedet; jubul cocc ba coset. Mbeqi ma a ngii:Ahãkày! Ku def jëf ju bon ba ay ñaawtéefam mëdd ko, ñooña ñoo'y ña'y dëkk Safara te da ñu fa'y béel."},{"question":"හෝර්ටන්තැන්න ජාතික උද්‍යානය ක්‍රියාකාරී වළාකුළු වනාන්තර ගැන කියන්න.","answer":"ලොවේ ඉපැරණිම වනාන්තරවලින් පැවත එයි. වසර මිලියන ගණනාවකට ඉහතදී ඇන්ටාර්ක්ටික් මහද්වීපය සමගින් ශ්‍රී ලංකා මහද්වීපය බැඳී පැවතුණු අතර මහාද්වීප තල පාවීමේ ප්‍රථිපලයක් ලෙස මෙම භූමිය සමකයෙන් උතුරට ගමන් කර ආසියාව හා නොගැටී පැවතියේය. එබැවින් ශීත කලාපයෙන් රැගෙන ආ දේශගුණය කඳු මුදුන්වල අදටත් නොනැසී පැවතීම තුළින් අතීතය හා පවතින දිගු සම්බන්ධතාවය පැහැදිලි කරයි. හෝර්ටන් තැන්නේ වළාකුළු වනාන්තර ලොවේ ඉපැරණිම වනාන්තරවලින් පැවත එයි.(වනජීවී සංරක්ෂණ දෙපාර්තමේන්තුව, හෝර්ටන්තැන්න කාර්‍යාලය)හෝර්ටන්තැන්න ජාතික උද්‍යානය ක්‍රියාකාරී වළාකුළු වනාන්තර හෝර්ටන් තැන්න ක්‍රියාකාරී වළාකුළු දැකගැනීමට ඇති සුදුසුම ස්ථානයයි. කඳුමුදුන්වල පහළ මට්ටමේ සිට ඉහළ නගින ජලවාෂ්ප රැගත් උණුසුම් වාතය කඳුමුදුන්වල ගැටී ඝනීභවනය වී වළාකුළු බවට පත්වන අතර වළාකුළු සවස් කාලයේදී කඳු ආවරණය කර ගැනීමෙන් වැස්ස ඇතිවේ.ලෝකාන්තයේදී මෙසේ ඝනීභවනය වී ජලවාෂ්ප, ජලබිංදු වශයෙන් ශාක දිගේ වෑස්සීම සිදුවෙයි. මෙම ජල බිංදු වෙනත් ශාක මත වැඩෙන ශාක වර්ධනයට උදව් දෙන අතර මෙවැනි ශාක පිහිටීම හේතුවෙන් මෙම ශාක විසින් ජලය රදවා ගන්නා බැවින් මෙම ජලය පසට ලබා දීමෙන් ජනාවාස පෝෂණය කිරීමට වැදගත් වන ගංගා නිර්මාණය කරයි."},{"question":"Ƙirƙiri labari dan wannan kundun labarin mai zuwa: Muhamman abubuwa da suka faru a Najeriya a wannan makon na 17 ga watan Satumba 2022.","answer":"Yayin da ake shirin shiga sabon mako, bari mu yi waiwaye kan wasu abubuwa masu muhimmanci da suka faru a Najeriya a makon da ya gabata daga ranar Lahadi 12 ga watan Satumba zuwa Asabar 18 ga watan na Satumba. Jirgin yaƙin rundunar sojin Najeriya ya yi aman wuta kan fararen hula Wani jirgin yaƙin rundunar sojin Najeriya ya yi aman wuta a yankin ƙauyen Buhari da ke ƙaramar hukumar Yunusari a jihar Yobe da safiyar Laraba, 15 ga watan Satumba kuma ya yi sanadin mutuwar fararen hula da dama. Al'ummar garin sun shaida wa BBC cewa sun wayi gari ne da ganin jiragen yaƙi har uku suna shawagi a sararin samaniyar garin nasu. Daga bisani ɗaya daga cikin jiragen ya yi aman wuta kan wani ɓangaren garin, kamar yadda wasu da suka shaida lamarin suka bayyana wa BBC. Ɓullar wannan labarin ke da wuya, rundunar sojin Najeriya ta musanta aukuwar lamarin kuma ta ce ba hannunta a ciki. Sai dai bayan kwana guda rundunar ta fitar da wata sanarwa inda ta ce bisa kuskure ne jirgin sojinta ya kai hari tare da kashe fararen hula a garin na Buhari da ke karamar hukumar Yunusari a jihar Yobe. Sanarwar mai dauke da sa hannun daraktan yada labaran rundunar sojin saman Air Commodore Edward Gabkwet, ta ce jiragen sojin na shawagi ne yankin Kogin Kamadougou Yobe don tattara bayanan sirri kan ayyukan kungiyoyin Boko Hraam da ISWAP. Shaidu sun ce harin jirgin saman na ranar Laraba ya yi sanadin kashe aƙalla mutum goma, baya ga gommai da suka jikkata cikinsu har da mata da ƙananan yara. Rundunar ta ce a kafa wani kwamitin bincike kan abin da ya haddasa lamarin. Jiri ya ɗebi Shugaban hukumar EFCC Abdulrasheed Bawa a taro Ranar Alhamis 16 ga watan Satumba yayin gabatar da jawabi a wani taron Ranar Shaida a Najeriya, jiri ya ɗebi shugaban hukumar EFCC Abdulrasheed Bawa. Abdulrasheed Bawa na tsaka da yin jawabin nasa ne a fadar shugaban Najeriya sai ya dakata da yin magana kuma ya fara yamutsa fuska sannan ya sa tafin hannunsa ya riƙa shafa fuskar tasa. Ya ce \\"ina tunanin zan dakata haka nan, na gode muku ƙwarai\\" sannan ya sauka daga kan dandamali ya nufi kujerarsa, inda wasu manyan jami'an gwamnati ciki har da ministan sadarwa Farfesa Isa Ali Pantami suka tarbe shi kuma suka rirriƙe shi zuwa kujerar tasa. Zamansa a kujerar ke da wuya, sai ɗaya daga cikin jami'an ya kwantar da shi a kan kujerar yayin da shi kuma Abdulrasheed Bawa ya ci gaba da dafe kansa. An fitar da shugaban EFCC ɗin daga ɗakin da ake gudanar da taron kuma daga baya Farfesa Pantami ya sanar da cewa Abdulrasheed ya samu sauƙi. Haka kuma, Hukumar EFCC ta fitar da sanarwa a ranar inda ta ce shugaban nata na cikin ƙoshin lafiya kuma ya koma bakin aikinsa. FemiFani-Kayode ya sauya sheƙa zuwa jam'iyyar APC Tsohon ministan jiragen sama a Najeriya kuma babban mai sukar gwamnatin Shugaban Muhammadu Buhari, Femi Fani-Kayode ya sauya sheƙa daga babbar jam'iyyar hamayya ta PDP zuwa jam'iyya mai mulki ta APC ranar Alhamis 16 ga watan Satumba. Dama dai an daɗe ana raɗe raɗin cewa ministan zai koma APC daga jam'iyyar da ya jima yana kare wa faɗa musamman a shafukan sada zumunta wato PDP, kuma tsohon ministan ya sha musanta wannan jita-jita. Shugaba Muhammadu Buhari da Shugaban jam'iyyar APC kuma gwamnan jihar Yobe, Gwamna Mai Mala Buni ne suka tarbe shi a fadar shugaban kasa. Femi Fani-Kayode ya ce ya sauya sheƙar ne saboda yana ganin hakan ne mafi dacewa a dai-dai wannan lokacin kuma yana da burin taimaka wa Shugaba Buhari don ciyar da Najeriya gaba. Lauyoyin Sheikh Abduljabbar sun janye daga wakiltarsa, asibitin ƙwaƙwalwa na Dawanau ya ce malamin lafiyarsa ƙalau A ci gaba da zaman sauraren ƙarar malamin da ake yi, duka lauyoyin Sheikh Abduljabbar ba su halarci zaman kotun ba na ranar Alhamis 16 ga watan Satumba. Wakilin BBC da ya halarci zaman kotun ya ce lauyan Abduljabbar ɗaya ne ya je kotun, wato Barista Haruna Magashi kuma take ya ce ya janye daga wakiltar malamin. Ya kuma ce \\"Sauran lauyoyin su ma sun janye daga kare Abduljabbar shi ya sa dukkansu babu wanda ya halarci zaman kotun. Haka kuma, asibitin masu fama da matsalar kwakwalwa na Dawanau da ke jihar Kano a arewacin Najeriya ya ce Abduljabbar Kabara ba shi da matsalar kwakwalwa. Sai dai asibitin ya ce an taɓa kwantar da shi a asibitin tsawon kwana huɗu lokacin da ya taɓa yin rikici da ɗanuwansa amma ba a yi masa gwaji ba kuma ba a ba shi magani ba. Dama dai a ranar 2 ga watan Satumbar da muke ciki ne wata Kotun Musuluncin da ke shari'ar Malamin ta umarci a yi masa gwajin kwakwalwa da kunne a wani zaman ci gaban shari'ar da aka yi. Kotu ta bayar da umarnin ne bayan  ya gaza amsa tambayoyin da alƙalin kotun Mai Shari'a Sarki Ibrahim Yola ya yi masa ranar 2 ga watan. Wata kotu ta umarci Najeriya ta biya Sunday Igboho Naira biliyan 20 Wata kotu a jihar Oyo ta umarci gwamnatin tarayya ta biya jagoran ƴan awaren Yarabawa, Sunday Igboho Naira biliyan 20 ranar Juma'a 17 ga watan Satumba. Babbar kotun ta ce kuɗin diyya ne bisa lalata masa gida da gwamnatin tarayya ta yi a lokacin da jami'an tsaro su ke nemansa ruwa a jallo. Kotun ta ɗauki matakin ne bayan da Sunday Igboho ya shigar da ƙarar hukumar bincike na farin kaya da gwamnatin tarayya inda ya buƙaci su biya shi diyyar Naira biliyan 500 kan lalata masa gida a lokacin wani samame. Ranar 1 ga watan Yulin 2021 ne jami'an tsaro suka kai samame gidan Sunday Igboho kuma suka kama mutane da dama."},{"question":"請回答這個問題：在數學中，什麼是微分幾何學？","answer":"答案：微分幾何學是研究曲線、曲面和高維流形等幾何對象的性質和變化的數學學科，利用微分和積分等工具分析幾何形狀的特徵。"},{"question":"Cé hé James Collins? ","answer":"Polaiteoir Éireannach ab ea James Collins (30 Deireadh Fómhair 1900 – 1 Meán Fómhair 1967). Bhí sé ina bhall d'Fhianna Fáil. Rugadh sé ar an 30 Deireadh Fómhair 1990. Fuair sé bás ar an 1 Meán Fómhair 1967. Bhí sé 66 bliana d'aois. "},{"question":"Como é feita a água com gás?","answer":"Existem duas formas de gaseificar a água para obter água com gás, a forma natural e a forma artificial:Gaseificação Natural: O próprio reservatório de água subterrâneo libera minerais e o calor agrega vapores e gases. A água aquecida fica leve e acaba subindo, onde é envasada para comercialização e consumo.Gaseificação Artificial: É o processo mais usado no Brasil e nos países que produzem água mineral. A água é retirada da fonte e armazenada em reservatórios de aço inox. Neste ambiente a água passa por um processo chamado desairador, onde se tira todo o oxigênio de sua composição e o gás carbônico é acrescentado no lugar, deixando a água gaseificada para consumo."},{"question":"问题：印度菜中的咖喱是什么？","answer":"答案：咖喱是印度菜的重要调味料，由多种香料混合而成。印度咖喱以其丰富的口味和多样的风味而闻名，常与肉类、蔬菜或豆类搭配烹制。"},{"question":"O ma ṣe o, ile-ẹjọ sọ ọkọ, iyawo ati iyaayawo sẹwọn ọgọta ọdun l’Ekiti","answer":"Boya bi wọn ba mọ pe ibi tọrọ awọn maa ja si nile-ẹjọ ree, boya wọn iba ti ma lọwọ ninu iwa jibiti ti wọn lu yii, ṣugbọn abamọ ki i ṣaaju ọrọ, tori ile-ẹjọ giga ipinlẹ Ekiti kan ti paṣẹ pe ki Ọgbẹni Ebenezer Adeolu Alongẹ, iyawo  ẹ, Isakunle Ọlamide Oyinlọla, ati iya iyawo ẹ, Abilekọ Isakunle Eunice Moradekẹ, lọọ fẹwọn ọgọta ọdun jura.Gẹgẹ bi Alukoro ajọ EFCC, Ọgbẹni Wilson Uwajurẹn, ṣe wi, o ni ẹsun mejila ọtọọtọ ni ajọ naa ka sawọn afurasi ọdaran naa lẹsẹ nile-ejọ giga ipinlẹ Ekiti to fikalẹ siluu Ado-Ekiti, awọn si ti wa lẹnu ẹjọ naa lati ọdun mẹta sẹyin ki idajọ too ṣẹṣẹ waye lori ẹ lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee yii.O ṣalaye pe iṣẹ awọn to n gbowo tabi sanwo fun kọsitọma lori kanta, tawọn eleebo n pe ni kaṣia (cashier) ni Ebenezer n ṣe ni ọkan lara awọn banki to lookọ nilẹ wa, ṣugbọn ti wọn forukọ bo laṣiiri.Ohun to ṣẹlẹ gẹgẹ bo ṣe wi ni pe, lọjọ kẹẹẹdogun, oṣu keji, ọdun 2018, Ebenezer Alongẹ gba miliọnu mejilelọgọta o le irinwo naira (#62,400,000) wọle latọdọ kọsitọma kan, ṣugbọn kaka ko kowo naa sinu akaunti kọsitọma ọhun, ko ṣe bẹẹ, ọtọ ni ibi to dari owo si.Nigba ti kọsitọma reti titi, ti ko ri ẹri pe owo ti wọle sakaunti oun niyẹn ba lọọ fẹjọ sun ni banki, o si ko awọn iwe ẹri to fihan pe loootọ loun sanwo wọle lọjọ naa dani.Banki lo fọrọ ọhun to ajọ Economic and Financial Crimes Commission (EFCC) ẹka ti Ibadan leti, pe ki wọn waa ba awọn tanna wodi iṣẹlẹ ọhun, lọgan si ni iwadii bẹrẹ.Iwadii ọhun lo tu aṣiri pe Alongẹ lo gbowo lọwọ kọsitọma loootọ, o si buwọ lu u pe oun gbowo, iwadii tun fihan pe niṣe lo dari ele ori owo naa tiye rẹ n lọ si miliọnu mọkanlelogun naira (#21 million) sinu akaunti iyawo rẹ, Ọlamide.Lẹyin eyi lo tun dọgbọn tọju awọn owo to gba lọwọ awọn kọsitọma mi-in sinu akaunti iya-iyawo rẹ, Eunice Moradekẹ.Miliọnu mọkanlelogun lowo olowo ti wọn lawọn mẹtẹẹta fi ṣara rindin, wọn lọkunrin naa ti kọle ringindin siluu Ado-Ekiti lara owo ọhun.Agbẹjọro fun ijọba, Ọgbẹni Abdulrasheed Lanre Suleiman, atawọn lọọya mi-in ti wọn ṣoju fun EFCC fidi ẹ mulẹ pe loootọ niṣẹlẹ naa waye, ati pe ko ṣeeṣi, niṣe lawọn afurasi mẹtẹẹta naa diidi lu awọn kọsitọma banki ọhun ni jibiti. Wọn pe ẹlẹrii meji lati ta ko awọn afurasi ọdaran naa, wọn si ko ọpọ ẹsibiiti da silẹ pẹlu.Lara ẹsun mejila ti wọn fi kan awọn afurasi naa ni pe wọn lu jibiti, wọn jale, wọn feru gba ohun ti ki i ṣe tiwọn, wọn si tun gbimọ-pọ lati huwa buruku. Wọn lawọn ẹsun wọnyi ta ko isọri okoodinnirinwo ati mẹwaa (390) apa kẹsan-an iwe ofin iwa ọdaran tọdun 2012 ti ipinlẹ Ekiti n lo.Nigba to n gbe idajọ rẹ kalẹ, Onidaajọ Adekanye Ogunmoye sọ pe olupẹjọ ti fi ẹri to pọ to han, ko si ruju rara pe loootọ lawọn olujẹjọ naa huwa buruku ọhun. O lawọn mẹtẹẹta nile-ẹjọ yii da lẹbi awọn ẹsun mejila ti wọn fi kan wọn.Adajọ Ogunmoye paṣẹ pe ki ọkọọkan wọn lọọ faṣọ penpe roko ọba lẹwọn fun ọdun marun-un marun-un lori ẹsun kọọkan, eyi ti aropọ rẹ jẹ ọgọta ọdun ẹni kọọkan wọn, bo tilẹ jẹ pe, bo ṣe wi, wọn maa ṣẹwọn ọdun marun-un marun-un naa papọ ni, ki wọn si bẹrẹ si i ka a fun wọn latọdun 2018 ti wọn ti wa lakolo awọn agbofinro, o si tun paṣẹ pe ki wọn ta ile ti Alongẹ kọ, atawọn dukia mi-in to jọju, ki wọn fi di gbese jibiti to lu.O ni eyi maa jẹ arikọgbọn fawọn mi-in ti wọn ba fẹẹ daṣa palapala bii eyi."},{"question":"Is the tweet below expressing a positive, negative, or neutral sentiment?@user Ana wulaqanci a duniya wlh 😂😂","answer":"The tweet is expressed: neutral"},{"question":"Complete a frase: \\"No campo da educação, a aprendizagem online...\\"","answer":"No campo da educação, a aprendizagem online está revolucionando a forma como as pessoas adquirem conhecimento e habilidades."},{"question":"Συμπλήρωσε αυτήν την πρόταση. \\"Ο Ησίοδος είναι ένας από τους δύο μεγάλους επικούς ποιητές της αρχαίας\\"","answer":"Απάντηση: \\"Ελλάδας\\""},{"question":"Qu'est-ce que les géologues font?","answer":"Les géologues sont des scientifiques qui étudient l'histoire de la planète Terre. Ils se posent beaucoup de questions sur la formation et l'évolution des roches au fil du temps."},{"question":"Apakah air celup?","answer":"Air berwarna untuk mewarnakan sesuatu"},{"question":"قاہرہ (انگریزی: Cairo) (تلفظ: /ˈkaɪroʊ/ KY-roh; عربی: القاهرة، تلفظ [ælqɑ(ː)ˈheɾɑ]) مصر کا دار الحکومت ، افریقہ، عرب دنیا اور مشرق وسطیٰ میں سب سے بڑا شہری مجموعہ ہے۔ قاہرہ کبری میٹروپولیٹن علاقہ، جس کی آبادی 21.9 ملین ہے، [3] آبادی کے لحاظ سے دنیا کا بارہواں بڑا میگا شہر ہے۔ قاہرہ کا تعلق قدیم مصر سے ہے، کیونکہ اہرامات جیزہ اور قدیم شہر ممفس اور عين شمس اس کے جغرافیائی علاقے میں واقع ہیں۔ نیل ڈیلٹا کے قریب واقع، [4][5] شہر سب سے پہلے فسطاط کے طور پر آباد ہوا، ایک بستی جس کی بنیاد مسلمانوں کی فتح مصر کے بعد 640ء میں ایک موجودہ قدیم رومی قلعے، بابلیون کے ساتھ رکھی گئی تھی۔ دولت فاطمیہ کے تحت 969ء میں قریب ہی ایک نئے شہر القاہرہ کی بنیاد رکھی گئی۔ اس نے بعد میں ایوبی سلطنت اور سلطنت مملوک (مصر) ادوار (بارہویں-سولہویں صدی) کے دوران میں فسطاط کو مرکزی شہری مرکز کے طور پر پیچھے چھوڑ دیا۔[6] قاہرہ طویل عرصے سے اس خطے کی سیاسی اور ثقافتی زندگی کا مرکز رہا ہے، اور اسلامی فن تعمیر کی پیش رفت کی وجہ سے اسے \\"ہزار میناروں کا شہر\\" کا عنوان دیا گیا ہے۔ قاہرہ کے تاریخی مرکز (قاہرہ المعز) کو 1979ء میں یونیسکو عالمی ثقافتی ورثہ کا درجہ دیا گیا۔ [7] عالمگیریت اور عالمی شہر تحقیق نیٹ ورک کے مطابق قاہرہ کو \\"بیٹا +\\" درجہ بندی کے ساتھ عالمی شہر سمجھا جاتا ہے۔ [8]آج، قاہرہ میں عرب دنیا کی سب سے قدیم اور سب سے بڑی سنیما اور موسیقی کی صنعت ہے، نیز دنیا کا دوسرا قدیم ترین اعلیٰ تعلیم کا ادارہ، جامعہ الازہر بھی یہیں واقع ہے۔ بہت سے بین الاقوامی میڈیا، کاروباری اداروں اور تنظیموں کے علاقائی ہیڈ کوارٹر شہر میں ہیں۔ عرب لیگ کا صدر دفتر قاہرہ میں اپنے زیادہ تر وجود میں رہا ہے۔453 مربع کلومیٹر (175 مربع میل) پر پھیلا ہوا 10 ملین[9] سے زیادہ آبادی کے ساتھ، قاہرہ مصر کا سب سے بڑا شہر ہے۔ مزید 9.5 ملین باشندے شہر کے قریب رہتے ہیں۔ قاہرہ، بہت سے دوسرے شہروں کی طرح، آلودگی اور ٹریفک کی اعلیٰ سطح کے مسائل کا شکار ہے۔ قاہرہ میٹرو، جو 1987ء میں کھولی گئی، افریقہ کا سب سے پرانا میٹرو نظام ہے، [10][11] اور اس کا شمار دنیا کے پندرہ مصروف ترین نظاموں میں ہوتا ہے، جس میں سالانہ 1 بلین[12] مسافروں کی سواری ہوتی ہے۔ قاہرہ کی معیشت 2005ء میں مشرق وسطیٰ میں پہلے نمبر پر تھی، [13] اور فارن پالیسی (رسالہ) کے 2010ء گلوبل سٹیز انڈیکس میں عالمی سطح پر 43 ویں نمبر پر ہے۔[14]اشتقاقیاتخلیفہ معز لدین اللہ کے دور کا ایک سکہمصری اکثر قاہرہ کو مصری عربی، یں مصر (کلمہ نویسی Maṣr (بین الاقوامی اصواتی ابجدیہ: [mɑsˤɾ]; مَصر) کہتے ہیں، جو ملک کے لیے شہر کی اہمیت پر زور دیتے ہیں۔ [15][16] اس کا رسمی نام القاہرہ (القاهرة) کا مطلب ہے 'فتح کرنے والا' یا 'قاتح، اس حقیقت کی وجہ سے کہ سیارہ مریخ، نجم القاہر (النجم القاہر، 'فتح کرنے والا ستارہ')، اس وقت عروج پر تھا جب شہر کی بنیاد رکھی گئی تھی۔[17] ممکنہ طور پر دولت فاطمیہ کے خلیفہ معز لدین اللہ کی آمد کے حوالے سے بھی جو 973ء میں فاطمیوں کے پرانے دار الحکومت مہدیہ (شہر) سے قاہرہ پہنچے تھے۔ قدیم شہر عين شمس کا مقام عين شمس (قاہرہ) (عربی زبان: عين شمس، 'سورج کی آنکھ') قاہرہ کا مضافاتی علاقہ ہے۔شہر کے چند قبطی نام ہیں۔ Tikešrōmi (قبطی: Ϯⲕⲉϣⲣⲱⲙⲓ موخر قبطی: [di.kɑʃˈɾoːmi]) 1211 کی عبارت (The Martyrdom of John of Phanijoit) میں تصدیق شدہ ہے اور یا تو ایک کالک ہے جس کا مطلب ہے 'مرد توڑنے والا' (Ϯ-، 'the'، ⲕⲁϣ-، 'to break'، and ⲣⲱⲙⲓ، 'man')، عربی القاہرہ کے مشابہ۔","answer":"قاہرہ مصر کا دارالحکومت اور افریقہ، عرب دنیا اور مشرق وسطیٰ کا سب سے بڑا شہری علاقہ ہے۔ یہ قدیم مصر کے ساتھ اپنی وابستگی کے لئے جانا جاتا ہے اور مشہور نشانیوں کا گھر ہے جیسے اہرام گیزا۔ اس شہر کی آبادی 21.9 ملین ہے اور اسے عالمی شہر سمجھا جاتا ہے۔ اس کی ایک بھرپور تاریخ ہے اور یہ صدیوں سے خطے میں سیاسی اور ثقافتی زندگی کا مرکز رہا ہے۔ قاہرہ کے تاریخی مرکز کو یونیسکو کے عالمی ثقافتی ورثے کے طور پر نامزد کیا گیا ہے۔قاہرہ عرب دنیا کی سب سے قدیم اور سب سے بڑی فلم اور موسیقی کی صنعت کے لیے جانا جاتا ہے۔ یہ الازہر یونیورسٹی کا گھر بھی ہے، جو دنیا کی دوسری قدیم ترین یونیورسٹی ہے۔ مزید برآں، بہت سے بین الاقوامی میڈیا، کاروبار، اور تنظیموں کے قاہرہ میں اپنے علاقائی دفاتر ہیں۔ عرب لیگ کافی عرصے سے شہر میں مقیم ہے۔قاہرہ مصر کا سب سے بڑا شہر ہے جس کی آبادی 10 ملین سے زیادہ ہے اور اس کے آس پاس مزید 9.5 ملین رہتے ہیں۔ اسے آلودگی اور ٹریفک کے مسائل کا سامنا ہے۔ قاہرہ میٹرو، جو 1987 میں قائم کی گئی تھی، افریقہ کا سب سے پرانا میٹرو سسٹم ہے اور دنیا کے مصروف ترین نظاموں میں سے ایک ہے، جو سالانہ 1 بلین سے زیادہ مسافروں کی خدمت کرتا ہے۔ 2005 میں، قاہرہ کی معیشت مشرق وسطیٰ میں سرفہرست تھی، اور 2010 کے گلوبل سٹیز انڈیکس میں اسے عالمی سطح پر 43 ویں نمبر پر رکھا گیا تھا۔مشتقات مالیاتی آلات ہیں جو اپنی قیمت کسی بنیادی اثاثہ یا بینچ مارک سے اخذ کرتے ہیں۔ وہ عام طور پر مالیاتی منڈیوں میں ہیجنگ یا قیاس آرائی کے مقاصد کے لیے استعمال ہوتے ہیں۔مصر کے دارالحکومت قاہرہ کو اکثر مصری عربی میں مصر کہا جاتا ہے، ملک کے لیے اس کی اہمیت پر زور دیا جاتا ہے۔ اس کا سرکاری نام، القاہرہ، کا مطلب ہے 'فاتح' اور اس کا تعلق سیارہ مریخ سے ہے۔ اس نام کا تعلق 973 میں فاطمی خلیفہ معیز الدین اللہ کی آمد سے بھی ہو سکتا ہے۔ قاہرہ کا نواحی علاقہ عین شمس قدیم شہر عین شمس کے مقام پر واقع ہے۔شہر کے متعدد قبطی نام ہیں، جن میں سے ایک Tikešrōmi ہے۔ اس نام کا تذکرہ 1211 کے ایک متن میں کیا گیا ہے جسے The Martyrdom of John of Phanijoit کہا جاتا ہے۔ Tikešrōmi کی تشریح عربی اصطلاح القائرہ کی طرح 'مرد توڑنے والا' کے طور پر کی جا سکتی ہے۔"},{"question":"இந்தியாவிற்கு எந்த திசையில் வங்காள விரிகுடா அமைந்துள்ளது?","answer":"வங்காள விரிகுடா இந்தியாவின் கிழக்கே அமைந்துள்ளது, அரபிக் கடல் அதன் மேற்கில் அமைந்துள்ளது. நாடு மத்திய ஆசியாவிலிருந்து வடக்கே இமயமலையால் பிரிக்கப்பட்டு தெற்கே இந்தியப் பெருங்கடலால் சூழப்பட்டுள்ளது.வங்காள விரிகுடா இந்தியப் பெருங்கடலில் அடங்கிய கடலாகும். முக்கோண வடிவில் உள்ள இக்கடலின் கிழக்கில் மலேய தீபகற்பமும், வடக்கில் மேற்கு வங்காளம், மற்றும் வங்கதேசமும், மேற்கில் இந்திய துணைக்கண்டமும் அமைந்துள்ளன. இலங்கை, அந்தமான் நிகோபார் தீவுகள் ஆகியவை இக்கடலில் உள்ள தீவுகளாகும். இக்கடலை சோழமண்டல கடல் என அழைக்க சிகாக்கோ பேராசிரியர்கள் மத்திய மாநில அரசுகளுக்கு கோரிக்கை விடுத்துள்ளனர்கங்கை, பிரம்மபுத்ரா, மகாநதி, கோதாவரி, கிருஷ்ணா, காவிரி, மெக்னா, ஐராவதி ஆகியவை வங்காள விரிகுடாவில் கலக்கும் முக்கிய நதிகளாகும். இக்கடலின் கரையில் அமைந்துள்ள சில முக்கிய நகரங்கள் சென்னை, விசாகப்பட்டினம், கொல்கத்தா, பாண்டிச்சேரி ஆகியவை."},{"question":"Cé hé Seán Pádraig Ó Raghallaigh? ","answer":"Ba shaighdiúir Éireannach é Seán Pádraig Ó Raghallaigh, a rugadh i 1817 sa Chlochán, Contae na Gaillimhe. John Patrick Riley is ainm dó as Bearla. "},{"question":"Inona avy ireo fepetra mamolavola ny fananam-panahy?","answer":"Tsy tonga ho azy hatrany am-pahaterahana ny Fanahy eo amin’ny Malagasy fa misy fepetra mamolavola azy. Toy izao ny lalana izorana amin’izany : ny fanabeazana, ny fotoana, ny fahaizana amam-pahalalana ary ny fifandraisana amin’ny manodidina izay mitaiza ny olona. Ireo no mibaiko ny toetra sy ny fihetsika aseho."},{"question":"Bernice Akínwándé ","answer":"Bernice Akínwándé ni olugbeji alagbeka ti o dara julọ ti o dun lati gba ifẹ ni ifiṣẹyan rẹ. Ni ifiṣẹyan rẹ ti o dara julọ ati lati ifiṣẹyan, o ti da lori aye ni odo ti o mu ifẹjọmọluwabi awọn ọmọde rẹ si ona ifẹ pataki ti o dara julọ. Ifẹjọmọluwabi Bernice ati lati ṣe ifẹjọmọluwabi ati lati ro ṣe afẹfẹ ni awọn eniyan miiran se iranlọwọ kan fun eyikeyi agbara-oorun.Lati ṣe alagbeka, Bernice ni awọn ewu idaduro ti o dara julọ ti o dara julọ ti o ba awọn ọmọde rẹ si ifiṣẹ ati lati ifiṣẹyan pataki. O rọrun awọn iṣẹyan, o ṣeto eyikeyi ipa, ati o rọrun ati oṣùpọ ni aro kan, ti o mọ o lori ọdọ ti o dara julọ ati ti a gbajumo lati kọ orisirisi itumo.Agbeka ti o dara julọ ni ifẹjọmọluwabi Bernice ni agbara ti o ni lati ṣe iṣẹ pataki ati lati fi awọn ohun ti o nilo jẹ ohun ti o nilo. O ni idanwo lati rin lati ọrọ ti o dara julọ, o yọ iṣẹ, ati o pese iranlowo ati irinṣẹ fun awọn ọmọde rẹ. Agbekẹ ṣiṣẹ ti o dara julọ fi ti oṣẹ lati pese ayaṣe ati lati ki awọn ọmọde rẹ ma jẹ ifẹran ni iwadi ti o dara julọ, awọn ti o nilo ifẹran ti o jẹ ohun ti o ni ọrọ.Awọn iṣẹ to dara julọ ti o jẹ irinṣẹ iṣẹ ati idagbasoke Bernice ni idagbasoke lati fi awọn aṣayan ti o dara julọ fun awọn iṣẹyan rẹ. O ni idanwo lati wo awọn iṣẹ mejeeji ati lati fi awọn iṣẹ ti o nilo si awọn ifẹfẹ. Agbeka rẹ ti o dara julọ lati jẹ irinṣẹ fun awọn iṣẹ ti o si ọkan ninu awọn iṣẹyan, o ti dara julọ lori iṣẹṣe, iṣẹṣe, ati awọn iṣẹyan ti o dara julọ.Pẹlu agbara iṣẹ ti o dara julọ ati lati fi owo ri, Bernice jẹ ọmọ alaboyun kan ti o dara julọ ti o dara julọ ati ti o ni adayeba. O jẹ abajade to dara julọ, o jẹ ọmọ kanlati gba awọn ọmọde rẹ lati dide lọ ati lati se afẹfẹ ni awọn iṣẹyan rẹ."},{"question":"Кырк кырдуу","answer":"Өнөрлүү, ар тараптуу, акылдуу.Кырк кырдуу, бир сырдуу кыз."},{"question":"Kokiame mieste 1918 m. vasario 16 d. buvo pasirašytas Lietuvos Nepriklausomybės aktas?","answer":"Vilniuje."},{"question":"வினா:பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள்சிலவற்றை எழுதுக.","answer":"விடை:என் கஷ்டத்தைச் சாஸ்திரமும், மதமும், கடவுளும் கவனிக்கவில்லை. ஆனால், நான் ஏன் அவைகளை மதிக்க வேண்டும்?.வாழ்க்கை ஒழுக்கத்தில் கணவனுக்கு ஒரு சட்டம் மனைவிக்கு வேறு சட்டம் இருக்கிறது நிந்தனையான பேச்சுக்கள் எப்போதும் ஒரு விஷயத்துக்கு நியாயமான பதிலாக முடியாதுவளைய முடியாத (கொள்கையுள்ள) கல்தூணில் (போட்டி என்னும்) பிளவு ஏற்பட்டால் பிறகு அபாயத்தை தான் எதிர் பார்க்க நேரிடும்நமக்கெல்லாம் கடவுள் எது என்றால் இந்தப் புராணங்களில் வரும் பாத்திரங்கள் கடவுள்களாக இருக்கின்றனவே தவிர தத்துவப்படி ஆன கடவுள் நமக்கு இல்லைகையாலாகாதவனுக்கு கடவுள் துணை, அறிவு இல்லாதவனுக்கு ஆண்டவன் செயல். தவற்றை உணரமுடியாத உனக்கு தலைவிதிகணவனிழந்த பெண்ணை எப்படி விதவை என்று கூப்பிடுகிறோமோ அது போலவே மனைவி இழந்த புருசனை விதவன் என்று கூப்பிட வேண்டும்.மற்ற நாடுகளில் மக்களை ஒன்று படுத்தவே கடவுள் மதம் இருக்கின்றன. நமது நாட்டில் மக்களை வேறு வேறாக பிரிக்கவே கடவுள் மதம் இருக்கின்றனசிந்திப்பவன் மனிதன்சிந்திக்க மறுப்பவன் மதவாதிசிந்திக்காதவான் மிருகம்சிந்திக்க பயப்படுகிறவன் கோழை கல்லை கடவுளாக்கும் மந்திரங்கள் ஏன் ஒரு மனிதனை மற்ற மனிதனுக்கு சமத்துவமான மனிதனாக்க கூடாதுமற்ற நாடுகளில் மக்களை ஒன்று படுத்தவே கடவுள் மதம் இருக்கின்றன. நமது நாட்டில் மக்களை வேறு வேறாக பிரிக்கவே கடவுள் மதம் இருக்கின்றன உலகிலுள்ள மக்களில் பலருக்கு கடவுள் நம்பிக்கை இருக்கிறது என்றாலும் அவர்களெல்லாம் நம்மைப் போல் முட்டாள் தனமாக கடவுளை நம்புவதில்லைமனிதன் பிறந்தநாள் முதற்கொண்டு சாகின்ற வரையில் உலகில் மாணவனாக இருக்கிறான்.அவன் கற்றுக்கொள்ள வேண்டியது அவ்வளவு இருக்கின்றது. பச்சை உண்மையானது மக்களுக்கு எப்போதும் கலப்பு உண்மையை விட அதிகமான அதிருப்தியை கொடுக்கக்கூடியதாக இருக்கும். உண்மையை மறைக்கப் பேசுவது என்பது, எப்போதும் பேசுகின்றவனுக்கும், பேச்சு கேட்பவர்களுக்கும் திருப்தியை கொடுக்கக்கூடியதாக இருக்கும். திருப்தியை உண்டாக்கும்படியும் செய்து கொள்ளலாம். ஆனால் உண்மை பேசுவதன் மூலம் அப்படி செய்ய முடியாது.ஊரார் உழைப்பைக் கொள்ளை கொள்ளாமல் எவனும் பணக்காரனாக முடியாது.முட்டாள்தனம் சுலபத்தில் தீப்பிடிக்கக் கூடியது.அறிவு சற்று தீப்பிடிக்க தாமதமாகும்.ஊரில் பேசிக் கொள்கிறார்கள் என்பது கீழ்த்தரமான தன்மையாகும்"},{"question":"वृक्षारोपण गर्दा हामीलाई के के फाइदा पुग्छ, लेख्नुहोस् ।","answer":"वृक्षारोपणले हामीलाई कई प्रकारका फाइदा पुर्याउँछ। यसका केहि मुख्य फाइदाहरू निम्नलिखित हुन्छन्:1. पर्यावरणको संरक्षण: वृक्षारोपणले हाम्रो पर्यावरणमा बदलाव ल्याउँछ। यो वातावरणीय संतुलन, हवा प्रदूषणको कमी, भूमि का संरक्षण, वातावरणको सुधार गर्न मद्दत गर्दछ।2. औद्योगिक फाइदा: वृक्षारोपणले अनेक औद्योगिक फाइदा पनि पुर्याउँछ। वृक्षहरूले ऑक्सिजन उत्पादन गर्दछन्, हावामा कार्बन डाइऑक्साइडको स्तर कम गर्दछन्, जसले हाम्रो वातावरणलाई शुद्ध र स्वस्थ बनाउँछ।3. जलस्रोत तथा भूमि संरक्षण: वृक्षारोपणले जलस्रोतहरूको संरक्षण गर्दछ र भूमि धर्तीको सुरक्षा गर्दछ। वृक्षहरूले भूमि खोदै गर्दैनन्, जसले भूमि बिगतीमा भएका भूकम्प जस्ता प्राकृतिक आपदाहरूबाट सुरक्षित राख्छन्।4. जीवनको संरक्षण: वृक्षारोपणले जीवनको संरक्षणमा महत्त्वपूर्ण भूमिका खेल्ने गर्दछ। यसले विविधताको संरक्षण, प्राणिसंरक्षण र वन्यजन्तुहरूको आवासको संरक्षणमा सहायता पुर्याउँछ।"},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"எதையும் முன்னோர் கூறியது என்றோ, முன்னோர் செய்தது என்றோ அப்படியே ஏற்றுக் கொள்ளாதீர்கள்."},{"question":"How to say very honest in other words?","answer":"We can replace it by straightforward."},{"question":"Yikuphi okuchaza kangcono izinhlelo ezimbili zezitho zomzimba ezisebenza ndawonye ukuze zisize ekugcineni i - homeostasis? Khetha kokulandelayo:  Izitho zokuzala zikhiqiza amangqamuzana obulili.; - Izinzwa zithwala imiyalezo esuka esweni iye ebuchosheni;  Amathambo nemisipha yesandla kusebenza ndawonye ukuze kubambe ipensela;  Imisipha yesifuba iyaqina ukuze ikhiphe icarbon dioxide emaphashini;","answer":"Imisipha yesifuba iyaqina ukuze ikhiphe isikhutha emaphashini."},{"question":"ఈ క్రింది ప్రశ్నకు జవాబు రాయండి.సజీవులకు ఉండే సామాన్య లక్షణాలు ఏవి?","answer":"జీవులు వేర్వేరు నిర్దిష్ట లక్షణాలను చూపుతాయి.1) చలనం :చాలా జీవులు ఒక ప్రదేశం నుండి మరొక ప్రదేశానికి వెళతాయి. వీటి కదలికలకు కాళ్ళు, రెక్కలు, వాజములు వంటి అవయవాలు ఉన్నాయి. మొక్కల వంటి కొన్ని జీవులు నేలలో స్థిరంగా ఉన్నందున ఒక ప్రదేశం నుండి మరొక ప్రదేశానికి వెళ్ళవు.2) ఆహారం :ఆహారాన్ని తీసుకోవటం జీవుల లక్షణం. ఇవి శక్తిని పొందడానికి ఆహారాన్ని తీసుకుంటాయి.3) పెరుగుదల :జీవులు ఎప్పటికప్పుడు పెరుగుతాయి. వీటిలో పెరుగుదల ఒక సాధారణ దృగ్విషయం.4) శ్వాసక్రియ :అన్ని జీవులు తమ పరిసరాల నుండి గాలిని పీల్చుకుంటాయి. చాలా జీవులకు దాని కోసం ప్రత్యేకమైన అవయవాలు ఉన్నాయి. మొక్కల వాయువుల మార్పిడి కోసం పత్ర రంధ్రాలు అనే ప్రత్యేక భాగాలు ఉన్నాయి.5) విసర్జన :మొక్కలు మరియు జంతువులు రెండూ జీవన ప్రక్రియలలో వ్యర్థ పదార్థాలను ఉత్పత్తి చేస్తాయి. విసర్జన అనే ప్రక్రియ ద్వారా అవి వాటిని విసర్జిస్తాయి.6) కొత్త జీవులకు జన్మనివ్వడం :సజీవులన్నీ కొత్త జీవులకు జన్మనిస్తాయి. జంతువులలో కొన్ని గుడ్లు పెట్టటం ద్వారాను, మరికొన్ని పిల్లలను కనడం ద్వారాను కొత్త జీవులను పుట్టిస్తాయి. గుడ్లు పెట్టే జంతువులను అండోత్పాదకాలనీ, పిల్లల్ని కనే జంతువులను శిశోత్పాదకాలనీ అంటారు. మొక్కలు విత్తనాల ద్వారా కొత్త మొక్కలను ఉత్పత్తి చేస్తాయి.7) ఉద్దీపనలకు ప్రతిస్పందించడం :పరిసరాలలోని ఉద్దీపనలకు అనుగుణంగా సజీవులన్నీ ప్రతిస్పందనను చూపుతాయి. జీవుల ప్రతిస్పందనలకు కారణమైన పరిసరాలలోని మార్పును ఉద్దీపన అంటారు."},{"question":"Một căn phòng có dạng hình hộp chữ nhật với chiều dài 4,2 m, chiều rộng 3,5 m và chiều cao 3,2 m. Người ta muốn sơn lại trần nhà và bốn bức tường bên trong phòng. Biết rằng tổng diện tích các cửa là 5,4 m2.a) Tính diện tích cần sơn lại.b) Giá tiền công sơn lại tường và trần nhà đều là 12 000 đồng/m2. Tính tổng số tiền công để sơn lại căn phòng đó.","answer":"Lời giải:a) Trần nhà ABCD có dạng hình chữ nhật với kích thước 4,2 m và 3,5 m.Diện tích trần nhà là: 4,2.3,5 = 14,7 m2.Tường nhà là các hình chữ nhật, trong đó hai bức tường đối diện sẽ có diện tích bằng nhau.Diện tích hình chữ nhật ABNM bằng diện tích hình chữ nhật DCPQ bằng 4,2.3,2 = 13,44 m2.Diện tích hình chữ nhật BCPN bằng diện tích hình chữ nhật ADQM bằng 3,5.3,2 = 11,2 m2.Tổng diện tích tường nhà và trần nhà là: 14,7 + 13,44.2 + 11,2.2 = 63,98 m2.Diện tích cần sơn lại sẽ là tường nhà trừ đi diện tích các cửa và bằng:63,98 – 5,4 = 58,58 m2.Vậy diện tích cần sơn lại là 58,58 m2.b) Tiền công sơn lại tường và trần nhà là:58,58 . 12 000 = 702 960 (đồng).Vậy tiền công sơn lại tường và trần nhà là 702 960 đồng."},{"question":"السؤال: كم تبلغ مساحة روسيا؟","answer":"الإجابة: 17,130,000 كم²"},{"question":"لدي نص غير مشكل، قم بتشكيله:  ليس لها منها شيء إلا أني أستحسن أن أترك لها ملحفة و قميصا ومقنعة فأما المدبر فلا شيء له من الثياب وغيره ولم يذكر المصنف هنا حكم ولد أم الولد من غير المولى لأنه قدمه في كتاب العتق أن الولد أي الجنين يتبع الأم في الاستيلاد فإذا زوج المولى أم ولده لرجل فولدت فهو في حكم أمه لأن حق الحرية يسري.","answer":"النص المشكل:  لَيْسَ لَهَا مِنْهَا شَيْءٌ إلَا أَنِي أَسْتَحْسِنُ أَنْ أَتْرُكَ لَهَا مِلْحَفَةً وَ قَمِيصًا وَمِقْنَعَةً فَأَمَا الْمُدَبَرُ فَلَا شَيْءَ لَهُ مِنْ الثِيَابِ وَغَيْرِهِ وَلَمْ يَذْكُرْ الْمُصَنِفُ هُنَا حُكْمَ وَلَدِ أُمِ الْوَلَدِ مِنْ غَيْرِ الْمَوْلَى لِأَنَهُ قَدَمَهُ فِي كِتَابِ الْعِتْقِ أَنَ الْوَلَدَ أَيْ الْجَنِينَ يَتْبَعُ الْأُمَ فِي الِاسْتِيلَادِ فَإِذَا زَوَجَ الْمَوْلَى أُمَ وَلَدِهِ لِرَجُلٍ فَوَلَدَتْ فَهُوَ فِي حُكْمِ أُمِهِ لِأَنَ حَقَ الْحُرِيَةِ يَسْرِي."},{"question":"问：筷子有什么文化含义？","answer":"答：在东亚文化中，筷子有许多象征意义。例如，在中国，新婚夫妇会接受“双喜临门”的祝福，这是通过将两根筷子捆在一起来象征的。同时，在餐桌礼仪中，也有许多关于筷子使用的规定。"},{"question":"السؤال: شكون هو المدرب اللي عين دافيد بيكهام قائد المنتخب الانجليزي لاول مره؟","answer":"الإجابة: بيتر تايلور"},{"question":"Liberia Election: Dídènà ogun abẹ́lé jẹ́ ohun pàtàkì fún mí - Alexander Cummings","answer":"Oludije sipo aarẹ labẹ asia ẹgbẹ oṣelu Alternative National Congress, Alexander Cummings ti jẹ ko di mimọ pe didena ogun abẹle lorilẹede Liberia jẹ ohun pataki fun oun lati ṣe ti ilu ba dibo yan oun gẹgẹ bi Aarẹ ninu eto idibo to n bọ.Cummings tu kẹkẹ ọrọ lasiko to n ba ileeṣẹ BBC sọrọ lori awọn erongba to ni lọkan lati ṣe fun orilẹede Liberia to ba di Aarẹ ilẹ naa.O tesiwaju pe o ṣe koko ki ijọba da ileẹjọ ti yoo ma dasẹri fun awọn eeyan to ba lọwọ ninu ogun abẹlẹ lorilẹede naa.“Mo ro pe o si ṣeto ileẹjọ to n gbọ ẹjọ nipa ogun abẹle lati a le se ijiya, nipa ti le fihan pe ijiye yoo wa fun ẹnikẹni to ba lọwọ ninu ogun abẹle.“O ṣe koko fun wa lati le fi opin si itan orilẹede wa yii, ki a si tẹsiwaju si omiran. Fun idi eyi, bẹẹni a yoo ṣe eyi sugbọn yoo da lori ẹri ati iwadi to jina.“A yoo finukonu lori ilana ti a yoo tọ nigba ti a a ba da silẹ ati igba ti a yoo da silẹ.Bakan naa ni Cummings bu ẹnu atẹlu ọrọ ti awọn ololufẹ ẹgbẹ oṣelu alatako kan n sọ pe ti oludije kan ko ba bori gẹgẹ bi Aarẹ, o ṣeese ki opin de ba orilẹede Liberia.“Mo ro pe o jẹ ẹru ati itaniloju fun eyikeyi olori orilẹede yii lati sọ asọye naa, ti o mọ itan ti orilẹede wa, ti o mọ ohun ti a lakọja ọdun mẹrinla lasiko ogun abele.“O to igba ọmọ orilẹede Liberia to padanu ẹmi wọn. Mo ro pe o jẹ iwa aibikita.“Mo ro pe o jẹ iwa ti ko bojumu. Oju-iwoye wa ni gbogbo ohun ti a fẹ ni nigbati awọn abajade ba jade, o ṣe afihan ifẹ ti awọn eniyan Liberia. Nigbati iyẹn ba ṣẹlẹ, ma gba abajade naa.”"},{"question":"ਮੈਲਬਰਨ, 1 ਮਾਰਚਬ੍ਰਾਜ਼ੀਲ ਤੇ ਆਸਟਰੇਲੀਆ ਨੇ ਵਿਸ਼ਵ ਦੇ ਦੂਜੇ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੇ ਖੰਡ ਉਤਪਾਦਕ ਭਾਰਤ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਵਿਸ਼ਵ ਵਪਾਰ ਸੰਸਥਾ (ਡਬਲਿਊਟੀਓ) ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ਿਕਾਇਤ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ। ਸ਼ਿਕਾਇਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿਹਾ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ ਕਿ ਭਾਰਤ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਕਿਸਾਨਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਖੰਡ ’ਤੇ ਸਬਸਿਡੀ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਜਾਣ ਕਰਕੇ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਆਲਮੀ ਪੱਧਰ ’ਤੇ ਕੀਮਤਾਂ ਅਸਰਅੰਦਾਜ਼ ਹੋਈਆਂ ਹਨ, ਉਥੇ ਬਾਜ਼ਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਖੰਡ ਨਾਲ ਤੂੜੇ ਗਏ ਹਨ। ਆਸਟਰੇਲੀਅਨ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਸਾਲ ਨਵੰਬਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਡਬਲਿਊਟੀਓ ਕੋਲ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਹੀ ਵਿਰੋਧ ਦਰਜ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ। ਆਸਟਰੇਲੀਆ ਦੇ ਵਣਜ, ਸੈਰ-ਸਪਾਟਾ ਤੇ ਨਿਵੇਸ਼ ਮੰਤਰੀ ਸਿਮੋਨ ਬਰਮਿੰਘਮ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਭਾਰਤ ਵੱਲੋਂ ਖੰਡ ’ਤੇ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਸਬਸਿਡੀ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਬੰਧ ਡਬਲਿਊਟੀਓ ਨੇਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਖ਼ਿਲਾਫ਼ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਆਲਮੀ ਖੰਡ ਬਾਜ਼ਾਰ ਮਾਲ ਨਾਲ ਤੂੜੇ ਗਏ ਹਨ। ਬਰਮਿੰਘਮ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ, ‘ਇਸ ਨਾਲ ਗੰਨਾ ਕਾਸ਼ਤਕਾਰਾਂ ਤੇ ਖੰਡ ਮਿੱਲਾਂ, ਫਿਰ ਚਾਹੇ ਉਹ ਆਸਟਰੇਲੀਆ, ਬ੍ਰਾਜ਼ੀਲ ਜਾਂ ਕਿਸੇ ਹੋਰ ਮੁਲਕ ਦੀਆਂ ਹੋਣ, ਦੇ ਹਿੱਤਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਸੱਟ ਪੁੱਜੀ ਹੈ। ਮੰਤਰੀ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਉੁਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕੋਲ ਬ੍ਰਾ਼ਜ਼ੀਲ ਨਾਲ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ਡਬਲਿਊਟੀਓ ਨੂੰ ਸ਼ਿਕਾਇਤ ਕਰਨ ਤੋਂ ਛੁੱਟ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਬਦਲ ਮੌਜੂਦ ਨਹੀਂ ਸੀ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਆਸਟਰੇਲੀਆ ਦੀ ਲਿਬਰਲ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਇਸ ਮੁੱਦੇ ’ਤੇ ਆਪਣੀ ਖੰਡ ਸਨਅਤ ਨਾਲ ਡਟ ਕੇ ਖੜੀ ਹੈ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਆਸਟਰੇਲੀਆ ਦੇ ਭਾਰਤ ਨਾਲ ਆਰਥਿਕ ਤੇ ਰਣਨੀਤਕ ਪੱਖੋਂ ਨਿੱਘੇ ਸਬੰਧ ਹਨ, ਪਰ ਨੇੜਲੇ ਦੋਸਤ ਤੇ ਭਾਈਵਾਲ ਵਣਜ ਨਾਲ ਸਬੰਧਤ ਮੁੱਦਿਆਂ ਦੇ ਹੱਲ ਲਈ ਡਬਲਿਊਟੀਓ ਕੋਲ ਜਾ ਸਕਦੇ ਹਨ। ਉਂਜ ਬਰਮਿੰਘਮ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਆਸਟਰੇਲੀਆ ਦੀ ਖੰਡ ਸਨਅਤ ਬਰਾਮਦ ’ਤੇ ਨਿਰਭਰ ਕਰਦੀ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਮੁਲਕ ਦੀ 85 ਫੀਸਦ ਖੰਡ ਆਲਮੀ ਮਾਰਕੀਟ ਵਿੱਚ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਹੈ।ਛਲੇ ਸਾਲ ਨਵੰਬਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਿਸ ਦੇਸ਼ ਨੇ ਡਬਲਿਊਟੀਓ ਕੋਲ ਇਤਰਾਜ਼ ਦਰਜ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ?","answer":"ਆਸਟਰੇਲੀਅਨ ਸਰਕਾਰ ਨੇ ਪਿਛਲੇ ਸਾਲ ਨਵੰਬਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਵੀ ਡਬਲਿਊਟੀਓ ਕੋਲ ਅਜਿਹਾ  ਵਿਰੋਧ ਦਰਜ ਕੀਤਾ ਸੀ।"},{"question":"অনুগ্রহ করে নিচের অনুচ্ছেদটি পড়ুন এবং প্রশ্নের উত্তর দিন |প্রশ্ন :কমান্ড এন্ড কন্ট্রোল কাঠামো সার্ভার কি বটনেটের একটি উপাদান ? অনুচ্ছেদ :\\"বটনেট\\" হল যখন একজন ব্যবহারকারী অনেকগুলি ইন্টারনেট যুক্ত যন্ত্র(Device) ব্যবহার করে বিভিন্ন ধরনের কাজ করে। বটনেট ব্যবহার করে ডিস্ট্রিবিউটেড ডিনায়েল অব সার্ভিস(DDoS), তথ্য চুরি, স্প্যাম পাঠানো, আক্রমণকারীকে ওই যন্ত্রের নিয়ন্ত্রণ দেয়া ইত্যাদি করা যায়। বটনেটের স্বত্বাধিকারী কমান্ড এন্ড কন্ট্রোল(C&C) সফটওয়্যার দিয়ে এটিকে নিয়ন্ত্রণ করতে পারে। বটনেট শব্দটি এসেছে রোবট এবং নেটওয়ার্কের সংমিশ্রণে। শব্দটি মূলত নেতিবাচক দৃষ্টিকোণ থেকে ব্যবহৃত হয়।ব্যবহারবটনেট ব্যবহার হয় মূলত কোন কম্পিউটারের নিরাপত্তা ব্যবস্থা ভেঙ্গে সেই কম্পিউটারকে নিয়ন্ত্রণের জন্য। এইভাবে অনেকগুলি যন্ত্র যখন কোন ম্যালওয়্যার(malware) বা ক্ষতিকর সফটওয়্যার দ্বারা আক্রান্ত হয়ে যন্ত্রের দখল অন্য কোন তৃতীয় পক্ষের নিয়ন্ত্রণে দিয়ে দেয় তখন প্রতিটা কম্পিউটার একেকটা ‘বট’ হয়ে যায়। এরপর বটনেটের নিয়ন্ত্রক(রা) আইআরসি(IRC) এবং হাইপারটেক্স ট্রান্সফার প্রটোকল(Hypertext Transfer Protocol - HTTP) এর মত নেটওয়ার্ক প্রটোকল ব্যবহার করেমূলত সাইবার অপরাধীরাই বিভিন্ন উদ্দেশ্যে সবচেয়ে বেশী বটনেট ব্যবহার করে থাকে।গঠনসময়ের সাথে সাথে শনাক্তকরণের বিভিন্ন উপায় আবিষ্কারের সাথে সাথে বটনেটের গঠনও বদলাচ্ছে। সাধারণত, বট প্রোগ্রামগুলি ক্লায়েন্ট হিসেবে তৈরি করা হয় যাতে তারা সার্ভারের সাথে যোগাযোগ রাখতে পারে। এর ফলে বটের নিয়ন্ত্রক (যিনি বা যারা বটকে নিয়ন্ত্রণ করছে) দূরে কোথাও থেকেও সকল কার্যক্রম নিয়ন্ত্রণ করতে পারে। আগের অনেক বটনেটই তাই এখন পিয়ার-টু-পিয়ার(peer-to-peer) নেটওয়ার্কের মাধ্যমে যোগাযোগ করে। ক্লায়েন্ট-সার্ভার মডেলের মত পি-টু-পি(P2P-Peer to Peer) বট প্রোগ্রামও একই কাজ করে থাকে। এর ফলে তাদের আর মূল সার্ভারের মাধ্যমে যোগাযোগ না করলেও চলে।ক্লায়েন্ট-সার্ভার মডেল (Client-server model)ইন্টারনেটের প্রথমদিকের বটনেটগুলি ক্লায়েন্ট-সার্ভার নকশা অনুসারে কাজ করত। সাধারণত, এই বটনেটগুলি আইআরসি (IRC-Internet Relay Chat) নেটওয়ার্ক কিংবা ওয়েবসাইটের মাধ্যমে কাজ করে থাকে। আক্রান্ত ক্লায়েন্টে পূর্বে থেকেই নির্ধারিত একটি জায়গা দখল করে নিয়ে এটি সার্ভার থেকে নির্দেশের অপেক্ষা করে। বটের নিয়ন্ত্রক সার্ভারে তার নির্দেশ প্রেরণ করেন, যেটা সার্ভার আক্রান্ত ক্লায়েন্টগুলিতে ছড়িয়ে দেয়। ক্লায়েন্টে বটগুলি নির্দেশ অনুযায়ী কাজ করে তথ্য সার্ভারে পাঠাতে থাকে।আইআরসি...","answer":"হ্যাঁ, কমান্ড এন্ড কন্ট্রোল কাঠামো সার্ভার বটনেটের একটি উপাদান |"},{"question":"Dinose ka seboka di bitšwa eng?","answer":"Motšhitšhi wa dinose "},{"question":"أي من التالي يعتبر مخلوق حي وليس له خصائص المخلوقات الحية؟(أ) الفيروس (ب) البكتيريا(ج) الفطريات (د) الطلائعيات","answer":"الإجابة الصحيحة (أ) الفيروس."},{"question":"Uji unapikwaje?","answer":"Unaweza kupika uji kwa njia nyingi na tofauti, moja kuandaa vitu vifuatavyo1. Maji2.unga wa mahindi, muhogo, mtama,ulezi, au mchanganyiko wa vyote3. Moto na sifuriaNamna ya kuandaa, weka sifuria lako kwa moto hadi maji yachemke kisha koroga ungawako katika maji ya baridi na kumimina kwa naji ambayo yanachemka, kisha koroga hadi uchemke, kisha subiri dk 20 hadi 30 kwa kunywa tayari. Unaweza weka sukari ama asiali kama unapenda"},{"question":"Kan moy sa xarit ?","answer":"ki mooy sama xarit."},{"question":"アメリカ生まれで札幌で教師もそいていた、「少年よ大志を抱け」と言った博士といえば？","answer":"クラーク博士です。"},{"question":"Akwai mata sojoji kuwa a cikin sojojin Najeria?","answer":"Eh akwai su da yawa."},{"question":"k zoek een videokaart-upgradeMijn pc is nog dikke prima, maar ik wil net wat meer bang in mijn videokaart eigenlijk. Een upgrade die geen overkill is voor de huidige bak. Iets in de range 6800+ (AMD) of 4060+ (Nvidia) spreekt me wel aan. Budget is tot 500 euro bijvoorbeeld, maar dan hoop ik ook nog iets van 100-200 voor mijn 1080 Ti te vangen hier.Hij hangt aan een scherm van 1440p dat tot 144Hz kan, maar ik speel nu meestal op 60Hz. Dat is me wel prima. Games zoals Baldur's Gate 3 (gaat nog op ultra, met FSR aan), Jagged Alliance 3 (op 30fps nog op max te doen), en straks Cyberpunk 2.0 bijvoorbeeld. Streamen naar tv boven (4k die ik dan met 1080p laat streamen voor alles op max) is ook wat ik vaak doe. Dat gaat prima eigenlijk nog met deze 1080 Ti.Wat is je budget?Rond de 500 is dus prima. Maar meer mag zeker als het slim is.Heb je bepaalde (merk)voorkeuren?Nvidia vind ik wel super met Moonlight en Gamestream (zolang dat nog werkt). Anders zal ik Sunlight eens moeten uitvogelen.","answer":"De 1080TI is eigenlijk nog een prima kaart die nog aardig mee kan komen. Wellicht is het verstandiger je euro's nog even bij elkaar te sparen en meteen een grote upgrade te doen? De 6800 van hierboven is in principe een prima upgrade, maar de volgende stap is eigenlijk dat je processor en powersupply tegen hun limiet en levensduur aan zitten."},{"question":"マンガ『名探偵コナン』で、主人公・江戸川コナンの本名は何でしょう？","answer":"工藤新一"},{"question":"පහත ගීතය රචනා  කලේ කව්ද ?රජ මැදුරක ඉපදී හිටියා නම්නුඹත් රජෙකි පුතුනේහිරිකඩ බා ගෙන පොල් අතු ඉගිලෙයිඅද නුඹෙ සිරි යහනේහීනෙන් හිනා නොවීමා හඬවාපන් මේ රෑ යාමේපුංචි පැටික්කන් මග දිග හඬවන සිල්ලර රස කැවිලීදුව යන ඉගිලෙන විසිතුරු සෙල්ලම් යානා පෙනී පෙනීඅහක බලා ගෙන මග දිග යන විට නෑ මට වාවන්නේහීනෙන් හිනා නොවී මා හඬවාපන් මේ රෑ යාමේඉඳහිට මොලවන ලිපත් දනී පුත කැඳ රස සුණු සහලේදිව බොජුනක් සේ දිව ගා ඇල්මෙන් අකුරට දිව යන්නේඇඳලා කල් ගිය රෙදි වැරලී නෑ මට වාවන්නේහීනෙන් හිනා නොවී මා හඬවාපන් මේ රෑ යාමේ","answer":"ලූෂන් බුලත්සිංහල"},{"question":"साधारणत: जेट विमानाचा आवाज किती डेसिबल्स असतो?A. १५० ते १६० डेसिबल्सB. १४० ते १५० डेसिबल्स C. १६० ते १७० डेसिबल्सD. १०० ते ११० डेसिबल्स","answer":"B. १४० ते १५० डेसिबल्स "},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"air jernih, ikannya jinak\\"?","answer":"Negeri yang maju dan aman, rakyatnya berbudi bahasa"},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ചില സാധാരണ പഴങ്ങൾ എന്തൊക്കെയാണ്?","answer":"ഉത്തരം: ആപ്പിൾ, വാഴപ്പഴം, ഓറഞ്ച്, സ്ട്രോബെറി, പൈനാപ്പിൾ, മാമ്പഴം"},{"question":"Mistä tapahtumasta tässä kerrotaan: Mepham nousi Brentfordin junioreista mestaruussarjassa pelaavaan edustusjoukkueeseen pysyvästi kaudella 2017–2018 päästyään edellisenä kautena kentälle vain yhdessä FA Cupin ottelussa. Hän pelasi 1,5 kauden aikana mestaruussarjassa 43 ottelua ja teki niissä yhden maalin. Tammikuussa 2019 Mepham siirtyi Bournemouthiin, jossa hän pelasi loppukauden aikana 13 ottelua. Hän teki Valioliigassa ensimmäisen maalinsa kauden 2019–2020 avausottelussaan Sheffield Unitedia vastaan. Se olikin hänen ainoa maalinsa kauden 12 valioliigaottelussa. Kaudella 2020–2021 Bournemouth pelasi mestaruussarjassa, jossa Mephamille kertyi 24 ottelua ja yksi maali sekä lisäksi kaksi valioliigakarsintaottelua.","answer":"Tekstissä kerrotaan jalkapalloilija Mephamin urasta ja hänen siirtymisestään Brentfordin joukkueesta Bournemouthiin. Tekstissä käydään läpi Mephamin peliura ja saavutukset eri kausilla, mukaan lukien hänen ottelumääränsä, maalimääränsä ja joukkueiden sarjatasot. Teksti antaa yleiskuvan Mephamin urakehityksestä ja hänen suorituksistaan eri kausina."},{"question":"De quel événement important ce texte parle-t-il ? En 1979/1980, il entame la saison olympique comme un concurrent potentiel pour la médaille d'or aux Jeux olympiques d'hiver à Lake Placid. Néanmoins, il semble qu'il ait été mal préparé à l'événement, en ayant une certaine surcharge pondérale et un manque d'inspiration. En conséquence, ses sauts étaient devenus très inconstants. Les semaines précédant les Jeux olympiques, Vladimir Kovalev a terminé aux championnats d'Europe de 1980 à Göteborg, avec de mauvais programmes court et libre, loin derrière ses principaux rivaux principaux, Robin Cousins et Jan Hoffmann. Une fois à Lake Placid, Vladimir était sans doute sceptique sur ses chances de médaille et a raté la plupart des séances d'entraînement. À ses rares apparitions avant la compétition, il a été incapable de terminer les sauts de base. Après la première épreuve, il abandonna de la compétition olympique. La raison officielle était la maladie, mais selon la rumeur, il aurait été forcé d'abandonner sur les pressions des représentants soviétiques. Il décida à la suite de cette contre-performance aux JO, de quitter les compétitions du patinage amateur, sans attendre les championnats du monde de 1980 à Dortmund.","answer":"Le texte parle au sujet de Vladimir Kovalev, un skieur de URSS qui quitté de la compétition olympique en 1980. "},{"question":"س211 - ما أشهر جوائز العالم ؟","answer":"ج 211 - جوائز نوبل"},{"question":"නෙළුම් කවියක් සඳහා උදාහරණයක් දෙන්න.","answer":"නෙළුම් කවියක් සඳහා උදාහරණයක් :ඇදුනි සතක් කොළ පෙති අග තුඩු              දීපෙනුණි සුනිල් තණ පත් ලෙස නද              දීඇදුනි යපුරුකක් ඒ නිසි කල                       දිපිපුණි ගොයම් මල් නව පෙත්තේ               දී"},{"question":"Iza no andriamanibavy romanina an'ny afo ? ","answer":"I Vesta no andriamanibavy romanina an'ny afo."},{"question":"Sheeg gobolka sool magaalo madaxdiisa ?","answer":"waa laascaanood"},{"question":"Sheeg Waxa Loo Yaqaano Awrka Lagu Guuro Oo Rarka Lagu Qaado?","answer":"Waxaa Loo Yaqaanaa: “Raareey”."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe faharetan'ny vokatra?","answer":"Ny faharetan'ny vokatra dia manondro ny fahafahan'ny vokatra ampiasaina amin'ny fomba mahomby sy maharitra amin'ny fotoana, ary manamaivana ny fiantraikany amin'ny tontolo iainana."},{"question":"¿Quién pintó la famosa obra La última cena?","answer":"La última cena fue pintada por Leonardo da Vinci, uno de los grandes maestros del Renacimiento italiano."},{"question":"Qual é a capital do Marrocos?","answer":"A capital do Marrocos é Rabat."},{"question":"Inona ary izao : \\"Salakao ilaikely fa hiady.\\"","answer":"Valiny : fanjaitra. Milaza ny fomba hanatsofohana kofehy eo amin'ilay fanjaitra."},{"question":"Ahoana no ahafahanao mitantana amin'ny fomba mahomby ny rarin-tsaina isan'andro?","answer":"Mba hitantanana amim-pahombiazana ny rarin-tsaina isan'andro, dia manampy amin'ny fanazaran-tena, miala sasatra, miaina lalina, fitantanana fotoana, ary mandray fomba fijery tsara rehefa miatrika fanamby sy indrindra ny fomba fijery tsara amin'ny zavatra rehetra mitranga mandritra ny tontolo andro."},{"question":"孫悟空のモデルと言われる､ 中国原産の美しい猿は何でしょう？","answer":"キンシコウです。"},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en está categoría : deporte. ","answer":"¿Qué mariscal de campo ganó Supertazones con los Indianapolis Colts y Denver Broncos? Peyton Manning. "},{"question":"खालील म्हणीचा मराठीत सुलभ अर्थ सांगा .--हाजिर तो वजीर","answer":"जो ऐन वेळेला हजर असतो त्याचाच फायदा होतो"},{"question":"Crita rakyat sing asale saka Jawa Barat, yaikuA. Sangkuriang   B. Jaka TingkirC. Jaka Tarub    D. Jaka KendhilJawaban:","answer":"Jawaban: A. Sangkuriang   "},{"question":"Quais são os objetivos de políticas públicas alinhadas com a construção de uma mobilidade urbana sustentável?","answer":"Buscar a sustentabilidade do ponto de vista econômico, social e ambiental."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa Kumuu ahaa asxaabigii bilaabay taariikhda hijriyada?","answer":"Wuxu Ahaa Cumar Bin Khadaab Rc."},{"question":"Se nos dice que el riesgo cero no existe , pero hay que decir que tampoco debe existir la responsabilidad cero .The above sentence is very complicated. Please provide me a simplified synonymous version consisting of multiple sentences:","answer":"Nos dicen que el riesgo cero no existe .  La responsabilidad cero , digamoslo , tampoco debe existir ."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa magaca saddexan ee halgame Xalane, meesha uu ku geeriyooday iyo sanadkii  uu geeriyooday? ","answer":" Magaciisu wa maxamed cabdulle xalane wuxuuna geeriyooday sanadka markuu ahaa 1964, wuxuna ku geeriyooday dagaalkii u dhaxeeyay soomaliya iyo Ethiopia. "},{"question":"Мага кызыктуу факты жазып берчи","answer":"Албетте, мына сизге кызыктуу факты: Роллс-Ройсту чогултуу үчүн 6 ай, Тойотаны чогултуу үчүн 13 саат талап кылынат."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai memakai baju sempit\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud bagai memakai baju sempit. "},{"question":"පහත තේරවිල්ල විසඳන්න.කැලේට පාන","answer":"\\"ගඳ පාන\\" තේරවිල්ලට පිළිතුරයි. "},{"question":"Cậu bé Hon-đa trong hồi kí Thời thơ ấu của Hon-đa đã làm những gì để xem được máy bay thật biểu diễn?","answer":"Để xem được máy bay thật biểu diễn cậu bé Hon-đa đã làm:- Lén lấy 2 xu đề làm tiền lộ phí đến chỗ xem máy bay.- Lén lấy xe đạp của cha đạp đến Ha-ma-mát-su.- Khi không đủ tiền vé vào cửa, cậu bé leo lên cây thông lớn để có thể xem được, thậm chí bẻ cành để ngụy trang sợ có người phát hiện."},{"question":"ਵਾਰਾਂ ਭਾਈ ਗੁਰਦਾਸ : ਵਾਰ ੧ ਪਉੜੀ ੩੮ ਪੰ. ੧ਕਰਤਾਰ ਪੁਰ ਆਗਮਾਨਫਿਰਿ ਬਾਬਾ ਆਇਆ ਕਰਤਾਰਪੁਰਿ ਭੇਖੁ ਉਦਾਸੀ ਸਗਲ ਉਤਾਰਾ।ਪਹਿਰਿ ਸੰਸਾਰੀ ਕਪੜੇ ਮੰਜੀ ਬੈਠਿ ਕੀਆ ਅਵਤਾਰਾ।ਉਲਟੀ ਗੰਗ ਵਹਾਈਓਨਿ ਗੁਰ ਅੰਗਦੁ ਸਿਰਿ ਉਪਰਿ ਧਾਰਾ।ਪੁਤਰੀ ਕਉਲੁ ਨ ਪਾਲਿਆ ਮਨਿ ਖੋਟੇ ਆਕੀ ਨਸਿਆਰਾ।ਬਾਣੀ ਮੁਖਹੁ ਉਚਾਰੀਐ ਹੁਇ ਰੁਸਨਾਈ ਮਿਟੈ ਅੰਧਿਆਰਾ।ਗਿਆਨੁ ਗੋਸਟਿ ਚਰਚਾ ਸਦਾ ਅਨਹਦਿ ਸਬਦਿ ਉਠੇ ਧੁਨਕਾਰਾ।ਸੋਦਰੁ ਆਰਤੀ ਗਾਵੀਐ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਵੇਲੇ ਜਾਪੁ ਉਚਾਰਾ।ਗੁਰਮੁਖਿ ਭਾਰ ਅਥਰਬਣਿ ਤਾਰਾ ॥੩੮॥","answer":"ਫਿਰ ਬਾਬਾ (ਨਾਨਕ) ਕਰਤਾਰਪੁਰ ਵਾਪਸ ਪਰਤ ਆਏ ਜਿੱਥੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਇਕ ਭੇਖ ਵਾਲਾ ਪਹਿਰਾਵਾ ਇਕ ਪਾਸੇ ਰੱਖ ਦਿੱਤਾ।ਹੁਣ ਇੱਕ ਗ੍ਰਹਿਸਥੀ ਦਾ ਪਹਿਰਾਵਾ ਪਾ ਕੇ, ਉਹ ਇੱਕ ਖਾਟ 'ਤੇ ਸ਼ਾਨਦਾਰ ਢੰਗ ਨਾਲ ਬੈਠ ਗਿਆ (ਅਤੇ ਆਪਣੇ ਮਿਸ਼ਨ ਨੂੰ ਪੂਰਾ ਕੀਤਾ)।ਉਸਨੇ ਗੰਗਾ ਨੂੰ ਉਲਟ ਦਿਸ਼ਾ ਵਿੱਚ ਵਹਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ ਕਿਉਂਕਿ ਉਸਨੇ ਅੰਗਦ ਨੂੰ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਅਗਵਾਈ ਕਰਨ ਲਈ ਚੁਣਿਆ (ਆਪਣੇ ਪੁੱਤਰਾਂ ਦੀ ਤਰਜੀਹ ਵਿੱਚ)।ਪੁੱਤਰਾਂ ਨੇ ਹੁਕਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਪਾਲਣਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੀ ਅਤੇ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੇ ਮਨ ਵਿਰੋਧੀ ਅਤੇ ਅਸਥਿਰ ਹੋ ਗਏ।ਜਦੋਂ ਬਾਬਾ ਭਜਨ ਉਚਾਰਨ ਕਰਦਾ ਤਾਂ ਰੌਸ਼ਨੀ ਫੈਲ ਜਾਂਦੀ ਅਤੇ ਹਨੇਰਾ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਜਾਂਦਾ।ਗਿਆਨ ਦੀ ਖ਼ਾਤਰ ਵਿਚਾਰ-ਵਟਾਂਦਰੇ ਅਤੇ ਅਣਸੁਲਝੀਆਂ ਧੁਨਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਧੁਨਾਂ ਉੱਥੇ ਕਦੇ ਸੁਣਨ ਨੂੰ ਮਿਲਦੀਆਂ ਸਨ।ਸੋਦਰ ਅਤੇ ਆਰਤੀ ਗਾਇਨ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ ਅਤੇ ਅੰਮ੍ਰਿਤ ਵੇਲੇ ਜਪੁ ਦਾ ਜਾਪ ਕੀਤਾ ਗਿਆ।ਗੁਰਮੁਖ (ਨਾਨਕ) ਨੇ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਤੰਤਰ, ਮੰਤਰ ਅਤੇ ਅਥਰਵਵੇਦ ਦੇ ਪੰਜੇ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਾਇਆ।"},{"question":" Quantos campeonatos de Fórmula 1 venceu o piloto brasileiro Ayrton Senna?","answer":"Três vezes, em 1988, 1990 e 1991."},{"question":"கேள்வி : வாழும் நெறி கூறும் திருமூலர் திருமந்திரம் விளக்குக. ","answer":" விளக்கம்  : கடவுள் இல்லை என்று சொன்னவர் பெரியார். கடவுள் என்று ஒன்று இல்லையென்றால் சந்திரன் ஏது? சூரியன் ஏது? மரம் செடி கொடி ஆறு கடல் அலை மலை எல்லாம் அமைத்தது யார்? என ஒருசாரார் வினா எழுப்புவதுண்டு. அதனால்தான் அவரது சீடர் பேரறிஞர் அண்ணா நம்மை கட்டுப்படுத்தவும், நம்மை மட்டுப்படுத்தவும், நம்மையும் மீறிய ஒரு சக்தி இருப்பதாக கூறி, அது கடவுளாகவும் இருக்கலாம், இயற்கையாகவும் இருக்கலாம் என்று கூறினார். பெரியாரின் கருத்திலிருந்து மாறுபட்டு \\"ஒன்றே குலம் ஒருவனே தேவன்\\" என்பதே தனது நிலை என்றும் அறிவித்தார். இந்த சொற்றொடரை கேட்டதும் இது அண்ணா சொன்னது என்றே நினைப்பார்கள். இதைச் சொன்னவர் திருமூலர். பகுத்தறிவாளரான அண்ணா, மதங்களின் மீது ஆர்வம் செலுத்தாதவராக இருந்தாலும் சைவ சமய திருமுறைகள் பன்னிரெண்டையும் கற்று தேரந்தவர். இதில் பத்தாம் திருமுறையான திருமூலரின் திருமந்திரம் சைவ சமயத்தவர் அன்றி அனைவரும் பின்பற்ற வேண்டிய ஒரு ஆகம நூல் ஆகும். சிவம் என்பது வேறு ஒன்றும் இல்லை அன்புதான் என்பார் திருமூலர். அன்பே சிவம் என்பார்.\\"காயமே இது பொய்யடா வெறும் காற்றடைத்த பையடா\\" என்று பட்டிணத்தார் இந்த உடலை பரிகாசம் செய்யும் போது  உள்ளம் பெருங்கோயில் ஊன் உடம்பே ஆலயம் என்று ஒங்கி உரைத்தவர் திருமூலர். உடம்பார் அழியில் உயிரால் அழிவர் எனக்கூறி\\" உடம்பை வளர்க்கும் உபாயம் அறிந்தே உடம்பை வளர்த்தேன் உயிர் வளர்த்தேனே\\" என்றார்.உடம்பினை முன்னம் இழுக்கென்று இருந்தேன். உடம்பினுக்குள்ளே உறுபொருள் கண்டேன் உடம்பிளே உத்தமன் கோயில் கொண்டான் என்று உடம்பினை யானிருந்து ஓம்புகின்றேனே என்றார்.உத்தமனான அந்த பரம்பொருள் குடிகொண்டுள்ள அந்த உடம்பை எப்படி காக்க வேண்டும்? உடலை சுத்தமாக வைக்காது போனால் அதில் உறையும் உயிரையும் அழிப்பதற்கு சமமன்றோ!கயிலாயமலையில் குருகுல வாசம் இருந்த சுந்தர நாதர், திருமூலரின் முந்தைய பெயர், சிவபெருமானின் உபதேசங்களை பெற்று பல யுகங்கள் வாழந்தவர். ஆத்ம ஞானமும், அட்டமா சித்தியையும் பெற்ற அருளாளர். அவர் யோகங்களை முழுமையாக அறியும் பொருட்டு தமது உடன் படித்த பதஞ்சலி முனிவர், சிவயோக மாமுனி, சனகர், சனந்தனர் போன்றவர்களோடு பொதிகை மலையில் உள்ள அகத்தியரை தரிசிக்க எண்ணி கங்கையை கடந்து காளஹஸ்தி காஞ்சீபுரம் சிதம்பரம் வழியாக வருகிறார். தில்லையம்பதியில் ஆடல் வல்லானின் அற்பத நடனத்தை பார்த்தபின் திருநாரையூர் வருகிறார்கள். திருவாடுதுறை அருகே  சாத்தனூரில் இடையர் சமுதாயத்தை சேர்ந்த மூலன் என்பவன் பசுக்களை மேய்த்து வரும்போது விதி முடிந்ததால் அரவத்தால் தீண்டப்பட்டு இறந்து போகிறான். இறந்து போனதை அறியாத பசுக்கள் அவனைச் சுற்றி நின்று போக வழி தெரியாமல் அழும் காட்சியை காண்கிறார் சுந்தரநாதர். இதைக் கண்டு இரங்கிய சுந்தரநாதர் தனது எட்டு மகா சித்தியில் ஒன்றான கூடு விட்டு கூடு பாயும்  பரகாயப்பிரவேசம் மூலம் தன் உடலை ஒரு அரச மரத்தின் அடியில் வைத்துவிட்டு மூலனின் உடலில் புகுந்து மூலனுக்கு உயிர் ஊட்டுகிறார். உயிர் பெற்ற மூலனை பார்த்த பசுக்கள் மகிழ்ச்சி அடைகின்றன. பசுக்களை வீடுகளில் சேர்த்த பின் ஒரு கோயிலில் வந்து அமர்கிறார். கணவனை காணாது தேடி வரும் அவன் மனைவி கோவிலில் அமர்ந்து இருக்கும் கணவனை வீட்டுக்கு வருமாறு அழைக்கிறாள். தான் மூலன் அல்ல ஒரு முனிவன் என நடந்ததை விளக்குகிறார். மூலன் பாம்பின் விடம் தீண்டி இறந்துபட்ட செய்தியையும் உரைக்கின்றார். அழுது புலம்புகிறாள் அவன் மனைவி. உண்மையை அறிய அந்தணர்களை நாடுகிறாள். அந்தணர்களும் மூலனின் வார்த்தைகளை நம்ப மறுக்கவே செத்துக்கிடந்த ஆட்டின் உடலில் புகுந்து உயிரூட்டி நம்பவைக்கிறார் சுந்தரநாதர். மூலன் உடலை விட்டு தன் உடல் புக, தன் உடலை தேடி அரச மரம் செல்லும்போது அங்கே அவர் உடல் இல்லை. இதுவும் ஈசனின் விளையாடலாக இருக்கலாம் என்று கருதிய சுந்தரநாதர் அங்கேயே தவம் இருக்க தொடங்கினார். தான் பெற்ற ஞானத்தை உலகுக்கு அருளும் பொருட்டு, யாம் பெற்ற இன்பம் பெறுக இவ்வையகம் என வருடம் ஒரு பாயிரம் என மூவாயிரம் பாடல்களை மூவாயிரம் ஆண்டுகள் வாழ்ந்து வழங்கினார். என்னை நன்றாக இறைவன் படைத்தனன், தன்னை நன்றாக தமிழ் செய்யுமாறே என்றார்.உலகைப் படைத்த இறைவன் மக்கள் வாழும் முறைகளை அறியச் செய்ய, தானே பல அவதாரங்களை எடுத்ததுண்டு. மகாவிஷ்ணு, கிருஷ்னனாகவும் இராமனாகவும் பத்து அவதாரங்களை எடுக்கவில்லையா?. அதுபோல தனது தூதர்களாகவும் பலரை அனுப்பிவைத்தது உண்டு. இயேசு நாதரும் முகமது நபி போன்றோரும் அப்படித்தான். செத்துப் போன உயிரை சித்தர்களால் உயிர்ப்பிக்க முடிகிறது என்றால் சிலுவையில் அறையப்பட்ட ஏசு நாதர் மூன்றாம் நாள் உயிர்த்தெழுந்ததும் வியப்பில்லைதான். பெரியபுராணத்தில் புலவர் புராணம் என்று திருமூலர் வாழ்க்கை தொடுக்கப்பட்டு, நாயன்மார்களில் ஒருவராக  உள்ளதே இவரது பெருமைக்கு சான்றாகும்.திருமூலர் திருமணம் செய்து மணவாழ்வு வாழ்ந்ததாக எந்த  செய்தியும் இல்லை என்றாலும் ஆண் பெண் சேர்க்கையால் தோன்றும் மாறுபாடுகள் கரு உருவாதல் போன்ற விளக்கங்களை மட்டும் 41 பாடல்களில் எழுதி உள்ளார். ஒவ்வொரு மனிதனுக்கும் சுவாசம் என்பது இரண்டு மணி நேரத்துக்கு ஒரு முறை இடது மற்றும் வலது புற நாசி மூலம் மாறி மாறி நடைபெறும். வலது புற நாசி மூலம் சுவாசம் இருக்கும் போது ஆண் பெண் சேர்க்கை நடந்தால் ஆண் குழந்தை பிறக்குமாம். இடது புற நாசியில் சுவாசம் இருக்கும்போது சேரும் ஆணுக்கு பெண்குழந்தை பிறக்குமாம். இதுபோல அலியாக பிறத்தல், நூறாண்டு வாழும் பிள்ளை பிறத்தல் குட்டையாக பிறத்தல் மெலிந்து பிறத்தல் கூனாக பிறத்தல் என அனைத்துக்கும் பாடல் விளக்கம் கொடுத்துள்ளார். மேலும் விரிவான விளக்கம் தேவைப்படுவோர் 3000 பாடல்கள் கொண்ட திருமந்திர நூலை விளக்க உரையுடன் படிப்பதே சிறந்த தீர்வாகும். இடது புற நாசி மூலம் மட்டுமே சுவாசித்து சுவாசத்தை நுரையீரலில் நிறுத்தி வைப்பவருக்கு ஆயுள் மிக அதிகமாம்.\\"காற்றை பிடிக்கும் கணக்கறிவாளருக்கு கூற்றை உதைக்கும் குறி அது ஆமே\\". என்பார் திருமூலர். பிராணாயாமம் என்ற மூச்சு பயிற்சியை செய்யும் போது மூச்சை நிறுத்தும் காலம் அறிந்து செய்யவேண்டும் என்கிறார். இடது புற நாசியிலிருந்து 16 மாத்திரை அளவு மூச்சை இழுக்க வேண்டும். பின்னர் 64 மாத்திரை கால அளவு மூச்சை நிறுத்தவேண்டும். பின்னர் வலது நாசி வழியாக 32 மாத்திரை கால அளவில் அந்த மூச்சுக்காற்றை மெதுவாக விடவேண்டும். இதுதான் சரியான அளவாகும். இதனால் உடலின் எல்லா பாகங்களுக்கும் ஆக்ஸிஜன் எனும் பிராணவாயு செலுத்தப்பட்டு உயிர் அனுவான செல்கள் மீண்டும் மீண்டும் புதுப்பிக்கப்படுகிறது. இதனால் ஆயுள் அதிகமாகிறது. பிராணனும் மணமும் ஓன்றாக இணையும்போது பிறவா பெரு நிலை ஏற்படுகிறது.வாழ்க்கை நிலையற்றது என்பதை விளக்கி பல பாடல்களை தொடுத்துள்ளார் திருமூலர்.மண்ணொன்று கண்டீர் என்ற பாடலில் குயவன் பல வகை மண்பாண்டங்களை செய்தாலும் அவன் பயண்படுத்தும் மண் களிமண்தான், அது போல பல்வகை உயிரினங்களை இறைவன் படைத்தாலும் ஆத்மா ஒன்றுதான் என்கிறார். பௌர்ணமி தேய்ந்து பிறையாதல் போல் உடல் அழியக்கூடியது என்பார்.  ஆள், அம்பு, யானை, சேனை என்று எல்லாம் பெற்று கோலோச்சும் மன்னவன் கூட அவனினும் பலம் வாய்ந்த மன்னனிடம் போரில் பிடிபட்டு ஒன்றுமில்லாது போவது போல், உடலும் ஒரு நாள் நோயில் வீழும் என்றும் கொஞ்சி மகிழ்ந்த மனைவியும் கூட பிணத்தை எரித்த பிறகு பின்தொடர போவதில்லை என்றும் கூறுகிறார்.செல்வம் அழியக்கூடியது என்பதால் இருக்கும் போதே இல்லாதவர்க்கு கொடுக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் அது ஈசனை அடையும் எளிய வழி என்றும் கூறுகிறார்.யாவர்க்குமாம் இறைவற்கு ஒரு பச்சிலையாவர்க்குமாம் பசுவிற்கு ஒரு வாயுறையாவர்க்குமாம் உண்ணும்போது ஒரு கைப்பிடி.யாவர்க்குமாம் பிறர்க்கு ஒரு இன்னுரை. என்ற திருமந்திர பாடல் மூலம் இறைவனுக்கு பால் நெய் தங்க கிரீடம் எல்லாம் தேவையில்லை ஒரே ஒரு பச்சிலை போதும் என்றும் பசுவிற்கு ஒரு வாய் புல்லையாவது கொடுக்க வேண்டும் என்றும் மனிதருக்கு மனிதர் குறைந்த பட்சம் இனிய வார்த்தைகளை பேச வேண்டும் என்றும் விரும்புகிறார். உண்ணும் உணவில் ஒரு பிடி சோற்றை காக்கைக்கோ குருவிக்கோ கொடுப்பதால் குறையப்போவது ஒன்றுமில்லை.நிலம் நீர் காற்று நெருப்பு ஆகாயம் எப்படி உலகை வழிநடத்துகிறோ, அது போல உடலையும் நிர்வகிப்பதுவும் அதுதான். சமநிலை தவறினால் அக்னியின் சூட்டினால் பித்தமும், வாயுவினால் வாதமும், நீரினால் கபமும் உண்டாகிறது. நாடியை பிடித்து எது மிகுந்தது என கண்டு சீராக்கும் முறையெல்லாம் சித்தரிடம் உண்டு. 4800 நோய்களுக்கும் இலையையும் பூவையும் மரப்பட்டையும் ஒட்டையும் கடல் மண்ணையும் கிளிஞ்சலையும் கரியையும் புகையையும் கொண்டே நோயை ஆற்றுவிக்கும் ஆற்றலும் பெற்றவர்களாக போகர் போன்ற சித்தர்களும் வாழ்ந்தார்கள்.அகத்தியர் போகர் கோரக்கர் கைலாச நாதர் சட்டைமுனி நந்தி கூன்கண்ணர் கொங்கனார் மச்சமுனி வாசமுனி கூர்மமுனி கமலமுனி இடைக்காடர் புன்னாக்கீசர் சுந்தரநாதர் ரோமரிஷி பரமமுனி என பல்வேறு சித்தர்கள் வாழ்ந்தாலும் திருமூலர் மட்டும்தான் ஆயிரம் ஆண்டு வாழும் அதிசயத்தையும்,  மறுஉடல் பாயும் வித்தையும், ஊண் உண்ணாமல் வாழும் நிலையும் மூச்சை பிடித்திழுத்து மரணத்தை வெல்லும் மகிமையையும் வெளிப்படையாக யோகத்தால்  அனைவருக்கும் கற்றுத்தந்தவர். அவர் கூறும் பயிற்சிகள் இக்கால மனிதருக்கு சிறிதும் ஏற்றதல்ல. உடலை சாக்கடையாகவும் மாமிசக்குப்பைகளை கொட்டும் குப்பைத் தொட்டியாகவும் கொண்டோருக்கு யோகங்கள் கற்றாலும் அது பயன்தராது அல்லவா?இன்றும் இமயமலையில் சித்தர்களை போன்ற யோகிகள் வாழ்வதாக சூப்பர்ஸ்டார் ரஜினிகாந்த் சொல்கிறார். 800 ஆண்டுகளாக சிலரது கண்களுக்கு மட்டுமே காட்சி கொடுக்கும் பாபாஜியின் ஒளி வடிவத்தை தானே பார்த்ததாக கூறுகிறார். இப்படிப்பட்ட யோகிகள் ஆயிரம் கிலோமீட்டருக்கு அப்பால் உள்ளவருடன் ஆன்மாவால் பேசும் அமைப்பை பெற்று இருப்பார்கள். இமய மலைச் சாலையில் தனது ருத்ராட்சத்தை இழந்து அதைத் தேடி அங்கும் இங்கும் அலைந்தபோது,  யாசகம் கேட்கும் சாதுவின் தோற்றத்தில் இருந்த ஒரு யோகி \\"ருத்ராட்சத்தை தேடுகிறாயா\\" எனக்கேட்டு அது விரைவில் உன்னை அடையும் என்று சொன்னதையும் அது போல அந்த ருத்ராட்சம் தன்னை அடைந்தையும் இன்றும் வியப்பாகக் கூறுவார். சிறுவயதில் எத்தனை தீயபழக்கங்கள் உள்ளதோ,  அத்தனையும் தெரிந்தோ தெரியாமலோ பெற்ற ரஜினி திருமணத்துக்கு சில ஆண்டுகள் பின்னர் அகவாழ்வில் இருந்து விலகி பரமஹம்ச யோகானந்தர் போன்றோரால் அடிப்படை யோகங்களை கற்று தூய இருதயத்துடன் செயல்பட்டதால் 72 வயதிலும் இளைஞனாக நடிக்கும் ஆற்றலையும் பொருளீட்டுவதிலும் முதலிடம் பெறும் நிலையை பெற்றுள்ளார்.புணர்ச்சியை குறைத்து, அளவோடு உணவை அருந்தினால் ஆயுள் கூடும் என்கிறார். அளவான உணவு என்பது அரை வயிறு உணவு கால் வயிறு நீர் கால் வயிறு காற்று என்பதாகும். உடல் அழியா நிலையை அடைய அறுபதுக்கும் மேற்பட்ட காயகல்ப முறையை கூறுகிறார்.  யோக முறையையும் கூறுகிறார். மருந்து வேலை செய்ய உடல் மனம் ஆன்மா மூன்றும் தூய்மையாக இருக்கவேண்டும். இம்மூன்றையும் தூய்மை செய்யும் வல்லமை கடுக்காய்க்கு இருப்பதாக கூறுகிறார்.அதனால்தான் ஔவையார்,தேவர் குறளும் திருநான்மறைமுடிவும் மூவர் தமிழும் முனிமொழியும் கோவை திருவாசகமும் திருமூலர் சொல்லும் ஒருவாசகம் என் றுணர் என்றார்.ஆயிரம் நூல்கள் சொல்லும் செய்தியை மேற்கண்ட நூல்களை மட்டுமே கற்று அறியலாம்.திருமூலரின் மூன்று நான்கு பாடல்களை படித்து விளக்கவே ஆயிரம் வார்த்தைகள் தேவைப்படும்போது மூவாயிரம் பாடல்களை படிக்கவும் விளக்கவும் ஆயுள் முழுதும் கூட தேவைப்படும். அதனால் வரும் காலத்தில் கொஞ்சம் கொஞ்சமாக இந்தக் கடலைத் தாண்ட முயற்சி செய்வோம்."},{"question":"Madoda! Namuhla ngithokoze kakhulu ngoba induna ayizukulalaesitokisini.Ndabezitha!Yize icala lingaphelile kodwa mina nginethemba ngoba lesi silimaesinguMbandlwa asinaye ufakazi. (iqondise kuDlamini) Awuthi qaphuqaphu ngesimo secala khona umkhandlu wami uzothola sonkeisithombe.(asukume uDlamini) Ndabezitha! Ngizoqala ngokubonga uNdabezithangokungikhokhela ibheyili. Mina bengizoyithathaphi inkulungwaneyamarandi? Ndabezitha nani bandla lenkosi, icala lokushayangiyaliphika ngima ngentaba. Ngithi, uMbandlwa ngamsikaza ngendukumaqede yena wagxuma wazishayisa echosheni lobonda lwekilasi.Okuhle kakhulu ngukuthi mina amadoda engangihamba nawoayangifakazela. Yena akanaye ufakazi ngoba ikhansela lalingaphakathiekilasini kanye nezethameli zomhlangano. Lihlehlile-ke icala. Liyozelingene emuva kwezinyanga ezintathu.(kuzwakale ukuhhomuzela kwentokozo abanye behleka)(inkosi yelule isandla sakumhlalisa phansi uDlamini) Hhayi-ke!Siyabonga Mzizi, ungahlala phansi.(ahlale phansi) Ndabezitha!Kunjalo-ke madoda. Mina ngeke ngimsole uDlamini ngoba leli khanselaliyangeyisa. Lake lakubonaphi ukuthi umfokazana angamane abizeumhlangano endaweni yenkosi engadlulanga enkosini?(ahhomuzele)Uyagcwaneka lo.Yisizwe sakho lesi Ndabezitha! Singakufela thina!(aqondise emkhandlwini) Yehlisani umoya madoda! Thulani umsindo,uNdabezitha usakhuluma!Mina ngiyasola uDuma usabambelele kulokhu okwenzekayongesikhathi sodlame. Angithi ngikhuluma nje ungomunye walabaabehla benyuka lapha endaweni yami. Begqugquzela ngenkani ukufakaleli dungabantu ababelibiza ngomzabalazo.1. Xoxa ngenkinga ababhekana nayo oMbandlwa noDuma ngosukulomhlangano. ","answer":"UDlamini wawuhlakaza umhlangano,√ kwagcina sekunokuphambanaphakathi kwakhe noMbandlwa kwaphetha ngokuthi uDlamini ashayeuMbandlwa. √"},{"question":"ايش معنى الجملة التالية \\"يجحت الاسمنت من على البلاط\\" بالفصحى.","answer":"يجحت: يقشر شي ملتصق بشي اخر ( يجحت الاسمنت من على البلاط)."},{"question":"Wanene sarki na farko a Kano?","answer":"Bagauda, Masarautar Hausa ta Kano ta kasance a kan wani tsohon mazaunin Tudun Dala. Yayin da a baya akwai kananan masarautu a yankin, kamar yadda littafin tarihin Kano ya nuna, Bagauda, ​​jikan jarumin tatsuniyar Bayajidda, ya zama sarkin Kano na farko a shekarar 999, ya yi sarauta har zuwa 1063."},{"question":"Napisz ciąg dalszy: - Eurokomunizm stworzył alternatywną drogę rozwoju ruchu komunistycznego w stosunku do partii komunistycznych bloku wschodniego. Zakładał pozostanie na gruncie marksizmu (ale reformowalnego), odrzucenie leninizmu (jako totalitaryzmu), ideologii rewolucji społecznej i dyktatury proletariatu. Głosił ideę tzw. „kompromisu historycznego” między klasami, którego politycznym wyrazem miało być partnerstwo Włoskiej Partii Komunistycznej i Chrześcijańskiej Demokracji. Odmawiał KPZR prawa kierowania ruchem komunistycznym (tzw. doktryna policentryzmu). Potępiał interwencje radzieckie na Węgrzech (1956), w Czechosłowacji","answer":"(1968) i w Afganistanie (1979–1989) oraz łamanie praw człowieka. Przeprowadził krytykę realnego socjalizmu. Zakładał, że socjalizm można wprowadzić w ramach demokracji parlamentarnej. Opowiadał się za systemem wielopartyjnym i pluralizmem. Popierał utrzymanie świeckiego państwa, ale przy zagwarantowaniu swobody religijnej. W polityce zagranicznej eurokomuniści stawiali na EWG i opowiadali się za stopniową likwidacją obu bloków wojskowych."},{"question":"ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ පළමු වරට ජනමත විචාරණයක් පැවති රට","answer":"1982"},{"question":"Atsakyk į šį sudėtingą klausimą: Kokie yra pagrindiniai fotosintezės etapai?","answer":"Atsakymas: Visas fotosintezės procesas susideda iš dviejų fazių - šviesos ir tamsos."},{"question":"વિહાર મજમુદારની \\"કુમ કુમ શું આભ ખુલ્યું\\" કવિતા લખો.","answer":"કુમ કુમ શું આભ ખુલ્યું લાગે, કે માડી અંબા ઉતરતી લાગે..દિવ્ય તાલ સુર મધુર રાગે, કે માડી અંબા ઉતરતી લાગે..મીઠી આ નિંદરમાં, ખિલ્યા ફૂલ શમણાંનાં,મ્હેક એની પથરાઈ શ્વાસમાં;માડી ની ઠમકંતી કુમકુમ શી પગલીઓ, જોઇ મેં શમણે ઉજાસમાં,હું તો સુતી ને ધબકારા જાગે.. કે માડી અંબા ઉતરતી લાગે..ભીનું ચંદન, ભીની શ્રધ્ધાની લાગણીનાંદિવડા પ્રગટાવવાની વારતા..ત્રિભુવનની પટરાણી અંબા જગદંબાની, આરતી નાં ઘંટારવ ગાજતાં,સખી હૈયે અનંત નાદ જાગે.. કે માડી અંબા ઉતરતી લાગે..કુમ કુમ શું આભ ખુલ્યું લાગે, કે માડી અંબા ઉતરતી લાગે..દિવ્ય તાલ સુર મધુર રાગે, કે માડી અંબા ઉતરતી લાગે.."},{"question":"Na mitologia egípcia quem é Sekhmet?","answer":"Filha de Rá e por isso, reflete o aspecto destrutivo do sol."},{"question":"පහත ගීතය සම්පුර්ණ කරන්න. බිංදු බිංදු මල් වැස්සේ තෙමෙන්නට එපාගලින් ගලට පා තබමින් දුවන්නට එපාගල් මතුපිට ලිස්සනවා පය පැකිලේවී","answer":"බිංදු බිංදු මල් වැස්සේ තෙමෙන්නට එපාගලින් ගලට පා තබමින් දුවන්නට එපාගල් මතුපිට ලිස්සනවා පය පැකිලේවීආල හැඟුම් මං හින්දා හිතෙන්නට එපාදෑස තෙමා ලන දුක් ගිනි නැගෙන්නට එපාදෙමාපියන් පිට ගමකින් මට බහ දේවීනිල් ලන්දේ ගම් මැද්දේ ඉද්ද සමන් ඉපෙනවාවෙල් බැද්දේ වගුරු පුරා කෙකටිය දළු දිලෙනවාගේ මැද්දේ බරණි පුරා වී අස්වනු පිරෙනවාහිත මැද්දේ ලොකු අඩුවක් මගේ සතුට මකනවාආල හැඟුම් මං හින්දා.....ගමෙන් ඈත සිදාදියේ ලොකු නුවරක් තියෙනවාමාල වළලු අරුමෝසම් එහි ඇති බව කියනවාදෙමාපියන් ගමෙන් පිටට මා දෙන්නට හදනවාසිදාදියෙන් කුමාරයෙක් මා බලන්න වඩිනවාබිංදු බිංදු මල් වැස්සේ.....ආල හැඟුම් මං හින්දා.....එඩ්වඩ් ජයකොඩි, නන්දා පතිරණ"},{"question":"السؤال: أقوى وأشد أنواع الحجارة صلابة، يسمّى؟","answer":"الإجابة: الألماس."},{"question":"वातावरणीय इन्जिनियरहरूले शहरी क्षेत्रहरूमा पानी प्रदूषणलाई कसरी सम्बोधन गर्छन्?","answer":"सहरी क्षेत्रमा जल प्रदूषणमा काम गर्ने वातावरणीय इन्जिनियरहरूले फोहोर पानी प्रशोधन, आँधी पानी व्यवस्थापन, र प्रदूषण रोकथामका लागि समाधानहरू विकास र कार्यान्वयनमा ध्यान केन्द्रित गर्छन्। तिनीहरूको लक्ष्य पानीको गुणस्तर सुधार गर्ने, इकोसिस्टमको सुरक्षा गर्ने र शहरी वातावरणमा दिगो पानीको प्रयोगलाई प्रवर्द्धन गर्ने हो।"},{"question":"この質問はどのカテゴリーですか：南北戦争正式に終わったのはいつですか？","answer":"質問の出典は「歴史」です。"},{"question":"ਵਾਰਾਂ ਭਾਈ ਗੁਰਦਾਸ : ਵਾਰ ੧ ਪਉੜੀ ੧੯ ਪੰ. ੧ਭਿੱਖੂ ਨਿਰਣਯਭਈ ਗਿਲਾਨਿ ਜਗਤ ਵਿਚਿ ਚਾਰਿ ਵਰਨ ਆਸ੍ਰਮ ਉਪਾਏ।ਦਸ ਨਾਮਿ ਸੰਨਿਆਸੀਆ ਜੋਗੀ ਬਾਰਹ ਪੰਥਿ ਚਲਾਏ।ਜੰਗਮ ਅਤੇ ਸਰੇਵੜੇ ਦਗੇ ਦਿਗੰਬਰਿ ਵਾਦਿ ਕਰਾਏ।ਬ੍ਰਹਮਣਿ ਬਹੁ ਪਰਕਾਰਿ ਕਰਿ ਸਾਸਤ੍ਰਿ ਵੇਦ ਪੁਰਾਣਿ ਲੜਾਏ।ਖਟਿ ਦਰਸਨ ਬਹੁ ਵੈਰਿ ਕਰਿ ਨਾਲਿ ਛਤੀਸਿ ਪਖੰਡ ਰਲਾਏ।ਤੰਤ ਮੰਤ ਰਾਸਾਇਣਾ ਕਰਾਮਾਤਿ ਕਾਲਖਿ ਲਪਟਾਏਇਕਸਿ ਤੇ ਬਹੁ ਰੂਪਿ ਕਰਿ ਰੂਪ ਕਰੂਪੀ ਘਣੇ ਦਿਖਾਏ।ਕਲਿਜੁਗਿ ਅੰਦਰਿ ਭਰਮਿ ਭੁਲਾਏ ॥੧੯॥","answer":"ਸੰਸਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਪ੍ਰਚਲਤ ਮੰਦਹਾਲੀ ਦੇ ਮੱਦੇਨਜ਼ਰ ਚਾਰ ਵਰਣਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਚਾਰ ਆਸ਼ਰਮਾਂ ਦੀ ਸਥਾਪਨਾ ਕੀਤੀ ਗਈ।ਫਿਰ ਤਪੱਸਿਆ ਦੇ ਦਸ ਹੁਕਮ ਅਤੇ ਯੋਗੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਬਾਰਾਂ ਹੁਕਮ ਹੋਂਦ ਵਿਚ ਆਏ।ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਅੱਗੇ ਜੰਗਮ, ਭਟਕਣ ਵਾਲੇ, ਕਰਮੀਆਂ ਅਤੇ ਦਿਗੰਬਰਾਂ, ਨੰਗੇ ਜੈਨ ਸੰਨਿਆਸੀਆਂ ਨੇ ਵੀ ਆਪਣੇ ਵਿਵਾਦ ਸ਼ੁਰੂ ਕਰ ਦਿੱਤੇ।ਬ੍ਰਾਹਮਣਾਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਬਹੁਤ ਸਾਰੀਆਂ ਸ਼੍ਰੇਣੀਆਂ ਹੋਂਦ ਵਿਚ ਆਈਆਂ ਜਿਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਸ਼ਾਸਤਰਾਂ, ਵੇਦਾਂ ਅਤੇ ਪੁਰਾਣਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਕ ਦੂਜੇ ਦੇ ਉਲਟ ਪੇਸ਼ ਕੀਤਾ।ਛੇ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਦਰਸ਼ਨਾਂ ਦੀ ਆਪਸੀ ਮੇਲ-ਜੋਲ ਨੇ ਕਈ ਪਾਖੰਡਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਹੋਰ ਵਧਾ ਦਿੱਤਾ।ਰਸਾਇਣ, ਤੰਤਰ, ਮੰਤਰ ਅਤੇ ਚਮਤਕਾਰ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਲਈ ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਬਣ ਗਏ।ਅਣਗਿਣਤ ਸੰਪਰਦਾਵਾਂ (ਅਤੇ ਜਾਤਾਂ) ਵਿੱਚ ਵੰਡ ਕੇ ਉਹਨਾਂ ਨੇ ਇੱਕ ਭਿਆਨਕ ਰੂਪ ਪੈਦਾ ਕੀਤਾ।ਉਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਕਲਿਯੁਗ ਦੁਆਰਾ ਕੁਰਾਹੇ ਪਏ ਹੋਏ ਸਨ।"},{"question":"Đoạn văn sau đang nói về vấn đề gì? Cơ quan Cảnh sát điều tra Công an quận Đống Đa, Hà Nội, đã tạm giữ hình sự Đoàn Diệu Linh (26 tuổi) và chồng là Hoàng Thế Vũ (28 tuổi) để điều tra về hành vi hành hạ người khác. Hai nghi phạm được xác định liên quan đến việc cháu bé T. (1 tuổi, quê Hà Tĩnh) bị hành hạ, ngược đãi, phải nhập viện cấp cứu. Theo cơ quan chức năng, ngày 21/7, mẹ cháu T. là chị H. (28 tuổi) thuê Linh trông con với giá 3 triệu đồng/tháng. Cháu bé được Linh và chồng chăm sóc ở ngõ 198 Xã Đàn, phường Phương Liên, quận Đống Đa. Trong thời gian ở với Linh, cháu bé sốt, quấy khóc nên bị vợ chồng Vũ dùng dây sạc điện thoại buộc chân, dùng que gỗ, búa nhựa đánh vào đầu, người; dùng chăn quấn người và lấy băng dính dán miệng. Ngày 26/7, nạn nhân xuất hiện tình trạng mệt mỏi, khó thở, sốt cao nên được Linh và Vũ đưa đi cấp cứu. Sau đó, Bệnh viện Nhi Trung ương trình báo Công an phường Láng Thượng về trường hợp của T.","answer":"\\"Đôi vợ chồng bị bắt tạm giữ vì hành hạ trẻ em tại Đống Đa, Hà Nội\\""},{"question":"السؤال: ما هي السور الوحيدة من سور القرآن الكريم التي ليس فيها أي حرف ميم؟","answer":"الجواب: سورة الكوثر."},{"question":"次の段落の内容を書き続けてください： 高知県中土佐町では、船から1匹ずつかつおを釣る漁が盛んです。中土佐町では、かつおがおいしい今の季節に、みんなでかつおを食べるイベントをしています。","answer":"今年は、新型コロナウイルスのことを考えて、会場に来る人を400人にしました。 会場では、取ったばかりのかつおを使って、いろいろな料理を作っていました。わらにつけた火で焼いた「わら焼きタタキ」や、おなかの部分を焼いた「はらんぼ」などです。 集まった人たちは、おいしそうに料理を食べたり、お酒を飲みながら楽しんだりしていました。家族と来た男性は「中土佐町のかつおは新鮮で、とてもおいしいです」と話していました。"},{"question":"సరైన సమాధానాన్ని గుర్తించండి.పత్రరంధ్రాల ముఖ్య విధిA) ప్రసరణB) బాష్పోత్సేకంC) కిరణజన్య సంయోగక్రియD) శోషణ","answer":"B) బాష్పోత్సేకం"},{"question":"A government rocked by frequent scandals is an effete set of people with no credibility.","answer":"exhausted"},{"question":"امتى قامت ثورة القرنفل و فين؟ وبالنظر للسؤال السابق، اكتب سياق يحتوي على الإجابة. ممكن يكون من 1 - 20 جملة. السياق:","answer":"منذ ثورة القرنفل في عام 1974 ، والتي بلغت ذروتها في نهاية واحدة من أبرز مراحل التوسع الاقتصادي في البرتغال (التي بدأت في الستينيات) ، حدث تغيير كبير في النمو الاقتصادي السنوي للبلاد. بعد اضطراب ثورة 1974 وفترة PREC ، حاولت البرتغال التكيف مع الاقتصاد العالمي الحديث المتغير ، وهي عملية مستمرة في عام 2013. منذ التسعينات، نموذج التنمية الاقتصادية في البرتغال القائم على الاستهلاك العام بيحول ببطء لنظام بتركز على الصادرات والاستثمار الخاص وتطوير قطاع التكنولوجيا العالية. نتيجة لذلك، تجاوزت خدمات الأعمال الصناعات التقليدية زي المنسوجات والملابس والأحذية والغبار (البرتغال هي أكبر منتج للغبار في العالم) والمنتجات الخشبية والمشروبات."},{"question":"ध्यान र भावनात्मक लचिलोपन बीचको सम्बन्ध अन्वेषण गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"ध्यान व्यक्तिहरूलाई तनावमा शान्त रूपमा प्रतिक्रिया दिन सिकाएर भावनात्मक लचिलोपन बढाउँछ। यो अभ्यासले समग्र मानसिक स्वास्थ्यमा नकारात्मक भावनाहरूको प्रभावलाई कम गर्दै राम्रो भावनात्मक नियमन सक्षम बनाउँछ।"},{"question":"Explique brevemente o algoritmo de Dijkstra.","answer":"O algoritmo de Dijkstra é usado para encontrar o caminho mais curto entre dois pontos em um grafo ponderado. Ele começa de um nó inicial e expande as fronteiras até encontrar o caminho mais curto para todos os outros nós."},{"question":"පහත පද පෙරළි වලට කෙලිනම් විසඳුමසංජු මාව","answer":"මංජුසාව"},{"question":"Qual a categoria da seguinte questão: Qual é o terceiro maior rio do mundo?.","answer":"Geografia"},{"question":"من هو أول من فتق لسانه بالعربية؟\\t","answer":"إسماعيل عليه السلام وعمره 14 عام."},{"question":"\\"100\\"  อ่านว่าอะไร","answer":"\\"100\\"  อ่านว่า \\"หนึ่งร้อย\\""},{"question":" Quem é o artista que recebeu o título de Rei do Rock?","answer":"Elvis Presley"},{"question":"Uthe angaqeda ukukhuluma nocingo lwakhe lolo, waluvala.'Baba nawe Mama, ithanda ukungesinda mina le nto. Lo mnumzane uthi ufunangimelekelele. Ungibalisela ngokuhlupheka kwakhe. Ungitshela ukuthiakanayo imali ngenxa yokuthi wadilizwa emsebenzini. Ungitshela ukuthiwethembele kimi njengomkhwenyana wakwakhe. Ungitshela ukuthi akanayoimali eyanele. Kuyacaca ukuthi uyabona ukuthi lo msebenzi ubhekene nayengqo. Uzama ukungifaka ngekhanda nje. Ngeke ngiyivume mina leyo nto.Ufunani kimi?''Uphendule wathini wena kuyena ngenkathi nixoxa?' kubuza uyise.'Angimethembisanga lutho Baba. Ngithe ngizobona. Okokuqala, yenaakafanelanga ukukhuluma nami. Kufanele akhulume nani, hhayi mina.Ngibona sengathi ufuna ukungiqinela ngoba azi ukuthi ngiyamhlonipha. Utheuzobuye ashaye emva kwesikhashana.Yinina okufanele nikhulume naye,hhayi mina.''Ngiyakuzwa lokho okushoyo, kodwa ngibona sengathi usezohlalelaethembeni njengoba wena uthe usazobona nje,' kusho unina.'Kulungile. Akahlalele kulelo themba lakhe aze ayofa njengoba esihlaliseethembeni kwaze kwafa omunye nje. Elami lithi, ngeke ngize ngifake ngishoelimnyama isenti. Ningamelekelela nina uma ninemali eningi. Lo muntusisanda kumnikeza inqwaba yemali. Akasebenzise yona. Ukuba wayidedelaingane yakhe, ngabe asihluphani ngalutho nale ndoda. Bengizozithwalangikhululekile izindleko zomngcwabo. Bengingeke ngimeme omunye umuntu.'1. Ukuba wawunikwe ithuba lokweluleka umukhwe kaMandlenkosikule nkinga ayebhekene nayo, wawungameluleka uthini? ","answer":"Ngangiyomtshela ukuthi akasebenzise imali yeloboloukungcwaba indodakazi yakhe.√√/• Ngangiyomtshela ukuthi akathathe emalini aphuma nayoemsebenzini uma imali yelobolo ingasekho.√√/• Ngangiyomtshela ukuthi kumele aboleke ezihlotsheni zakheuma ingasekho eyempesheni ngoba yena wayehlulekileukwakha ubuhlobo noMandlenkosi.√√"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"adat tua menahan ragam\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud orang-orang tua terpaksalah menahan rasa tidak puas hati terhadap perbuatan anak cucunya yang tidak mematuhi kebenaran"},{"question":"කෘතීම බුද්ධියේ පියා ලෙස සැලකෙන්නේ","answer":"ජෝන් මැකාති"},{"question":"Odpowiedz na następujące pytanie:Kto przybył na pomoc Trojanom?","answer":"Eurypylos"},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Rubuta ɗari biyu da ashirin da tara a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 229"},{"question":"Як можна позолотити метал","answer":"З давніх-давен і аж до кінця ХІХ ст. золочення і сріблення робилося амальгамним способом. Золоту амальгаму - \\"палене золо­то\\", або \\"зіртутник\\", отримували, нагріваючи золото із ртуттю. В одно­му рукописному монастирському збірникові ХУІІ ст. читаємо: \\"Знайди яшірку жовту живу (мається на увазі золото) і розітри з ртуттю, а ртуті щоб було шоста частка проти ящірки. Ящірку живцем запечатай у горщик з ртуттю і в натоплену піч у великий жар поклади. Потримай якийсь час, а тоді вийми й поклади у скляну посудину\\". Амальгамами вкривали очищені вироби, які потім прогрівали над жаром до повного випаровування ртуті. Позолочена поверхня мала ма­товий оксамитовий вигляд. Для надання дзеркального блиску виробові його поверхню полірували спеціальними полірувальниками (зубом) з агату, натурального вовчого зуба або іншого твердого матеріалу. Ще одним, не менш давнім способом є покриття сухозліткою - на­клеювання найтонших листочків золота на заздалеrідь підготовлену по­верхню. З винаходом гальванічного елемента з'являється електролітний ме­тод, заснований на використанні зовнішнього джерела струму. Для цьо­го застосовують різні електроліти й розчинні аноди. Коли занурити в електроліт метал, то в електроліті починають рухатися йони і виникає струм. Позитивні йони (метали) переміщаються до негативно зарядже­ного електрода (катода), а негативні (йони металоїдів і кислотних за­лишків) рухаються до позитивного заряду - анода. При гальванічному покритті катодом служать вироби, які треба золотити, а розчинним ано­дом - золота пластина. Як анод можна застосовувати і нержавійну сталь, але в цьому випадку в електроліт необхідно додавати солі золота."},{"question":"Which of the following composition represents energy rich food?a. Vitamins and mineralsb. Carbohydrates and fatsc. Water and roughaged. Proteins and mineral salts","answer":"b)Carbohydrates and fats are energy rich foods. They have high calories.Vitamins and minerals boost the immune system. Water and roughage (fibers) aids in digestion and excretion. Proteins are also energy rich food but mineral salts are not."},{"question":"Selahattin Demirtaş oy kullanabilecek mi?","answer":"Demirtaş'ın avukatı Mahsuni Karaman, Gazete Pencere'ye yaptığı açıklamada; Demirtaş'ın hükümlü olmadığını mahkum olduğunu bütün tutukluların istisnasız oy kullanabileceğini belirtti. Demirtaş'ın oy kullanması konusunda herhangi bir sıkıntının olmadığını belirten Karaman, “Oy konusunda herhangi bir sıkıntı yok” dedi."},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"இளைஞர்களின் சகவாசத்தாலேயே எனது உணர்ச்சி முதுமையை அடையவில்லை."},{"question":"Turunçgiller meyve ailesine mensup olan 4 meyve öner? ","answer":"Portakal, greyfurt, kan portakalı, mandalina meyveleri turunçgillerdendir."},{"question":"கீழே உள்ள பகுதியை பார்க்கவும், பின்னர் அதே மொழியில் கேள்விக்கு பதிலளிக்கவும்: இந்த தளம் குறைந்தது 1331 முதல் டோர் ஆ செயிண்ட்-லாம்பர்ட்டால் கவுசெல்ம் டி காஸ்டிலன் கட்டப்பட்டபோது ஆக்கிரமிக்கப்பட்டுள்ளது, மேலும் தோட்டமானது குறைந்தது 1378 ஆம் ஆண்டுக்கு முந்தையது. நூறு வருடப் போரின் போது தாக்குதலுக்கு எதிராக பாதுகாக்க 300 மீட்டர் தொலைவில் ஒரு காவல்படை கோட்டை கட்டப்பட்டது. கோபுரம், காலப்போக்கில் லா டூர் என் செயின்ட் மாம்பெர்ட்  மற்றும் செயின்ட்-மாபேர்ட்  என பெயர் மாற்றம் அடைந்தது, கோட்டையைச் சுற்றியுள்ள தோட்டத்திற்கு அதன் பெயரைக் கொடுத்தது மற்றும் 1453 ஆம் ஆண்டில் காஸ்டிலன் போர் வரை ஆங்கிலக் கைகளில் இருந்தது, மற்றும் பிரான்ஸ் மன்னரின் படைகளால் அதன் முழுமையான அழிவு. அசல் கோபுரம் இனி இல்லை, ஆனால் 1620 களில் ஒரு வட்ட கோபுரம் (லா டூர் டி செயிண்ட்-லாம்பர்ட்) சைமன் லெட்விட்ஜ் பெயரிடப்பட்ட தோட்டத்தில் கட்டப்பட்டது. இது உண்மையில் ஒரு புறா குழி என வடிவமைக்கப்பட்டிருந்தாலும், இது திராட்சைத் தோட்டத்தின் வலுவான சின்னமாக உள்ளது. இரண்டு நூற்றாண்டுகள் வித்தியாசத்தில் இருந்தாலும், இந்த கட்டிடம் அசல் கட்டிடத்தைப் பயன்படுத்தி கட்டப்பட்டதாகக் கூறப்படுகிறது. 14 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டிலிருந்து இந்த இடத்தில் திராட்சைத் தோட்டங்கள் இருந்தன, மேலும் லாட்டூரின் மது சில ஆரம்பகால அங்கீகாரத்தைப் பெற்றது, இது 16 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டிலேயே மான்டேக்னேயின் கட்டுரைகளில் விவாதிக்கப்பட்டது. 16 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டின் இறுதியில், தோட்டத்தின் பல சிறிய நிலங்கள் டி முல்லே குடும்பத்தால் ஒரு சொத்தாக குவிக்கப்பட்டன. 1670 முதல், தொடர்புடைய குடும்ப உரிமையின் வம்சாவளி தொடங்கியது, இது 1963 வரை உடைக்கப்படவில்லை, அப்போது தோட்டம் டி சாவனெஸ் குடும்பத்தால் வாங்கப்பட்டது, மேலும் 1677 இல் டி க்ளூஸெல் குடும்பத்திற்கு திருமணத்தின் மூலம் அனுப்பப்பட்டது. அலெக்ஸாண்டர் டி செகுர் மேரி-தெரெஸ் டி க்ளூசலை மணந்தபோது, லாட்டூர் அவரது பரந்த சொத்தின் ஒரு பகுதியாக ஆனார், அதில் அவர் தனது மரணத்திற்கு சற்று முன்பு 1716 இல் சாட்டோ லாஃபிடேவைச் சேர்த்தார். 1718 ஆம் ஆண்டில் அவரது மகன் நிக்கோலஸ்-அலெக்சாண்டர் டி செகுர் தனது நிலங்களுக்கு சாட்டோ மவுட்டன் மற்றும் சாட்டோ காலன்-செகுரைச் சேர்த்தார், மேலும் சிறந்த தரமான ஒயின்களை தயாரிக்கத் தொடங்கினார். 18 ஆம் நூற்றாண்டின் தொடக்கத்தில் லத்தூரின் பரவலான புகழ் தோன்றியது, அதன் நிலை இங்கிலாந்து போன்ற ஏற்றுமதி சந்தைகளில் லாஃபைட், மர்கோ மற்றும் பொன்டாக் ஆகியோருடன் நிறுவப்பட்டது. 1755 இல் நிக்கோலஸ்-அலெக்சாண்ட்ரே செகூரின் மரணத்துடன், தோட்டத்தை நான்கு மகள்களுக்கு இடையில் பிரிக்கப்பட்டது, அவர்களில் மூன்று பேர் 1760 இல் லத்தூரைப் பெற்றனர், மற்றும் இல்லாத நில உரிமையாளர்களுடன்,...  கேள்வி: செயிண்ட்-மோபெர்ட் எதற்காக கட்டப்பட்டது?","answer":"தாக்குதலுக்கு எதிராக பாதுகாக்க."},{"question":"Do you remember when we were reading https://te.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E0%B0%AD%E0%B1%81%E0%B0%B5%E0%B0%A8%E0%B0%97%E0%B0%BF%E0%B0%B0%E0%B0%BF%20%E0%B0%95%E0%B1%8B%E0%B0%9F the other day? It started sth like document_plaintext[:100].. Can you continue it for up to another 1000 characters?","answer":"ులోని నల్గొండ జిల్లాకు చెందిన ఒక మండలము. భువనగిరి ఒక ముఖ్య పటణం. భువనగిరిలో ఉన్న కోట కాకతీయుల కాలంలో మిక్కిలి ప్రసిద్ధి చెందినది. ఈ కోట పశ్చిమ చాళుక్య వంశానికి చెందిన పాలకుడైన త్రిభువన మల్ల విక్రమదిత్య (ఆరవ) చే ఏకశిలారాతి గుట్టపై నిర్మించబడింది. అతని పేరు మీదుగా దీనికి త్రిభువనగిరి అని పేరు వచ్చింది.ఈ పేరు క్రమంగా భువనగిరి అయ్యింది. ఇదొక కథనం.కోటలోని విశేషాలుతెలంగాణాను పరిపాలించిన అందరు రాజుల పాలనలో భువనగిరి కూడా వుండేవుంటుంది. చరిత్రలో పేర్కొనబడింది చాళుక్యుల కాలం నుండే...భువనగిరి దుర్గం చాళుక్యుల కాలంలోనో, కాకతీయుల కాలంలోనో బలమైనదుర్గంగా వుండివుంటుందని సుంకిరెడ్డి నారాయణరెడ్డి గారు తన తెలంగాణా చరిత్ర</b>లో అభిప్రాయపడ్డారు.చరిత్రలో పేర్కొనబడుతున్న షోడశజనపదాల్లో అస్మక (అశ్మక, అస్సక, అసక, అళక పేర్లతో) జనపదం ఒకటి. సుత్తనిపాతంలో ప్రస్తావించిన బౌద్ధశ్రమణకులు సముద్రతీరం వరకు వెళ్ళడానికి నడిచిన దారి ఇప్పటి జాతీయరహదారేనని చరిత్రకారుల అభిప్రాయం. అంటే భువనగిరి నుండే వారు వెళ్ళివుంటారు. తెలంగాణాలోని వివిథప్రాంతాలలో నాగులు, యక్షులు, అశ్మకులు, మహిషకులు, తెలుగులు వంటి జాతులు నివసించాయి."},{"question":"பெரியாரின் எழுத்துகளிலிருந்து  மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"ஐம்புலன்களுக்குத் தட்டுப்படாத விஷயம், பொருள், நடப்பு, எதுவானாலும் அது பொய் என்பதே பகுத்தறிவாளனின் கொள்கை."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe lamaody haingana?","answer":"Ny lamaody haingana dia manondro ireo fironana izay mahazo laza haingana nefa manjavona haingana."},{"question":"ప్రశ్న : దీర్ఘచతురస్రాకారపు కార్డ్ బోర్డ్ ముక్కను తీసుకోండి. సూర్యునికాంతిని లేదా టార్చ్ లైట్ ను ఉపయోగించి ఆ కార్డ్ బోర్డ్ ముక్కతో వివిధ ఆకారాల నీడలను ఏర్పరచడానికి ప్రయత్నించండి. తదుపరి ప్రశ్నలకు సమాధానాలివ్వండి.1) ఆ కార్డ్ బోర్డ్ ముక్కతో చతురస్రాకారపు నీడను ఏర్పరచగలిగారా?2) త్రిభుజాకార నీడను ఏర్పరచగలిగారా?3) వృత్తాకార నీడను ఏర్పరచగలిగారా?4) ఏ ఇతర ఆకారాల నీడలు ఏర్పరచగలిగారు?5) ఒకే వస్తువుకు వివిధ ఆకారాల నీడలు ఎందుకు ఏర్పడుతున్నాయి?","answer":"1. కాంతి వనరు ముందు దీర్ఘచతురస్రాకార కార్డ్ బోర్డ్ ను కొంచెం వంచినప్పుడు అది చదరపు ఆకారపు నీడను ఏర్పరుస్తుంది.2. మనం వస్తువును కాంతి వైపు క్రమంగా తిప్పినప్పుడు చదరపు నీడ త్రిభుజంగా మారుతుంది.3. లేదు. వృత్తాకార నీడను ఏర్పరచలేకపోయాము.4. దీర్ఘచతురస్రాకారం, చదరము, సరళరేఖ, రాంబస్, త్రిభుజం వంటి ఆకారాలను ఏర్పరచగలిగాము.5. కాంతి కిరణాలు అనుసరించే సరళరేఖ మార్గం కారణంగా, ఒక వస్తువు యొక్క స్థానాన్ని మార్చి మనం వేర్వేరు ఆకారాలను పొందవచ్చు."},{"question":"Που θα υπήρχαν αποδείξεις της εξάπλωσης του θαλάσσιου βυθού;[-] υψηλότερα επίπεδα αλατότητας στο νερό του ωκεανού· [-] ισχυρότερα ρεύματα στην επιφάνεια του ωκεανού· [-] ψυχρό μάγμα που βρίσκεται στην άκρη των πλακών· [-] υψηλότερα επίπεδα αναπαραγωγής για οργανισμούς στον πυθμένα του ωκεανού·","answer":"Ψυχρό μάγμα που βρίσκεται στην άκρη των πλακών."},{"question":"Ndiri kuchata, ndipei rondedzero yemabasa makuru andinofanira kuita kuronga chiitiko.","answer":"\\"Makorokoto nekuroora! Heino rondedzero yemamwe emabasa makuru aunofanira kuita pazuva rako rinokosha:- Sarudza zuva remuchato.-Gadzira rondedzero yevaenzi.-Sarudza nzvimbo yemhemberero uye yemabiko emuchato.-Sarudza kwaunoenda kuhoneymoon.-Sarudza maitiro ekushongedza kwezuva rako.- Sarudza chipfeko chemuchato kana sutu.- Tsvaga vatengesi vepamusoro.- Rongedza hutongi hwese hwemuchato.-Sarudza menyu yemuchato.- Sarudza nzira yekugadzika vaenzi.-Sarudza zvikomba, zvapupu, varoora uye murume akanakisa.- Sarudza keke remuchato.- Tenga zvindori zvako zvemuchato.-Tsvaga zvese zvishongedzo zvekutaridzika kwemwenga.- Vhara rondedzero yevaenzi.- Book barber uye runako centre.-Gadzirira kit yekukurumidzira.- Gadzirira sutukesi yeusiku yemuchato.- Gadzirira sutukesi yehoneymoon.- Enda unotora bridal bouquet.- Zorora uye unakirwe nemaawa ekupedzisira ega.\\""},{"question":"Frase 1: Por el mando de Kholm en la defensa, Scherer fue galardonado personalmente con la Cruz de Caballero de la Cruz de Hierro con Hojas de Roble por Adolf Hitler. Frase 2: Scherer fue galardonado personalmente con la Cruz de Caballero de la Cruz de Hierro con Hojas de Roble por Adolf Hitler por el mando de la defensa de Kholm. Pregunta: ¿Expresan la frase 1 y la frase 2 el mismo significado? - ¿Sí o No? - No lo sé.","answer":"Sí. Las dos frases expresan el mismo significado."},{"question":"Zdanie 1: W listopadzie 1989, Delaney był członkiem nowojorskiej giełdy i został starszym dyrektorem zarządzającym w Henderson Brothers, Inc. i Bear Wagner. Zdanie 2: W listopadzie 1989, Delaney został członkiem nowojorskiej giełdy i był starszym dyrektorem zarządzającym w Henderson Brothers, Inc., i Bear Wagner. Pytanie: Czy zdanie 1 i zdanie 2 wyrażają to samo znaczenie? Tak czy nie?","answer":"Nie."},{"question":"Cé hé Aleksis Kivi? ","answer":"Is é Aleksis Kivi, nó Alexis Stenvall, mar ab ainm dó ar dtús, bunaitheoir na litríochta Fionlainnise. B'eisean a scríobh an chéad úrscéal Fionlainnise riamh, mar atá, Seitsemän veljestä (\\"Seachtar deartháireacha\\")."},{"question":"لأى موضوع ينتمى هذا السؤال: مّن هو نجم فيلم سبايدرمان؟.","answer":"الجواب هو: ينتمى هذا السؤال لموضوع الأفلام السينمائية."},{"question":"آیا خوراکی های بدون شکر برای افراد مبتلا به دیابت آزاد است و به هر میزان که بخواهند میتوانند از این خوراکی ها استفاده کنند؟","answer":"خوراکی های بدون شکر یا محصولات دیابتی، خوراکی هایی هستند که در تهیه آنها بجای شکر از شیرین کننده های رژیمی استفاده شده است. اما با این وجود، این خوراکی ها ممکن است از ترکیباتی که حاوی کربوهیدرات هستند مانند آرد، نشاسته، شکر و … تشکیل شده باشند بنابراین همچنان قادر هستند که قند خون را  بالا ببرند. برای مثال در تهیه بیسکوییت های بدون شکر از آرد استفاده میشود که خود منبع کربوهیدرات است و می تواند برروی قند خون تاثیر گذارد.در نتیجه در صورت تمایل به مصرف خوراکی های رژیمی یا دیابتی همچنان باید تعادل را رعایت کرد و به میزان کربوهیدرات موجود در آن آگاه بود. برای آگاهی از میزان کربوهیدرات خوراکی های مختلف باید جدول ارزش غذایی آنها را مطالعه کرد."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"zaman tuk nadur berkajang kain\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud aman yang lampau; sudah lama sekali."},{"question":"“Miisa 63 ny Antenimierandoholona eto Madagasikara. Ny roa ampahatelon’ny loholona no fidin’ny vondrombahoakam-paritra itsinjaram-pahefana ary ny ampahatelony no tendren’ny filohan’ny Repoblika”. Inona ny fanontaniana?","answer":"Comment sont choisis les membres du Sénat de Madagascar ?"},{"question":"\\"मोनालिसा\\" नामक चर्चित चित्रका कलाकार को हुन् ?","answer":"मोनालिसालाई इटालियन कलाकार लियोनार्डो दा भिन्चीले चित्रित गरेका थिए ।"},{"question":"Pilih jawapan yang betul untuk soalan berikut. Apakah tindakan yang diambil oleh pemandu apabila warna lampu isyarat telah bertukar kepada hijau dan ada pejalan kaki sedang melintas jalan?A. Tunggu dan berikan keutamaan kepada pejalan kakiB. Memulakan perjalanan serta-mertaC. Bunyikan hon dan menegur pejalan kaki","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah A. Tunggu dan berikan keutamaan kepada pejalan kaki"},{"question":"Oyetọla gbe aba eto-iṣuna ọdun 2021 lọ fawọn aṣofin l’Ọṣun","answer":"Lọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ yii ni Gomina ipinlẹ Ọṣun, Gboyega Oyetọla, gbe aba eto iṣuna ọdun 2021 lọ siwaju awọn ọmọ ileegbimọ aṣofin.Oyetọla sọ pe biliọnu to din diẹ ni aadọfa naira, (#109.9b) nipinlẹ Ọṣun yoo na lọdun to n bọ.Ninu atupalẹ bọjẹẹti naa, owo-oṣu awọn oṣiṣẹ ati gbogbo nnkan to ni i ṣe pẹlu eto iṣuna ni yoo gba owo to pọ ju nitori nnkan to le ni biliọnu lọna mẹtadinlogoji naira ni wọn fẹẹ na le e lori.Eto ẹkọ ni yoo tun gba owo to pọ tẹle ti iṣuna, nigba ti ọrọ ilera yoo tẹle e.Ninu ọrọ Olori ile, Ọnarebu Timothy Owoẹyẹ, o gboṣuba fun Oyetọla pẹlu bo ṣe fi ọpọlọ pipe yanju eto iṣuna ọdun 2020 lai fi ti ajakalẹ arun korona ṣe.O ni kijọba wa ọna lati maa pawo wọle labẹnu dipo bo ṣe jẹ pe owo lati ọdọ ijọba apapọ nikan ni wọn n gbọkan le."},{"question":"Apakah kuih bakul?","answer":"Kuih bakul ialah makanan Cina yang dibuat daripada tepung pulut dan gula[4] lalu dibentukkan seakan seperti dodol. Sungguhpun kuih ini boleh dimakan pada bila-bila masa, secara tradisi kuih ini paling selalunya dimakan ketika sambutan Tahun Baharu Cina. Memakan kuih bakul dipercayai membawa tuah pada masa perayaan ini kerana namanya: \\"nian gao\\" (年糕) di mana perkataan 糕 (gāo) bermaksud 'kuih' dalam nama kuih ini berbunyi sama seperti perkataan 高 (gāo) bermaksud 'tinggi' melambangkan erti \\"tahun demi tahun semakin tinggi\\" (年年高升, niánnián gāoshēng) atau mafhum ringkasnya, \\"setahun lagi kehidupan, setingkat lagi kemajuan\\"."},{"question":"Gaweo crita anak-anak nganggo judul: Kethek, Pitik, lan Yuyu.Topik: Wong kekancan kudu apik marang sapada-pada.Wangsulan:","answer":"Ing jaman ndisik, ana satunggaling pitik kang kekancan karo kethek. Ananging paseduluran kuwi ora awet suwe amarga kelakuan si kethek. Sawijining dina, kethek ngejak pitik mlaku mlaku sinambi golek pangan. Nganti wayah srengenge angslep ana ing kulon loro kewan kul mau durung ugo nemu pangan kang bisa maregake wetenge. Dumadakan tanpa disangka lan dinyana kethek kang wis kadung ngeleh duwe pikiran elek marang kancane yaiku si pitik. Tanpa rasa mesakake kethek nyekel si pithik lan mbubuti wulune kanthi niat arep mangan mbakar pithik kanggo mangan wengi iku. Ananging mergo pitik terus-terusan usaha kanggo lolosake awake, akhire dheweke bisa ucul saka si kethek. Pitik banjur mlayu nganti tumeka sawijining pinggir segara kang dipanggoni sawijining yuyu sing ora liya ugo dadi kancane si pitik.Ana ing panggonan kul pitik cerita marang yuyu:Pitik: Hei Yuyu kancaku, tulungono aku, aku lagi diuber karo kethek sing arep mangan akuYuyu: Ora usah kuwatir kancaku, aku bakal nyelametke awakmu saka kethek kang ora reti arti kekancan kui mau. Aku bakal weneh pelajaran supaya kethek kui mau ora wani maneh ganggu awakmu.Sawise kahanan leren, pitik lan yuyu ngatur siasat kanggo weneh pelajaran marang kethek mau. Yuyu due ide nggawe perahu saka lemah lendut kanggo nyeberang ana ing pulau sacerake segara kui. Sawisi perahu kang digawe kui dadi banjur pitik lan yuyu ngundang kethek kanggo nyebrang bareng ana ing pulau sacerake kanggo golek pangan. Mergo kahanan ora ana pangan ing sakiwo tengene panggonan kui, banjur kethek langsung wae nyaguhi ajakane pitik kanggo menyang pulau seberang. Sawise prahu mlaku ana ing tengah segara banjur pitik mau kluruk sinambi notol prahu kang pada di tumpake kui mau. Alon-alon prahu kang digawe saka lemah lendut kui mau otomatis bocor lan banyu mlebu ing prahu. Ora bisa ditahan maneh prahu kang pada ditumpaki kui mau ambles ing segara. Pitik kang wis siap lan ngencanakake kedadean kui kanthi siap langsung mabur ing darat, yuyu kang ugo wis siap kedadean kui banjur nglangi ing dasar segara, sawentara kethek kang jahat lan ora reti arti kekancan kui mau amung bisa tulung-tulung lan angslep amarga ora bisa nglangi. Singkat cerita kethek kui mau mati glagepen ing tengah segara. Saka crita iki, bisa kita njupuk pelajaran yen wong kekancan kudu apik marang sapada-pada. Amarga kita ora mangerti kapan kita ugo butuh kanca sapada-pada."},{"question":"NSCDC gba epo tanka kan lọwọ awọn to n fọ ọpa epo ni Kwara ","answer":"Ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ni ajọ ẹsọ alaabo ṣifu difẹnsi, ẹka ti ipinlẹ Kwara, ri ọkọ ajagbe agbepo kan gba lọwọ awọn to n ji epo bẹtiro ni abule Afọn, Laduba, nijọba ibilẹ Asa, nipinlẹ Kwara, ti awọn to ji epo ọhun si sa lọ.Ninu atẹjade kan ti Agbẹnusọ ajọ ẹsọ alaabo ọhun nipinlẹ Kwara, Babawale Zaid Afolabi, fi sita ni ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, lo ti sọ pe awọn to n lọọ bẹ ọpa epo naa fere ge e nigba ti wọn kẹẹfin ẹsọ alaabo naa ni oru ọjọ Furaidee, lakooko ti wọn n ṣiṣẹ ibi wọn lọwọ. Niṣe ni ọkọ tanka agbepo to gbe epo lita ẹgbẹrun lọna mẹtalelọgbọn (33,000 litres), yii ṣubu lulẹ lasiko ti wọn n gbinyanju lati sa lọ.Ọga agba ajọ ọhun nipinlẹ Kwara, Ọgbẹni Makinde, ti waa ṣeleri pe ọwọ ajọ naa yoo tẹ awọn ọdaran yii laipẹ, ti wọn yoo si foju kata ofin, ti ajọ NSCDC yoo si ri i daju pe wọn daabo bo gbogbo dukia ijọba nipinlẹ Kwara ati gbogbo agbegbe rẹ."},{"question":"В каком году к СССР присоединился Таджикистан?","answer":"Таджикистан присоединился к СССР (Советскому Союзу) в 1929 году."},{"question":"Khi bị xơ gan, các loại thực phẩm nào nên kiêng kén?","answer":"Người bệnh xơ gan nên kiêng ăn đường vì có thể tích trữ mỡ trong gan, hạn chế ăn muối do làm tăng tích nước.Người bệnh xơ gan có thể gặp biến chứng tiểu đường, tim mạch do khả năng chuyển hóa đường, chất béo tại gan suy yếu. Do đó, nên hạn chế những thực phẩm dưới đây.Đồ ăn nhanh: Món này nhiều calo, muối, chất béo bão hòa nhưng thiếu vitamin, khoáng chất, chất xơ. Gan nhiễm mỡ quá mức có thể gây viêm, quá trình xơ hóa gan diễn ra nhanh hơn.Rượu bia, đồ uống có cồn: Người từng uống rượu có nguy cơ xơ gan gấp ba lần người bình thường. Rượu, bia có thể kích thích phản ứng viêm, hoại tử tế bào gan, thúc đẩy xơ gan tiến triển nhanh thành suy gan, ung thư.Thực phẩm nhiều muối: Người bệnh xơ gan dễ bị cổ trướng (tích nước quá mức trong cơ thể) khiến ổ bụng hay tay chân sưng to. Muối ăn làm gan tăng khả năng giữ nước. Bác sĩ khuyến cáo người bệnh hạn chế ăn muối, dưới mức 5,2 g mỗi ngày."},{"question":"ചോദ്യം: ഏഷ്യയിലെ ആദ്യത്തെ ആർച്ച് ഡാം ഏതാണ്? ഉത്തരം:","answer":"കുറവൻ, കുറത്തി മലകൾക്ക് കുറുകെ നിർമ്മിച്ച ഇടുക്കിയിലെ ആർച്ച് ഡാം ലോകത്തിലെ രണ്ടാമത്തെയും ഏഷ്യയിലെ ആദ്യത്തെയും ആർച്ച് അണക്കെട്ടാണ്."},{"question":"Sino ang kauna-unahang Pilipinong nanalo ng gintong medalya sa Olympics?","answer":"Ang kauna-unahang Pilipino na nanalo ng gintong medalya sa Olympics ay si Hidilyn Diaz noong Summer Olympics 2020 sa Japan para sa kompetisyong weightlifting at sa kategoryong 55kg."},{"question":"नेपालको प्रदेश नम्बर २ को बारेमा भन।","answer":"नेपालको प्रदेश २ (तराई प्रदेश) दक्षिणी तराईमा रहेका सबै जिल्लाहरू भएको एक मात्र प्रदेश हो। यस प्रदेशको भौगोलिक क्षेत्रलाई भारत उपमहाद्वीपको प्राचीन मिथिला संस्कृतिको उत्तरी भाग मानिन्छ। यस प्रदेशका आठ जिल्लाहरू धेरै हदसम्म समतल र धेरै उर्वर छन् जसको भूदृश्यमा बग्ने धेरै नदीहरू कृषि उत्पादकत्वका लागि आवश्यक प्रशस्त गाँसो जम्मा गर्छन्। नेपाली बाहेक, मैथली मुख्यतया यस क्षेत्रका मानिसहरूले व्यापक रूपमा प्रयोग गर्ने भाषा हो जुन धेरैजसो हिन्दूहरू छन्।प्रदेश दुईका जिल्लाहरुः पर्सा, बारा, रौतहट, सर्लाही, महोत्तरी, धनुषा, सिरहा र सप्तरी।"},{"question":"மல்லிகை சூடினாள் – ஆகுபெயர் கூறுக?","answer":"விடை: பொருளாகு பெயர்"},{"question":"Apakah cara memandu semaa hujan lebat?A. Membunyikan hon dan menyalakan lampu tinggi.B. Memandu dengan lau keraa takut sesak jalan raya nanti.C. Memandu dengan lebih berhati-hati","answer":"Jawapan yang betul ialah C. Memandu dengan lebih berhati-hati"},{"question":"I have ben.","answer":"I have been pulled over days now, into looking at various conceptual believes of cohabitation in a relationship. "},{"question":"Hãy viết tiếp nội dung cho đoạn văn sau: Kể từ đầu dịch đến nay Việt Nam có 10.779.632 ca nhiễm, đứng thứ 12/227 quốc gia và vùng lãnh thổ, trong khi với tỷ lệ số ca nhiễm/1 triệu dân, Việt Nam đứng thứ 112/227 quốc gia và vùng lãnh thổ (bình quân cứ 1 triệu người có 108.745 ca nhiễm). Tình hình điều trị COVID-19 1. Số bệnh nhân khỏi bệnh: - Bệnh nhân được công bố khỏi bệnh trong ngày: 7.877 ca - ","answer":"Tổng số ca được điều trị khỏi: 9.913.396 ca 2. Số bệnh nhân đang thở ô xy là 50 ca, trong đó: - Thở ô xy qua mặt nạ: 46 ca - Thở ô xy dòng cao HFNC: 2 ca - Thở máy không xâm lấn: 2 ca - Thở máy xâm lấn: 0 ca - ECMO: 0 ca 3. Số bệnh nhân tử vong: - Từ 17h30 ngày 30/7 đến 17h30 ngày 31/7 ghi nhận 0 ca tử vong. - Trung bình số tử vong ghi nhận trong 07 ngày qua: 0 ca. - Tổng số ca tử vong do COVID-19 tại Việt Nam tính đến nay là 43.093 ca, chiếm tỷ lệ 0,4% so với tổng số ca nhiễm. - Tổng số ca tử vong xếp thứ 24/227 vùng lãnh thổ, số ca tử vong trên 1 triệu dân xếp thứ 134/227 quốc gia, vùng lãnh thổ trên thế giới. "},{"question":"3/4 बाट 2/5 घटाउनुहोस् र परिणामलाई सरलीकृत अंशको रूपमा व्यक्त गर्नुहोस्।","answer":"भिन्नहरू घटाउनको लागि, एउटा साझा भाजक फेला पार्नुहोस्, जुन यस अवस्थामा 20 हो। त्यसैले, (3/4) - (2/5) = (15/20) - (8/20) = 7/20।"},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga _\\" maty kiambo tohin'ny olotra ozy ka eny ambon'ny tay no manao tsongolo _\\"","answer":" maty kiambo tohin'ny olotra ozy ka eny ambon'ny tay no manao tsongolo batiba"},{"question":"Qual è la domanda a: \\"È sposata con il consulente politico democratico James Carville\\"? L'argomento è Mary Matalin.","answer":"\\"Con chi è sposata Mary Matalin?\\""},{"question":"Schrijf een voortzetting van de zin: Tijdens de Hussietenoorlogen","answer":"behoorde hij in 1435 tot de coalitie van Silezische vorsten die een akkoord sloten met de Hussieten om zo zijn grondgebied verwoestingen te besparen."},{"question":"සාපේක්ෂතා න්‍යාය ඉදිරිපත් කලේ කවුද?","answer":"ඇල්බට් අයින්ස්ටයින්"},{"question":"TAMBAYA: Shin yaya za a rubuta ɗari biyu da hamsin da biyar a matsayin lamba?","answer":"Amsa: 255"},{"question":"Inona avy ireo antony lehibe nahatonga ny fianjeran’ny Fanjakana Romanina?","answer":"Ny fianjeran'ny Empira Romana dia azo lazaina amin'ny anton-javatra maro, anisan'izany ny faneren'ny fananiham-bohitra barbariana, ny fihemorana ara-politika sy ara-toekarena, ny fizarazarana ny Empira ho vondrona roa samihafa (ny Fanjakana Romanina Tandrefana sy Atsinanana), ary koa ny olana anatiny toy ny ny kolikoly sy ny krizin’ny vola."},{"question":"Huzursuz bağırsak sendromu ne tetikler?","answer":"Huzursuz bağırsak sendromunun nedenleri nelerdir? Enfeksiyon, gıda intoleransı, yeteri oranda lif içermeyen beslenme şekilleri, stres, antibiyotik, antiasit ve ağrı kesici gibi ilaçlar, alkol ve sigara tüketimi huzursuz bağırsak sendromunun bazı nedenleridir."},{"question":"Descreva a bandeira de Singapura.","answer":"A bandeira de Singapura é um verdadeiro retrato falado da nação. Lá em cima, tem uma faixa vermelha, que fala alto sobre igualdade e fraternidade, como se cada pedacinho do tecido estivesse dando um abraço fraterno em todos. Embaixo, a faixa branca vem como um sussurro de pureza e virtude, lembrando aquela paz e tranquilidade que a gente tanto busca.E olha só, no cantinho da parte vermelha, tem um crescente branco, meio que sorrindo, simbolizando um país que é jovem mas tá crescendo rápido. E as cinco estrelas brancas, ali, parecem dançar em círculo, cada uma representando um ideal precioso: democracia, paz, progresso, justiça e igualdade. É como se fossem cinco amigos inseparáveis, unidos por um propósito.Essa bandeira conta a história de um povo que olha pra frente, com esperança e determinação. É um pedaço de Singapura que voa ao vento, mostrando ao mundo o que essa nação representa e o que ela sonha em ser."},{"question":"Mace ce ta sha azumi amma ba ta rama ba kuma ga sabon azumi ya zo?","answer":"Wanda ta jinkirta ba ta rama ba har wani Ramadan ya zo, to ta tuba ga Allah (SWT) da wannan mummunan aiki da ta yi don bai halatta ba mutum ya yi jinkirin biyan azumi har wani Ramadan amma ba na biya sai a watan Sha’aban.” Wannan Hadisi na A’isha (RA) bai halatta ga mutum ya yi jinkirin abin da ake bin sa na azumi har wani Ramadan ya zo ba. Don haka ta tuba zuwa ga Allah (SWT), in sabon azumin ya wuce sai ta biya amma za ta ciyar gwargwadon azumin da ta sha, amma in ya wuce ta rama.Hukunci kan shan maganin hana haila don yin azumi"},{"question":"Bunga kebangsaan Malaysia mempunyai berapa kelopak? Pilih jawapan yang betul dari pilihan berikut.  A. 4 B. 5 C. 6 D. 7","answer":"Jawapannya ialah B. 5.Lima kelopak melambangkan prinsip-prinsip Rukun Negara."},{"question":"Inona no zava-nitranga tamin’ny taona 1897 nanehoana ny fiafaran’ny fanjakan’ny Malagasy?","answer":"Ny nahasesitany ny mpanjakavavy Ranavalona III tany Alzeria ny taona 1897 no zava-nitranga nanehoana ny fiafaran’ny fanjakan’ny Malagasy"},{"question":"पितृ तर्पण कोणत्या दिशेला करावे?उत्तर-","answer":"दक्षिण दिशेने"},{"question":"Mejuo ilu a:Adịghị asị onye maara ihe","answer":"Azịza:Pụta n'anwụIhe okwu a pụtara bụ na anaghị agwa onye mara ihe ihe oma okwesiri imere onwe ya. "},{"question":"ਉੱਭਰ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਤਕਨਾਲੋਜੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਨੈਤਿਕ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ ਕੀ ਹਨ?","answer":"ਉੱਭਰ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਤਕਨਾਲੋਜੀਆਂ ਨਵੀਆਂ ਤਕਨੀਕਾਂ ਹਨ ਜੋ ਅਜੇ ਵੀ ਵਿਕਾਸ ਅਧੀਨ ਹਨ। ਉੱਭਰ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਤਕਨਾਲੋਜੀਆਂ ਦੀਆਂ ਕੁਝ ਉਦਾਹਰਣਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਨਕਲੀ ਬੁੱਧੀ, ਜੀਨ ਸੰਪਾਦਨ ਅਤੇ ਨੈਨੋ ਤਕਨਾਲੋਜੀ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹਨ। ਇਹਨਾਂ ਤਕਨੀਕਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਸਮਾਜ ਨੂੰ ਬਹੁਤ ਲਾਭ ਪਹੁੰਚਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਸਮਰੱਥਾ ਹੈ, ਪਰ ਇਹ ਨੈਤਿਕ ਚਿੰਤਾਵਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਵੀ ਵਧਾਉਂਦੀਆਂ ਹਨ। ਉੱਭਰ ਰਹੀਆਂ ਤਕਨਾਲੋਜੀਆਂ ਨਾਲ ਜੁੜੀਆਂ ਕੁਝ ਨੈਤਿਕ ਚਿੰਤਾਵਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਸ਼ਾਮਲ ਹਨ:-ਇਹਨਾਂ ਤਕਨੀਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਦੁਰਵਰਤੋਂ ਦੀ ਸੰਭਾਵਨਾ-ਗੋਪਨੀਯਤਾ ਅਤੇ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ 'ਤੇ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਤਕਨਾਲੋਜੀਆਂ ਦਾ ਪ੍ਰਭਾਵ-ਇਹਨਾਂ ਤਕਨੀਕਾਂ ਦੀ ਅਸਮਾਨਤਾ ਨੂੰ ਵਧਾਉਣ ਦੀ ਸੰਭਾਵਨਾ"},{"question":"Ity misy ampahan-dahatsoratra: \\"any Afrika Atsimo: tsy mahazo mihoatra ny roa ambin'ny folo isan-jato (12%) isan-taona ny zana-bola alain’ny banky. Ny eto Madagasikara anefa mahatratra efapolo isan-jato (40%) isan-taona.\\"Araka ny voalaza amin' ny ampahan-dahatsoratra etsy ambony, inona no olana amin'ny zana-bolan'ny banky eto Madagasikara?","answer":"Mahatratra efapolo isan-jato (40%) isan-taona ny zana-bola alain'ny banky eto Madagasikara raha toa ka voafetra ho roa ambin' ny folo isan-jato (12%) izany any amin'ny firenena hafa."},{"question":"\\" શીંગોડા શીંગોડા \\" બાળગીત લખો.","answer":"શીંગોડા શીંગોડા, અમને આપો થોડાએક પછી એક આવો, નહિતર પડી જશો મોડામોડા મોડા મોડા\\tએક શીંગોડું એવું મારું, આખો દિવસ રડતુંએક શીંગોડું એવું મારું, આખો દિવસ રડતુંકજિયા કરતું, એં એં કરતુંકજિયા કરતું, એં એં કરતુંકહો એ તમને ગમતું?  ના ના ના!શીંગોડા શીંગોડા, અમને આપો થોડાએક પછી એક આવો, નહિતર પડી જશો મોડામોડા મોડા મોડાએક શીંગોડું એવું મારું, આખો દિવસ લડતુંએક શીંગોડું એવું મારું, આખો દિવસ લડતુંબટકાં ભરતું, ચિંટીયા ભરતુંબટકાં ભરતું, ચિંટીયા ભરતુંકહો એ તમને ગમતું?  ના ભાઈ ના!\\tશીંગોડા શીંગોડા, અમને આપો થોડાએક પછી એક આવો, નહિતર પડી જશો મોડામોડા મોડા મોડાએક શીંગોડું એવું મારું, આખો દિવસ હસતુંએક શીંગોડું એવું મારું, આખો દિવસ હસતુંભલે ને દુઃખ હોય કે ભલે ને સુખ હોયકહો એ તમને ગમતું? હા ભાઈ હા!  હા હા હા!શીંગોડા શીંગોડા, અમને આપો થોડાએક પછી એક આવો, નહિતર પડી જશો મોડામોડા મોડા મોડા"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"sungkei\\" dalam dialek atau Bahasa Melayu Sarawak?","answer":"Maksud \\"sungkei\\" dalam Bahasa Melayu Sarawak ialah buka puasa. Contoh ayat adalah seperti berikut:Contoh: Kitak sungkei sine hari tok?Maksud: Awak berbuka puasa di mana hari ini?"},{"question":"س215 - من الديانات المهمة في اليابان ومعناها الطريق إلى الآلهة ؟","answer":"ج215 - الشنتو"},{"question":"音楽の問題です。半音あげるのは「♯(シャープ)」、では半音上がったり下がったりした音を元に戻すのは何？","answer":"ナチュラルです。"},{"question":"Onde se localizam as runínas de Machu Picchu?a) Colômbiab) Peruc) Chinad) Bolíviae) Índia","answer":"A alternativa correta é: b) Peru."},{"question":"Từ “Nhưng” ở dòng 9 có vai trò gì trong bài Ông đồ Ngữ văn lớp 7?","answer":"- Từ “Nhưng” ở dòng 9 có vai trò dẫn dắt ý thớ từ khổ trước với khổ sau và tạo bước ngoặt trong cảm xúc của người đọc."},{"question":"සූන්‍යෂ්ටික සෙෙල යනු කුමක්ද?","answer":"ශාක, සතුන්, දිලීර, ප්‍රෝටසෝවාවන්, සහ ඇල්ගාවන් සියළුදෙනාම සූන්‍යෂ්ටිකයෝ වේ. සූන්‍යෂ්ටික සෙෙල, ප්‍රාග්න්‍යෂ්ටික සෙෙල පළල මෙන් පහලොස් ගුණයක් පමණ විශාල වන අතර, පරිමාව සැළකීමේදී දහස්වාරයක් පමණ විශාල විය හැකිවේ. ප්‍රාග්න්‍යෂ්ටික සෙෙල සමග සසඳන විට සූන්‍යෂ්ටික සෙෙල වල දැකගත හැකි ප්‍රධාන ලක්ෂණයක් වන්නේ, සූන්‍යෂ්ටික සෙෙලය පටල මගින් තවත් කොටස් වලට බෙදී ඒවා තුල විශේෂිත පරිවෘත්තීය ක්‍රියාවන් සිදුවීමයි. ඒ අතුරින් සූන්‍යෂ්ටික සෙෙලයක් තුල DNA ගබඩා කොට පවත්වා ගන්නා සෙෙල න්‍යෂ්ටිය විශේෂ කොට දැක්විය හැකිවේ."},{"question":"Quantos caracteres tem na seguinte frase: O amor é o que faz o mundo girar.","answer":"Essa frase tem 33 caracteres."},{"question":"Waxaad Sheegtaa  Nabiga Nnkh Yaa Ugu Hor Rumeeyey Caruurta Yar Yar?","answer":"Wuxu Ahaa Cali Bin Abuu Daalib Rc."},{"question":"Jawab soalan selepas merujuk kepada petikan berikut. Petikan: Tanpa bukti berekod mengenai harimau di hutan Laos selama hampir sedekad, laporan baharu daripada Tabung Hidupan Liar Sedunia (WWF) menyatakan haiwan berkenaan kemungkinan telah pupus di negara itu.Menurut Agensi Berita Vietnam (VNA), Laporan Kesan WWF terhadap Pemulihan Harimau 2010-2022 menekankan keperluan untuk tindakan segera dalam pemulihan harimau, terutamanya di Laos kerana dibimbangi mamalia itu mungkin pupus.Laos dikatakan adalah satu daripada 13 negara di dunia di mana harimau yang terancam kekal di alam liar. Bagaimanapun, carian meluas yang dilakukan dan melalui penggunaan kamera hidupan liar, tidak satu pun daripada haiwan itu dikesan di mana-mana di Laos dalam tempoh hampir 10 tahun.Walaupun kawasan hutan yang luas dan habitat yang sesuai, harimau tempatan itu sering diburu sehingga mengalami kepupusan, tambah kenyataan itu. Soalan: Berapakah negara di dunia yang dikatakan masih mempunyai harimau di luar? ","answer":"Jawapannya ialah 13 negara, termasuk Laos. Namun, berdasarkan petikan ini, terdapat kebimbangan bahawa mamalia ini mungkin sudah pupus di Laos tanpa bukti berekodnya selama hampir sedekad. "},{"question":"జంతువుల వర్ణకాలపై కాంతి ప్రభావం ఏమిటి?","answer":"జంతువుల దేహరణంపై కాంతి ప్రభావం చాలా ఎక్కువగా ఉంటుంది. తక్కువ కాంతిలో నివసించే జంతువులు లేత వర్ణంలోను, ఎక్కువ కాంతిలో నివసించే జంతువు గాఢ వర్ణంలో ఉంటాయి."},{"question":"बलियो वा कमजोर मुद्राले देशको अर्थतन्त्रमा कस्तो आर्थिक प्रभाव पार्छ?","answer":"बलियो मुद्राले आयातको लागि क्रयशक्ति बढाउँछ तर निर्यात प्रतिस्पर्धात्मकतालाई हानि पुर्याउँछ, जबकि कमजोर मुद्राले निर्यातलाई समर्थन गर्छ तर उच्च आयात लागतमार्फत मुद्रास्फीति बढाउन सक्छ।"},{"question":"Fehezanteny voalohany: Ny fianarana any amin'ny oniversite dia manome fahalalana sy fahaiza-manao sarobidy ho an'ny mpianatra ho avy.Fehezanteny faharoa: Ny olona sasany dia mety misafidy ny tsy hianatra any amin'ny oniversite ary mbola tafita amin'ny asa nofidiny.Mifanaraka ve ireo fehezanteny roa ireo?","answer":"Eny, tsy mifanipaka ireo fehezanteny roa ireo ary mifandray amin'ny fomba fijery samihafa momba ny fampianarana eny amin'ny oniversite."},{"question":"Hãy đặt một tiêu đề phù hợp với đoạn văn sau: Sở hữu hơn 430 ha đất thì không lừa đảo? Theo cáo trạng vụ án, 23 bị can trong vụ án đã vẽ ra 58 dự án bất động sản không có thật tại các tỉnh Đồng Nai, Bà Rịa - Vũng Tàu và Bình Thuận, tự phân lô, tách thửa trái pháp luật để bán cho 4.361 bị hại, chiếm đoạt số tiền 2.264 tỷ đồng. Nguyễn Thái Luyện bị cáo buộc là chủ mưu vụ án. Tuy nhiên cáo trạng nêu, bị can Luyện không thừa nhận hành vi phạm tội. Nguyễn Thái Luyện cho rằng mình không quảng cáo gian dối, không chiếm đoạt tiền của ai, không phân lô trái pháp luật. Toàn bộ giấy chứng nhận quyền sử dụng đất đều có quy hoạch rõ ràng; Việc phân lô bán nền được bị can chỉ đạo các nhân viên thực hiện theo đúng quy định của pháp luật. Đáng lưu ý là bị can Nguyễn Thái Luyện nói đang sở hữu hơn 430ha đất nên quy kết bị can về tội \\"Lừa đảo chiếm đoạt tài sản\\" là không có căn cứ pháp luật. 5 bước để trên 4.361 bị hại tin tưởng và nộp tiền Theo Cơ quan Điều tra, nhằm tạo niềm tin cho nhà đầu tư, Nguyễn Thái Luyện đưa ra các thông tin không có thật về các \\"dự án\\" do Luyện tự đặt tên trên đất nông nghiệp, chỉ đạo các đồng phạm thực hiện 5 bước để các bị hại tin tưởng và nộp tiền cho Luyện qua các pháp nhân, cụ thể: Bước 1: Nguyễn Thái Luyện dùng phần nhỏ tiền cá nhân và phần lớn tiền chiếm đoạt từ khách hàng chỉ đạo các cá nhân là người thân, nhân viên thân tín thuộc Công ty Alibaba đứng tên nhận chuyển nhượng đất nông nghiệp với số lượng lớn, tại các tỉnh Đồng Nai, Bà Rịa - Vũng Tàu và Bình Thuận. Bước 2: Những cá nhân đứng tên nhận chuyển nhượng đất như nêu trên lập hợp đồng ủy quyền cho các pháp nhân do Luyện thành lập để các công ty này tự vẽ \\"dự án\\" không có thật trên nền đất nông nghiệp, phân lô, tách thửa trái quy định theo chỉ đạo của Luyện. Bước 3: Sau khi nhận ủy quyền, các pháp nhân nêu trên với tư cách là chủ đầu tư các dự án \\"tự vẽ\\", không có thật trên nền đất nông nghiệp, phân lô, dùng truyền thông để quảng cáo bán sản phẩm. Bước 4: Luyện tiếp tục chỉ đạo các chủ đầu tư ký hợp đồng hợp tác kinh doanh phân phối bán đất nền trong dự án \\"tự vẽ\\" với Công ty Alibaba để Công ty Alibaba trở thành đại lý phân phối đất nền cho các khách hàng, nhằm mục đích che giấu nguồn gốc bất hợp pháp của các dự án; đồng thời tạo ra giao dịch ảo để khách hàng tin tưởng là các dự án có đủ tính pháp lý, đủ điều kiện chuyển nhượng theo Luật Kinh doanh Bất động sản mà đồng ý mua. Bước 5: Sau khi khách hàng đồng ý mua, theo sự quảng cáo của Công ty Alibaba thì Luyện chỉ đạo các pháp nhân đứng tên nêu trên ký hợp đồng thỏa thuận, chuyển nhượng quyền sử dụng đất cho khách hàng, nhưng tiền được nộp về Công ty Alibaba để Luyện quản lý, sử dụng. Theo TAND TPHCM, vụ án lừa đảo, rửa tiền xảy ra tại Công ty Alibaba là vụ án kỷ lục trong lịch sử tố tụng, đặc biệt là về số lượng bị hại với 4.361 người, 1 triệu bút lục và hơn 200 người được xác định có quyền lợi và nghĩa vụ liên quan. Hiện hồ sơ vụ án được đựng trong 140 rương ( thùng). Riêng cáo trạng vụ án lên tới 500 trang. Cơ quan tố tụng cho biết phải sử dụng 2 xe tải để vận chuyển hồ sơ. TAND TP.HCM sẽ căng rạp ở sân tòa, đồng thời liên thông hai phòng xử lớn nhất của tòa để tiến hành xét xử vào ngày 12/8 tới. Theo TAND TPHCM, vụ án lừa đảo, rửa tiền xảy ra tại Công ty Alibaba là vụ án kỷ lục trong lịch sử tố tụng, đặc biệt là về số lượng bị hại với 4.361 người, 1 triệu bút lục và hơn 200 người được xác định có quyền lợi và nghĩa vụ liên quan. Hiện hồ sơ vụ án được đựng trong 140 rương ( thùng).","answer":"\\"Vụ Công ty Alibaba: Bóc mẽ chiêu thức 5 bước lừa đảo khách hàng.\\""},{"question":"Конфедерация деген эмне?","answer":"Конфедерация- бул,  өзүнүн толук көз каранды эместигин сактаган жана конкреттүү белгиленген чөйрөдө бириккен, атайын органдарды түзгөн мамлекеттердин союзу."},{"question":"Jawab soalan ini: Kumpulan organisma mana yang dapat menunjukkan perubahan ciri yang ketara dalam tempoh masa yang paling singkat? Pilih dari: * bakteria. * burung. * Ikan. * Reptilia.","answer":"bakteria"},{"question":"\\"ഞാൻ എന്റെ ഹിന്ദി പരീക്ഷയിൽ പരാജയപ്പെട്ടു, ഞാൻ അത് വീണ്ടും എഴുതേണ്ടിവരും\\" എന്ന ഈ പ്രസ്താവനയുടെ വികാരം എന്താണ്?","answer":"ഈ വാചകം സങ്കടത്തെ സൂചിപ്പിക്കുന്നു, കാരണം പരീക്ഷയിൽ പരാജയപ്പെട്ടതിൽ വ്യക്തി നിരാശനാണ്."},{"question":"Hoàn thiện đoạn văn sau: Dù hoạt động miễn phí, người sử dụng cần có tài khoản trên nền tảng của OpenAI. Tại Việt Nam, siêu AI này cũng được quan tâm từ những ngày đầu, nhưng bất ngờ trở thành cơn sốt sau kỳ nghỉ Tết. ","answer":"Người dùng trong nước muốn trải nghiệm phải sử dụng mạng riêng ảo (VPN), thuê số điện thoại nước ngoài với giá khoảng một USD, dùng thẻ thanh toán quốc tế để đăng ký, hoặc mua tài khoản từ người khác. "},{"question":" Idan za a yi sallar gawa, liman yana tsayuwa ne a daidai kan mamaci idan na miji ne, amma idan gawar mace ce to zai tsaya ne a -","answer":" (a) a daidai tsakiyar ta (b) zai rufe kirjin ta ne saboda idanun masallata (c) zai tsaya ne a bayan ta"},{"question":"පළමු ඔලිම්පික් තරගාවලියේ ජයග්‍රහණය කළ රට කුමක්ද?","answer":"පළමු ඔලිම්පික් තරගාවලියේ ජයග්‍රහණය කළ රට ඇමරිකාවයි."},{"question":"Completa il seguente paragrafo:\\"Nata in una famiglia della media borghesia statunitense, si avvicinò ancora adolescente al mondo del varietà, debuttando come ballerina nel 1938. Nel 1941 sposò l'attore e ballerino Gene Kelly, dal quale ebbe una figlia, Kerry, e da cui divorziò nel 1957. Nel 1947 interpretò la sua prima pellicola cinematografica, \\"La colpa di Janet Ames\\". Con il ruolo di Clara Snyder in \\"Marty, vita di un timido\\" (1955), conquistò il BAFTA come migliore attrice internazionale, e ottenne la candidatura al...","answer":"...Premio Oscar quale miglior attrice protagonista.\\""},{"question":"Qui était l’artiste Yeesookyung ?","answer":"Yeesookyung, une artiste coréenne, est connue pour sa série « Translated Vases », où elle assemble des fragments de céramique brisée pour créer des formes nouvelles et saisissantes. Ses œuvres reflètent l'idée de transformation et de renouveau, mettant en valeur la beauté qui peut émerger des imperfections."},{"question":"السؤال: شنو هي السور التي بدأت بالحمد ؟","answer":"الإجابة: عدد سور القرآن اللي كات بدا بالحمد خمسة وهي: سورة الفاتحة، سورة الأنعام، سورة الكهف، سورة سبأ، سورة فاطر."},{"question":"Apakah jawapan untuk teka-teki berikut: Apakah yang ada di tengah rumah?","answer":"Jawapannya ialah huruf M kerana \\"huruf M\\" berada di tengah perkataan \\"rumah.\\""},{"question":"ம. சிங்காரவேலர் மேற்கோள் ஒன்றை தரவும்.","answer":"ம. சிங்காரவேலரின் மேற்கோள்:'புலியும் பசுவும் ஒரு துறையில் நீர் அருந்தினாலும் அருந்தும். ஆனால், முதலாளியும் தொழிலாளியும் சரிசமத்துவமாக தங்கள் தேசப் பொருள்களை, காந்தியாரின் சுயராஜ்ஜியத்தில் அனுபவிப்பார்கள்எ ன்பது பகற்கனவே.'"},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum Jordanie","answer":"Péeyum réwum Jordanie mu ngi tudu Amman"},{"question":"Tambaya: Mi ake nufi da \\"pineapple\\" da Hausa? \\t\\t\\t\\t\\t","answer":"Amsa: tana nufin \\"abarba\\"\\t"},{"question":"ফুটবল শব্দটি দিয়ে একটি বাক্য লিখ।","answer":"ফুটবল শব্দটি দিয়ে একটি বাক্য নিন্মরূপ:ফুটবল বিশ্বকাপ একটি অত্যন্ত জনপ্রিয় ক্রীড়া।"},{"question":"inona no atao hiarovana ny voly amin'ny mpangalatra?","answer":"mba iarovana ny voly amin'ny mpangalatra dia manao dinam-pokonolona sy ady amin'ny dahalo, izay tanterahin'ny fokonolona sy ny mpitandro ny filaminana"},{"question":"Quais times da NFL não ganharam um Super Bowl?","answer":"Browns, Lions, Jaguars e Texans"},{"question":"Jawab soalan berikut. Siapakah yang mengarahkan  album \\"Out of the Woods\\" dari Taylor Swift?","answer":"Joseph Kahn"},{"question":"ලොව ප්‍රථම බහුජාතික සමාගම","answer":"ලොව ප්‍රථම බහුජාතික සමාගම වන්නේ ඕලන්ද පෙරදිග ඉන්දියා වෙළඳ සමාගමයි."},{"question":"文中の主な言葉を見つけて、その内容を説明しなさい。 花粉が飛ぶと、花粉症の人はくしゃみが出たり目がかゆくなったりして大変です。東京都は、今年の春に杉とひのきの花粉がどのくらい飛びそうか発表しました。花粉は去年の2.7倍飛んで、調べ始めてから約40年の間で、4番目に多いです。花粉が飛び始めるのは、いつもの年と同じ2月13日から17日ごろです。花粉が多い日は51日ぐらいです。今までの10年の平均より18日増えそうです。花粉は夏の初めにできます。去年、このときに太陽が出ている時間が長くて、杉やひのきが大きくなりました。このため花粉が多くなると東京都は考えています。東京都は、マスクや眼鏡を使ったり、うがいをして手を洗ったりするように言っています。そして花粉症になったら、病院に行くことも大切だと言っています。","answer":"文にある主な言葉とその内容はこちらです。"},{"question":"குடும்பம் என்றால் என்ன","answer":"ஒரு குடும்பம் என்பது பிறப்பு, திருமணம் அல்லது தத்தெடுப்பு மூலம் ஒன்றாக வாழும் இரண்டு அல்லது அதற்கு மேற்பட்ட நபர்களின் குழுவாகும். அத்தகைய தொடர்புடைய நபர்கள் அனைவரும் ஒரு குடும்பத்தின் உறுப்பினர்களாகக் கருதப்படுகிறார்கள்."},{"question":"Awọn eeyan ya bo ibudo tijọba ko ounjẹ iranwọ korona si ni Kwara","answer":"Bi ki i ba ṣe tawọn agbofinro ti wọn tete da awọn eeyan to n gbiyanju lati wọ ibudo tijọba ipinlẹ Kwara ko awọn ohun iranwọ si lọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, niṣe ni  wọn iba palẹ gbogbo ẹ mọ.Ọpọlọpọ araalu ni wọn ya bo ibudo naa to wa ni Ilorin Cargo Terminal, lati le ri ounjẹ atawọn nnkan mi-in gbe, lẹyin ti wọn gbọ pe awọn janduku kan ti bo ibi tijọba ko awọn kinni ọhun si.Ṣe l’Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọsẹ yii, nijọba ti figbe ta pe awọn janduku kan tawọn oloṣelu n ṣe onigbọwọ fun, gbero lati fọ ibudo naa, ati lati ba awọn dukia ijọba jẹ.Lati ọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọsẹ yii, nijọba ti bẹrẹ pinpin awọn ohun iranwọ naa fun awọn to fara gba ọsẹ ti atẹgun ojo ati iṣẹlẹ omiyale ṣe laipẹ yii nipinlẹ Kwara. Ṣadeede lawọn janduku kan ya bo ibudo naa lasiko tawọn aṣoju ijọba n pin awọn ounjẹ naa lọwọ, ti wọn si gbiyanju lati da gbogbo agbegbe naa ru, ki wọn le ri nnkan ko lọ.Ọrọ ọhun di ohun tawọn agbofinro atawọn janduku n fa mọ ara wọn lọwọ titi ta a fi pari akojọ iroyin yii."},{"question":"Fan moy péeyum réwum Moldavie","answer":"Péeyum réwum Moldavie mu ngi tudu Chisinau"},{"question":"දීර්ඝතම ගර්භනි කාලයක් සහිත කිරිබී වැඩෙන සත්වයා  කවුද?","answer":"දීර්ඝතම ගර්භනී කාලය ඇති සත්වයා  ආසියානු අලියා වේ. ආසියානු අලියෙකුගේ ගර්භණී කාලය මාස 22 ක් දක්වා විය හැකිය, එය වසර දෙකකට ආසන්න වේ. මෙම දිගු ගැබ් ගැනීම සියලු සත්ව විශේෂ අතර දීර්ඝතම එකකි."},{"question":"In 1994, thosaigh Louis Antonelli ar thionscadal trí bliana chun an t-oibre is fearr de Film Noir, 'The Hitch-Hiker' (1953) a d' stiúradh ag an Ida Lupino legendary, a athchóiriú agus a athscaoileadh. ","answer":"Ar ndóigh, is é leagan níos casta den abairt \\"In 1994, thosaigh Louis Antonelli ar thionscadal trí bliana chun an t-ealaín Film Noir, 'The Hitch-Hiker' (1953 ) a athchóiriú agus a athscaoileadh, arna stiúradh ag an Ida Lupino legendary ag obair i gcomhar leis an Roan Group agus Leabharlann na Comhdhála.\\" "},{"question":"A que se deve a mudança das estações?","answer":"As estações do ano, ou sazões, são divisões do ano baseadas em padrões do clima e resultado da inclinação do eixo de rotação da Terra por 66,6º relativo ao seu plano de translação (23,4º em relação à normal ao plano). O eixo de rotação da Terra é a linha imaginária que une o pólo Norte ao pólo Sul e sua inclinação faz com que, em certas épocas do ano, um hemisfério receba a luz do Sol mais diretamente que o outro hemisfério."},{"question":"その場しのぎでごまかすことをたとえて、お茶をどうするという？","answer":"にごすです。"},{"question":"Omowumi Dada","answer":"Ọmọ́wùmí Dàda jẹ́ òṣèré ọmọ Nàìjíríà, tí ó gbajúmọ̀ jùlọ fún ipa rẹ̀ gẹ́gẹ́ bi Folákẹ́ nínu eré tẹlifíṣọ̀nù ti M-Net kan, Jemeji.  Ó tún jẹ́ ọ̀kan lára àwọn tó kópa nínu fíìmù èdè Yorùbá kan, Somewhere in the Dark ní ọdún 2017, èyítí ó gba àmì ẹ̀yẹ ti fíìmù abínibí tí ó dára jùlọ níbi ayẹyẹ AMVCA Awards ti ọdún 2017, fíìmù náà sì ṣokùn fa yíyàn rẹ̀ fún ti amúgbálẹ́gbẹ̀ẹ́ òṣèré tí ó dára jùlọ (ẹ̀ka ède Yorùbá) níbi ayẹyẹ Best of Nollywood Awards ní ọdún 2017 bákan náà.A bí Dàda ní Ìpínlẹ́ Èkó, níbi tí ó ti lọ sí Ìfàkọ̀ International Nursery and Primary School fún ètò ẹ̀kọ́ alákọ́bẹ̀rẹ̀ rẹ̀. Ní àkókò náà, ó darapọ̀ mọ́ Ẹ̀gbẹ́ Àṣà ilẹ̀ Yorùbá. Ó tẹ̀síwájú láti lọ sí Ilé-ìwé Command Day Secondary School, tó wà ní ìlu Oshòdì, fún ètò-ẹ̀kọ́ girama rẹ̀ sááju kí ó tó lọ kẹ́ẹ̀kọ́ Creative Arts ní ilé-ìwé gíga University of Lagos.Dáda bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ òṣèrè rẹ̀ pẹ̀lú ṣíṣe àwọn ipa kékeré ní àwọn eré ìpele ní àkókò ìgbà tí ó wà ní Ilé-ẹ̀kọ́ gíga. Àkọ́kọ́ ipa gbòógì tí ó ṣe lóri ìpele wáyé nínu eré Moremi Ajasoro, èyítí Fẹ́mi Òké ṣe olùdarí rẹ̀. Ní ọdún 2013, ó bẹ̀rẹ̀ iṣẹ́ fíìmù rẹ̀ pẹ̀lú ipa kan nínu fíìmù Òyà pẹ̀lú àjọsepọ̀ òṣèré Túnjí Sotimirin, lẹ́hìn náà ló tẹ̀síwájú láti ṣe ìfihàn nínu àwọn fíìmù míràn tó fi mọ́ fíìmù tí Kúnlé Afoláyan darí, Omugwo ní àjosepọ̀ pẹ̀lú Patience Ozokwor àti Ayọ̀ Adésànyà.Dàda ti ṣe ìfihàn nínu ọ̀pọ̀lọpọ̀ eré tẹlifíṣọ̀nù, tó fi mọ́ àwọn eré EbonylifeTv bi Married to the Game, Best Friends àti Dere, eré tí n ṣe ìbádọ́gba “Cinderella“ ti Disney ní ilẹ̀ Áfíríkà. Ó tún kópa nínu eré tẹlifíṣọ̀nù Mnet tí àkọ́lé r̀ jẹ́ Jemeji, ó sì ti ní àwọn ipa nínu Tinsel, So Wrong so Wright, Needles Eyes, Bella’s Place àti àwọn míràn."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Leupolz var en del av Tysklands trupp i","answer":"VM i Kanada år 2015. Hon fick speltid i alla Tysklands matcher i turneringen, förutom i gruppspelsmatchen mot Norge. Hon gjorde ett mål i gruppspelsmatchen mot Thailand."},{"question":"வினா : ரஷ்யாவின் தலைநகரம்?","answer":"விடை : மாஸ்கோ"},{"question":"Crie um verso contendo a palavra: Caminho","answer":"Verso: No caminho da vida, cada passo é um aprendizado,Em direção ao futuro, nosso destino é traçado."},{"question":"Q: A major step in animal evolution was the evolution of what rigid rod that runs the length of the body?Read this paragraph and choose the correct option from the provided answers:Another major step in animal evolution was the evolution of a notochord. A notochord is a rigid rod that runs the length of the body. It supports the body and gives it shape (see Figure below ). It also provides a place for muscles to anchor, and counterbalances them when they contract. Animals with a notochord are called chordates. They also have a hollow nerve cord that runs along the top of the body. Gill slits and a tail are two other chordate features. Many modern chordates have some of these structures only as embryos. Choices:- mitochondria- notochord- limbic system- endodermA:","answer":"The correct answer is notochord."},{"question":"ઓણમની પ્રવૃત્તિઓ જણાવો.","answer":"ઓણમ તમિલ લોકસમુહ દ્વારા ઉજવાતો પ્રસિદ્ધ તહેવાર છે ઓણમની ખૂબ મહત્ત્વાની બાબતોમાં બે વસ્તુઓનો સમાવેશ થાય છે, ઓનાક્કોડિ , આ દિવસે પહેરવામાં આવતા નવા વસ્ત્રો અને ઓણમ સાદયા , જે આ દિવસે ખાવામાં આવતી મિઠાઇ છે. સામાન્ય રીતે મિઠાઇને કેળના પાન પર ભાતની સાથે પીરસવામાં આવે છે અને તેને ૪ વસ્તુઓની શણગારવામાં પણ આવે છે. પરંપરાગત અથાણા અને પાપડ પણ પીરસવામાં આવે છે. મધુર વાનગીમાં મોટે ભાગે 'પાયસમ'(ખીર) હોય છે, જે દૂધ, ખાંડ અને અન્ય ભારતીય પરંપરાગત વસ્તુઓનો ઉપયોગ કરીને બનાવવામાં આવી હોય છે. ઓણમ દરમિયાન, લોકો વિવિધ રંગના ફુલોથી તેમના ઘરની સામે સુશોભન કરે છે, જેને પૂક્કાલમ કહેવામાં આવે છે. યુવાન બાળકો અને વિશેષરૂપે છોકરીઓને ફૂલોને એકઠા કરવાની અને તેને સરસ રીતે ગોઠવવાની કામગીરી સોંપવામાં આવે છે. ફૂલોની આ રચના બનાવવાની સ્પર્ધા પણ ઓણમના દિવસે યોજવામાં આવે છે. તે સામાન્ય રીતે ગોળાકારમાં ૧.૫ મિટરનો ઘેરાવો ધરાવતી હોય છે. ડિઝાઇનના ભાગરૂપે દિવડો પણ મુકવામાં આવે છે. તાજેતરના વર્ષોમાં, ફૂલોની ડિઝાઇનમાં કેરળના જીવનના સાંસ્કૃતિક અને સામાજિક પાસાઓને પણ દર્શાવતી પારંપરિક ગોળાકાર રચનાનો સમાવેશ કરવામાં આવે છે.વલ્લમકલી (સર્પાકાર હોડીની સ્પર્ધા) પણ ઓણમનું એક અભિન્ન અંગ છે. જાણીતી સ્પર્ધાઓમાં અરણમુલા બોટ રેસ અને નેહરૂ ટ્રોફિ બોટ રેસનો સમાવેશ થાય છે. આશરે ૧૦૦ હલેસા મારનારા વિશાળ અને સુશોભિત સર્પાકાર હોડીઓનો ચલાવે છે અને નજીક તેમજ દૂરના વિસ્તારોમાંથી પુરૂષો અને સ્ત્રીઓ પાણીમાં સરકતી હોડીઓનો નિહાળવા આવે છે. જેમ હિન્દુઓ ગણેશ ચતુર્થીની ઉજવણી સમયે ભગવાન ગણેશની મૂર્તિની સ્થાપના કરે છે તેવી જ રીતે ઓણમ દરમિયાન કેરળવાસી હિન્દુઓ ત્રીક્કાક્કરાયપ્પન (વામનના સ્વરૂપમાં વિષ્ણુ)ની ઘરમાં સ્થાપના કરે છે. આ તહેવાર કેરળના બધા જ સમુદાયોમાં લોકપ્રિય હોવાથી પણ ખૂબ મહત્વ ધરાવે છે. ઓણમનો તહેવાર હિન્દુ ધર્મ સાથે જોડાયેલો હોવા છતાં, આજે કેરળમાં હિન્દુઓ, મુસ્લીમો, અને ખ્રિસ્તીઓ દ્વારા એકસમાન ભાવનાથી ઉજવવામાં આવે છે. ઉજવણી દરમિયાન, કેરળના હિન્દુ મંદિરોમાં ઘણા દિવડાઓ પ્રગટાવવામાં આવે છે. મંદિરોની સામે તાડનું વૃક્ષ ઉભું કરવામાં આવે છે અને જેની આસપાસ લાકડાની થાંભલીઓ કરીને તેને સૂકા તાડના પાંદડાઓથી ઢાંકવામાં આવે છે. મહાબલિ બલિદાન આપીને નર્કમાં ગયા તે દર્શાવવા માટે તેને મશાલથી બાળી નાખવામાં આવે છે."},{"question":"Deze stad was tot in de 15de eeuw de hoofdstad van Denemarken. De stad werd gesticht rond 980 door Harald I van Denemarken. Hij zou een houten kerk hebben gebouwd bij de haven, waarin hij later begraven werd. Vanaf dat moment was de stad de verblijfplaats van de koning en hoofdstad van Denemarken. Wat is de naam van deze stad, één van de oudste van Denemarken, die ook om een andere reden een belletje zal doen rinkelen?","answer":"Roskilde "},{"question":"請回答這個問題：地球上最大的半島是哪個？","answer":"阿拉伯半島"},{"question":"Faarax Murtiile","answer":"Afkaba Daahisu Waa Dibnaha’ooLayidhi Kii Dabolan waa DahabeDabayshu Dhulkay ka DuushaDaruurta Cirkaana DaadihiseDadkana Dabar kiisu waa DiinRagana Dumarka Dugsoon u ahoHadanay Dadab Galin DabayshadeAdigu Diidaney Adaa DahaboQalbiga Dajiso indhaha DeeqdeSidii Dayax soo Baxaad tahayNaf Caashaqu DagoooKu Daydayaysaad Dabiib utaheDawee GacalooyAdoo qaba nabaradiisaJacaylka nitaaqadiisaQofaad unugushahay xagiisaMadaysid nasteexadiisaWaxaad neceb tahay dhibtiisaMa raadisid niyad jabkiisaNaftaadana waad kusortayNayayire waa agtiisaNasiib aad leedahay weeyeNolosha isagaad ku soortayNabdiga ruuxad kuhaysoNaruuro hadaad kawaydoWalina rajo naawilaysoJacaylku nusqaami maayoQalbigu nacab uma yaqaanoNaflaha wuu kaaga dhawyahayAdaan ka nagaan agtiisaWaayahoo cakirmaa cidhiidhi dhalooNasiib nin casuumay baa midkale ciileeRuuxii caydhnimo Shalay cawinaaMarbuu cawa dhalad noqdaa calanlooCadceedii dhalataba noloshu waa caynCurdin iyo hadaad caruur weli tahayDa’diyo cimriguba ruux bay cuskadeenAdoo caga qaba hadaad cabanaysoCuryaan waxa jira nolosha ku cadibanCiyaaro hadii caruus loo tumayCawayska midbaa ciidda lagu rogayCuudkaagu haduu adiga cimidh yahayTiriyo cadad maleh sabool caydhihiHadaad ku cawayso cisiyo nabadDadbaa ciil iyo colaad la ildaranDantoo ku cuslaysay ceeb maleheKu ceesh baryadaa cibaaro la’e."},{"question":"Биринчи диний мусулман мектептери кайсы мамлекетте пайда болгон?а)Египетте в)Аравиядаб)Индиядаг)Борбордук Азияда","answer":"Туура жообу:в)Аравияда"},{"question":"أجب على السؤال 'متى اصدر ماناك ماركوف الاغنية \\" امان هاير \\" ؟ ' بشكل مطول:","answer":"في 25 ديسمبر 2012 تم اصدار اغنية امان هاير من قبل تسجيلات موفيبوكس تحت عنوان ملك الشعبي وتحت العنوان الفرعي الاستاد ماناك وضم عددا من الفنانين يترجمون اغانيه، وتم عرضه أول مرة في جوائز الموسيقى لعام 2012 من قبل انجريج علي ."},{"question":"Orile Igboro kanjangbọn lọwọ awọn Fulani, wọn pa wọn tọmọtọmọ","answer":"Orile-Igboro, ilu kan ti awọn eeyan ibẹ ko foju kan oorun lalẹ ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee, ọjọ kejila, oṣu keji, ọdun 2021. Ba a si ṣe n kọroyin yii, ibẹ ko ti i fara rọ latari ibẹru to ṣi wa lọkan awọn eeyan, leyin ti awọn Fulani wọle tọ wọn lọwọ alẹ, ti wọn ṣa wọn ladaa tọmọtọmọ, ti wọn si yin awọn mi-in nibọn pa.Ilẹ Ketu ni ilu yii wa, ni Yewa. Awọn agbegbe bii Egua, Ijoun ati Ọja Ọdan ko jinna sibẹ. Beeyan ba kọja ibi kan ti wọn n pe ni Iyana-Mẹta. Ikọlu to si ti waye nibẹ latọwọ awọn Fulani tawọn eeyan naa fẹẹ le kuro nibẹ ko kere rara.Lati alẹ ọjọ Jimọ ti ikọlu yii waye lawọn eeyan ti n kede ẹ lawọn oju opo ayelujara, pe awọn Fulani ti ya bo Orile-Igboro o, wọn ti n pa awọn eeyan, wọn n dana sunle, wọn si n ṣa awọn ọmọde paapaa ladaa, bẹẹ ni ko si iranlọwọ kankan fawọn eeyan naa. Ko si agbofinro kankan nitosi, ko tilẹ si kinni kan to jẹ iranwọ, awọn eeyan naa ko sọwọ awọn Fulani to n gbẹsan ẹṣẹ ti wọn ko ṣẹ lara wọn ni.Nigba tilẹ yoo fi mọ, aworan awọn ti wọn wọle pa, awọn ti wọn ṣa ladaa atawọn ti wọn yin nibọn lo gba ori afẹfẹ, bẹẹ ni awọn eeyan n sọrọ abuku sijọba ipinlẹ Ogun lori ayelujara, wọn ni wọn ti kawọ gbera ju, wọn ko ṣe nnkan kan si ohun to n ṣẹlẹ yii, bẹẹ, bi ogun yoo ba ṣẹlẹ, bo ti n kọkọ ri naa ree, ibẹrẹ ogun leeyan n mọ, o loju ẹni ti i ri ipari ogun.Nibi ti ọrọ ọhun le de, ALAROYE gbọ pe wọn ti gbe Kọmiṣanna ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ogun, Edward Awolọlọwọ Ajogun, lọ sipinlẹ Plateau bayii. Jos ni wọn ni wọn gbe e lọ, bo tilẹ jẹ pe wọn ko ti i kede ẹni ti yoo rọpo rẹ nipinlẹ Ogun.Ẹ oo ranti pe ninu ọsẹ yii kan naa ni awọn Fulani paayan meji ni Owode-Ketu, bo tilẹ jẹ pe meji to foju han niyẹn ni, to jẹ eeyan mẹfa lawọn mi-in ti wọn jẹ olugbe ibẹ sọ pe wọn ku, bẹẹ awọn Fulani lo ṣigun lọọ ba wọn lọsan-an gangan. Niṣe ni wọn ti awọn ileewe ati ọna aje wọn gbogbo pa, nigba ti ilu ko toro, to jẹ kaluku n wa ọna ti yoo fi sa kuro nile ki wọn ma baa ba ogun ọsan gangan naa lọ ni.Ẹ oo ranti pe bawọn Fulani ṣe n daamu awọn eeyan ilẹ Yewa yii lo mu Sunday Igboho, ajijagbara ọmọ Yoruba nni, wa si ipinlẹ Ogun yii, apẹyinda wiwa naa lo di bawọn Fulani ṣe bẹrẹ si i koju awọn ọmọ oniluu bayii, ti wọn n kọju ija si wọn tọsan-toru.Ohun to n pa ọpọ eeyan lẹkun lori iṣẹlẹ yii ni pe ijọba ji giri sọrọ awọn to fẹẹ ṣewọde pe ki wọn ma ṣi Too-geeti Lekki, l’Ekoo, wọn ko ọlọpaa lọ sibẹ biba, wọn si n mu awọn ti wọn n ṣewọde wọọrọwọ lai lo nnkan ija kankan. Ṣugbọn ko sẹnikan to ji giri si ipaniyan to n ṣẹlẹ nipinlẹ Ogun, wọn ko mu Fulani kan bayii latigba ti ipaniyan ti n waye, awọn eeyan si n padanu ẹmi, wọn n padanu dukia wọn.ALAROYE gbiyanju lati ba aṣofin to n ṣoju ẹkun Yewa keji nile-igbimọ aṣofin Ogun, iyẹn Ọnarebu Wahab Haruna Egungbohun, sọrọ, niṣe ni nọmba rẹ n wa lori ipe mi-in titi, atẹjiṣẹ ta a si fi ṣọwọ si i pẹlu, ko ti i fesi rẹ ta a fi pari iroyin yii. Ṣugbọn ẹka iroyin oloyinbo kan ti wọn ni ọkunrin naa ba awọn sọrọ, sọ pe Egungbohun fidi ẹ mulẹ pe eeyan mẹrin lawọn ti ri oku wọn laaarọ ọjọ Satide ti i ṣe ọjọ keji ikọlu yii, ati pe awọn to ṣeṣe pọ, awọn ti wọn si n wa naa wa nibẹ pẹlu.Ṣa, ohun tawọn eeyan yii n rawọ ẹbẹ sijọba si latigba ti wahala yii ti n ṣẹlẹ ni pe ki wọn bawọn kapa awọn Fulani yii, ki wọn le wọn lọ tefetefe, ki wọn wa ibomi-in ti wọn yoo ti maa fẹran jẹko fun wọn."},{"question":"ايش اهم اللهجات اليمنية و من يتكلم بها؟","answer":"اللهجة الصنعانيةيتحدث بهذه اللهجة سكان مدينة صنعاء وما حولها، نطق حرف القاف مثل حرف g بالإنجليزية وينطق الضاد مثل الظاء كما أن حروف الراء والحاء والخاء تنطق مرققة دائماً ويبدل المتحدثون بهذه اللهجة الدال بالطاء في بعض الكلمات مثل «صدم» التي تنطق «صطم» أما بقية الحروف فنطقها مقارب جداً لللغة العربية الفصحى. كما تحتوي لهجة صنعاء على العديد من الكلمات ذات الأصل التركي وذلك بسبب التواجد التركي في صنعاء أثناء الحكم العثماني لليمن مثال على ذلك كلمة «ساني» التي تعني في خط مستقيم.اللهجة اليافعيةلهجة أهل الجبال الجنوبية، يافع أرض جبلية قاسية وعرة واسعة تمتد من الضالع غرباً إلى لودر شرقاً.اللهجة العدينيةيطلق هذا التعبير على المناطق اليمنية ذات اللهجة الشبيهة بلهجة أهل العدين وليس العدين فقط. تشمل هذه اللهجة مناطق مختلفة من اليمن مثل إب، العدين، مذيخرة، شرعب، صبر، ذي السفال، حبيش، بني عواض، السياني، جبلة، عتمة، سمة، ريمة، وصابين، بعض من الحجرية، بعض من حراز، رازح، الضالع ويافع. تتميز اللهجة العدينية أساسا بالاتي:كاف العديني: وهو إلحاق حرف الكاف «ك» في أواخر الأفعال الماضية نيابة عن تاء الفاعل والمخاطب «ت». مثلا يقال كنك، عملك، صنعك، فعلك، رجعك، وهكذا بدلا عن كنت، عملت، صنعت، فعلت، رجعت. وتعمم هذه القاعدة حتى في الجمع فيقال مثلا هل عملكم هذا أمس؟ ولا يقال هل عملتم هذا أمس؟. بالطبع هناك اختلافات أخرى في صيغ الكلمات والجمل ولكن لا تأخذ أهمية كبرى إما لكونها دارجة في العربية عموما أو بسبب حرج الكثير من استعمالها.يعد إبدال التاء بحرف الكاف من اللغة العربية إلاّ أنه نادر الاستعمال ربما وقد ذُكرت في العديد من كُتب اللغة. ذكرها ابن هشام في مغني اللبيب، وأبو الفتح عثمان بن جني في سر صناعة الإعراب فقد ورد أن عبد بني الحساس كان إذا أنشد شعرا حسنا قال:«أحسنكَ والله»، يريد أحسنت والله.وفي نشيد أبو علي «من الرجز»:يا ابن الزبير طالما عَصيكا وطالما عنّيتنا إليكالنضربن بسيفنا قفيكافقال: عصيك، أبدل تاء «عصيت» كافا."},{"question":"திருக்குறளின் வேறு பெயர்கள் என்ன ?","answer":"பொய்யாமொழி ,திருவள்ளுவம் ,உலகப்பொதுமறை ,வாயுறைவாழ்த்து, தெய்வநூல், முப்பால், தமிழ் மறை ,பொதுமறை, முப்பானூல் "},{"question":"Sheeg muddada uu uurka ku sido Nibiriga ilmihiisa?","answer":"Nibiriga wuxu ilmihiisa caloosha ku sidaa 365 Maalmood (hal sano)."},{"question":"నరసరాయనిపాలెం గుంటూరు జిల్లా, వినుకొండ మండలంలోని గ్రామం.  ఇది మండల కేంద్రమైన వినుకొండ నుండి 17 కి. మీ. దూరంలో ఉంది. 2011 భారత జనగణన గణాంకాల ప్రకారం ఈ గ్రామం 146 ఇళ్లతో, 597 జనాభాతో 509 హెక్టార్లలో విస్తరించి ఉంది. గ్రామంలో మగవారి సంఖ్య 300, ఆడవారి సంఖ్య 297. షెడ్యూల్డ్ కులాల సంఖ్య 8 కాగా షెడ్యూల్డ్ తెగల సంఖ్య 116. గ్రామం యొక్క జనగణన లొకేషన్ కోడ్ 590073[1].పిన్ కోడ్: 522647.డ","answer":"నరసరాయనిపాలెం"},{"question":"Miksi teiden varsille on vedetty keltaista nauhaa?","answer":"Hirvinauha on muovista nauhaa, joka asennetaan metsänreunaan aitamaisesti. Hirvinauha on koettu kustannustehokkaaksi tavaksi keinoksi vähentää hirvionnettomuuksia, koska nauhan asentaminen ja ylläpitäminen tulee maksamaan ainoastaan muutamia satoja euroja per kilometri. Vertailukohtana kannattaa käyttää riista-aitaa, jonka rakentamiskustannukset ovat 20 000 – 30 000 euroa per kilometri.Nauhajaksot toteutetaan paikallisten metsästysseurojen ja tienpitäjän yhteistyönä ja seurat sitoutuvat ylläpitämään hirvinauhajaksoa. Ylläpitoon liitetään usein metsänreunan aluskasvillisuuden raivaustöitä, mikä osaltaan parantaa turvallisuutta.Hirvinauhojen on todettu ohjaavan hirvien liikkumista. Havaittuaan nauhan hirvi hidastaa kulkuaan tai mahdollisesti kääntyy ylittämättä tietä. Myös autoilijat ovat kertoneet valpastuvansa havainnoimaan metsänreunoissa mahdollisesti tapahtuvaa liikettä hirvinauhajaksojen kohdalla.Hirvinauhalla ei kyetä estämään hirvien liikkumista ajoradalle kuten riista-aidoilla, mutta sen asentaminen on huomattavasti edullisempaa. Tästä syystä nauhaa on perusteltua käyttää sellaisilla tiejaksoilla, joilla hirvionnettomuusriski on suuri, mutta jonne ei nykytilanteessa ole mahdollista toteuttaa riista-aitaa taloudellisista tai muista syistä johtuen."},{"question":"‘స్త్రీలే ప్రధానమైన చరిత్ర నిర్మాతలు’ – సమర్థించండి.","answer":"20వ శతాబ్దపు సామాజికాభివృద్ధిలో, సామాజిక మార్పులలో, స్త్రీలకు కల భాగస్వామ్యాన్ని గురించి ఆలోచిస్తే, ఎన్నో విషయాలు మహిళావరణం సంపాదకుల ముందుకు వచ్చాయి. 20వ శతాబ్దాన్ని స్త్రీల శతాబ్దంగా చెప్పవచ్చునని వారికి అనిపించింది. జరిగిన శతాబ్దం చరిత్ర నిర్మాతలుగా, స్త్రీలకు తిరుగులేని స్థానం ఉందని వారికి అనిపించింది.గడిచిన 20వ శతాబ్దంలో స్త్రీలు చేసిన పోరాటాలు, వారు పాలుపంచుకున్న ఉద్యమాలు, వారు రాణించిన రంగాలు ఎన్నో ఉన్నాయి. 20వ శతాబ్దంలో మొదటిసారి చదువుకున్న స్త్రీలు, మొదటి వితంతు వివాహం చేసుకున్న సాహసురాండ్రు, స్త్రీ విద్య కావాలని, ఉద్యమించిన స్త్రీలు, ఉద్యమాలు చేసి జైలుకు వెళ్ళిన స్త్రీలూ ఉన్నారు. నాటకం, సినిమా, రేడియో, వంటి రంగాలలో స్త్రీలు మొదటిసారిగా 20వ శతాబ్దంలోనే అడుగుపెట్టారు. స్త్రీలలో ఎందరో మొదటితరం డాక్టర్లు, శాస్త్రవేత్తలు, కళాకారిణులు, విద్యాధికులు నాడు ఉన్నారు.శరీరం పులకరింపజేసే ఎందరో సాహసమూర్తులు, ఆ శతాబ్దంలోనే ఉన్నారు. అందువల్లనే 20వ శతాబ్దంలో స్త్రీలే .. ప్రధానమైన చరిత్ర నిర్మాతలు అని చెప్పవచ్చు."},{"question":"\\"વખાણેલી ખીચડી દાંતે વળગે\\"  કહેવતનો અર્થ સમજાવો.","answer":"\\"વખાણેલી ખીચડી દાંતે વળગે\\" કહેવતનો અર્થ :ઘણીવાર વખાણેલી જ વસ્તુ કે વ્યક્તિ ખરાબ નીકળે"},{"question":"バス、デスカント、アルト、ソプラノなどの種類がある、ここにいる皆さんはおそらく大半の人が触ったことがあるであろう楽器は何？","answer":"リコーダー"},{"question":"Ndàx mbind mii jub na?Wóor na ne danga leen fekk ñoom [Yahuud ya] ñu nekk di ñu gën a xér ci nit ñi ci bëgg dundu, ak ci ñiy bokkaale. [Danga ca gis] ca ñoom ku ne siiw ñu guddal fanam junniy at. Waaye du ko soreel mbugal ma! Dundu gu guddu googu Yàllaa ngi ne jàkk ci li ñuy def.","answer":"Déedet; jubul cocc ba coset. Mbeqi ma a ngii:Wóor na ne da nga léen fekk ñoom [Yahuud ya] ñu nekk di ñu gën a xér ci nit ñi ci bëgg dund, ak ci ñi'y bokkaale. [Da nga ca gis] ca ñoom ku ne sìiw ñu guddal fanam junniy àt. Waaye du ko soreel mbugal ma! Dund gu gudd googu Yàllaa ngi ne jàkk ci li ñu'y def."},{"question":"Kodi chamba ndi chololezedwa?","answer":"Kuyambira kumayambiriro kwa zaka za zana la 20 century, mayiko ambiri akhazikitsa malamulo oletsa kulima, kukhala ndi kapena kusamutsa chamba. Malamulowa adasokoneza kulima chamba pazinthu zosasangalatsa, koma pali madera ambiri komwe kugwiritsira ntchito chamba ndikovomerezeka kapena kuli ndi chilolezo. Maboma ambiri achepetsa zilango zopezeka ndi chamba chochepa kotero kuti amalangidwa polandidwa komanso nthawi zina chindapusa, m'malo momangidwa, kuyang'ana kwambiri omwe amagulitsa mankhwalawa pamsika wakuda.M'madera ena omwe kale anthu ankaloledwa kugwiritsa ntchito chamba, ziletso zatsopano zinakhazikitsidwa, monga kutsekedwa kwa malo ogulitsira khofi wa chamba pafupi ndi malire a Netherlands, komanso kutseka kwa malo ogulitsira khofi pafupi ndi masukulu akusekondale ku Netherlands. Ku Copenhagen, Denmark mu 2014, meya a Frank Jensen adakambirana za kuthekera kwa mzindawu kuvomereza mwalamulo kupanga chamba ndi malonda.M'madera ena amagwiritsa ntchito mapulogalamu aulere odzifunira komanso/kapena zovomerezeka zochizira anthu odziwika. Kukhala m'ndende kutha kukhala m'ndende nthawi yayitali m'maiko ena, makamaka ku East Asia, komwe kugulitsa chamba kumatha kupangitsa kuti akhale m'ndende moyo wonse kapena kunyongedwa. Zipani zandale, mabungwe osachita phindu, ndi zoyambitsa kutengera kuvomerezeka kwa chamba yachipatala komanso/kapena kuvomerezeka kwa mbewuyo (ndi zoletsa zina) zatulukira m'maiko monga China ndi Thailand."},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 今年は、関東大震災から100年です。亡くなった人と行方不明の人は10万人以上います。この中の90%の人は火事が原因です。東京の秋葉原駅の近くに、ポンプがある建物が残っていました。関東大震災の1年前にできたポンプ所です。関東大震災では、この建物の周りのほとんどの場所が火事で焼けました。しかし、この建物がある町と隣の町の一部だけが焼けませんでした。専門家は、町の人がポンプを使って一生懸命火を消したことも、町を守った理由だと言っています。ポンプ所は6年前まで使っていましたが、壊すことになって工事が始まりました。この町の76歳の男性は「このポンプ所の水を使ってみんなで火を消した話は、よく聞きました。なくなるのは寂しいですが、町は変わっていくので、しかたがないと思います」と話しました。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。- 関東大震災: 1）1923年（大正十二年）九月一日、関東地方をおそった大地震。火事による被害が大きく、死者九万九千人になった。- 行方不明: 1）どこに行ったのかわからないこと。- ポンプ: 1）水や油などを低い所から高い所へ上げたり、一か所から他へ送ったりするのに使う機械。- 一部: 1）全体の中の、ある部分。2）新聞や雑誌などを数えるときの、一つ。- 守っ: 1）害を受けないように、防ぐ。2）決めたとおりにする。- 工事: 1）建物・道路・橋などを造ったり、直したりすること。また、その仕事。- しかたがない: 1）他によい方法がない。2）よくない。しようがない。3）たまらない。"},{"question":"صحابي قتلو صفوان ابن اميه بيديه فماسه الرجيع والمشركون بغاو يمثلوا بالجثه ديالو فحماه ظل من الدبابير وما قدروش المشركون يديروا ذاك الشي اللي بغاو.. شكون هو؟","answer":"زيد بن الدثنة"},{"question":"Nitori ipolongo to ṣe fun Fayẹmi, awọn aṣofin fun alaga ijọba ibilẹ Ikẹrẹ niwee gbele-ẹ","answer":"Ile-igbimọ aṣofin ipinlẹ Ekiti ti fun alaga ijọba ibilẹ Ikẹrẹ, Ọnarebu Fẹmi Ayọdele, niwee gbele-ẹ lẹyin ọjọ diẹ to polongo atilẹyin fun iyansipo Gomina Kayọde Fayẹmi gẹgẹ bii aarẹ ilẹ yii lọdun 2020.Ayọdele lo gbe igbesẹ naa pẹlu awọn iwe ipolongo to gbe sori intanẹẹti, eyi to ti da wahala silẹ laarin awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ ati lagbo oṣelu kaakiri ilẹ yii.Ṣaaju loun funra ẹ ti sọ pe oun ṣe ipolongo naa lati fi atilẹyin han fun Fayẹmi, ẹni tawọn kan ro pe oun ko fẹran, ati pe ootọ inu loun fi ṣe e. Ṣugbọn latigba tọrọ naa ti di wahala lo ti dakẹ, ko si ba ẹnikẹni sọrọ lori rogbodiyan ọhun mọ.Bakan naa ni Fayẹmi kede pe oun ko mọ nnkan kan nipa igbesẹ ọhun, bẹẹ ni inu oun ko dun si i nitori o da nnkan toun ko reti silẹ. O ni ọrọ idagbasoke Ekiti lo jẹ oun logun lasiko yii, ki i ṣe ibo 2023.Lonii ni ile igbimọ aṣofin labẹ idari abẹnugan wọn, Ọnarebu Funminiyi Afuyẹ, sọ pe ki Ayọdele lọọ sinmi nile titi ti iwadii yoo fi pari lori iwa to hu, eyi to lodi sọfin.Olori ọmọ ile to pọ ju, Ọnarebu Gboyega Aribiṣogan, lo gbe aba naa kalẹ, bẹẹ ni Ọnarebu Tajudeen Akingbolu kin in lẹyin, bẹẹ lawọn mi-in sọ pe abuku gbaa ni nnkan ti alaga ọhun ṣe jẹ fun Fayẹmi.Ile naa waa gbe iṣẹ iwadii ijinlẹ fun igbimọ to n ri si ijọba ibilẹ ati oye jijẹ, wọn yoo si jabọ laarin ọsẹ kan."},{"question":"Hòn đảo nào có loài thằn lằn lớn nhất còn sống trên thế giới?Chọn câu trả lời đúng cho câu hỏi trên trong những câu sau:A. Đảo JavaB. Đảo KomodoC. Đảo Sumatra","answer":"Đáp án B. Đảo KomodoGiải thích: Đảo Komodo nằm trong vườn quốc gia Komodo, diện tích khoảng 390 km2 và có 2.000 người sinh sống. Hòn đảo này được đặt theo tên của một loài thằn lằn giống khủng long khổng lồ đang bị đe dọa tuyệt chủng là rồng Komodo.Loài đặc hữu của Indonesia này đi lang thang trên các đảo Đông Nusa Tenggara. Nó có kích thước khổng lồ, có thể cao tới 3 m và đạt trọng lượng khoảng 135 kg.Theo website của Bảo tàng thiên nhiên Mỹ, rồng Komodo là loài thằn lắn lớn nhất và mạnh nhất thế giới còn sống."},{"question":"Ułóż zdanie przeciwne do podanego: Ptaki potrafią latać.","answer":"Ptaki nie potrafią latać."},{"question":"Kodi matenda a chickenpox ndi chani?","answer":"Chickenpox ndi matenda opatsirana kwambiri omwe amayamba chifukwa cha varicella-zoster virus (VZV). Zingayambitse kuyabwa, ngati zithupsa pakati pa zizindikiro zina. Ziphuphu zimayamba kuoneka pachifuwa, msana, ndi kumaso, kenako zimafalikira thupi lonse."},{"question":"பின்வரும் சொற்றொடரை முடிக்கவும்:2011-ஆம் ஆண்டில் பிரான்ஸ் தேசிய காற்பந்து அணிக்காக முதன்முறையாக விளையாடினார். இன்றுவரை 50 முறைகளுக்கு மேல் பங்கேற்றுள்ள இவர்","answer":"யூரோ 2012 மற்றும் 2014 உலகக்கோப்பை காற்பந்து போட்டித்தொடர்களில் காலிறுதியை எட்டிய அணியில் இடம்பெற்றவர்."},{"question":"දෙසැම්බර් 8 ගැන කථා කරමු.","answer":"දෙසැම්බර් 8, ග්‍රෙගරි දින දසුනට අනුව අවුරුද්දේ 342 වන දිනය වේ (අධික අවුරුද්දක නම් 343 වන දිනය). අවුරුද්ද අවසන් වීමට තවත් දින 23 ඉතිරිව තිබේ."},{"question":"तलको प्रश्नको सहि उत्तर छान्नुहोस । २५x२५ (गुणन गर्नुहोस् । )(क) ६२५(ख) ६७५(ग) ४२५(घ) ५७५","answer":"२५x२५ गुणन गर्दा \\"(क) ६२५\\" हुन्छ । "},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga:“Avo fijery Andriamanitra ka mahita ny _”","answer":"“Avo fijery Andriamanitra ka mahita ny takona”"},{"question":"வினா : திருவள்ளுவருக்கு அய்யன் எனப் பெயர் சூட்டியவர் யார் ?","answer":"விடை : திரு.மு. கருணாநிதி"},{"question":"Verfasse eine Zusammenfassung des folgenden Texts:        Das Absperrbauwerk Murwani besteht aus drei Teilen: einem Staudamm mit einer Kronenlänge von 575 m auf der rechten Seite, einer Hochwasserentlastung in der Mitte sowie einem weiteren Staudamm mit einer Kronenlänge von 437 m auf der linken Seite. Die beiden Staudämme verfügen über einen Asphaltkern, um die Dichtigkeit sicherzustellen. Dafür wurden insgesamt 27.500 m3 (bzw. 80.000 t) Asphalt benötigt.  Die Dammkrone liegt auf einer Höhe von 251 m über dem Meeresspiegel. Die Höhe des rechten Staudamms beträgt 102 (bzw. 91 oder 101) m über der Gründungssohle, sein Volumen liegt bei 5,35 Mio. m3. Die Werte für den linken Staudamm liegen bei 30 m Höhe bzw. einem Volumen von 0,65 Mio. m3.  Der Stausee kann bis zu 150 Mio. m3 Wasser speichern. Der jährliche Zufluss in den Stausee wird auf 31 Mio. m3 geschätzt, wovon ungefähr die Hälfte in einer Anlage zur Trinkwassergewinnung verwendet werden soll, die unterhalb des Staudamms liegt. Die Anlage soll 40.000 m3 Wasser am Tag verarbeiten können.  Da die Verdunstung bei Stauseen in Wadis bis zu 80 % pro Jahr betragen kann und im Falle des Stausees Murwani auf bis zu 6 m pro Jahr geschätzt wird, gibt es Überlegungen, einen Teil des im Stausee gespeicherten Wassers in einen Aquifer weiterzuleiten.  Der Auftragswert für das Projekt betrug 263 Mio. SAR. Die Talsperre Murwani ist Teil eines Projekts der saudischen Regierung, die insgesamt fünf Dämme mit einem Auftragswert von ca. 1 Mrd. SAR errichten lassen will.","answer":"Die Talsperre Murwani besteht aus drei Teilen. Zwei Staudämmen, sowie einer Hochwasserentlastung."},{"question":"உலகப்பொதுமறை  என அழைக்கப்படும்   நூல் எது","answer":"திருக்குறள்"},{"question":"Vì sao nhà thờ Chính tòa Đà Lạt còn được gọi là Nhà thờ Con Gà?","answer":"Nhà thờ Chính tòa Đà Lạt được gọi là nhà thờ Con Gà, vì trên đỉnh tháp chuông có con gà làm bằng hợp kim, rỗng bên trong, dài 0,66 m, cao 0,58 m, quay quanh một trục để chỉ hướng gió.Nhà thờ Chính tòa Ðà Lạt, tên chính thức là nhà thờ Chính tòa Thánh Nicôla Bari, là một trong những công trình kiến trúc tiêu biểu và cổ xưa nhất của Đà Lạt, do người Pháp để lại. Nhà thờ được thiết kế theo kiểu mẫu của các nhà thờ Công giáo Rôma ở châu Âu, tiêu biểu cho trường phái kiến trúc Roman."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Aktürkoğlu debuterade för Turkiets landslag den 27 maj 2021 i en 2–1-vinst över Azerbajdzjan, där han blev inbytt i halvlek mot Cengiz Ünder. I juni 2021 blev Aktürkoğlu uttagen i Turkiets trupp till","answer":"EM i fotboll 2020."},{"question":"Thabo Mbeki","answer":"Thabo Mvuyelwa Mbeki tí wọ́n bí ní Ọjọ́ kejìdínlógún oṣù kẹfà ọdún 1942 (18 June, 1942) jẹ́ Ààrẹ àná orílẹ̀-èdè Guusu Áfíríkà láti ọdún 1999 títí dé 2008."},{"question":"Iza ilay Farao Ejiptiana mifandray amin'ny fananganana ny Piramida Lehibe any Gizea?","answer":"Farao Cheops, antsoina koa hoe Cheops, no mifandray amin'ny fananganana ny Piramida Lehibe any Gizea."},{"question":"Tope Oshin","answer":"Tope Oshin je adarí fíìmù ni Nàìjíríà, ó sì jẹ ìkan laarin awọn gbajúmọ̀ nínú ẹ̀ka eré ni odun 2019. Ní ọdún 2015, Ìwé ìròyìn Pulse sọ wí pé ó wà láàrin àwọn obìnrin mẹsan tí ó ṣe adarí eré tí ó yẹ kí àwọn èèyàn mọ. Ní ọdún 2018, ní ìrántí oṣù obìnrin, OkayAfrica yẹ́ Tope sì gẹ́gẹ́ bí ìkan lára àwọn Okay100 Women.Ó lọ sí ilé ẹ̀kọ́ gíga tí University of Ilorin níbi tí ó tí ká economics, ṣùgbọ́n kò parí níbẹ̀, ó padà parí ni ilẹ̀ Ẹ̀kọ́ gíga tí Lagos State University níbi tí ó tí gboyè nínú Theatre Art. Ó tesiwaju nínú ẹ̀kọ́ ìmọ̀ èrè sise nígbà tí ó lọ sí Colorado Film School ni Community College of Aurora tí ó wà ní Denver àti Met Film School ní London. Tope jẹ́ ọmọ ẹgbẹ́ tẹ́lẹ̀ fún Talents Durban àti Berlinale Talents.Tope jẹ́ òṣèré fún ọdún méjìlá, ó sì ti fara hàn nínú àwọn eré bíi Relentless. Ó ṣe ìgbà kejì adarí fún eré The Apprentice Africa. Ó ti ṣe adarí fún àwọn eré bíi In line, Ireti, New Horizon, Hush, Hotel Majestic, Tinsel àti MTV Shuga. Óun ni ó ṣe adarí fún àwọn eré gbajúmọ̀ bíi Up North àti New Money. Ní oṣù Kejìlá ọdún 2015, eré Fifty tí ó ṣe pá #20 million ni ọ̀sẹ̀ tí ó jáde. Ere The wedding party tí ó ṣe ní ọdún 2018, jẹ́ ère tí ó tà ju ni Nàìjíríà ni odun náà. Ní ọdún 2016, ó ṣe eré ìtàn, Amaka’s Kin  ni ìrántí gbajúmò òṣèré Amaka Igwe tí ó kú ní ọdún 2014. Ní ọdún 2017, ó ṣe ère ìtàn Nigeria - Shooting it like a woman. Ní ọdún 2018, ó ṣe eré We Don't live here anymore fun àwọn TIERs. Eré náà kò ṣe wò lórí sinema nítorí àwọn àríyànjiyàn tí ó wà pẹ̀lú eré náà. Ó ti ṣe ère fún oríṣiríṣi fíìmù àti eré orí telefisionu bíi MTV Shuga apá kẹrin àti apá kẹfà. Láti ọdún 2015, ní o ti wa láàrín àwọn adájọ́ fún International Emmy Award."},{"question":"Metin Akpınar'ın kızlarının ismi nedir?","answer":"Sevgi ve Duygu Nebioğlu"},{"question":"به نظر شما نویسنده ی نظر زیر، حس مثبت داشته یا منفی؟ چرا؟نظر: واقعا‌‎​‎‎​ رستوران خوبیه ، غذاهاش‌‎‌​‌​ عالیه ، فضای خیلی قشنگی‌‎​‎‏‏ داره و پرسنلش خیلی محترمن","answer":"به وضوح نویسنده حس مثبتی داشته چون به صفات مثبتی برای رستوران،‌ غذاها و پرسنل اشاره کرده است.صفات خوب، عالی، قشنگ و محترم نشاندهنده ی حس مثبت شخص است."},{"question":"ਪੰਜਾਬ ਦੇ ਕੁੱਝ ਮੌਸਮੀ ਦਰਿਆਵਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਮ ਲਿਖੋ ।","answer":"ਘੱਗਰ, ਕਾਲੀ ਵੇਈਂ, ਚਿੱਟੀ ਵੇਈਂ, ਚੱਕੀ ਖੱਡ, ਸਵਾਨ ਆਦਿ ।"},{"question":"పరిణామాత్మక రాజ్యాంగం అంటే ఏమిటి ?","answer":"పరిణామాత్మక రాజ్యాంగాన్ని క్రమానుగత రాజ్యాంగం అని కూడా అంటారు. అనేక పరిణామాల పర్యవసానంగా ఈ రాజ్యాంగం రూపొందుతుంది. రాజ్యంలోని రాజకీయ సంస్థలకు ఈ రాజ్యాంగం ప్రాతిపదికగా ఉంటుంది. గతంలో సంభవించిన పరిణామాల ప్రాతిపదికగా ఇది క్రమానుగతంగా వృద్ధి చెందుతుంది. కావున ఏ ఒక్కరి చేతనో ఏ ఒక్క సమయంలోనో ఒకేసారి ఈ రాజ్యాంగం రూపొందదు. అనేక ఆచార సంప్రదాయాలు, వాడుక పద్ధతులు, అలవాట్లు ఈ రాజ్యాంగానికి ఆధారాలుగా ఉంటాయి."},{"question":"为以下的原文给译文：狄梁公与娄师德同为相。狄公排斥师德非一日，则天问狄公曰：“朕大用卿，卿知所自乎？”对曰：“臣以文章直道进身，非碌碌因人成事。”则天久之曰：“朕比不知卿，卿之遭遇，实师德之力。”因命左右取筐箧，得十许通荐表，以赐梁公。梁公阅之，恐惧引咎，则天不责。出于外曰：“吾不意为娄公所涵！”而娄公未尝有矜色。","answer":"狄梁公与娄师德一同作相国。狄仁杰一直排斥娄师德，武则天问他说：“朕重用你，你知道原因吗？”狄仁杰回答说：“我因为文章出色和品行端正而受到重用，并不是无所作为而依靠别人。”过了一会，武则天对他说：“我曾经不了解你，你作了高官，全仗娄师德提拔。”于是令侍从拿来文件箱，拿了十几篇推荐狄仁杰的奏折给狄仁杰。狄仁杰读了之后，害怕得连忙认错，武则天没有指责他。狄仁杰走出去后说：“我没想到竟一直被娄大人容忍！”而娄公从来没有骄矜的表现。"},{"question":"السؤال: كم عدد أولي العزم من الرسل؟","answer":"خيارات: ( ستة ، خمسة، أربعة)"},{"question":"شكون الشاعر العربي اللي سميتو الحقيقيه أحمد بن الحسين؟","answer":"المتنبي المعروف بشاعر العرب تولد سنه 303 هجريه الموافق ل 915 ميلاديه وتوفى ف 354 هجريه الموافق 965 ميلاديه. عندو واحد المكانه كبيره وسط الشعراء العرب بعد الاسلام بحيث تيتعتبر عبقري فالشعر وفالادب والحكمه وكل القصائد ديالو كاتتكلم على نفسو اولا مدح الملوك. ومعروف بالذكاء ديالو منذ الصغر ديالو بحيث الف اول بيت شعري لما كانت عندو تسع سنين"},{"question":"Là một học sinh cấp 2, hãy viết đoạn văn 200 chữ bàn về vấn đề \\"Biến đổi khí hậu và những thiên tai\\".","answer":"Nhân loại đang đứng trước nguy cơ bị diệt vong do tác động của nạn ô nhiễm môi trường dẫn đến “sự biến đổi khí hậu và những thiên tai gần đây như động đất, sóng thần, núi lửa … đang gây nên những hiểm họa khôn lường cho nhân loại” Từ vài năm trở lại đây nhân loại phải đứng trước những đe dọa của thiên nhiên, thiên tai và dịch bệnh gây nguy hại cho đời sống con người. Còn nhớ năm 2005, sóng thần đã cuốn trồi hàng chục ngàn người ở Thái Lan và Indonesia. Năm 2008, động đất làm tan hoang Tứ Xuyên (Trung Quốc). Ngày càng nhiều làng “Ung thư” xuất hiện ở Việt Nam và thế giới… đây là những con số đáng báo động, cho thấy sự nổi giận của thiên nhiên trước những sai lầm của con người. Nguyên nhân dẫn đến những hậu quả trên là do: Sự tác động của con người tới thiên nhiên như: chặt phá rừng mất cân bằng sinh thái, sử dụng hóa chất như thuốc sâu, thuốc cỏ thiếu khoa học. Rồi khói thải công nghiệp, khói thải đô thị làm thủng tầng Ô Zôn gây nên hiệu ứng nhà kính và tình trạng nóng dần lên của trái đất. Con người không ngừng xây dựng, đục khoét trái đất, xây hầm, khai thác mỏ làm biến dạng lớp vỏ trái đất. Con người với những hận thù, tham vọng bá chủ thế giới, không ngừng chạy đua vũ trang, sản xuất vũ khí hóa học, bom đạn, gây chiến tranh liên miên… "},{"question":"ರೈನ್ ಒಂದು ಯುರೋಪಿಯನ್ ನದಿಯಾಗಿದ್ದು, ಇದು ಜರ್ಮನಿಯ ಮೂಲಕ ಹರಿಯುತ್ತಿದೆ, ಆಗ್ನೇಯ ಸ್ವಿಸ್ ಆಲ್ಪ್ಸ್ನಲ್ಲಿ ಸ್ವಿಸ್ ಕ್ಯಾಂಟನ್ ಆಫ್ ಗ್ರೈಸನ್ಸ್ ನಿಂದ ಹರಿಯುತ್ತದೆ, ಮತ್ತು ಅಂತಿಮವಾಗಿ ನೆದರ್ಲ್ಯಾಂಡ್ಸ್ ಉತ್ತರ ಸಮುದ್ರದ ಕರಾವಳಿಯಲ್ಲಿ ಸೇರುತ್ತದೆ. ಇದು ಯೂರೋಪ್‌ನಲ್ಲಿ ಹನ್ನೆರಡನೇ ಅತಿ ಉದ್ದದ ನದಿಯಾಗಿದೆ. ಪ್ರಶ್ನೆ : ರೈನ್ ನದಿ ಯಾವ ದೇಶದಲ್ಲಿ ಜನಿಸುತ್ತದೆ  ಉತ್ತರ:","answer":"ಜರ್ಮನಿ "},{"question":"(Khona manjalo ehle eseshwibeka embhedeni esalokhu egqoke amaphijama akhelawo maqedane ahoshe insilana ngaphansi kombhede. Amhlubule ingubo umkakheamdonse ngengalo maqedane akhwele adilike ngayo emhlane, ezinqeni ayehlisenangamahlombe imbala. Azame ukumephuca esandleni kodwa imizamo yakheiphelele ezeni. Akhale abe wuqanduqandu uMaMlanduli.)MAMLANDULI: (Ukhuluma enhlinhliza) Kulungile! Ngithi ngishaye uze ungibulaleuma uthanda kodwa okusalayo wukuthi uyoyithola ngifile le ntooyifunayo. Akumele ume ngeqholo lokuthi wangilobola ngoba ufunakonke ngempoqo nangendlovu yangena. Awungilobolelanga khonaphela ukuba ngibe yisigqili socansi okumele usehle isitafu nje nomayikanjani ukuze kwaneliseke izinkanuko zakho.(Kuwo lowo mnyama kuzwakale ukudlukuzeka kwehendlela lesicabha sekamelo yilonaongaphandle. Kuxakekwe nje ukuthi uLondiwe lona ubusevuke nini ekamelweni lakhemaqedane washwibeka emhubheni wendlu eqondene nekamelo labazali bakhengokushesha okungangokucwayiza kangaka.)LONDIWE: (Uzwakala engaphandle kwekamelo) Kodwa kwakhala nyonini kulomuzi bakithi? Ngivuleleni ngizokhuza umhlola.(Umsindo wokudlukuzisa ihendlela nokubhaklaza isicabha usalokhu uqhubekile njengokungenamkhawulo lapha kuLondiwe ngakolunye uhlangothi lwekamelo.)(Uzwakala ngesankahlu engaphakathi.) Udlala ngesikhathi nje wenaLondiwe uma ucabanga ukuthi uzongena eyethu bazali bakho. Minangisaziqondisela izigwegwe nje lapha kunyoko.(Uzwakala engaphandle ngezwi elinokuhefuzela.)Enough is enough! Ngithi sekwanele-ke manje baba namanjeawukafuni wena ukuwuyeka lo mkhuba wakho wokudlala ngomame?Kungcono ngisale sengifa lapha kofela khona umame minakunokuba ngibekezelele la manyala. Ngiyasigqekeza futhi manje lesisicabha mina ngoba angivulelwa muntu.(Uzwakala engaphakathi) Sengathi ungake ulinge nje.Inkosi impela uyokubona okwabonwa ngumlisa mumbeowanyathela umthente engafake zingxabulela ezinyaweni.(UMaMlanduli usalokhu ekhala lapha ngaphakathi njengalokhusisamnetha nje isibhaxu.)(Uzwakala ngaphandle) Kodwa nawe mame uthatha kude kakhulu.Angazi nje ukuthi uncengeni kubaba kangaka njengalokhuekuhlukumeza kangaka ngalolu hlobo kodwa wena ujikeungambophisi. Abantu besilisa abenze nje badinga ukuboshwangempela. Kungagcini lapho futhi. Kuphinde kucelwe nencwadiyesivikelo emaphoyiseni ukuze ibenqabele ukwenza noma yini kuwengesihluku. Mina ukuba umuntu owenza njengobaba uganweyimina nje, bengingamgeza igilo libemhlophe qwa ngimkhombiseukuthi angisiyona neze into yokudlala. (Ngokushesha uLondiweaphumele phandle kwendlu nemfonomfono yakhe leyo ebizwangomakhalekhukhwini.)1. Iyini inhloso yombhali yokwethula ipholavuthondaba kulo mdlalo? Sekelaimpendulo yakho.","answer":"Umbhali uhlose ukusinikeza ulwazi olumayelana nezixazululo ezitholakalakosonhlalakahle ezimayelana nokuthola imali yokukhokhela izifundonjengoba uZenyezile weluleka uLondiwe ngezindlela zokutholaimifundaze/imixhaso. Uphinde asinike ulwazi lokungaphatheki kahlekomndeni kaMemela ngokuwushiya uma eya eSudani. Yingakho baze bethi‘Kudela Owaziyo ukuthi uma engase athole elinye ithuba lokuphila angabuyaeseguqukile yini njengoba kwazamazama umhlaba eSudani."},{"question":"Kucing itu .............................. semasa ditemui Suraya.","answer":"Nyawa-nyawa ikan"},{"question":"Iza no renivohitr'i Bulgarie ?","answer":"I Sofia no renivohitr'i Bulgarie ."},{"question":"Sheeg goormuu soo islaamay Xamza Bin Cabdi Mudalib?","answer":"Xamza Bin Cabdi Mudalib wuxuu soo islaamay sanadkii lixaad ee nabinimada Nabiga (SCW) oo 6 sano nebi ah ayuu soo islaamay Xamza sidoo kale sanadkaan waxaa soo islaamay Cumar Bin Khadaab."},{"question":" كم عدد أرجل العنكبوت ؟","answer":" 8 أرجل"},{"question":"Tambaya: Wanene dan wasa fim da ke taka rawar malami a makarantar sakandare?","answer":"Irene Santiago-Baron yar fim ce, kuma tana koyarwa"},{"question":"Inona no fihetseham-po tsapa avy amin'ity fanambarana manaraka ity ? \\"Tena nahafinaritra ahy ny fety tandroany!\\"","answer":"Hafaliana no tsapa avy amin'io fanambarana io. "},{"question":"வட்டெழுத்து எப்படி தோன்றியது?","answer":"வட்டெழுத்துக்கள் பிராமி எழுத்து முறையில் இருந்து தோன்றியதாக கருதப்படுகிறது. பிராமி எழுத்துக்களை ஓலைச்சுவடிகளில் எழுதுவதற்கிணங்க அதை மாற்றியதால் வட்டெழுத்து தோன்றியது எனப் பொதுவாக கருதப்படுகின்றது. பிராமி எழுத்துக்கள் கோடுகளாக இருப்பதால் (கோடுகளை ஓலைச்சுவடியில் எழுதினால் அவை கிழிந்து விடும்) ஓலைச்சுவடியில் எழுதும் பொருட்டு அவற்றை வட்ட வடிவில் மாற்றி எழுதப்பட்டதால் வட்டெழுத்து உருவானதாகக் கருதலாம்.ஆனால் சிலர் வட்டெழுத்தே தமிழரின் பழங்கால எழுத்து முறையென்றும் அதிலிருந்தே தமிழ் பிராமி எழுத்துக்கள் தோன்றியன என்றும் வாதிடுகின்றனர். மு.வரதராசனார் தன்னுடைய தமிழ் இலக்கிய வரலாறு என்னும் நூலில் வெட்டெழுத்தே தமிழரின் பழங்கால எழுத்துமுறை என்றும் வட பிராமி தென் பிராமியாக திரிபுற்றது வட்டெழுத்தை ஒட்டி வளர்ந்த வளர்ச்சியே காரணம் என்றும் கூறியுள்ளார். ஆனால் இந்த வாதம் பலரால் ஒப்புகொள்ளப்படவில்லை.கி.பி 8ஆம் நூற்றாண்டுகளில் வட்டெழுத்து கிரந்த எழுத்துக்களுடன் மணிப்பிரவாளத்தை எழுத பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டது.கி.பி 11ஆம் நூற்றாண்டுகளில் வட்டெழுத்து தமிழ் நாட்டில் வழக்கொழிந்து, தற்கால தமிழ் எழுத்துக்களை ஒத்த எழுத்து முறை பயன்படுத்தப்பட துவங்கப்பட்டது. ஆனால் கேரளத்தில் 15ஆம் நூற்றாண்டுவரை வட்டெழுத்து மலையாளத்தை எழுத பயன்படுத்தப்பட்டது."},{"question":"Waxaad sheegtaa cuntada oo lagu sumoobo, astamaha Iyo dadka nugul ?","answer":"Cuntada aan cunno markay ay lee dahay wasakh ka timid ilma qabatada sida bakteeriyada, fayruska iyo dulinka waxay keentaa cunto ku sumoowga taas oo sii kororta marka ay sii badato tirida ilma qabatada.Astaamaha cuntada oo lagu sumoobo: Cunto ku sumowga waxa la xariira astaamo iyo calaamado badan kuwaas oo lamid noqon kara sida calaamadaha cuduro kale iyo xaalado kale oo jirka intiisa kale kajira. Cunto ku sumowga astaamahiisa waxa ay ku xiran yihiin nooca ilma qabatada. Astaamaha qaar waxaa ka mid ah.ShubanTabar dariMadax xanuunCalool xanuunMatagQandho yarLalabo.Yaa halis ugu jira cunto ku sumowga?Qof kasta noloshiisa waxuu cunnada ku sumoobaa ugu yaraa hal mar.Waxaa halis ugu jira iney cunnada ku sumoobaanDumarka xiliga ay uurka lee yihiinCaruurtaDadka Da’da ahDadka uu difaaca jirkooda uu daciifka yahayMaxaa sababa cunto ku sumowga?Sababta ugu weyn waa wasakh la socota cunnada ama cabitaanada oo aan si fiican loo diyaarin inta aan lacabin ka hor, sidoo kale waxaa sababi kara in lagu sumoobo cunnada hadii aan cunnada sida hilibka iyo qudaarta aa si fiican loo dhaqin inta aan la kar karin ka hor waxaa cunnada soo raaci kara wasakh ay la socoto ilma qabato.Sidee looga hortagi karaa in cunnada lagu sumoobo?Sida ugu wanaagsan ee looga hortagi karo in lagu sumoobo cunnada ayaa ah in laga ilaaliyo cunada wasakhda, cunoooyinka qaar sida loo diyaariyo ayaa adkeyn karta in laga ilaaliyo wasakhda. Cunto ku sumowga waxaa lagu yareyn karaa::-In laaga taxadaro habka iyo qaabka loo diyaarinaayo cunnadaIn si buuxda loo dhaqo khudaarta iyo ansalaatadaIn la hubiyo in cunnooyinka dhan ay wada daboolan yahiinIn si fiican loo kar kariyo hilibka inta aan la gurin ka hor ama la cunin."},{"question":"السؤال: ما هو اسم الغار الذي احتمى فيه الرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم عند هجرته إلى المدينة ؟","answer":"الإجابة: غار ثور"},{"question":"ゲーテの小説「若きウェルテルの悩み」のヒロインにちなんで社名がついた、「お口の恋人」のキャッチフレーズで知られるお菓子メーカーはどこでしょう？","answer":"ロッテです。"},{"question":"भूदान चळवळीची सुरूवात कोणी केली होती ?","answer":"भूदान चळवळीची सुरूवात विनोबा भावेंनी केली."},{"question":"भारतातील सर्वोच्च पुरस्कार कोणता?उत्तर :","answer":"भारतरत्न"},{"question":"Cad é an Córan? ","answer":"Is é an Córan, nó an Córán (Araibis: القرآن Al Qur’án), leabhar naofa an Ioslaim. An urraim a thugtar don Chóran san Ioslam, tá sí cosúil leis an urraim a thugtar d'Íosa sa chreideamh Críostaí. "},{"question":"inona ny toetra halanao?","answer":"ny toetra halako dia ny mihatsara velatsihy"},{"question":"Nyika yeZimbabwe yakawana rusununguko gore ripi?","answer":"1980"},{"question":"铅笔有硬软之分,用英文字母来表示,下列符号相比哪个表示较硬:A\\"H\\" B\\"HB\\" C\\"B\\"D\\"2B\\"","answer":"A\\"H\\""},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe fanagasiana?","answer":"Ny fanagasiana dia fanovana mampanome endrika malagasy ny zavatra iray: teny, anarana, fampianarana, na kolontsaina. Ny fanagasiana koa dia pôlitika nentin' ny governemanta malagasy taorian' ny rotaky ny mpianatra tamin' ny 1972, ary taty aoriana nandritry ny fanomezan-dalan' ny filoham-pirenena Marc Ravalomanana faharoa tamin' ny taona 2007. Ny fanagasiana indrindraindrindra dia mikasika ny fampianarana satria araka ny dinika nataon' ny Firenena Mikambana, dia moramora kokoa ho an' ny ankizy ny mianatra amin' ny tenin-dreniny."},{"question":"Qual é a capital da Islândia?","answer":"A capital da Islândia é Reykjavik."},{"question":"Cad iad na bealaí chun madra a thabhairt isteach do chait go sábháilte? I","answer":"s é an bealach is fearr chun madra agus cat a thabhairt isteach ná é sin a dhéanamh go mall agus de réir a chéile, i dtimpeallacht dearfach agus tacaíochta. D'fhonn é seo a dhéanamh, is féidir linn go leor rudaí éagsúla a dhéanamh. An bhfuil tú ag iarraidh dom cúpla príomh-leideanna a chur in iúl?"},{"question":"கார்கில் போர் நடந்தபோது, நிவாரண நிதி சேகரிப்பின் ஒரு பகுதியாக இவர் தெருவோர நிகழ்ச்சிகளை செய்தார். 2019இல் புல்வாமா தாக்குதல் நடந்தபோது, இவர், தனது மாணவர்களுடன் தேசப் பக்தி பாடல்களை பாடினார். பெங்களூரில் உள்ள சித்ரகலா பரிஷத்தில் தனது சொந்த சுர்பஹார் அமைப்பு மூலம் மாநிலத்தின் பிரமுகர்கள் முன்னிலையில் \\" ஏ வதன் கே நௌஜாவன்\\" என்ற பாடலை அர்ப்பணித்தார்.","answer":"புல்வாமா தாக்குதல்"},{"question":"Sentença 1: Bhagat Beni também disse que Guru Arjan Dev alcançou a iluminação somente através da Palavra Sagrada. Sentença 2: O Guru Arjan Dev também disse que Bhagat Beni obteve a iluminação apenas através da Palavra Sagrada. Pergunta: A frase 1 e a frase 2 expressam o mesmo significado? Sim ou não?","answer":"Não, as duas frases não expressam o mesmo significado."},{"question":"National Orthopaedic Hospital, Igbobi","answer":"Ile-iwosan Orthopedic Igbobi jẹ ile-iwosan ni Ilu Eko, Nigeria.Ile-iwosan Orthopedic ti Orilẹ-ede, Igbobi, Lagos bẹrẹ awọn iṣẹ bii ile-iṣẹ isọdọtun fun awọn ọmọ ogun ti o gbọgbẹ lakoko Ogun Agbaye II ni ọdun 1943, lẹhin eyi o dagbasoke si ile-iwosan labẹ awọn iṣẹ iṣoogun ti Ilu Gẹẹsi ti Colonial Nigeria ti Colonial Nigeria ni 6 Oṣù Kejìlá 1945. Ile-iwosan naa, ti kọkọ pe orukọ rẹ. Ile-iwosan Royal Orthopedic ni ọdun 1956 tun ṣe iranlọwọ lati tọju awọn ọmọ ogun ti o farapa ati awọn ara ilu ti Ogun Abele Naijiria ti 1967-1970. Odun 1975 ni won fi ile-iwosan naa le ijoba ipinle Eko lowo, leyin naa ijoba apapo ni odun 1979.Ile-iwosan naa ni agbara oṣiṣẹ ti o to 1300. O ni ẹyọ itọju aladanla ati agbara ibusun 450 kan. Ile-iwosan ti wa ni bayi pe o jẹ ile-iwosan orthopedic ti o tobi julọ ni Iwọ-oorun Afirika. Mobolaji Bank Anthony ṣe owo fun apakan titun ti ile-iwosan ti o wa pẹlu atunṣe ti ile-iṣẹ pajawiri. National Orthopaedic Hospital Opens Skills Laboratory in Lagos – Channels Television (channelstv.com) NBTE accredits Orthopaedic Hospital’s college (vanguardngr.com) Igbobi hospital seeks improvement in health insurance, services | The Guardian Nigeria News - Nigeria and World News — Features — The Guardian Nigeria News – Nigeria and World News"},{"question":"ਪੈਰਾਡਾਈਸ ਪੇਪਰਸ : ਕਿਹੜੇ ਭਾਰਤੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਂ ਆਏ? ਜ਼ਿਆਦਾਤਰ ਦਸਤਾਵੇਜ਼ ਇੱਕੋ ਕੰਪਨੀ ਐੱਪਲਬੀ ਦੇ ਹਨ।ਭਾਰਤੀ ਅਖ਼ਬਾਰ ਇੰਡੀਅਨ ਐਕਸਪ੍ਰੈਸ, ਜੋ ਭਾਰਤ ਵਿੱਚ ਇਸ ਜਾਂਚ ਦਾ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਹੈ, ਦੇ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਪੈਰਾਡਾਈਸ ਪੇਪਰਸ ਵਿੱਚ 714 ਭਾਰਤੀ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਂ ਹਨ।ਪੈਰਾਡਾਈਸ ਪੇਪਰਸ : ਟੈਕਸ ਬਚਾਉਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਅਮੀਰਾਂ ਬਾਰੇ ਖੁਲਾਸੇ।   ਨੰਦ ਲਾਲ ਖੇਮਕਾ ਦੀ ਕੰਪਨੀ ਸੰਨ ਗਰੁਪ ਕੌਮਾਂਤਰੀ ਪੱਧਰ 'ਤੇ ਐੱਪਲਬੀ ਦੀ ਦੂਜੀ ਸਭ ਤੋਂ ਵੱਡੀ ਨਿਵੇਸ਼ਕ ਹੈ। ਇਸ ਦੀਆਂ 118 ਆਫਸ਼ੋਰ ਇਕਾਈਆਂ ਹਨ। ਐੱਪਲਬੀ ਦੇ ਭਾਰਤੀ ਨਿਵੇਸ਼ਕਾਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਕਈ ਨਾਮੀ ਕੰਪਨੀਆਂ ਹਨ ਜਿੰਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਦੀ ਜਾਂਚ ਸੀਬੀਆਈ ਅਤੇ ਐਨਫੋਕਸਮੈਂਟ ਡਾਏਰੈਕਟੋਰੇਟ ਕਰ ਰਹੇ ਹਨ।ਕਿਹੜੇ ਨਾਂ ਆਏ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ?1. ਵਿਜੇ ਮਾਲਿਆ2. ਨੀਰਾ ਰਾਡੀਆ3. ਡਾਕਟਰ ਅਸ਼ੋਕ ਸੇਠ4. ਰਵੀ ਕ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨ5. ਜਯੰਤ ਸਿਨਹਾ6. ਆਰ.ਕੇ. ਸਿਨਹਾ 7. ਅਮਿਤਾਭ ਬੱਚਨ (ਇੰਡੀਅਨ ਐਕਸਪ੍ਰੈਸ \\"ਇੰਟਰਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਕੰਸੌਰਟੀਅਮ ਆਫ ਇੰਵੈਸਟੀਗੇਟਿਵ ਜਰਨਅਲਿਸਟਸ\\" ਦਾ ਹਿੱਸਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਨੇ ਪੈਰਾਡਾਈਸ ਪੇਪਰਸ ਦੀ ਜਾਂਚ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ। ਬੀਬੀਸੀ ਨੇ ਇਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਤੱਥਾਂ ਦੀ ਆਪ ਜਾਂਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਕੀਤੀ ਹੈ।)","answer":"\\"ਇੰਟਰਨੈਸ਼ਨਲ ਕੰਸੌਰਟੀਅਮ ਆਫ ਇੰਵੈਸਟੀਗੇਟਿਵ ਜਰਨਅਲਿਸਟਸ\\" ਦੀ ਜਾਂਚ ਵਿੱਚ ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਦੇ ਨਾਂ ਦੇ ਖੁਲਾਸੇ ਹੋਏ ਹਨ ਜਿੰਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਨੇ ਟੈਕਸ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਣ ਲਈ ਪੈਸਾ ਆਫਸ਼ੋਰ ਕੰਪਨੀਆਂ ਵਿੱਚ ਨਿਵੇਸ਼ ਕੀਤਾ।"},{"question":"Tìm ý và lập dàn ý để kể lại một chuyến đi đáng nhớ của em.","answer":"+ Mở bài: Chuyến đi thăm di tích lịch sử thành Cổ Loa – chuyến đi đáng nhớ.+ Thân bài:  Lí do có chuyến đi đáng nhớ: Kết thúc học kì I, nhà trường và ban phụ huynh thống nhất tổ chức tham quan cho cả trường. Hành trình: Tập trung từ sớm → Khởi hành (2 tiếng) → Đến nơi → Tham quan đền thờ chính – An Dương Vương → Am thờ của Mị Châu →  Ra về. Kể lại sự việc đáng nhớ: Câu chuyện về nàng Mị Châu – bức tượng của nàng công chúa.+ Kết bài:  Bài học về dựng nước và giữ nước. Chuyến đi thăm quan bổ ích, lí thú."},{"question":"لارج لینگویج ماڈلز کے بارے میں کچھ بتایں۔","answer":"لارج لینگویج ماڈلز سے مراد وہ لینگویج ماڈلز ہیں جو اپنے سائز میں بہت بڑے ماڈلز ہوتے ہیں اور عموماً ان میں بلینز کے حساب سے پیرامیٹرز ہوتے ہیں۔ چند مشہور ماڈلز میں جی پی ٹی 3 جو اوپن آے آی کا ہے، پالم اور لمبڈا جو گوگل کے ہیں، للاما جو میٹا کا ہے۔ یہ ماڈلز بہت زیادہ طاقت کے حامل ہوتے ہیں اور لینگویج جینریشن کے لیے بہت طاقتور ہیں۔ یہ سوال جواب، ترجمہ، کوڈ لکھنے، وغیرہ جیسی خصوصیات کے حامل ہوتے ہیں۔ ان ماڈلز نے سرچینگ کو ایک نیا معنی دیا ہے۔"},{"question":"Kulak kristallerinin oynaması nelere sebep olur?","answer":"Aydın, \\"Halk dilindeki ismiyle 'Kristal Oynaması' ise hastalığın oluşma mekanizmasını açıklamaktadır. İç kulak kanalındaki kristaller, dengemizi sağlamamıza yardım eder. Kristallerin olması gerektiği yerler dışına sürüklenmesi Vertigo dediğimiz baş dönmesinin ortaya çıkmasına sebep olur\\" dedi."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Irlands herrjuniorlandslag i ishockey representerar Irland i ishockey för herrjuniorer. Laget spelade sin första landskamp","answer":"den 27 april 2001 i Luxemburg under kvalspelet till juniorvärldsmästerskapets Division III-grupp, och förlorade då med 0-10 mot Luxemburg."},{"question":"Nhiệt độ thấp nhất có thể có của sao Diêm Vương?","answer":"Nhiệt độ trung bình của hành tinh lùn có thể giảm xuống tới -232 độ C, với địa hình bao gồm những ngọn núi, thung lũng, sông băng."},{"question":"Iṣoro Naijiria kọja eyi ti Buhari le yanju, ki ẹnikẹni ma ro pe ayipada yoo wa ṣaaju 2023 – Biṣọọbu Adeoye","answer":"Alukooro igbimọ awọn Biṣọọbu lagbaaye (World Bishops Council) nilẹ Afrika, Biṣọọbu Ṣeun Adeoye, ti sọ pe iṣoro ti orileede yii n koju lọwọlọwọ kọja agbara Aarẹ Muhammadu Buhari, nitori ogun-ẹmi ni, to si lagbara pupọ.Adeoye, ẹni to tun jẹ oludasilẹ ijọ Sufficient Grace Truth Christian Church, Ọkinni, nipinlẹ Ọṣun, ṣalaye pe gẹgẹ bi Dagoni ko ṣe ri ojutuu si ọrọ apoti-ẹri Ọlọrun ninu iwe Samuel Kin-in-ni, ori karun-un, naa ni Aarẹ Buhari ko ni ipa kankan lati yanju ogun to n doju kọ orileede yii.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe wi, “Ninu adura mi fun orileede yii, mo ri i pe Naijiria n wọya ija pẹlu awọn agbara okunkun, ṣugbọn a ni awọn adari ti ko le koju ogun, Igbakeji aarẹ, Yẹmi Oṣinbajo, nikan ni mo ri to n tiraka lati ja ija yẹn.“Ko si ogun ti eeyan le ṣẹ loju-aye lai kọkọ ṣẹ ẹ ninu ẹmi. Ko si agbara eniyan to le ṣẹgun agbara okunkun. Ija ara nikan ni Aarẹ Buhari n fọkan si, wahala Naijiria si ju bẹẹ lọ.“Loootọ, baba ni Buhari jẹ, a si n reti pe ko jagun fun orileede yii ni gbogbo ọna, ṣugbọn agbara rẹ ko ka a ninu ẹmi.“Ọna abayọ kan ṣoṣo si wahala yii ni ki gbogbo awa ọmọ orileede yii bẹrẹ adura pe ki Ọlọrun ran Dafidi si wa lọdun 2023, ki ẹnikẹni ma ṣe ro pe ayipada kankan yoo wa ṣaaju igba idibo yẹn rara.“A gbọdọ beere fun aanu Ọlọrun, ki a si fara da ohun gbogbo to ba ṣẹlẹ titi di ọdun 2023. A gbọdọ beere fun ẹni bii ọkan Ọlọrun ti yoo jẹ aarẹ wa lati iha Ila-Oorun orileede yii."},{"question":"Fenoy ny banga:\\" Ataovy toy _ ka samy hiady mafy ho an'ny fandresena\\"","answer":"\\" Ataovy toy ny kitram-pirenena ka samy hiady mafy ho an'ny fandresena\\""},{"question":"வினா: இந்தியாவில் குடியரசுத் தலைவர் ஆட்சி முதன் முதலாக அமல்படுத்தப்பட்ட மாநிலம்  எது?                 1.குஜராத் 2.கேரளா 3.பஞ்சாப் 4.மேற்குவங்காளம்  ","answer":"விடை 2.கேரளா கேரளம் இந்தியாவின் தென்மாநிலங்களுள் ஒன்று. இது கிழக்கில் தமிழ் நாட்டையும், வடக்கில் கர்நாடகத்தையும் எல்லைகளாகக் கொண்டுள்ளது. மேற்கில் அரபுக் கடல் உள்ளது. மலையாளம் கேரளத்தின் முதன்மையான மொழியாகும். தமிழ் பேசுவோரும் அதிகமாக காணப்படுகின்றனர். கேரளத்தின் தலைநகரம் திருவனந்தபுரம். பிற குறிப்பிடத்தக்க நகரங்கள் கொச்சி,கோழிக்கோடு திருச்சூர் மற்றும் கோட்டயம் ஆகும். இந்திய மாநிலங்களில் கல்வியறிவு  விகிதத்தில் கேரளம் முதலிடம் வகிக்கிறது.பெயர்க் காரணம்கேரளம் என்ற சொல், தமிழ்ச் சொல்லான “சேரளம்” (மலைச் சரிவு) அல்லது சேர நாடு என்பதிலிருந்து தோன்றியது என்பது அறிஞர்களின் கூற்று.இன்றைய கேரளம், வரலாற்றுக் காலத்தில் “சேர நாடு” என்று அழைக்கப்பட்டு வந்தது. பொ.ஊ.மு. 3ஆம் நூற்றாண்டு பேரரசர் அசோகரின் கல்வெட்டில் “கேரளபுத்திரர்” எனக் குறிப்பிடப்பட்டுள்ளது.மேலும், ரோமானிய வணிகன் பெரிபுளீசின் நிலவரைபடத்தில், இன்றைய கேரளப் பகுதியை சேரபுத்ரா என்று குறிப்பிடுகின்றார். கேரள மக்கள் மலையாளிகள் என்று அழைக்கப்படுகின்றனர். மலையில் (மேற்கு தொடர்ச்சி மலைகள்) வாழ்பவர்கள் என்பது அதன் பொருள் ஆகும்."},{"question":"السؤال: من هو النبي الذي أعطاه الله القدرة على إحياء الموتى؟","answer":"الجواب: نبي الله عيسى عليه السلام."},{"question":"வினா: சிலை அழகு என்பது …………………. புணர்ச்சிக்குச் சான்றாகும்.அ) உயிரீற்றுஆ) மெய்யீற்றுஇ) உயிர்முதல்ஈ) மெய் முதல்","answer":"விடை: அ) உயிரீற்று"},{"question":"සාමය සහ සංවර්ධනය සඳහා වූ ලෝක විද්‍යා දිනය සමරනු ලබන්නේ කවදාද?","answer":"සාමය සහ සංවර්ධනය සඳහා වූ ලෝක විද්‍යා දිනය සෑම නොවැම්බර් 10 දිනකම සමරනු ලැබේ."},{"question":"வினா:தமிழ்நாட்டின் சமூக அமைப்பு குறித்து விரிவாக கூற முடியுமா?","answer":"விடை:தமிழ்நாட்டின் சமூக அமைப்பு பல்வேறு இனக்குழுக்களையும் சமூக வகுப்புகளையும் உள்ளடக்கியது. தமிழ்நாட்டில் பல சமூக அமைப்புக்கள் சமூகத்தில் சமத்துவம் மற்றும் சகோதரத்துவத்தை மேம்படுத்துவதற்கு பணியாற்றி வருகின்றன. தமிழ்நாட்டின் சமூக அமைப்பு மாநிலத்தின் பொருளாதாரம் மற்றும் அரசியல் வளர்ச்சிக்கு பெரும் பங்களிப்பு செய்கிறது."},{"question":"Вестминстер абатчылыгы жөнүндө.\\"Вестминстер абатчылыгынын дини кандай?\\"","answer":"\\"Вестминстердеги Ыйык Пётр чиркөөсү, көбүнчө Вестминстер абатчылыгы деп аталат, Лондондогу Вестминстер шаарындагы, Вестминстер сарайынын батыш жагында жайгашкан, негизинен готикалык стилдеги ири чиркөө\\". "},{"question":"Hãy viết một bài báo có thể sử dụng tiêu đề này: Thủ phạm gây ra cuộc đại tuyệt chủng lớn nhất trên Trái Đất","answer":"Một loài vi khuẩn sản sinh khí methane có thể đẩy đại đa số sinh vật trên Trái Đất vào cảnh tuyệt chủng hàng loạt ở kỷ Permi.Trái Đất đã trải qua 5 đợt tuyệt chủng lớn. Trong số đó, sự kiện tuyệt chủng ở kỷ Permi có tên cuộc \\"Đại diệt vong\\" xóa sổ khoảng 70% loài sống trên đất liền và 96% sinh vật biển trên Trái Đất. Khoảng cách niên đại 10 triệu năm của than đá tạo ra quanh thời kỳ tuyệt chủng này chứng tỏ một lượng lớn cây cối hình thành than đá tuyệt chủng trong sự kiện và mất hàng triệu năm để phục hồi, theo IFL Science.Tuy nhiên, tìm kiếm khoảng thời gian số lượng các loài giảm đột ngột từ dẫn liệu hóa thạch chỉ là phần dễ dàng. Giới khoa học đề xuất nhiều giả thuyết lý giải nguyên nhân dẫn đến cuộc đại tuyệt chủng, từ giải phóng khí methane dưới đáy biển tới va chạm tiểu hành tinh. Thông qua nghiên cứu đá ra đời trong sự kiện tuyệt chủng, các nhà nghiên cứu biết những đại dương và vùng nước nông thiếu oxy cuối kỷ Permi. Tình trạng thiếu oxy dường như góp phần gây ra sự kiện tuyệt chủng với hiệu ứng dây chuyền."},{"question":"A wane birni ne aka fara ba da rahoton bullar cutar ta COVID-19?","answer":"A birnin Wuhan."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai enau dalam belukar, melepaskan pucuk masing-masing\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud mementingkan diri sendiri, tidak bersepakat."},{"question":"اكتب قصة عن اليوم الأول لتلميذ في المدرسة الابتدائية.","answer":"\\"كان الشاب الصغير يشعر بالحماس والخوف معًا، فقد كان هذا اليوم الأول له في المدرسة الابتدائية. كان يرتدي كنزة حمراء ساطعة وبنطلون أسود جديد، وحمل حقيبته الصغيرة على ظهره، ووجهه يبدو متوترًا بينما كان يمشي مع والداه نحو باب المدرسة.عندما دخل الفصل الدراسي الخاص به، وجد أن كل شيء جديد ومثير. كانت الصفوف مصفوفة بشكل مثالي، والطاولات والكراسي الصغيرة تظاهر بأنها بانتظار طالب جديد. تعرف الشاب على معلمته الجديدة، والتي كانت تشعر بنفس الحماس تجاه السنة الدراسية الجديدة.بدأت الدروس، وأصبح الفصل ممتلئًا بالكلام والأصوات. كان الشاب متحمسًا بشكل خاص لدرس الرياضيات، وهو ما وجد بعض الصعوبة في حل المسائل الجديدة، لكن فرحته عندما حل المسألة بنفسه كانت كبيرة جدًا.بعد الصلاة والغذاء، جاءت فترة الاستراحة، والتي كانت مناسبة للشاب لتكوين صداقات جديدة مع زملائه الجدد، واللعب معهم في الفناء الخارجي. بينما كان يلعب، وجد شخصين يلعبان بطريقة غريبة، حيث كانوا يستخدمون الإعداد الذهني لحل المسائل الرياضية بسرعة. سألهم الشاب عن هذا الأسلوب، وشرح لهم أنهم كانوا يحضّرون للمسابقة المدرسية القادمة.بمجرد انتهاء اليوم، خرج الشاب مع والديه من المدرسة، وكان يشعر بالرضا والاستيعاب بعد يوم أول رائع في المدرسة الابتدائية. كان يتطلع إلى المزيد من الأيام المثيرة والمليئة بالتحديات والفرص الجديدة.\\""},{"question":"दहेज प्रथा","answer":"प्रस्तावना:- दहेज प्रथा में वर पक्ष के लोग वधू पक्ष के लोगों से कुछ धन मांगते हैं जिसे दहेज कहा जाता है यह बहुत ही बड़ा अपराध है लेकिन फिर भी आज के समय में बहुत सारे लोग दहेज का मांग करते हैं और यह हमारे देश की बहुत बड़ी समस्या है।दहेज प्रथा:- दहेज प्रथा हमारे देश की बहुत बड़ी समस्या है इसमें दूल्हे की तरफ से कुछ पैसे की मांग की जाती है जिसे दुल्हन की तरफ से उनके माता-पिता या उनके अपने लोग देते हैं लेकिन दहेज लेना कानूनन रूप से बहुत बड़ा अपराध है इसके लिए जुर्माना और जेल दोनों हो सकती हैं।हमारे देश में कई सारे शादियों में दहेज की मांग की जाती है लेकिन फिर भी वह लोग कानूनी रूप से अपराधी होते हुए भी बड़े आराम से हमारे बीच घूमते रहते हैं, कई शादियों में तो लोगों को पता रहता है कि यह रिश्ता दहेज से तय हुआ है लेकिन फिर भी लोग चुप रहते हैं।कई बार तो ऐसा भी होता है जब लड़की वाले उनके द्वारा मांगे गए पैसे को नहीं दे पाते हैं तो यह लोग बारात लेकर वापस चले जाते हैं या फिर बाराती लेकर नहीं आते हैं।और कभी-कभी तो दुल्हन और उसके पिता लज्जा के कारण आत्महत्या कर लेते हैं ऐसा हमारे देश में होता आया है और हो भी रहा है।दहेज प्रथा के निवारण:- दहेज प्रथा को समाप्त करने के लिए हमें भी आगे आना होगा अगर आपके घर में किसी व्यक्ति की शादी हो रही है तो आप ना तो किसी से दहेज ले हैं और ना ही किसी को दहेज दें अगर आपके घर में कोई लड़की है और उसकी शादी में दहेज मांगा जा रहा है तू आप उन्हें दहेज ना दें बल्कि आप अपने पास के पुलिस स्टेशन में इसकी रिपोर्ट दर्ज कराएं।अगर किसी शादी में आपको पता चलता है कि इसमें दहेज लिया जा रहा है तो भी आपको पुलिस को इसकी जानकारी देनी है क्योंकि जब तक आप दहेज देना बंद नहीं करेंगे और इसके खिलाफ आवाज नहीं उठाएंगे तब तक दहेज मांगने वाले लोग दहेज मांगते ही रहेंगे।अगर आप एक लड़की है तो जब आपकी शादी तय की जाए तो आप यह ध्यान जरूर दीजिएगा कि कहीं सामने से जो रिश्ता आया है यह सभी लोग दहेज की मांग तो नहीं कर रहे अगर दहेज की मांग की जा रही है तो आप दहेज ना दें या फिर उनसे कोई रिश्ता ही ना रखें क्योंकि जिनके नज़र मे पैसा ही सब कुछ है तो उनके नज़र मे रिस्ता क्या चीज़ है।दहेज प्रथा को बढ़ावा:- दहेज प्रथा को बढ़ावा देने में लड़की के पिता का भी हाथ होता है क्योंकि लड़की के पिता हमेशा अपनी इच्छा अनुसार दमाद की खोज करते हैं जैसे कि उन्हें केवल सुंदर और पैसे वाला दमाद चाहिए होता है क्योंकि लड़की के पिता सोचते हैं कि केवल पैसे और सुंदरता से ही उनकी बेटी खुश रह पाएगी लेकिन ऐसा बिल्कुल भी नहीं है हमें अपने लड़की के पसंद की शादी करनी चाहिए क्योंकि जीवन उसे व्यतीत करना है आपको नहीं।दहेज प्रथा अच्छा या खराब:- दहेज की प्रथा बहुत पहले से ही चली आ रही है लेकिन शुरुआत में लड़की के पिता अपनी मर्जी से जो कुछ हो पाता था खुशी खुशी अपने दामाद को पैसे देकर लड़की के साथ विदा कर दिया जाता था लेकिन धीरे धीरे चल कर यही चीज एक अपराध का रूप ले लिया।अगर लड़की के पिता खुशी खुशी बिना किसी दबाव में आकर कुछ पैसे दे रहे हैं तो यह कोई अपराध नहीं है लेकिन अगर लड़के वाले जबरन पैसे मांग रहे हैं तो यह एक अपराध है।निष्कर्ष:- किसी भी विवाह में जबरन पैसे लेना दहेज कहलाता है और दहेज लेना और देना दोनों कानूनी रूप से दंडनीय अपराध है हमें न तो दहेज लेना चाहिए और न ही दहेज देना चाहिए अगर आप से जबरन दहेज लिया जाता है तो आप अपने नजदीकी पुलिस स्टेशन में संपर्क करें।"},{"question":"Inona no renivohitr'i Espaina?","answer":"Ny renivohitr'i Espaina dia Madrid."},{"question":"Cahaya matahari jelas kelihatan ____________________ kaki langit pada waktu senja di Pantai Cherating. Apakah kata sesuai yang mengisikan tempat kosong?","answer":"mencurah ke"},{"question":"சார்லஸ் பாப்பேஜ் கண்டறிந்த அறிவியல் கருவி ……………………………அ) தொலைக்காட்சிஆ) கணினிஇ) கைப்பேசிஈ) மடிக்கணினி","answer":"ஆ) கணினி"},{"question":"accuracy-தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்","answer":"துல்லியம்"},{"question":"Tunjukkan resipi untuk kerepek sengkuang cina pedas dengan langkah-langkah yang terperinci. ","answer":"Bahan: 500 gram ubi ngaku , 4 sudu masak Cili Kering (dikisar)Bahan B: 1 biji bawang besar (ditumbuk), 3 ulas bawang putih (ditumbuk), 3 sudu gula, 2 sudu air asam jawa, 10 helai daun kari, minyak masak secukupnyaCara memasak:1. Kupas kulit ngaku dan basuh bersih2. Panaskan minyak dalam jumlah yang banyak.3. Ambil ngaku tadi dan sagat nipis ke dalam minyak.4. Bila ngaku sudah kekuningan, angkat, toskan minyak dan asingkan.5. Tinggalkan 3 sudu minyak masak dan tumis bahan B6. Masukkan cili kisar dan tumis hingga naik minyak.7. Masukkan air asap jawa, gula dan kacau.8. Kemudian masukkan kerepek Ngaku yang telah digoreng tadi.9. Taburkan daun kari dan kacau rata."},{"question":"\\" ශ්‍රී ලංකාවේ තේ වගාවේ පුරෝගාමියා \\" ලෙස සැලකෙන , ඉංග්‍රීසි ජාතික වැවිලිකරුවා කවුද ?","answer":"ජේම්ස් ටේලර්"},{"question":"Bu paragrafın devamını yazın: 1973 Petrol Krizi sonrasında İsveç, fosil yakıtların kullanım payını azaltma kararı aldı. O günden bugüne, elektrik enerjisinin en ağırlıklı üretim alanı nükleer ve hidroelektrik enerjiden sağlanmaktadır. Ancak yine de nükleer kaynakların kullanımı sınırlandırılmış durumdadır. Yine Amerika Birleşik Devletleri'nde 1979 yılında yaşanan Three Mile adası kazası","answer":"sonucunda İsveç hükûmeti, yeni nükleer santrallarin açılmasına engel olmaya başladı."},{"question":"Tuliskan satu karangan keperihalan tentang lawatan ke dusun datuk. ","answer":"Pada cuti sekolah yang lalu, bapa membawa kami sekeluarga pergi ke dusun datuk yang terletak di Pontian. Kami bertolak ke sana pada pukul 7.30 pagi dengan menaiki kereta bapa yang baharu.           Dalam perjalanan, kami berbual-bual dengan mesranya sambil menikmati pemandangan yang indah nian. Kami tiba di destinasi pada pukul 8.30 pagi. Kami melihat datuk dan nenek menunggu ketibaan kami sekeluarga dengan perasaan yang gembira. Kami pun terus bersalam dengan datuk dan nenek.         Selepas itu, kami memberikan buah tangan kepada datuk dan nenek. Kemudian, kami bersembang dengan datuk dan nenek di ruang tamu untuk mengeratkan hubungan antara satu sama lain. Bapa pula membaca surat khabar untuk mengetahui berita-berita terkini di dalam dan di luar negara.         Pada pukul 12.30 tengah hari, kami sekeluarga menikmati makanan tengah hari bersama datuk dan nenek. Kami makan dengan berseleranya kerana masakan nenek sungguh lazat. Selepas makan, ibu dan kakak membantu nenek mencuci pinggan mangkuk. Mereka juga membantu nenek mengemaskan dapur sehingga bersih dan kemas.         Pada waktu petang, datuk membawa kami sekeluarga pergi ke dusun buah-buahannya. Dusun datuk terletak berhampiran dengan rumahnya. Terdapat pelbagai jenis pokok buah di dusun datuk seperti durian, mangga, manggis, pisang dan sebagainya. Kami menikmati buah-buahan yang segar dan enak di dusun datuk. Datuk juga membawa saya dan adik pergi memancing ikan di sungai berdekatan dusunnya. Kami memancing ikan dengan sabarnya dan mendapat banyak ikan yang besar.        Pada pukul 6.00 petang, kami pun pulang ke rumah. Saya berasa gembira kerana dapat melawat ke kampung datuk. Saya berharap agar berpeluang ke sana lagi pada masa akan datang."},{"question":"Cá bhfuil ceanncheathrú MOS Burger? Is slabhra bia tapa tóir é MOS Burger sa tSeapáin agus san Áise. Cá bhfuil ceannchiste MOS Food Service, inc.? ","answer":"Tá ceanncheathrú MOS Food Service i gceantar Tokyo Disney Resort i bpréfecture Chiba sa Tseapáin."},{"question":"Awọn ọlọpaa ti sọrọ lori rogbodiyan Atan-Ọta","answer":"Alukoro ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun, DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi, ti sọrọ lori rogbodiyan to ṣẹlẹ ni teṣan ọlọpaa Atan-Ọta laaarọ Ọjọbọ, Wẹsidee, ọsẹ yii, nibi ti wọn ti ni DPO teṣan naa dagbere faye.Oyeyẹmi ṣalaye pe DCO teṣan naa, DSP Augustine Ogbeche, lawọn to fa rogbodiyan naa pa. O fi kun un pe bakan naa ni wọn tun ṣe DPO teṣan yii kan naa leṣe, koda o lawọn ko mọ ibi ti DPO naa torukọ ẹ n jẹ Sikiru Olugbenga, wa bayii.O tẹsiwaju pe araalu kan naa ku ninu rogbodiyan ọhun. Alukoro sọ pe yatọ si gbogbo eyi, awọn eeyan naa tun ji awọn dukia olowo iyebiye lọ ni teṣan ọlọpaa naa.Lọjọ Iṣẹgun yii kan naa lo ni awọn ọmọkunrin kan kọ lu teṣan ọlọpaa Ọbada-Oko, l’Abẹokuta, kan naa, wọn si ba ibẹ jẹ. Ati ẹ gbọ pe niṣe ni DPO ibẹ fikunlẹ bẹ ẹ fawọn bọisi naa, ohun ti ko jẹ ki wọn dana sun ibẹ niyẹn.Oyeyẹmi waa sọ pe o yẹ kawọn ọdọ ranti pe latigba ti ọrọ SARS yii ti bẹrẹ, ọlọpaa ko fa wahala, kódà pẹlu bawọn kan ṣe ba teṣan awọn jẹ. O ni gbogbo eeyan merindinlogoji (36) tọwọ ba lasiko rogbodiyan akọkọ lawọn ti fi silẹ, fun idi eyi, o ni kawọn ọdọ yee wahala awọn, ọlọpaa ki i ṣe onijagidijagan.Bakan naa lo ni kawọn obi ati olori ilu kilọ fawọn eeyan wọn."},{"question":"意大利的官方網站是？","answer":"網站是：www.italia.it"},{"question":"Quais países da América do Sul não fazem fronteira com o Brasil?","answer":"Chile e Equador."},{"question":"So sánh cơ sở hình thành của các nền văn minh phương Đông và phương Tây trên phương diện: điều kiện tự nhiên; kinh tế; và chính trị.","answer":"Văn minh phương Đông:Điều kiện tự nhiên: - Hình thành tại lưu vực các dòng sông lớn ở châu Phi và châu Á.- Có nhiều đồng bằng rộng lớn, màu mỡ.Cơ sở kinh tế- Nông nghiệp là ngành kinh tế chủ đạo.Cơ sở chính trị- Nhà nước quân chủ chuyên chế trung ương tập quyềnVăn minh phương TâyĐiều kiện tự nhiên : - Hình thành trên các bán đảo ở Nam Âu.- Địa hình nhiều núi và cao nguyên; đất đai khô, rắc; đồng bằng nhỏ hẹp- Có bờ biển dài, nhiều vũng, vịnhCơ sở kinh tế- Thủ công nghiệp và thương nghiệp là ngành kinh tế chủ đạo.Cơ sở chính trị- Thể chế dân chủ với các mô hình, như: dân chủ chủ nô, cộng hòa quý tộc,…"},{"question":"Dấu ba chấm trong dòng thơ ở khổ cuối cảu bài thơ Về thăm mẹ có tác dụng gì?","answer":"Dấu ba chấm trong dòng thơ ở khổ cuối “Nghẹn ngào thương mẹ nhiều hơn…” có tác giả thể hiện những tình cảm yêu thương, trân trọng của người con dành cho người mẹ mà không thể nói ra bằng lời."},{"question":"පහත තේරවිල්ල විසඳන්න.කිසිවෙකු නොකියවන පොත       ","answer":"ඉලපොත"},{"question":"¿Quiénes componen la banda de rock The Killers?","answer":"The Killers es una banda de rock estadounidense formada en 2001 en Las Vegas (Nevada) por el vocalista, teclista y bajista Brandon Flowers y el guitarrista Dave Keuning. La banda actualmente está formada por Brandon Flowers, Dave Keuning, Mark Stoermer y Ronnie Vannucci Jr.. Después de llamar la atención de un busca talentos, el grupo firmó con el sello independiente británico Lizard King Records y el estadounidense Island Records."},{"question":"Ijọba o gbọdọ fun ẹnikẹni labẹrẹ ajẹsara Korona ni tipatipa-Ile-ẹjọ lo sọ bẹẹ","answer":"Ile-ẹjọ giga apapọ kan to fikalẹ siluu Port-Harcourt, nipinlẹ Rivers, ti sọ pe ọrọ gbigba abẹrẹ ajẹsara arun Koronafairọọsi ni Naijiria, ẹni to ba fẹ, to si nifẹẹ si gbigba abẹrẹ naa lo le lọọ gba a, ki i ṣe ọrọ tulaasi, bẹẹ nijọba o gbọdọ fipa fun ẹnikẹni labẹrẹ ọhun.Ọjọ Iṣẹgun, Tusidee yii, nile-ẹjọ naa gbe aṣẹ yii kalẹ ninu idajọ lori ẹjọ kan ti nọmba rẹ jẹ FHC/PH/FHR/266/2021, eyi ti Ọgbẹni Charlse Godwin fi pe ijọba ipinlẹ Edo, Gomina Ọbaseki, atawọn mẹrin mi-in lẹjọ si kootu naa.Gomina Obaseki lo ti kọkọ paṣẹ laipẹ yii pe dandan ni ki gbogbo awọn olugbe ipinlẹ Edo lọọ gba abẹrẹ ajẹsara Korona, aijẹ bẹẹ, ijọba le ma jẹ ki wọn ṣejọsin ni ṣọọṣi ati mọṣalaṣi, awọn banki ati awọn ile-ijọba, wọn si tun le padanu awọn anfaani ati ẹtọ kan lọdọ ijọba ti wọn o ba ṣe bẹẹ.Ipinnu yii ni olupẹjọ naa lọ pẹjọ le lori, o ni kile-ẹjọ ba awọn da si i, boya ijọba laṣẹ lati sọ gbigba abẹrẹ arun Korona di kan-n-pa bẹẹ.Ninu alaye rẹ, agbẹjọro olupẹjọ rọ ile-ẹjọ lati da ijọba lọwọ kọ na, ki wọn si faaye gba a pe kawọn oniroyin ati iwe iroyin gbe gbogbo bi ẹjọ naa ba ṣe lọ si sojutaye.Adajọ Adamu Turaki Mohammed to bojuto ẹjọ yii sọ pe oun fọwọ si ẹbẹ olupẹjọ, o ni kijọba Edo ma ṣe mu ẹnikẹni nipa lati gba abẹrẹ ajẹsara Korona titi ti igbẹjọ yoo fi pari lori ẹjọ naa, o ni ẹnikẹni to ba nifẹẹ si i le lọọ gba a tabi kọyin si i.Adajọ naa sun igbẹjọ to kan si ọjọ kẹwaa, oṣu kẹsan-an, ọdun yii."},{"question":"onas is féidir liom leanbh a spreagadh chun é a tharraingt suas? ","answer":"D'fhéadfá iarracht a dhéanamh ag rá \\"taigh suas\\" nó \\"seas suas\\", ach is dócha nach n-oibreoidh sé an-mhaith. Níl leanaí in ann na rudaí seo a dhéanamh féin go dtí go bhfuil siad thart ar naoi mí d'aois, agus tá sé de dhualgas orainn cabhrú leo na scileanna seo a fhoghlaim. Mar sin, is féidir leat tosú ag seacht mí agus ansin leanúint ar aghaidh ag cleachtadh é ar do chuid féin sa bhaile. An níos mó a dhéanann tú é seo, an níos mó a thuigeann an leanbh go bhfuil sé ag iarraidh é sin a dhéanamh i ndáiríre."},{"question":"英語で雨はレイン。では虹は何という？","answer":"レインボーです。"},{"question":"はかなく消えてしまった恋のことを、「泡」という意味の言葉を使って「何の恋」というでしょう？","answer":"うたかたの恋です。"},{"question":"Iza ireo olona voakajy anatin’ny fumeurs passifs ?","answer":"Sokajiana ho fumeurs passifs avokoa ireo olona tsy mpifoka sigara nefa tafafoka tsy fidiny noho ny setroka sigara an’ireo olona mpifoka manodidina azy. Tafiditra ao anatin’izany ny ankizy, ny zaza ao am-bohoka, ny tanora sy ny olon-dehibe."},{"question":"人々に親しまれる警察をめざすということから「ピープル」と「ポリス」を合成して名付けられた、警視庁のマスコットキャラクターといえば何でしょう？","answer":"ピーポくんです。"},{"question":"句子1: 拉蒙加是新西兰北方地区的旺加雷郊区. 诺斯兰理工学院的主要校园在拉蒙加. 第二句: 是新西兰北方地区的拉蒙加郊区. 诺斯兰理工学院的主要校园位于旺格雷. 问题:第一句和第二句表达相同的意义吗? 相同还是不同?","answer":"不同"},{"question":"Ahoana no hipetrahan'ny saka amin'ny tongony rehefa lavo?","answer":"Ny saka dia manana hazondamosina malefaka ary afaka manodina ny vatany amin'ny rivotra mba hipetraka amin'ny tongony."},{"question":"Ал мени итсин деди.- Итмин - дедим...Тек гана терикпестен кулуп туруп.Не кылам жаман айтып жаакташыпМен анын ит экенин билип туруп.Жогорудагы ыр саптарынын автору ким? Жана бул ырдын аталышы кандай?","answer":"Бул ырдын автору кыргыз элинин таланттуу, таамай айтып жазган, сөздөрү курч акын Байдылда Сарногоевке таандык.КАЛА БЕРДИАл мени итсин деди.- Итмин - дедим...Тек гана терикпестен кулуп туруп.Не кылам жаман айтып жаакташыпМен анын ит экенин билип туруп.Ал мени эшек деди,- Обба - дедим.Болбосо шылдындоого жетет тилим...Не кылам ажылдашып, кажылдашыпМен анын билип туруп эшектигин.Ал мага албууттанып жана бердиСоздору жийиркентип кара жерди.Ролун эки айбандын бир аткарыпАртымдан ээрчий басып кала берди."},{"question":"Quem inventou o gramofone?","answer":"O gramofone foi inventado por Emile Berliner em 1887."},{"question":"Inona no atao hoe mokonazy?","answer":"Ny mokonazy dia voan' ny hazo atao hoe lamoty, maniry any amorontsiraka andrefanan'i Madagasikara, izay ohatra ny voam-boandelaka ny habeny, amidy betsaka fa maro mpitia aty afovoan-tany amin' ny fotoana fahavokarany (avrily-mey)."},{"question":"பசுவின் கன்று எவ்வாறு இறந்தது? கன்றினை இழந்த பசுவின் எண்ணத்தை மன்னர் எவ்வாறு வெளிப்படுத்தினார்?","answer":"அரசனின் மகன் தேரைத் தெருவில் ஓட்டிச் செல்லும்போது, அங்குத் துள்ளிக் குதித்துக் கொண்டிருந்த பசுவின் கன்று, எதிர்பாராத வகையில் தேர்க்காலில் மாட்டி இறந்தது.“நீயும் ஒரு மன்னனா? உனக்கு மகன் எப்படியோ அப்படியே எனக்கு என் கன்று அல்லவா? அந்தச் சின்னஞ்சிறு கன்று என்ன பாவம் செய்தது? அதன் உயிரைப் போக்க உங்களுக்கு எப்படி மனம் வந்தது? கன்றை இழந்து தவிக்கும் எனக்கு யார் ஆறுதல் தருவார்? இனி என் வாழ்நாளெல்லாம் வீண்தானோ என்று கேட்பது போல் இருக்கிறது” என்று பசுவின் எண்ணத்தை மன்னர் வெளிப்படுத்தினார்."},{"question":"Wọn ti mu Idris to gun mẹkaniiki pa n’Igbẹsa","answer":"Ọwọ ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ogun ti pada tẹ Bọbọ, ogbologboo ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun ti orukọ rẹ gan-an jẹ Babatunde Idris, ọmo ọdun mọkandinlogun, to gun mẹkaniiki to n ṣiṣẹ ẹ jẹẹjẹ nigo n’Igbẹsa lọjọ Aiku, Sannde ọsẹ yii, ti ọkunrin naa, Salaudeen Lawal, si ṣe bẹẹ dagbere faye.Ọjọ kejidinlogun, oṣu kẹwaa yii, ni Salawu mẹkaniiki n tun mọto kan ṣe nibi ti wọn ti pe e pe ko waa ba wọn tun un ṣe. Mọto naa lo n ṣe lọwọ gẹgẹ bawọn ọlọpaa ṣe wi, ti Bọbọ fi kọja, to si sọ pe mẹkaniiki naa ti fi ọkọ to n tunṣe di oju ọna. Ohun to dija naa ree, Idris fi mu akufọ igo, to fi gun Salawu lọwọ, bi iṣan ọwọ iyẹn ṣe ja niyẹn, lẹjẹ ba n ya.Wọn sare gbe ọkunrin naa lọ sọsibitu to wa nitosi, ṣugbọn nibi to ti n gba itọju lọwọ lo ku si, oro iṣan to ja latari igo ti Bọbọ gun un lo si ran an sọrun.Ọjọ Aiku ti Bọbọ gun mẹkaniiki naa pa lo ti sa lọ, ọjọ naa lawọn ọlọpaa si ti kede rẹ pe awọn n wa a o. Bi ẹnikẹni ba ba awọn ri ọmọ ẹgbẹ okunkun ti wọn bẹru ẹ ni gbogbo Igbẹsa naa, ki wọn ta awọn lolobo.Mọnde ọsẹ yii ti i ṣe ọjọ kọkandinlogun, oṣu kẹwaa, lọwọ ba afurasi naa ni Surulere, niluu Eko, to sa lọ lẹyin to gun eeyan pa n’Igbẹsa.Ọmọkunrin naa ti jẹwọ fawọn ọlọpaa pe oun loun huwa to fa iku Salawu, Alukoro ọlọpaa nipinlẹ Ogun, DSP Abimbọla Oyeyẹmi si fidi eleyii mulẹ.Ẹka to n gbọ ejọ awọn apaayan ni wọn taari ọmọ ọdun mọkandilogun naa lọ gẹgẹ bii aṣẹ ti CP Edward Ajogun pa."},{"question":"Tohizo izao ohabolana izao : \\" Hadinoy ny lasa ary _\\"","answer":"\\"  Hadinoy ny lasa ary aza tsikeraina intsony ny lavenonany.  \\" "},{"question":"السؤال: من اكتشف البنسلين؟","answer":"الإجابة: الكسندر فليمنج"},{"question":"a) Tìm số thích hợp ở ?:8 : 1 = ?;                          8 : 5 = ? (dư ?);8 : 2 = ?;                          8 : 6 = ? (dư ?);8 : 3 = ? (dư ?);                8 : 7 = ? (dư ?);8 : 4 = ?;                          8 : 8 = ?;b) Hãy chỉ ra các ước của 8.","answer":"Lời giải:a) Ta có: 8 : 1 = 88 : 2 = 48 : 3 = 2 (dư 2)8 : 4 = 28 : 5 = 1 (dư 3)8 : 6 = 1 (dư 2)8 : 7 = 1 (dư 1)8 : 8 = 1.b) Theo câu a, ta có 8 chia hết cho các số 1; 2; 4; 8 nên các ước của 8 là: 1; 2; 4; 8."},{"question":"Lẹyin ọdun mẹjọ to ti paayan ni Mowe, Sheu gbadajọ iku l’Abẹokuta","answer":"Gẹgẹ bi akọsilẹ kootu ṣe wi, ọjọ kẹẹẹdogun oṣu kẹsan-an ọdun 2013 ni ọkunrin kan ti wọn ni fijilante loun naa, Sheu Jimọh, yinbọn pa ẹnikan ti wọn pe orukọ ẹ ni Tosin Joye, ni Mowe. Ṣugbọn lọjọ Ẹti ti kọja yii, eyi ti i ṣe ọdun kẹjọ lẹyin iṣẹlẹ naa,kootu giga ilu Abẹokuta dajọ iku fun Sheu,wọn ni ki wọn yẹgi mọ ọn lọrun titi ti yoo fi ku.Adajọ Abiọdun Akinyẹmi  lo gbe idajọ naa kalẹ pẹlu alaye pe awijare kan ko si lori keesi yii mọ, gbogbo ẹ lo foju han pe Sheu yinbọn paayan, oun naa si gbọdọ ku gẹgẹ bi ofin ṣe wi ni.Obinrin ni agbefọba lori ẹsun yii, orukọ rẹ ni Abilekọ Oluwaṣeni  Ogunjimi. Obinrin yii ṣalaye pe ni nnkan bii aago mẹsan-an alẹ ọjọ kẹẹẹdogun, oṣu kẹsan-an ọdun 2013 ni Sheu to jẹ ọkan lara awọn fijilante igba naa , yinbọn pa Tosin Joye, ni ikorita Atala, lagbegbe Bọlatito, Mowe.O fi kun un pe Tosin pẹlu awọn ọrẹ ẹ fẹẹ lọọ ra omi inu ọra ti wọn  n pe ni piọ wọta ni. Afi bi fijilante yii ṣe yinbọn mọ wọn laiṣẹ,Tosin ni ibọn ọhun ba ninu gbogbo awọn ti wọn n lọ naa, nibi ti wọn si ti n gbe e lọ sileewosan lo ti dakẹ loju ọna, to ku patapata.Ẹnu ẹjọ yii ni wọn wa latigba naa, ko too di pe Adajọ Abiọdun Akinyẹmi da a lọjọ Ẹti to kọja yii, pe ki wọn yẹgi mọ Sheu lọrun, koun naa maa lọ sibi to ran Tosin Joye lọ."},{"question":"Буйрук сүйлөм - бул?","answer":"Буйрук сүйлөмСүйлөп жаткан адамдын, айтуучунун эркин, тилегин, өтүнүчүн, буйругун билдирген сүйлөм буйрук сүйлөм деп аталат. Мисалы: Окугула! Азыр жооп бересиңер! Токтогула! Кайда бара жатасыңар? Укпайсыңарбы! Өз билгениңди кыл!"},{"question":"atao inona ny ovy alohan'ny hitetehana azy?","answer":"voasana ny ovy alohan'ny hitetehana azy"},{"question":"Awọn ọlọpaa ti ju Sẹnetọ Rochas Okorocha, gomina  ipinlẹ Imo tẹlẹ, satimọle","answer":"Gomina to ṣẹṣẹ kuro lori aleefa nipinlẹ Imo, to tun jẹ ọmọ ileegbimọ aṣofin agba l’Abuja, Sẹnetọ Rochas Okorocha, ti wa lahaamọ awọn ọlọpaa bayii.Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ni awọn lawọn mu ọkunrin naa lọsan-an ọjọ Aiku, Sannde yii, latari bi wọn ṣe fẹsun kan an pe o ko awọn janduku kan atawọn ololufẹ rẹ sodi, wọn si lọọ ṣakọlu si otẹẹli kan ti wọn pe ni Royal Palm Estate, eyi tijọba ipinlẹ Imo faṣẹ ọba ti pa l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, to kọja yii.Gomina tẹlẹri naa ti kọkọ sọ pe ikọja-aaye ni fun ijọba to wa lori aleefa lati faṣẹ ọba ti otẹẹli to jẹ tiyawo oun, lai si ẹri tabi ẹsun kan nile-ẹjọ lodi si Abilekọ Okorocha lori ilẹ ati ile to kọ naa.A gbọ pe nnkan bii aago marun-un irọlẹ ọjọ Aiku yii, tibinu tibinu ni Sẹnetọ Okorocha atawọn isọngbe rẹ lọọ ja gbogbo agadagodo ati okun ti wọn so mọ ẹnu geeti otẹẹli naa danu.Wọn niṣẹlẹ yii mu kawọn janduku ba awọn ọkọ ayọkẹlẹ kan jẹ, ti wọn si ṣe awọn agbofinro kan atawọn to fẹẹ gbẹja aṣẹ gomina naa leṣe.Gẹgẹ bi Ajọ Akoroyinjọ ilẹ wa (NAN), ṣe wi, Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Imo ni wọn ti mu Okorocha atawọn janduku kan tọwọ ba sakata awọn ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Imo bayii, ati pe wọn yoo foju gbogbo wọn bale-ẹjọ lowurọ ọjọ Aje, fun ẹsun idaluru, didi alaafia ilu lọwọ, ati titapa si aṣẹ ijọba.Gomina to ṣẹṣẹ kuro lori aleefa nipinlẹ Imo, to tun jẹ ọmọ ileegbimọ aṣofin agba l’Abuja, Sẹnetọ Rochas Okorocha, ti wa lahaamọ awọn ọlọpaa bayii.Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ni awọn lawọn mu ọkunrin naa lọsan-an ọjọ Aiku, Sannde yii, latari bi wọn ṣe fẹsun kan an pe o ko awọn janduku kan atawọn ololufẹ rẹ sodi, wọn si lọọ ṣakọlu si otẹẹli kan ti wọn pe ni Royal Palm Estate, eyi tijọba ipinlẹ Imo faṣẹ ọba ti pa l’Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, to kọja yii.Gomina tẹlẹri naa ti kọkọ sọ pe ikọja-aaye ni fun ijọba to wa lori aleefa lati faṣẹ ọba ti otẹẹli to jẹ tiyawo oun, lai si ẹri tabi ẹsun kan nile-ẹjọ lodi si Abilekọ Okorocha lori ilẹ ati ile to kọ naa.A gbọ pe nnkan bii aago marun-un irọlẹ ọjọ Aiku yii, tibinu tibinu ni Sẹnetọ Okorocha atawọn isọngbe rẹ lọọ ja gbogbo agadagodo ati okun ti wọn so mọ ẹnu geeti otẹẹli naa danu.Wọn niṣẹlẹ yii mu kawọn janduku ba awọn ọkọ ayọkẹlẹ kan jẹ, ti wọn si ṣe awọn agbofinro kan atawọn to fẹẹ gbẹja aṣẹ gomina naa leṣe.Gẹgẹ bi Ajọ Akoroyinjọ ilẹ wa (NAN), ṣe wi, Ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Imo ni wọn ti mu Okorocha atawọn janduku kan tọwọ ba sakata awọn ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Imo bayii, ati pe wọn yoo foju gbogbo wọn bale-ẹjọ lowurọ ọjọ Aje, fun ẹsun idaluru, didi alaafia ilu lọwọ, ati titapa si aṣẹ ijọba."},{"question":"Escreva uma continuação parae esse parágrafo - Mladen Bratić ( em Sérvio Cirílico: Младен Братић ) foi um General Sérvio-Bósnio, nascido no extinto Reino da Ioguslávia, se tornou um general do Exército popular Ioguslavo ( JNA ), ele atuou no Front Croata durante a Guerra de Indepêndencia da Croácia, onde foi um teatro de bastante sangue durante a Guerra Civil Ioguslava, uma batalha marcante durante o conflito foi a Batalha de Vukovár,","answer":"onde instalaram-se defesas com peças de artilharia e Carros de combate, do lado dos Sérvios, também tinham organizações Para-militares, como o a Guarda Guarda Voluntária Sérvia ( Tigres de Arkan ), entre outras. Um dos principais centros desse combate como já dito foi a Batalha de Vukovár, que tem seu principal símbolo uma Caixa da água distruída por"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"adat dunia balas-membalas, syariat palu-memalu\\"?","answer":"Berbuat baik mendapat balasan yang baik dan berbuat jahat mendapat balasan buruk; manusia harus tolong-menolong antara satu sama lain dalam kehidupan"},{"question":"කරන්ගෑටි.... මේ වචනයේ තේරුම? ⁣","answer":"සරල විදියට කියන්නම්, වගාවක දී බලාපොරොත්තු වන්නේ සරු අස්වැන්නක් ඒ සදහා විවිධ දේ අවශ්‍යයයි. හොද බීජ,ජලය ,පස ආදී දේ අස්වැන්න නෙලීමට පෙර ජලය නියමිත ලෙස නොලැබුණොත් එහි ඵල ( ගෙඩි, කරල්, ) ආදිය සම්පූර්ණ නොවේ. ඒවා කරන්ගෑටි වේ.ඒ අනුව නියමිතපෝෂණය නොලැබුණු දෙයින් ලැබෙන අස්වැන්න කරන්ගෑටි ය.සමහර ග්‍රාමීය වැඩිහිටියන් කෘෂ ශරීර ඇති කුඩා දරුවන්ට ද ,කොල්ලා කරන්ගෑටි වෙලා, යනුවෙන් කියනවා අසා ඇත්තෙමි."},{"question":"Gini bu azịza gwam gwam gwam(agwụgwa) aGwa m nwa okoro ọcha gbara aka rịa ọjị","answer":"Ido"},{"question":"Бир өңчөй мүчөлүү сүйлөмдөр деген эмне ?","answer":"Сүйлөмдө бирдей суроого жооп берип, бирдей милдетти аткарган сөздөр бир өңчөй мүчөлөр болот. Бир өңчөй мүчөлөрдүн арасына үтүр белгиси коюлат. Бир өңчөй мүчөлөр катышкан сүйлөмдөр бир өңчөй мүчөлүү сүйлөмдөр деп аталат. Мисалы: Кыргызстанда Бишкек, Кант, Кара-Балта шаарлары бар. Бишкек, Кант, Кара-Балта – бир өңчөй мүчөлөр."},{"question":"Kenapakah tugu negara dibina?","answer":"Tugu Negara telah dibina sebagai tanda memperingati pejuang negara melawan tentera British."},{"question":"问题：什么是咖喱饭，它在印度菜中的地位如何？","answer":"答案：咖喱饭是一道由米饭和咖喱粉调制而成的菜肴。它在印度菜中被广泛食用，常作为主食或作为配菜搭配其他菜肴食用。"},{"question":"భారతదేశాన్ని కాపాడిన కొందరు వీరపురుషులను గురించి తెలపండి.","answer":"శివాజీఝాన్సీ లక్ష్మీబాయిరాణీ రుద్రమదేవిశ్రీకృష్ణదేవరాయలుపృథ్వీరాజుప్రతాపరుద్రుడు"},{"question":"Көздү кайсы азыктар талкалайт?","answer":"1. Кофеин - көздүн ички басымын жогорулатып, күч келтирет. Кофени ашыкча колдонуу, көздүн кан айлануусун начарлатышы мүмкүн.2. Туз - организмдеги суюктукту азайтып турат. Ашыкча колдонуу көздүн ички ткандарын кургатып жибериши мүмкүн. Андыктан, күнүнө 5 граммдан ашык колдонбоону адистер сунушташат.3. Шекер (сахар) - таттуунун бардык түрлөрүн ашыкча колдонуу, көз үчүн эле эмес ден соолук үчүн да чоң зыян алып келет. Биз колдонуп ичип жүргөн газ суусундуктары (пепси,кола) кантка толо."},{"question":"Sử dụng tiêu đề và tóm tắt sau để viết một bài báo tối đa 500 chữ.Tiêu đề: Nguy cơ mất mạng do nổ bóng bay chứa khí hydroTóm tắt: Bóng bay chứa khí hydro chỉ cần tiếp xúc với nhiệt độ cao có thể phát nổ gây bỏng mặt, mù mắt, bỏng, thậm chí nguy cơ tử vong.","answer":"Sáng 5/9, một vụ nổ bóng bay xảy ra tại lễ khai giảng trường Tiểu học Yên Phú, huyện Yên Định, Thanh Hóa khiến 10 trẻ bị bỏng. Một học sinh đã về nhà, 9 em tiếp tục ở lại viện theo dõi, điều trị. Nguyên nhân là một thầy giáo hút thuốc lá, lửa từ điếu thuốc châm vào bóng bay có bơm khí hydro, phát nổ.Bác sĩ Nguyễn Thái Ngọc Minh, Khoa Hồi sức Cấp cứu, Bệnh viện Bỏng Quốc gia Lê Hữu Trác, cho biết hydro là chất khí rất dễ bắt cháy, là nguyên nhân gây nhiều vụ nổ công nghiệp hoặc cháy nổ trong sinh hoạt. Mỗi năm, bệnh viện tiếp nhận hàng chục nạn nhân bị bỏng nặng do nổ bóng bay sử dụng khí này.Khí hydro có cấu trúc phân tử rất bé, dễ dàng thẩm thấu cực nhanh qua màng bóng bay, chỉ cần tiếp xúc với bóng đèn, gặp không khí nóng hoặc ra ngoài trời nắng là có thể nổ tung. Khí hydro bị nén trong bóng bay sẽ phát nổ rất mạnh, nguy cơ gây bỏng mặt, mù mắt, bỏng tay cho người cầm.\\"Nếu tiếp xúc nhiều, nạn nhân nguy cơ bỏng sâu, bỏng hô hấp, nguy hiểm tính mạng\\", ông Minh nói, thêm rằng, bỏng còn gây tác động rất mạnh về tâm thần đối với bệnh nhân. Bệnh nhân nguy cơ bị stress cấp, trầm cảm, lo âu. Do đó, ngoài điều trị thể xác, người bệnh phải điều trị tâm lý để tái hòa nhập cộng đồng, nhất là trẻ nhỏ.Tương tự, bác sĩ Trần Văn Phúc, Bệnh viện đa khoa Xanh Pôn, nói khí hydro hoặc khí heli đều giúp bóng bay được lên. Trong đó, heli không màu, không múi, không cháy ở nhiệt độ và áp suất bình thường. Còn hydro cũng không màu, không mùi, trong suốt nhưng dễ cháy và nổ ngay cả ở điều kiện nhiệt độ và áp suất bình thường, được sử dụng làm bom. Do đó, nhiều nước phát triển đã cấm dùng hydro mà chỉ cho phép bơm heli.Hiện, Việt Nam chưa ban hành lệnh cấm hydro. Ngoài ra, giá hydro chỉ bằng 1/4 so với heli, nên một số người bán bóng bay vẫn bơm hydro vào quả bóng để tiết kiệm kinh phí.\\"Khi phát nổ, quả bóng bay chứa hydro có thể biến thành quả cầu lửa gây bỏng, chưa kể áp lực tạo ra từ tiếng nổ có sức công phá rất lớn\\", bác sĩ cho biết. Nạn nhân có nguy cơ bị bỏng và tổn thương đụng dập mô mềm, mảnh bóng bay có thể xuyên qua cổ họng, làm mù mắt.Bác sĩ khuyến cáo khi bị gặp trường hợp nổ bóng bay cần bình tĩnh, tránh hoảng hốt gây thêm cháy nổ. Khi bị bỏng, mọi người nên hạ nhiệt vết thương cho nạn nhân bằng nước sạch, mát (16-20 độ c), sau đó che phủ tạm thời và vận chuyển nạn nhân đến cơ sở y tế. Tại cơ sở y tế, bệnh nhân có thể khám các triệu chứng bỏng đường hô hấp và bỏng kết giác mạc để được điều trị kịp thời, tránh để lại biến chứng. Trẻ em bị bỏng có nguy cơ sang chấn tâm lý, cần được gia đình và bác sĩ hỗ trợ điều trị thêm.Bên cạnh đó, người lớn cần lưu ý khi cho trẻ chơi bóng. Trường hợp mua bóng bay để trang trí, bắt buộc phải hỏi người bán, đảm bảo bóng bay được bơm khí heli, \\"do không thể phân biệt được bằng mắt thường\\". Không cho trẻ chơi bóng bay bơm khí hydro ở trong nhà, nơi dễ tiếp xúc với các nguồn lửa để tránh cháy nổ, có thể nguy hiểm tính mạng.Chính quyền cần ban hành lệnh cấm bóng bay ở những nơi đông người, như cấm mang bóng bay trên phương tiện giao thông công cộng, cấm dùng trong những bữa tiệc đông người."},{"question":"Tsumo inotevera inorevei?Murombo munhu.","answer":"Munhu chero chiri chirema kana benzi anongori munhu chete."},{"question":"Qual o segundo esporte mais popular no Brasil?","answer":"No Brasil, o futebol é, de longe, o esporte mais popular e amplamente praticado. No entanto, quando se trata do segundo esporte mais popular, o cenário pode variar ao longo do tempo e em diferentes regiões do país. Alguns esportes que têm uma presença significativa no Brasil após o futebol incluem:Vôlei: O voleibol é um esporte muito popular no Brasil, especialmente entre as mulheres. A seleção brasileira de vôlei conquistou numerosos títulos olímpicos e mundiais, tornando-se uma potência global no esporte.Futsal: O futsal, uma variante do futebol jogada em quadras menores, é popular em todo o Brasil, com muitas competições locais e nacionais.Surfe: O Brasil possui uma costa extensa e condições favoráveis para o surfe, o que levou ao crescimento do esporte em áreas costeiras. Vários surfistas brasileiros têm se destacado internacionalmente.Judô: O judô é um esporte popular no Brasil, com uma forte tradição de sucesso em competições internacionais, incluindo as Olimpíadas.MMA: As artes marciais mistas (MMA) ganharam popularidade no Brasil nas últimas décadas, com diversos lutadores brasileiros de destaque nas principais organizações de MMA em todo o mundo.É importante notar que a popularidade dos esportes pode variar em diferentes regiões do Brasil, e as preferências esportivas individuais também desempenham um papel significativo na determinação do segundo esporte mais popular em diferentes comunidades e grupos demográficos."},{"question":"வினா : இந்தியாவிலேயே அதிக மழை பெறும் மாநிலம்?","answer":"விடை: அஸ்ஸாம்"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"awak rendah sangkutan tinggi\\"?","answer":"I bermaksud perbelanjaan lebih besar daripada pendapatan"},{"question":"અહીં એક \\"કેડ, કંદોરો ને કાછડી\\" બાળવાર્તા ના શરૂઆતના ફકરા લખેલા છે:\\"એક હતો વાણિયો.એક નાના ગામમાં એની નાની સરખી હાટડી હતી. તેલ વેચવાનો ધંધો કરે. શેઠ પણ પોતે અને નોકર પણ પોતે. બધું કામ જાતે જ કરવાનું. એક વાર બાજુના ગામમાંથી કહેણ આવ્યું કે ‘શેઠ, અમારે થોડું તેલ ખરીદવું છે તો અમને આવીને આપી જાઓ.’વાણિયાએ તો કેડ પર કંદોરો પહેર્યો, મેલા-ઘેલા ધોતિયાની કાછડી બાંધી, એક હાથમાં તેલભરેલી તાંબડી લીધી, તેમાં તેલનું માપ રાખવાની પળી ભરાવી, બીજા હાથમાં ડાંગ જેવી લાકડી લીધી અને બાજુના ગામ જવાનો રસ્તો પકડ્યો.બાજુના ગામમાં તેલ વેચી, રોકડા રૂપિયા લઈ એ પાછો આવતો હતો ત્યારે તેને રસ્તામાં ચાર ચોર મળ્યા. વાણિયાને એકલો જતો જોઈ ચોર લોકોને થયું કે આને લૂંટી લેવામાં વાંધો નહિ આવે. એક ચોરે પૂ્છ્યું : ‘કેમ, શેઠ અત્યારે એકલા એકલા ક્યાં જાઓ છો?’\\"આ બાળવાર્તા ને પુરી કરો.","answer":"વાણિયો તો ચાર ચોરને જોઈ સમજી ગયો હતો કે હું એકલો છું અને આ લોકો ચાર છે એટલે જો કંઈક યુક્તિ નહિ કરું તો આજે જરૂર લૂંટાઈ જવાનો. પણ એનામાં હિમ્મત જબરી હતી. સાવ બેફિકર થઈને તેણે ડીંગ હાંકી : ‘હું એકલો ક્યાં છું. અમે તો બાર જણા સાથે નીકળ્યા છીએ.’ચોરોને થયું કે ઓહો, આ લોકો બાર જણા હોય તો આપણી કારી નહિ ફાવે. તો ય એક ચોરે પૂછ્યું : ‘અલ્યા, બાર જણ તે કોણ છે?‘વાણિયો કહે :કેડ, કંદોરો ને કાછડી, અમે ત્રણ જણા;તેલ, પળી ને તાંબડી અમે છ જણા;ડાંગ, ડોસો ને લાકડી, અમે નવ જણા;શેઠ, વાણિયો ને હાટડી અમે બાર જણા.’ચોરોને તો કંઈ સમજાયું જ નહિ કે વાણિયો શું કહે છે. તેઓએ તો માન્યું કે વાણિયાની સાથે ઘણાં બધાં જણા છે એટલે તેને લૂંટવા જતાં આપણે જ માર ખાવાનો વખત આવશે. બીને તેઓ ત્યાંથી ઝટપટ રવાના થઈ ગયા. અને યુક્તિબાજ વાણિયો હસતો હસતો ઘરભેગો થઈ ગયો."},{"question":"长枪与短枪哪个射出去的子弹打得远？","answer":"长枪"},{"question":"Ijọba Kwara fẹẹ sọ ibudo imọkoko Dada di tigbalode -Oyin-Zubair","answer":"Ni idaahun si ẹbẹ awọn to n ṣe ikoko ibilẹ nibudo to gbajumọ daadaa lagbegbe Dada, niluu Ilọrin, ijọba ipinlẹ Kwara ti ni eto ti n lọ lọwọ lati sọ ibudo naa di ti igbalode nipa ipese awọn ohun eelo ti yoo mu iṣẹ rọrun fawọn amọkoko naa.Oluranlọwọ pataki fun Gomina Abdulrahman Abdulrazaq nipa ọrọ ilu, SSA Community Intervention, Ọgbẹni Kayọde Oyin-Zubair, lo sọrọ ọhun nibi ipade kan to ṣe pẹlu awọn obinrin to n mọ ikoko ni Dada, niluu Ilọrin.Oyin-Zubair ni, ṣiṣe igbelarugẹ awọn okoowo keekeeke to tun jẹ tibilẹ bii ti ikoko mimọ yii jẹ ijọba Kwara logun gidi. Idi niyi tijọba fi ri i pe pupọ lara awọn obinrin to n ṣe iṣẹ naa janfaani owo iranwọ fawọn oniṣowo kekeeke eyi to waye laipẹ yii.O tẹsiwaju pe pataki ohun to gbe ijọba wa sibudo naa ni lati tun fi da awọn obinrin naa loju pe ijọba fẹẹ mu aye dẹrun fun okoowo wọn lati sọ ọ di igbalode ati ape-waa-wo fun agbaye.Awọn obinrin naa fi idunnu wọn han si bi aṣoju gomina ṣe waa bẹ wọn wo. Wọn lo anfaani naa lati dupẹ lọwọ ijọba fun owo iranwọ ti ọpọlọpọ wọn janfaani.Ṣaaju ni Alhaja Raliat Saka to jẹ adari awọn obinrin to n mọ ikoko nibudo Dada ti beere fun awọn ẹrọ igbalode lati mu ki iṣẹ wọn rọrun ati ko si tun joju ju bo ṣe wa lọ."},{"question":"Ngimkhumbule namuhla uMntungwa. Sasivame ukuhlala sobabiliphansi kwalesi sihlahla. Ngixakwa yilaba abangibelesele ngendabakaDumisani. Bayahlanya. Abazi ukuthi angiyingeni indaba yokungenwamina. Kodwa yena uMntungwa angathini lapho ekhona? Noma ngabeuDumisani usekhulile nje, ngeke ungibone ngimgana mina. Minaangisiye owokuganga. Naye ngizomgada manje uma efikile. Umaengeshela nje ngiyomkhombisa ikheli. Ngimbuze ukuthi ungithandamanini nje. Uma enganakile futhi siyodumelana kube kuncane indawo.Uyazi angimazi nalo muntu owasungula isiko lokungenwa wayehlushweyini. Abantu bayathanda ukusungula amasiko adala izinkinga.(Ezwe izigi) Nangu umama eza. Uma eqala le ndaba yesiko lakheuzongizwa kahle namuhla. Angihleki angithi nsi. Angifuni ndoda njeeduze kwami manje.Uyawuthanda lo msebenzi wokuthunga koti bo. (Ahlale phansi)Ngenzela ukuthi ngingakhohlwa mama. Nawo umshini awufuni ukuhlalaisikhathi eside ungasebenzi.Kuzofuneka ungifundise nami makoti ngizithungele.Awu mama uthi kungalunga ufundiswa imfundamakhwela?Akubonakali ukuthi usafunda koti. Ukwenza kwakho kukhombisaubumpetha. Impela ngicela ungifundise. Siningi kabi isikhathiesizosihlala nawe ngingagcina sengiwushaya njengawe nje.Usho ukuthini umama uma ethi sisazohlala isikhathi eside?Kanti uyahamba yini?Ngingeze ngasho ukuthi ngiyahamba mama. Uma sekukhunyulwe inzilobengizocela ukuba ngibuyele ekhaya. 1. Hlobo luni lomdlalo lolu? Sekela impendulo yakho ngephuzu ELILODWA.","answer":"Imbangalusizi. √Umdlalo unosizi phakathi ngoba kuchitheka igazi, kwashona uSikhumbuzonoSipho. Kwalimala uDumisani.√"},{"question":"\\"વર્ડપ્રેસ\\" સોફ્ટવેર શું છે?","answer":"વર્ડપ્રેસ એ મફત અને ઓપન-સોર્સ બ્લોગીંગ ટુલ્સ અને કન્ટેન્ટ મેનેજમેન્ટ સીસ્ટમ છે. તે PHP (પીએચપી) પ્રોગ્રામિંગ ભાષા અને MySql ડેટાબેઝ પર આધારિત છે. જેની પહેલી આવૃત્તિ ૨૦૦૩ માં મેટ મુલેનવેગ અને માઇક લિટલ દ્વારા બહાર પાડવા માં આવી હતી. ૨૦૧૧ માં \\"અલેક્ષા.કોમ\\" નામની સાઈટ કે જે વેબસાઈટ નું મૂલ્યાંકન કરે છે, તેના રીપોર્ટ મુજબ દુનિયા ની ટોપ ૧ મિલિયન વેબસાઈટ માંથી લગભગ ૧૬.૭% વેબસાઈટ વર્ડપ્રેસ ના પ્લેટફોર્મ પર આધારિત હતી."},{"question":"パソコンなど通信速度を表す単位「ｂｐｓ」とは、何の略でしょう？","answer":"ビット パー セカンド（ｂｉｔｓ ｐａｒ ｓｅｃｏｎｄ）です。"},{"question":"Fat soluble vitamins:","answer":"waxaa loo kala qeybiyaalaba nuuc oo kala ah1.Vit. B.complex2. Vit. CWater soluble vitamins:- waxa loo kalaqeybiyaa afar nuucoo kala ah:-1.Vit. A2.Vit. D3.Vit. E4.Vit. K"},{"question":"Ittihaz etmek ne demek hukuk?","answer":"İttihaz sözcüğü daha çok 'ittihaz etmek' şeklinde karşımıza çıkar. Bunun anlamı ise gerekeni yapmak veya almak şeklinde yorumlanır."},{"question":"Inona no vahaolana ?","answer":"Ny vahaolana dia ny  miresaka"},{"question":"ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి భావం రాయండి:మ|| తెలిజాతిన్ జెలువార నచ్చరపడంతిం దిద్ది యా సోగ కన్నుల పజ్జన్ నిను నీవు దిద్దుకొని, సంతోషించుచున్నాడవా!భళిరే ! శిల్పిజగంబులోన జిరజీవత్వంబు సృష్టించుకోగల నీకెవ్వడు సాటివచ్చును? నమస్కారంబు నీ ప్రజ్ఞకున్.","answer":"భావం :ఓ శిల్పీ ! తెల్లని చంద్రకాంత శిలలో అప్సరసను చెక్కి, ఆమె దీర్ఘమైన కన్నులకు ప్రక్కగా నిన్ను నీవు మలచుకొని సంతోషపడుతున్నావా ? భళా ! శిల్పి ప్రపంచంలో శాశ్వతత్వాన్ని కల్పించుకోగలిగిన నీకు, ఎవరూ సాటిరారు. నీ ప్రజ్ఞకు నా నమస్కారాలు."},{"question":"Sentença 1: Uma vez que o treinador está com o objeto, o cão é recompensado (e durante o treino, libertado). Sentença 2: Quando o líder do cão está com o objeto, o cão é libertado (e recompensado durante o treino). Pergunta: A frase 1 e a frase 2 expressam o mesmo significado? Sim ou não?","answer":"Sim, as duas frases expressam o mesmo significado."},{"question":"童謡『赤とんぼ』で、ねえやが嫁に行ったのはいくつのときだったでしょう？","answer":"15"},{"question":"Ẹṣọ alaabo mu awọn Fulani darandaran to ya wọ  Kwara lọna aitọ","answer":"Ajọ ẹsọ alaabo, ṣifu difẹnsi, ẹka ti ipinlẹ Kwara, pẹlu ajọṣepọ ọmọ ologun ati ileeṣẹ ọlọpaa, ti mu awọn Fulani darandaran pẹlu awọn maaluu wọn, ni Ẹrinle si Ọffa, latari pe wọn wọ ipinlẹ naa lọna aitọ.Ninu atẹjade kan ti agbẹnusọ ajọ ẹsọ alaabo ṣifu difẹnsi, Babawale Zaid Afolabi, fi lede ni Ọjọbọ, Tọsidee, ọṣẹ yii, niluu Ilọrin, lo ti sọ pe ajọ naa pẹlu ajọṣepọ ọmọ ologun ati ọlọpaa ti mu awọn afurasi Fulani darandaran pẹlu awọn maaluu wọn ni Ọjọruu, Wẹsidee, ọṣẹ yii, lagbegbe ilu Ẹrinle si Ọffa, ti wọn si ni ilu Ajaṣẹ-Ipo, nijọba ibilẹ Irẹpọdun, ni awọn n lọ fun ibujoko ayọ, ti awọn ẹsọ alaabo si tẹle wọn de ilu Ajaṣẹ-Ipo ti wọn n lọ fun ayẹwo finni-finni ati ẹkunrẹrẹ iwadii."},{"question":"ఆడినమాట తప్పకపోవడం, దానగుణం కలిగి ఉండడం మొదలయిన విశిష్ట లక్షణాల ఆవశ్యకతను తెలుపుతూ నీ మిత్రునికి / స్నేహితురాలికి లేఖ రాయండి.","answer":"భద్రాచలం,X X X X X.మిత్రుడు రామ్ పాల్కు, / మిత్రురాలు రాధికకు,నీ లేఖ చేరింది. నిత్య జీవితంలో మనం ఎలా నడచుకోవాలో తెలుపుతూ మా రామాలయంలో ఓ సాధువుగారు మాట్లాడారు. ఆయన జీవితంలో సత్యవాక్కు, దానగుణము ఉండాలని చెప్పారు. ఆయన మాటలు నాకు నచ్చాయి.పురాణాల్లో కర్ణుడుని దానకర్ణుడు అంటారు. తన ప్రాణానికి ముప్పు వస్తుందని తెలిసినా కర్ణుడు తన సహజ కవచకుండలాలను దానం చేశాడు. అలాగే మనం చదివిన దానశీలము పాఠంలో బలిచక్రవర్తి, గురువు గారు వద్దంటున్న మానకుండా వామనుడికి మూడు అడుగుల నేలను సంతోషంగా ధారపోశాడు. ఆ దానం వల్ల బలి చక్రవర్తి పాతాళలోకంలోకి తొక్కి వేయబడ్డాడు. అయినా ఈ భూమండలం ఉన్నంతవరకు బలిచక్రవర్తి కీర్తి శాశ్వతంగా నిలిచింది.అలాగే శిబి చక్రవర్తి పావురాన్ని రక్షించడానికి తన శరీరాన్ని కోసి ఇచ్చాడు. వారి కీర్తి చిరస్థాయిగా నిలిచింది. మనం కూడా చీటికీ మాటికీ అబద్ధాలు ఆడడం మాని వేయాలి. సత్యవాక్యాన్ని నిలబెట్టాలి. మన మిత్రులకు అవసరం అయినప్పుడు దానం చెయ్యాలి.నేను సత్యమే మాట్లాడతానని, ఉన్నమేరకు ఇతరులకు దానధర్మాలు చేస్తానని ప్రతిజ్ఞ చేశాను. నీవు కూడ తప్పక ఈ మంచి గుణాలను పాటించు.ఇట్లు,నీ మిత్రుడు, / మిత్రురాలు,శివరావు. / సరోజ.చిరునామా :పి. రామ్ గోపాల్, / పి. రాధిక,S/o వెంకట్రావు, / D/o వెంకట్రావు,10వ తరగతి, బాపూజీ నగర్,ఖమ్మం, తెలంగాణ."},{"question":"Bi irọ ba lọ logun ọdun… (2)","answer":"Eyi ti mo fẹẹ sọ yii ki i ṣe wọn ni wọn pe o, ohun to ṣoju iru awa yii daadaa ni. Iyẹn nipa wahala ti mo n ṣalaye ẹ lọsẹ to kọja, ọro ogun wẹẹti-ẹ ti mo mẹnu ba wẹrẹ, oju temi yii lo ṣe o. Ijọba awọn Hausa yii naa ni, bi gbogbo nnkan si ṣe n lọ lasiko yii naa lo ri nigba ti mo n sọ yii. Tafawa Balewa lolori ijọba, Nnamdi Azikiwe ni olori Naijiria, oun lo yẹ ko je ọga fun Balewa, bi nnkan ba lọ bo ti yẹ ko lọ. Ṣugbọn Sardauna Sokoto, iyẹn Ahmadu Bello, ni olori ẹgbẹ awọn Balewa, eyi ja si pe oun ni ọga fun Balewa to n ṣejọba, ohun ti oun ba fẹ ni Balewa n ṣe, ki i ṣe eyi ti Azikiwe ba fẹ. Gbogbo ohun to wa lọkan Sardauna yii ko ju bi Hausa-Fulani yoo ṣe di olori fun Naijiria pata lọ. Iyẹn ni mo ṣe sọ pe bi ọrọ wa ṣe ri nigba naa lo tun n ri lọ yii o.Nnkan le mọ Yoruba lara. Emi yii si wa lara awọn ti wọn n tẹle Awolọwọ ati Akintọla, lati ileewe la ti n ba wọn ṣe. Ṣugbọn nigbai ti ọrọ Yoruba fẹẹ dojuru pata, Sardauna ati Ladoke Akintọla to jẹ olori ijọba wa di ọrẹ nla. Kia ni ija ti de, nitori awọn Sardauna fi ọgbọn fa Akintọla mọra ni. Akintọla bẹre si i gun baba wa garagara, o gba agbara kun agbara lọwọ awọn Sardauan, o fi ara ẹ joye olori Yoruba ni apapandodo. Nibi ti inu bi wa de, bii ka da ina nla ka sọ Akintọla yii si ni. Ṣugbọn pẹlu iranlọwọ oun Akintọla yii, awọn Sardauna sọ Awolọwọ sẹwọn, gbogbo agbara oṣẹlu ilẹ Yoruba si wa lọwọ Akintọla. Kinni naa o tẹ wa lọrun rara, ṣugbọn ki la fẹẹ ṣe. A kan n woran ni.Ṣugbọn ipakọ ko gbọ ṣuti, ori ẹlẹgan lo bajẹ ni Akintọla n fi ọrọ naa ṣe, lojopjumọ lawọn ọmọ wọn n bu wa, gẹgẹ bi awọn oloṣelu wa asiko yii naa ni o. Akintọla gbagbọ pe ko sohun ti ẹnikẹni fẹẹ fi oun ṣe, ati pe ohun yoowu ti oun ba ṣe nigba naa, aṣegbe ni. Ko si ohun ti a le fi i ṣe loootọ, o ti gba gbogbo agbara lọwọ wa. Inu to n bi wa yii, a ti ro pe bi asiko ibo ba de, a maa fi ibo le e lọ ni, a ti leri pe ẹni yoowu ti Akintọla ba wa lẹyin ẹ, awa o ni i dibo fun un. A o mọ pe agbara Akintọla pọ to bẹẹ yẹn, gbogbo eto idibo naa ko ri bi a ṣe ro o si, awọn eeyan Akintọla lo wọle, ohun ti a si foju ri ko ṣee maa fẹnu sọ. Ni 1964 yii, ẹ wo o, inu bi wa, ṣugbọn ko sohun ta a le ṣe. Awọn Sardauna ati Akintọla da ọlọpaa sigboro, ẹni it wọn ba si ri mu ninu wa, ẹwọn ni, nitori adaluru ni wọn n pe wa.1965 lo ku ti a n reti, ibo awọn Akintọla gan-an niyẹn, ibo to fẹẹ fi wọle ẹẹkeji ni. Bi ibo ta a di lakọọkọ ṣe ri, bẹẹ ni ti 1965 yii naa ri, koda, ti 1965 ti mo n sọ yii  tiẹ buru debii pe awọn ti o dije rara, orukọ ẹlomi-in n jade pe oun lo wọle. Awọn eeyan tiwa to dije ti wọn si wọle, orukọ wọn o jade ninu iwe awọn ti wọn ṣeto idibo.Nigba ta a dibo tan, ibinu wa waa le si, n la ba bẹrẹ iwọde pe eru ni eto idibo ti wọn ṣe, aa si fẹ Akintọla ni olori ijọba wa. Iwọde la ṣe titi to fi di nnkan mi-in, iwọde yii la ṣe to fi di wahala nla gan-an. Nibi ti aya mi ti n ja fun ti eyi ti a n ṣe lọwọ yii niyi, nitori eyi ti mo n sọ yii ṣoju emi o. Ṣe ẹ ri i, nigba ti iwọde ba bẹrẹ, awọn eeyan ti ọrọ dun, awọn eeyan ti wọn mọ ohun to ṣẹlẹ gan-an, ti wọn si n fẹ ayipada ẹ, awọn ni wọn maa n ṣaaju, wọn si le fi ọjọ meji mẹta ṣe e ko too di pe kakuku gba ile ẹ jokoo, niwọnba igba ti wọn ba ti ri i tawọn ijọba ti n lakaka lati ṣe ohun ti wọn n beere fun. Iru ẹ lawa ṣe ni tiwa.Ṣugbọn ọrọ iwọde ki i bẹrẹ bẹẹ ko pari bẹẹ, paapaa to ba jẹ iwọde ti awọn oloṣẹlu. Ohun to kọkọ maa n ṣẹlẹ ni pe awọn onijangbọn naa aa jade, bo tilẹ jẹ ko si eyi to kan wọn pẹlu iwọde naa. Ṣugbọn tiwọn dara. Awọn ti tiwọn buru lawọn ọdaran, awọn ọmọọta, ati awọn ti wọn wa niluu ti wọn o niṣẹ, ti wọn o si ri nnkan ṣe. Awọn yii lo buru ju, nitori bi iwọde gidi ba tan, iwọde tiwọn o ni i tan, awọn aa lo anfani naa lati jale, lati kole, ati lati fiya jẹ awọn oloṣẹlu ati ọlọla ti wọn ti mọ tẹlẹ, agaga awọn ti wọn ba sọ pe wọn o ba mẹkunnu ṣe, ti wọn o si n fun mekunnu ni nnkan.Bi wọn ti n kuro nile oloṣelu kan ni wọn aa maa lọ sile oloṣelu mi-in, tabi to jẹ bi wọn ti n kuro nile olowo kan ni wọn aa maa lọ sile olowo mi-in, ti wọn aa si maa ko wọn ni nnkan.  Awọn naa ni wọn maa n pa awọn oloṣelu tabi olowo mi-in ti wọn ba ri. Bi awọn ti wọn ko niṣẹ lọwọ ba ṣe pọ ni adugbo kan to, bẹẹ lawọn janduku ọjọ naa yoo ṣe to. Bi awọn ọmọọta adugbo kan ba ti pọ to, bẹe lawọn ti wọn aa maa dana sunle ati dukia aa ṣe pọ to. Bi idaamu, ikowojẹ ati iwa ibajẹ awọn oloṣelu ati olori ijọba ba ṣe pọ to, bẹẹ ni ibinu awọn ti wọn n yide yii yoo ṣe maa pọ si i, wọn aa si ṣe bẹẹ titi ti wọn aa fi ba nnkan jẹ kọja atunṣe.Ibo ti mo n sọ pe a di ni 1965 yii, lẹyin ti ibo ti di wahala tan, awọn ọmọọta gba gbogbo oju popo, wọn n da gbogbo mọto lọna, wọn n gbowo, wọn si n fiya jẹ ọlọpaa tabi oloṣẹlu ti wọn ba ri. Awa ti a bẹrẹ ija yii gan-an ti wa nile wa o, a ko si ninu awọn onijaadi yii rara. Awọn mi-in ko lọ soju ọna, tabi titi kan, ojule si ojule lawọn n tọ kiri. Ile awọn oloṣelu ta a ti sọ fun wọn pe iwa wọn ko daa, tabi ta a ti pariwo pe wọn kowo jẹ, ni wọn n lọ. Oloṣelu ti eṣu ba ṣe, ti wọn jaja ri mu, wọn maa n da bẹntiroolu si wọn latori delẹ ni, wọn aa fi bẹntiroolu wẹ ẹ, nnkan ti wọn n pe ni wẹẹti-ẹ niyẹn. Bi wọn ba ti fi wẹ ẹ bayii, wọn aa ṣana si i ni. Tọhun yoo jona ku ni. Bi ogun wẹẹti-ẹ ṣe fẹju niyẹn.Awa oloṣelu tinu bi ti wọle o, ṣugbọn awọn janduku, ọmọọta ati araalu ko wọle mọ, wọn ti sọ kinni naa di ounjẹ, wọn ti sọ ọ di iṣẹ oojọ:  wọn ko roko, wọn ko yẹna mọ, ohun to ku ti wọn ṣe niyẹn. Paripari rẹ waa ni pe ko si ilu kan tabi ileto kan, bo ti wu ki ibẹ kere to ti ogun yii ko de ni ilẹ Yoruba, bẹẹ o ti kuro ni ogun awọn oloṣẹlu, nitori apa awọn oloṣelu paapaa ko ka a mọ, awọn ọdaran yii kan fi ọrọ Awolọwọ ati ti ọta ẹgbẹ Dẹmọ kẹwọ ni, awọn to ku to n ja ija yi, awọn ọmọọta atawọn ti wọn ko niṣẹ ati araalu ti inu to n bi wọn ju tiwa lọ lo ku nidii ẹ. Igba ti wọn o kuku ni iṣẹ gidi kan lọwọ tẹlẹ, ko jẹ ki ogun naa tan. Wọn ko ni ibi ti wọn n lọ, nibi ti wọn ba ti de ti wọn ri ounjẹ ni wọn ti n jẹun, ti wọn ba si ti jẹun tan, wọn aa tun ko si wahala wọn ni. Bi wọn ṣe ṣe ti oṣu kin-in-ni pari, ti oṣu keji tẹle e niyẹn.Ki i ṣe pe awọn ọlọpaa o gbiyanju, wọn ṣe titi apa wọn ko ka a ni. Bi araalu tabi awọn janduku ba gba igboro, ki i ṣe awọn ọlọpaa lo le le wọn wọle. Bo ṣe ri ni 1965 yii ree, wahala naa si ni wọn fa titi ti awọn ṣọja fi fibinu gbajọba lẹyin oṣu kẹta ti wọn ti n dana sunle, ti wọn n dana sun awọn eeyan, ti ohun ti ọpọlọpọ awọn oloṣelu wa fi eru ko jọ ti jona loju wọn. Bi awọn ṣọja ti gbajọba ni ọrọ tun dija laarin awọn naa, nitori ogun ẹleyamẹya ti awọn onibajẹ oloṣelu ti da silẹ, ija to si ṣẹlẹ laarin awọn ṣọja yii ko pari, ogun abẹle lo da nitori wọn fẹẹ fi agbara han ara wọn. Bii miliọnu meji ọmọ Naijiria lo ku si ogun ti wọn fi ọdun mẹta ja yii, bi iru ẹ ba si ṣẹlẹ lasiko yii, iye miliọnu eeyan to maa ba kinni naa lọ, afi ki Ọlọrun ma jẹ ka ri i. Bẹẹ ilu ko fara rọ, gbogbo ohun to ṣẹlẹ ni 1964 si 1965, to ṣoju awa yii, naa lo tun n ṣẹlẹ yii o.Awọn oloṣelu ni wọn maa n da a silẹ, paapaa awọn oloṣelu ti wọn ba gbabọde fun Yoruba, lọdọ wọn ni kinni naa ti n bẹrẹ ko too di ohun to kari ilu yikayika. O ti tun n bẹrẹ bayii o. Ki Ọlọrun ma jẹ ki awa ọmọ Naijiria tun foju wina ogun. Mo tun n fi asiko ti mo ni yii kilọ fawọn oloṣelu Yoruba ki wọn ṣọra wọn, igbẹyin rogbodiyan tabi ijaagboro ki i daa fun wọn o, gbogbo ohun ti wọn ba ko jọ ni yoo bajẹ pata loju wọn."},{"question":"السؤال: من أول من آمن بالرسول صلى الله عليه وسلم من الصبيان؟","answer":"الإجابة: علي بن أبي طالب"},{"question":"క్రింద ఇచ్చిన పద్యానికి ప్రతిపదార్ధం మరియు తాత్పర్యం ఇవ్వండి:తే|| పాండవులు తండ్రి సచ్చిన ప్రజలు వారినరసి ప్రోచితి శైశవ మాదిగాఁగనడుమ నిష్కారణము దిగవిడువఁ దగునె ?పారమొందంగ రక్షింపు గారవమున","answer":"ప్రతిపదార్థం :పాండవులు = ధర్మజాదులుతండ్రి చచ్చిన ప్రజలు = తండ్రిలేని బిడ్డలువారిన్ = వారలనుశైశవము + ఆగాగన్ = చిన్నప్పటి నుంచిఅరసి ప్రోచితి(వి) = చక్కగ కాపాడావునడుమన్ = మధ్యలోనిష్కారణము + అ = కారణం లేకుండాదిగన్ + విడువన్ + తగునే = వదలి వేయవచ్చునా ?పారము + ఒందగన్ = ఆవలిగట్టు చేరువరకూ (చివరి వరకు)గారవమునన్ = ఆదరంతో రక్షింపు(ము), కాపాడుముతాత్పర్యం : పాండవులు తండ్రిలేని పిల్లలు. వారిని పసితనం నుంచి చల్లగా కాపాడావు. ఇప్పుడు వారిని కారణం లేకుండా మధ్యలోనే విడిచిపెట్టటం న్యాయం కాదు. చివరివరకు నీవు ప్రేమతో వారిని కాపాడవలసి ఉంది."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"ada taring\\"?","answer":"Simpulan bahasa ini bermaksud seseorang yang berkuasa."},{"question":"\\"Адамды шайтан азгырат ...\\"  деген макал-лакапты улантып берчи?","answer":"Сиз суранган макал-лакап мындай болушу мүмкүн: \\"Адамды шайтан азгырат, артык дөөлөт мас кылат, тумшугу таштай катаарда, тууган менен кас кылат.\\""},{"question":"Dede namahrem mi?","answer":"Kan bağı ile mahrem olanlar: Bir erkek için, anne, nine, kız, kız kardeş, hala, teyze, erkek kardeşin kızları, kız kardeşin kızları kan bağı ile mahremdir. Bir kadın için, baba, dede, oğul, erkek kardeş, amca, dayı, erkek kardeşin oğulları, kız kardeşin oğulları kan bağı ile mahremdir."},{"question":"Dime cuál es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿Quién fue la tercera esposa del Rey Enrique VIII?","answer":"El tema principal de esta pregunta es \\"la tercera esposa del Rey Enrique VIII\\", la categoría de historia. "},{"question":" புற்றுநோயை குணப்படுத்துவதில்   முருங்கை கீரையின்  பங்கு ?","answer":"முருங்கை கீரை :- நமது உணவில் அன்றாடம் பயன்படுத்தும் பல உணவு பொருட்களில் எண்ணற்ற மருத்துவ குணங்கள் உள்ளது. அப்படிப்பட்ட ஒன்றுதான் முருங்கை கீரையும். பொதுவாக குழந்தைகளுக்கு கீரை வகைகளை கண்டாலே பிடிக்காது. ஆனால் அவர்கள் அடம்பிடிக்கிறார்கள் என்பதற்காக கீரைகளை அவர்களுக்கு கொடுக்காமல் விட்டுவிடாதீர்கள். எல்லா கீரை வகைகளிலும் எக்கச்சக்க ஊட்டச்சத்துக்கள் உள்ளன. இதற்கு எந்த வகையிலும் முருங்கை கீரை துளி அளவும் குறைந்தது இல்லை. இதில் பல்வேறு வகையான சத்து பொருட்கள் இருக்கிறது.ண்மையிலேயே முருங்கை கீரை புற்றுநோயை தடுக்க பயன்படுவதாக ஆரய்ச்சியாளர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர். இது புற்றுநோய் கட்டிகள் உடலில் உருவாவதை முன்கூட்டியே தடுக்கும். அத்துடன் புற்றுநோய் கட்டிகளை அழிக்க இது நன்கு உதவுகிறது. பென்சயில் இசோதியோசைனட் என்னும் மூல பொருள் முருங்கையில் அதிகம் உள்ளதால் புற்றுநோய் ஏற்படாமல் காக்கும். எனவே புற்றுநோயை தடுக்கும் ஆற்றல் இயற்கையகவே முருங்கைக்கு உள்ளது. இனி எவ்வாறு இது புற்றுநோயை குணப்படுத்தும் என்பதை தெரிந்து கொள்ளலாம்.அண்மை ஆராய்ச்சி :- சில அண்மைய ஆராய்ச்சிகள் முருங்கையில் உள்ள எண்ணற்ற நன்மைகளை கண்டறிந்தனர். அதில் மிக முக்கியமான சிலவற்றை இதுவே… – கல்லீரலை சுத்தம் செய்யும் – நுரையீரலில் புற்றுநோய் செல்கள் உருவாவதை தடுக்கும் – உடலில் உள்ள புற்றுநோய் கட்டிகளை அழிக்கும். – எதிர்ப்பு சக்தி மண்டலத்தை உறுதிப்படுத்தும்எவ்வாறு புற்றுநோயை குணப்படுத்தும் ..? தினமும் முருங்கை கீரையின் சாற்றை 300 ml குடித்து வந்தால் புற்றுநோய் கட்டிகளை எளிதில் உடலில் இருந்து நீக்க முடியும் என்கிறது இந்த ஆராய்ச்சி. எதிர்ப்பு சக்தி மண்டலத்தை வலிமையாக்கி வெள்ளை ரத்த அணுக்களை அதிகரிக்கிறது. இதில் உள்ள நியாஸிமிஸின்  என்ற மூல பொருள் ஆரம்ப கட்டத்தில் இருக்கும் புற்றுநோய் செல்களை சிறிது சிறிதாக அழிக்கவும், செல்கள் வளர்ச்சியை முற்றிலுமாக தடை செய்கிறது. மேலும் இப்போதெல்லாம் முருங்கை இலையை பொடி செய்து அதனை கேப்சியூல் போன்று விற்க தொடங்கி விட்டனர். இது பெரிதும் உதவுவதாக மருத்துவர்கள் கூறுகின்றனர்.தினமும் முருங்கையா..? தினமும் பச்சை காய்கறிகள் உண்பது எவ்வளவு உடலுக்கு நல்லதோ அதே போன்றுதான் கீரை வகைகளை உணவில் சேர்த்து கொள்வதும். தினமும் முருங்கை கீரையை மட்டும் சாப்பிடாமல் ஒவ்வொரு நாளும் வெவ்வேரு கீரைகளை உட்கொள்ளுதல் அதிக ஆரோக்கியத்தை பெறலாம். புற்றுநோய்க்கு மட்டுமில்லாமல் இது பல பயன்களையும் கொண்டுள்ளது."},{"question":"اكمل الجملة التالية:في النهاية يتعين على كين مراجعة نفسه، فبايرن ميونخ تعاقد معه","answer":"على كونه الهداف صانع الخطورة وقائد هجوم توتنهام، وليس كمنفذ لركلات الجزاء."},{"question":"‘ஆளுக்கொரு மரம் வளர்ப்போம்’  என்னும் தொடர் வாயிலாக எதனை வலியுறுத்துவாய்?","answer":"ஆளுக்கொரு மரம் வளர்ப்போம்’ என்ற  தொடர் வாயிலாக பின்வருவனவற்றை எடுத்துரைப்பேன.இயற்கையை காப்போம் .மழைக்கு ஆதாரம் மரம்.உயிர்வளிக்கு உதவுவது மரம்.மண் அரிப்பைத் தடுக்கும் மரம்.மரம் தரும் நிழல் குளிர்ச்சி என்று கூறுவேன்."},{"question":"Табышмактын жообун тап:Бурум-бурум, бурум токой,Бурулушуп калган токой.Аптыкайым алган токой,Айкалышып калган токой.","answer":"Табышмактын жообу: Кишен."},{"question":"Slutför den här frasen: Eckart höll ett känt anförande på ett partimöte den 14 augusti 1919. Snart därefter, 12 september 1919, kom Hitler för första gången dit, som utsänd spion. Hitler gillade partiets hållning i mycket och gick med som medlem och fick själv tala 16 oktober samma år och kom Eckart nära. Under de kommande åren utövade han sedan ett betydande inflytande över Hitlers politiska tänkande, som en mentor. Eckart antas ha etablerat begreppet Tredje riket (\\"das Dritte Reich\\") i partiet redan 1919, möjligen influerad av Ibsen, bara något innan Arthur Moeller van den Bruck gav ut sin bok \\"Das Dritte Reich\\" 1923. Han blev den förste att kalla Hitler för sin \\"Führer\\" 1921, likt dem som följde nationalisten Georg von Schönerer. Även Eckart fängslades efter","answer":"Ölkällarkuppen 1923, men släpptes snart på grund av sviktande hälsa; han var morfinist. Dödsorsaken blev hjärtinfarkt, sannolikt vållad av morfinmissbruket. Hitler dedicerade andra delen av \\"Mein Kampf\\" till Eckart, och efter maktövertagandet uppkallades teatern Waldbühne 1936 efter honom. Till Eckarts minne gav man också hans födelsestad Neumarkt in der Oberpfalz stadshederstiteln \\"Dietrich-Eckart-Stadt\\"."},{"question":"با توجه به متن زیر به سؤال پرسیده شده پاسخ دهید:  متن: یکی از قوانین مهم واترپلو این است که بازیکنان زمین اجازه ندارند توپ را با دو دست بگیرند(بجز دروازه بان) و باید آن را فقط با یک دست کنترل کنند. در فاصله دو متری از دروازه بان‌های هر تیم نشانه‌هایی به نام خط دو متری وجود دارد. بازیکنان تیم مقابل اگر توپ نداشته باشند نباید وارد این محوطه شوند در غیر این صورت خطا به سود تیم مقابل گرفته می‌شود. دیگر خطا های رایج در واترپلو کشیدن یا فرو کردن بازیکن مقابل زیر اب است که ممکن است منجرب به اخراج شود . اگر بازیکنی از زمین اخراج شود ۲۰ ثانیه از زمین بیرون خواهد بود.هر بازیکن فقط ۳ مرتبه حق اخراج ۲۰ ثانیه ای را دارد و بعد از بار سوم حق شرکت در ادامه مسابقه را ندارد.سؤال: یکی از خطاهای رایج در بازی واترپلو رو عنوان کنید.","answer":"یک خطای رایج در واترپلو کشیدن یا فرو کردن بازیکن مقابل زیر اب است که ممکن است منجرب به اخراج شود."},{"question":"「♪アンアンアンとっても大好きドラえもん」この曲の１番の歌い出しを歌いなさい。","answer":"こんなこといいなです。"},{"question":"what important event is this text about: Slavianski Pazarı'nı kazandıktan sonra, Kudaibergen düzenli olarak ulusal TV şovlarında ve halka açık etkinliklerde yer aldı. Konuk olarak katıldığı performansları arasında İtalya'nın Milano kentinde düzenlenen Expo 2015; Kazak Hanlığının 550. yıldönümüne ithaf edilen tiyatro gösterisi Mangilik El; Almatı'daki 2015 Avrasya Uluslararası Film Festivali; Çin Devlet Başkanı Şi Cinping'in de katıldığı Astana Opera Konseri de yer alıyordu.","answer":"Kudaibergen ve katıldığı uluslararası etkinlikler"},{"question":"\\"Agarrar com unhas e dentes.\\" O que significa esta expressão?","answer":"    Significa lutar ferozmente ou defender algo com grande determinação."},{"question":"Ọlọpaa ko le da wa duro, dandan ni ka ṣewọde fun iṣọkan Yoruba l’Ọṣun ni Satide – Ọba Ogboni","answer":"Oluaye Ọba Ogboni agbaye, Ọba Adetoyeṣe Abdul Ọlakisan, ti kilọ fawọn agbofinro ti wọn ba n gbero lati da iwọde iṣọkan ilẹ Yoruba to fẹẹ waye niluu Oṣogbo ni ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, duro lati tun ero wọn pa nitori awọn ko ni i ṣe ohunkohun to lodi si ofin orileede yii.Ninu atẹjade kan ti kabiesi naa fi ṣọwọ si ALAROYE lo ti sọ pe aarọ ọjọ Abamẹta, Satide, ni iwọde naa, eleyii ti ẹgbẹ Ọmọ Oduduwa United ati Ilana Ọmọ Ooduduwa ṣagbekalẹ rẹ, yoo waye.Ọba Ọlakisan ṣalaye pe eredi iwọde alaafia naa ni lati ji awọn ọmọ Yoruba loju oorun wọn, ki wọn le mọ pe iṣọkan ti pada sinu iran naa.O ni gbogbo awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ ni wọn yoo wọ aṣọ ẹgbẹjọda, bẹẹ si ni awọn ọmọ Yoruba atawọn ẹya mi-in ti wọn nifẹẹ lati darapọ le wa sibi eto naa.Gẹgẹ bo ṣe wi, “A ti ṣeto aabo to nipọn silẹ fun gbogbo awọn to maa wa nibẹ. Ẹni to bọwọ fun ofin ni wa, a ko si le ṣe ohunkohun ti yoo ta ko ofin orileede yii, idi niyẹn ti a fi n sọ pe ki awọn agbofinro ma wulẹ dabaa lati da wa duro.“A ṣetan lati fọwọsowọpọ pẹlu gbogbo awọn agbofinro ki wọn le pese aabo fun ẹmi ati dukia awọn araalu ṣaaju, lasiko ati lẹyin iwọde naa.“A n kilọ fun awọn janduku atawọn tọọgi ti wọn le fẹẹ darapọ mọ wa lati da wahala silẹ lasiko iwọde naa lati ma ṣe wa rara, nitori a ko ni i beṣu-bẹgba lati fa wọn le awọn agbofinro lọwọ.“A ko wa lati gboju agan si ẹnikẹni tabi ba nnkan jẹ, bi ko ṣe lati la awọn eeyan wa lọyẹ lori idi ti wọn fi nilo lati fọwọsowọpọ pẹlu wa ki iran Yoruba le ni ominira patapata”"},{"question":"Cuál es el tema principal de esta pregunta: ¿Quién se postuló en las elecciones democráticas primarias en 2020 y se graduó de la Universidad Howard?","answer":"El tema de la pregunta es política."},{"question":"Strese bağlı saç dökülmesi ne zaman geçer?","answer":"Strese bağlı alopesi sonrası herhangi bir yeniden büyüme görmeye başlamadan önce yaklaşık 6 ay gerektiğini ve saçın ilk haline dönmesinin 12 ila 18 ay sürebileceğini unutmayın."},{"question":"Дүйнөдөгү эң чоң саат кайсы?","answer":"Дүйнөдөгү эң чоң саат - Исламдын эң касиеттүү шаары - Мекке шаарындагы саат. Саат тетиги орнотулган имараттын бийиктиги - 601 метр. Имаратта жалпы эсеби төрт саат жайгашып,  дүйнөнүн төрт тарабына багытталган."},{"question":"உனக்குப் பிடித்த செல்லப் பிராணி எது? அதனிடம் நீ எவ்வாறு நடந்து கொள்வாய்? எழுதி வருக.","answer":"எனக்குப் பிடித்த செல்லப் பிராணி நாய். நான் அதனிடம் அன்பாக நடந்து கொள்வேன். தினமும் காலையும் மாலையும் அதனை அழைத்துக் கொண்டு காலார நடப்பேன். மூன்று வேலையும் அதற்கான உணவைக் கொடுப்பேன். அதனிடம் பேசிக் கொண்டே இருப்பேன். மாலை நேரத்தில் கொஞ்ச நேரம் விளையாடுவேன். எங்களில் ஒருவனாக அந்த நாய்க்குட்டியைப் பார்த்துக் கொள்வேன். கட்டிப்போட மாட்டேன். சுதந்திரமாக வீடு முழுவதும் சுற்றிவரும் எங்கள் வீட்டு நாய்க்குட்டி."},{"question":"Nitori ti ọkọ rẹ n yan ale, Bọsẹ binu para rẹ l’Akurẹ","answer":"Abilekọ kan ti wọn porukọ rẹ ni Bọsẹ Ọdunayọ, ti binu pa ara rẹ lori ẹsun to fi kan ọkọ rẹ pe ọkunrin naa n yan ale mọ oun lara.Bọsẹ ni wọn lo gboogun jẹ nile ọkọ rẹ to wa lagbegbe Igoba, nijọba ibilẹ Ariwa Akurẹ, lọsẹ to kọja, to si mori le ọdọ awọn obi rẹ ni Ifira Akoko, nibi to pada ku si.Ohun ta a gbọ ni pe Bọsẹ pada lahun fawọn eeyan rẹ ko too ku pe ti oun ba ti ku, ọkọ oun lo ṣeku pa oun, nitori ṣe loun mọ-ọn-mọ gbe nnkan jẹ nitori ọkan ninu awọn ale rẹ to pe oun sori aago, to si n halẹ mọ oun pe oun mọ nipa bi oyun ṣe n bajẹ lara oun ni gbogbo igba.ALAROYE gbọ lati ẹnu ẹnikan to sun mọ oloogbe ọhun daadaa pe ki i ṣe igba akọkọ ree ti Bọsẹ ti n gbe nnkan jẹ pẹlu erongba ati pa ara rẹ si ọkọ rẹ to jẹ ọkan ninu awọn ọmọ ẹgbẹ awakọ ti ilu Akurẹ lọrun.O ni o ti kọkọ gbiyanju ati pa ara rẹ pẹlu bo ṣe gbe majele jẹ ni ọdun 2021, ṣugbọn ti ọkọ rẹ tete ṣakiyesi rẹ to si sare gbe e lọ si ọsibitu, nibi ti wọn ti fọ majele ọhun kuro ninu rẹ, ko too pa a lara.O ni kayeefi patapata lo jẹ fun awọn ti awọn sun mọ obinrin naa pe o tun le dan iru nnkan bẹẹ wo lẹyin ti Ọlọrun ti ko o yọ ninu ti akọkọ.O ni o ṣee ṣe ki ọkọ rẹ tete fura, ko si lọọ tọju rẹ, ka ni ko lọ siluu abinibi rẹ lẹyin to gbe nnkan jẹ tan.Lẹyin ti obinrin yii ku tan ni wọn gbe oku rẹ pada sile ọkọ rẹ to wa ni Igoba, nibi ti wọn sin in si lẹyin ọpọlọpọ etutu."},{"question":"Schrijf een gedicht over seksualiteit.","answer":"Met gretige borsten staat begeerte aan het aanrechtzoent het zaad uit tomaten, kijkt naar het zwellenvan beslag onder vochtig doek. Haar hand liefkoostde haas van een jonge stier, zijn zoekende tongis gemaakt voor de hare, verzaligd streelt zezijn ballen de pan in."},{"question":"Activity-தமிழில் மொழிபெயர்க்கவும்","answer":"http://aangilam.blogspot.com/"},{"question":"When do we use spatial data analysis?is there any grammar issue?","answer":"There are no grammar issues in your sentence. It is grammatically correct."},{"question":"Skriv en fortsättning på den här paragrafen - Crus Rydberg inledde sin ishockeykarriär i moderklubben Tingsryds AIF. 2009 spelade han TV-pucken för Småland och noterades för 19 poäng på 8 matcher (12 mål, 7 assist). Han vann både lagets interna poängliga och lagets skytteliga. Året därpå tog han ett silver i TV-pucken med Småland. Han tilldelades också Sven Tumbas stipendium, som går till turneringens bästa forward. Crus Rydberg vann såval poäng-, som assistligan. På 8 matcher stod han för 20 poäng (5 mål, 15 assist). Dessutom hade han turneringens bästa plus/minus-statistik. Inför säsongen 2011/12 lämnade Crus Rydberg Tingsryd för spel med Linköping HC:s juniorverksamhet. Han kombinerade spel med Linköpings J18- och J20-lag. Crus Rydberg tilldelades ett SM-guld med LHC J20 samma säsong. Under sin andra säsong i Linköping hade han ett poängsnitt på en poäng per match i klubbens J20-lag. På 35 matcher noterades han för lika många poäng (12 mål, 23 assist). Samma säsong blev han också uttagen till sin första match med Linköpings seniorlag i SHL, den 5 januari 2013. Han fick dock ingen speltid i matchen som slutade 3–1 mot AIK. Vid NHL-draften 2013","answer":"blev Crus Rydberg vald i den femte rundan av New York Islanders som 136:e spelare totalt."},{"question":"Julius lu  ọrẹkunrin iyawo rẹ pa l’Ondo","answer":"Ọwọ ọlọpaa ipinlẹ Ondo ti tẹ redioniiki kan, Julius Badejọ, lori ẹsun lilu ọrẹkunrin iyawo rẹ, Isaac Bolodeoku pa, niluu Ondo.Ni ibamu pẹlu ohun ta a gbọ, o ti n lọ si bii ogun ọdun ti Julius ati iyawo rẹ, Abilekọ Abiye Ọlayẹle, ti n gbe pọ gẹgẹ bii ọkọ ati aya.Ọmọ marun-un lo wa laarin awọn mejeeji, bo tilẹ jẹ pe ọkunrin ọmọ bibi ilu Ondo ọhun ko ti i fẹ iyawo rẹ nisu lọka.Lati bii ọdun mẹẹẹdogun sẹyin ni wọn ni ija buruku ti n waye laarin Julius ati iyawo rẹ, airi ọrọ ija yii yanju lo ṣokunfa bi awọn ẹbi obinrin ti wọn n pe ni Iya Marvelous naa ṣe binu lọọ ko ẹru rẹ kuro nile baba awọn ọmọ rẹ.Adugbo kan ti wọn n pe ni Ẹbunoluwa, Ayeyẹmi, lo lọọ da gba ile tirẹ sì, to si ko gbogbo awọn ọmọ to bi tira, to n da tọju wọn.Ibẹrẹ ọdun to kọja ni iya ọlọmọ marun-un ọhun pade Isaac labule Laoṣo, nijọba ibilẹ Iwọ-Oorun Ondo, nibi to ti n sisẹ lebira lẹyin to ko kuro nile ọkọ.Ọjọ aisun ọdun to kọja lawọn ololufẹ tuntun naa pada siluu Ondo, ile ti Abilekọ Abiye n gbe ni Ẹbunoluwa lawọn mejeeji si de si fun ayẹyẹ ọdun.Lojiji ni wọn deedee ri Julius to waa ka wọn mọle lalẹ ọjọ Isẹgun, Tusidee, ọsẹ to kọja, to si bẹrẹ ijakadi nla pẹlu Isaac to jẹ ọrẹkunrin iyawo rẹ.Wọn ni bo ṣe kọkọ wọnu yara to ba a nibi to sun si lori bẹẹdi lo rọ omi koroba nla kan le e lori, leyii to mu ko tete taji loju oorun to wa.Níbi to ti n gbiyanju ati rọna sa jade ninu yara lo tun ti gba a mu, to si la pako nla kan tọwọ rẹ ba lasiko naa mọ ọn lori.Awọn to wa nitosi gbiyanju lati du ẹmi rẹ loootọ pẹlu bi wọn ṣe sare gbe e lọ si awọn ileewosan kan, nibi tawọn dokita ti fidi rẹ mulẹ pe o ti ku.Ninu ọrọ ti Abilekọ Abiye b’ALAROYE sọ nigba ta a n fọrọ wa a lẹnu wo lọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, igba ti ọkọ oun fẹẹ fi iya gbẹmi oun loun ko kuro nile rẹ tọmọtọmọ lati lọọ maa ṣiṣẹ lebira labule Laoṣo.Lati bii ọdun mẹta sẹyin ti wọn ti pinya lo ni oun ti pinnu pe ko si ohun to tun le pa oun pẹlu rẹ pọ mọ latari iya to ti fi jẹ oun.O ni funra oun loun da gba ile ti oun n gbe lati igba naa, ati pe laipẹ yii ni oloogbe ṣẹṣẹ ba oun da sọrọ owo ile sisan.Alagba Adeṣemoye Ọladuti to jẹ ẹgbọn abilekọ naa kin ọrọ aburo rẹ lẹyin ninu alaye diẹ to ṣe fun wa. O ni funra oun loun lọọ binu ko ẹru rẹ kuro nile Julius nigba to fẹẹ fi lilu rán án lọrun ọsan gangan. Bẹẹ lo si fọ igo mọ obinrin kan to jẹ aburo iyawo rẹ lori lọdun to kọja.O juwe ana rẹ yii gẹgẹ bii onijagidijagan eeyan, gbogbo awọn ẹbi rẹ lo ni wọn ti kẹyin si i latari iwa ki i gbọ, ki i gba, to n hu."},{"question":"Joxeel péeteg waat yi ci kàddu gii: Da di kày, lu soof Màki Sàll sàf na nu.","answer":"Waat yi nekk ci kàddu gii di \\"Da di kày, lu soof Màki Sàll sàf na nu.\\" ak séen i péete ñoo di:Da: AUXdi: AUXkày: ADV,: PUNCTlu: PRONsoof: ADJMàki: PROPNSàll: PROPNsàf: ADJna: AUXnu: PRON.: PUNCT"},{"question":"வினா :உலகிலேயே மிகவும் புகழ்பெற்றதாக மோனலிசா ஓவியம் திகழ்கிறது. இந்த ஓவியத்தில், மோனலிசாவின் சிரிப்புக்குப் பின்னால் உள்ள அறிவியல் என்ன தெரியுமா?","answer":"விடை :உலகிலேயே மிகவும் புகழ்பெற்றதாக மோனலிசா ஓவியம் திகழ்கிறது. இந்த ஓவியம் பல்துறை மேதை லியானர்டோ டா வின்சி-யால் வரையப்பட்டது. ஒரு கலைஞர் என்பதைத் தாண்டி லியானர்டோ பல துறைகளில் ஞானியாகத் திகழ்ந்தார். ஓவியத்தைக் கடந்து பல துறைகள் குறித்து அறிந்துகொள்ள வேண்டும் என்கிற அறிவுப்பசி கொண்டவர் அவர். கணிதவியல், ஒளியியல், உடற்கூறியல் முக்கியமாக, உடற்கூராய்வில் அவர் நாட்டம் கொண்டிருந்தார்.அவர் கலையையும் அறிவியலையும் பிரித்துப் பார்க்கவில்லை. பிணவறையில் என்ன பார்க்கிறாரோ, அவை அவருடைய ஓவியங்களில் பிரதிபலித்தன. லியானர்டோவின் ஓவியங்களை பகுப்பாய்வு செய்வது மகிழ்ச்சிகரமான ஒன்று. ஏனெனில் அவருடைய அசாதாரண திறமை அந்த ஆய்வில்தான் ஜொலிக்கிறது.ஆனால், உடற்கூராய்வு மீதான காதல்தான் மிக பிரபலமான மோனலிசா முகத்தை வரைய அவருக்கு உதவியது என உங்களுக்குத் தெரியவந்தால், அந்த ஓவியத்தை நீங்கள் பார்க்கும் விதம் முன்பு போன்று இருக்காது. எல்லாவற்றிலும் அவர் தன் அறிவை பயன்படுத்தியிருக்கிறார் என்பது அவருடைய ஓவியங்கள், குறிப்புகளில் இருந்தும் தெரியவருகிறது.“ஒளியியலில் இருந்து ஓவியத்தைக் கற்றுக்கொண்டார்” என சொல்வதன் அர்த்தம் என்ன? ஒரு அறையில் நீங்கள் எங்கு சென்றாலும் மோனலிசாவின் கண்கள் உங்களையே சுற்றிவருவதை போல் உணர்ந்திருக்கிறீர்கள் அல்லவா? அதையே ஒரு உதாரணமாக எடுத்துக்கொள்வோம்.கண்ணில் உள்ள கருவிழி, யாரை பார்க்கிறோமோ அதனை நேராக பார்ப்பதாலும் எதிர்திசையில் இருப்பவரின் கருவிழி அப்படி நேராக இல்லாமல் சமமற்ற விதத்திலும் இருக்கும். இதுதான் மோனலிசாவின் மாயைக்குக் காரணம். இது ‘மோனலிசா விளைவு’ என்று கூறப்படும் அளவுக்கு மிக மிக பிரபலமாக உள்ளது. ஆனால், இது மாயை அல்ல. முழுக்க முழுக்க ஒளியியல் அடிப்படையிலானது.மோனலிசாவின் புகழ்பெற்ற சிரிப்பை எடுத்துக்கொள்ளுங்கள். மோனலிசாவை நீங்கள் நேராக நோக்கினால், அவர் சிரிக்காதது போன்றே இருக்கும். இப்போது, அவரை நீங்கள் ஒருபுறத்திலிருந்து மேலோட்டமாக பார்த்தால், சிரிப்பது போன்று இருக்கும்.ஓவியங்களில் ‘ஸ்ஃபுமாட்டோ’ எனப்படும் தெளிவற்ற புறக்கோடுகளை மோனலிசாவின் உதடுகளின் மூலையில் பயன்படுத்தியிருப்பார். ஒளியியலை நன்கு அறிந்த லியானர்டோ, நாம் ஒன்றை நேராக பார்க்கும்போதுதான் நம் பார்வை கூரானதாக இருக்கும் என்பதை உணர்ந்திருந்தார்.நமது கண்கள் ஏமாற்றப்படலாம். மிக நேர்த்தியாக வரையப்பட்ட ஓவியத்தில், மோனலிசாவின் உதட்டின் மூலையில் கீழ்நோக்கிய கோடுகளை வரைந்திருப்பதன் மூலம் இந்த விளைவை ஏற்படுத்தியுள்ளார். மோனலிசா சிரிக்கவில்லை. ஓவியத்தில் உள்ளவரின் பார்வை அழுத்தமாக வரையப்பட்டு, உதடுகள் மங்கலாகும்போது உதட்டின் மூலைகள் மேல்நோக்கி எழுவது போன்று தோன்றும். இதனால், உதட்டின் வடிவம் மாறும். அதனால்தான் அவர் சிரிப்பது போன்று தோன்றும். இது கிட்டத்தட்ட கண்ணுக்கு புலப்படாது. இதனால்தான் அவரது உதடு அசைந்துகொண்டே சிரிப்பது போன்ற மாயத்தோற்றம் ஏற்படும்.கலை விமர்சகரும் வரலாற்று ஆய்வாளருமான எஸ்தெல் லோவட் கூறுகையில், “மோனலிசாவின் முகத்தில் அடர்த்தியான புறக்கோடுகள் இருக்காது, அனைத்துமே மங்கலாகத்தான் இருக்கும். இதனால் அவரது முகம் அசைவது போன்ற உணர்வை ஏற்படுத்தும். மேலும், உங்களை நோக்கியது போன்று அவர் வரையப்படவில்லை. வேறு திசையில் இருப்பதால் அவர் அசைவது போன்று தோன்றும். மேலும், அவர் முப்பரிணாமத்தில் இருப்பதாகவும் தோன்றும். ஆக்ஸ்ஃபோர்டு பல்கலைக்கழகத்தில் கலை வரலாற்று துறையில் எமெரிட்டஸ் ஆய்வு பேராசிரியரான மார்ட்டின் கெம்ப் கூறுகையில், “லியானர்டோ என்ன செய்கிறார் என மக்கள் உணரும்போது அவர் மகிழ்ச்சியடைந்திருப்பார் என நினைக்கிறேன். உடல் பக்கவாட்டு திசையிலும் மோனலிசாவின் பார்வை நேராகவும் இருக்கும் இந்த ஓவியம் மிக தைரியமானது என்று நினைக்கிறேன். ஆண்களின் கண்களை நோக்குவது கண்ணியமானது அல்ல என்ற கருத்து இருப்பதால், பெண்களின் ஓவியங்கள் பல, ஆண்களின் கண்களை நேரடியாக நோக்குவது போன்று இருக்காது. இதனால், அந்த ஓவியங்களில் கண்கள் கீழ்நோக்கி இருக்கும். அந்த வழக்கத்தை லியானர்டோ உடைத்துள்ளார்” என்றார்."},{"question":"Bratislava mooy péeyu ban réew?","answer":"Bratislava mooy péeyu réewum Slovaquie."},{"question":"Бул жомоктун уландысын жазып берчи: \\"— Мен сени чакырган жокмун, чарчаганыман жөн гана үшкүрдүм,- деди абышка.\\"","answer":"Бул жомоктун уландысы мындай болушу мүмкүн: \\"— Эмесе менин атым Өкүш… Бул балаңды жетелеп кайда барасың?- деди чал.\\""},{"question":"Meye hukuncin sallar wanda ya ɗauki yaro acikin sallarsa alhali kuma yaron yayi bayan gari a cikin pampers?","answer":"Tsarƙi yana daga cikin sharuɗɗan ingancin sallah. Sallar mutum bata inganta har sai mutum ya tsarƙaƙe jikinsa, tufan sa da wurin yin sallar sa. Saboda haka baya halatta mutum yayi sallah alhali yana ɗauke da najasa sai dai idan bai sani ba."},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai bertandang ke rumah orang meranda\\"?","answer":"Ia bermaksud berkunjung ke rumah orang dan tidak dijamu apa-apa"},{"question":"السؤال: من هي أول رائدة فضاء عربية مسلمة؟","answer":"الإجابة:  مريم عدنان"},{"question":"Nina Dlamini, selokhu naba yizinduna, anikaze nihole kodwa lezizinqukuza ngamakhanda zamakhansela, ziyahola. Futhi aziholi ubala.Nani-ke kufanele lo Hulumeni aniholele.(ehleka sakubhuqa) He! He! Wo! Ubani!? Aholele bani? Phela labobacabangelana bodwa. Uma ungesiye usopolitiki awuyinto yalutho.Abanye bathola ithuba ekukhethweni nje ngoba babelwa kakhulungenkathi kubulalana abantu bezinhlangano zepolitiki. Thina sazi ukuthiuma kubekwa indoda, ibekwa ngoba ihlakaniphile futhi ingumnumzaneonemfuyo. Lokhu kwabo kwehlukile.We Dlamini! Awusho. Uma efika uDuma ezocela imvume ngohlelo afunaukulwenza, ngithini?(ahebeze ngezandla) Cha! Cha! Ndabezitha ungazikhamanisi. Umchithe!Umchithe zisuka nje. Phela ukubusa kwakho kungazulelwa ngamanqe.Cha! Ngiyaphika Ndabezitha. (anikine ikhanda)1. Chaza isizinda salo mdlalo ngokwendawo. Nikeza iphuzu ELILODWA.","answer":"Iphuzu ELILODWA kwalandelayo:• Indawo okusabusa kakhulu inkosi nezinduna kuyona. • Abantu basancike kakhulu emfuyweni yabo. • Amaleyithi awakhokhelwa.• Kusaliwa ngezinduku uma kunengxabano"},{"question":"Do you remember when we were reading https://te.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E0%B0%89%E0%B0%B7%E0%B1%8D%E0%B0%A3%E0%B0%AE%E0%B0%82%E0%B0%A1%E0%B0%B2%20%E0%B0%B5%E0%B0%B0%E0%B1%8D%E0%B0%B7%E0%B0%BE%E0%B0%B0%E0%B0%A3%E0%B1%8D%E0%B0%AF%E0%B0%82 the other day? It started sth like document_plaintext[:100].. Can you continue it for up to another 1000 characters?","answer":"వి ఆసియా, ఆస్ట్రేలియా, ఆఫ్రికా, దక్షిణ అమెరికా, మధ్య అమెరికా, మెక్సికో మరియు ఎన్నో పసిఫిక్ ద్వీపాలలో కనిపిస్తాయి. వరల్డ్ వన్యప్రాణి ఫండ్ యొక్క జీవపరిణామ వర్గీకరణలో, ఉష్ణమండల వర్షారణ్యాలను ఒక రకమైన ఉష్ణమండల తడి అటవీప్రాంతం (లేదా ఉష్ణమండల తేమ విశాలపత్ర అటవీప్రాంతం) అని భావిస్తారు మరియు లోతట్టు భూమధ్యరేఖాప్రాంత సతతహరిత వర్షారణ్యం</i>గా కూడా చెప్పవచ్చు. ఈ వాతావరణ ప్రాంతంలో కనీస సాధారణ వార్షిక వర్షపాతం 175cm (69in) మరియు 200cm (79in) మధ్య ఉంటుంది. సంవత్సరం పొడవునా అన్ని నెలలలోనూ సగటు మాస ఉష్ణోగ్రతలు 18°C (64°F) పైబడి ఉంటాయి.[3] వర్షారణ్యాలు ఈ భూమిపై సగం సజీవ జంతు మరియు వృక్ష జాతులకు నివాసస్థానాలుగా ఉంటాయి.[4]నేల మట్టం స్థాయిలో సూర్యకాంతి లేకపోవడం వలన ఎన్నో ప్రాంతాలలో కలుపుమొక్కల పెరుగుదలకు వర్షారణ్యం ప్రతికూలంగా ఉంటుంది.[5] ఇందువలన మనుషులు మరియు ఇతర జంతువులు ఈ అటవీప్రాంతంలో నడవడానికి అనువుగా ఉంటుంది. ఏదైనా కారణం చేత ఆకులతో కూడిన పైకప్పు వంటి కవచం పాడయినా లేదా పలుచబడినా, అక్కడి నేలలో వెనువెంటనే దట్టమైన తీగలు, పొదలు మరియు చిన్న చెట్లతో కూడిన కీకారణ్యం పెరుగుతుంది.[6]"},{"question":"次の文章から重要な語彙を探し、その意味を説明しなさい。 物の値段が高くなって、困っている家庭が増えています。NGOの「セーブ・ザ・チルドレン・ジャパン」は、生活が苦しい家庭の子どもに、食べ物を送る活動をしています。NGOは6日、給食がなくなる夏休みの前に、食べ物を送る準備をしました。ボランティアなどが集まって、協力する会社にもらった米やレトルト食品、お菓子などを箱に入れました。申し込みがあった5000の家庭に送ります。NGOが親たちに聞くと、物の値段が全部高くなって、子どもたちの昼ごはんを用意できるか心配だという意見がたくさんありました。NGOの人は「夏休みは給食がなくなるので、十分に食べることができない子どもが増えます。困っている人たちのことを伝えて、国にも助けてもらいたいです」と話しています。","answer":"この文章に出てくる重要な語彙とその意味は次の通りである。- NGO: 1）貧困・飢餓・難民・環境などの問題に国境をこえて取り組む、民間の組織のこと。- 苦しい: 1）体や心がつらくて、がまんできない。2）お金や物が足りなくて困るようすだ。3）無理がある。4）…しにくい。- 活動: 1）元気よく動いたり、働いたりすること。- 給食: 1）学校や会社などで、児童・生徒や従業員などに食事を出すこと。また、その食事。- ボランティア: 1）社会のために、自分から進んで、無料で奉仕活動をする人。- 協力: 1）力を合わせて、ものごとを行うこと。- レトルト食品: 1）調理済みの食品をふくろにつめたもの。ふくろごと熱湯に入れ、温めて食べる。- 申し込み: 1）申しこむこと。- 親: 1）父や母。両親。2）子や卵をうんだもの。3）トランプやかるたなどの遊びで、カードを配る人。4）中心となるもの。大きいもの。- 助け: 1）危ないことや苦しいことから救う。2）力を貸す。手伝う。"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai awak rendah, sangkutan tinggi\\"?","answer":"Maksudnya ialah besar belanja daripada pendapatan. Contoh ayat: Ismail selalu membeli barangan berjenama bagai awak rendah, sangkutan tinggi walaupun bekerja sebagai kerani di pejabat kecil."},{"question":"Кыргыз тилинде антонимдер деп эмнени айтабыз?","answer":" Антонимдер – карама каршы аталыш же бири бирине каршы маанидеги сөздөрдү атоого болот. Мисалы: ак-кара, узун-кыска, жакшы-жаман, ысык-суук, өйдө-ылдый жана башка сөздөрдү келтирүүгө болот."},{"question":"Hoe noemt men in keukentermen een met olie ingewreven stuk bakpapier of aluminiumfolie waarin kleine stukken vlees of vis, met eventueel toevoeging van groenten of fruit in de oven worden gegaard?","answer":"Papillote "},{"question":"السؤال: من هو الصحابي الجليل الذي كان أول من استل سيفًا في سبيل الله ؟","answer":"الجواب: الزبير بن العوام."},{"question":"ஏழைகளின் ஆப்பிள் என அழைக்கப்படும் பப்பாளி பழத்தின் மகத்துவம் என்ன?","answer":"ஆப்பிளைவிட சிறந்த பழம் பப்பாளி. இதில் ஆப்பிளில் உள்ளதைவிட அதிக அளவு சத்துக்கள் நிறைந்துள்ளன. விலையும் மிகமலிவு. இதனால் இதை ஏழைகளின் ஆப்பிள் என்றே அழைக்கலாம். பழங்களில் மிக மிக குறைவான கலோரி பப்பாளியில் தான் உள்ளது. 100 கிராம் பப்பாளியில் 32 கலோரிகளே உள்ளன. ஆப்பிளைக் காட்டிலும் இனிப்பான பழம் பப்பாளி. பப்பாளியை தினமும் நம் உணவுடன் சேர்த்து சாப்பிட்டால் நோய் நொடியின்றி நல்ல ஆரோக்கியமாக வாழலாம்.பப்பாளியை நாம் எந்தக் காலத்திலும் எப்பொழுது வேண்டுமானாலும் சாப்பிடலாம். இது ஒரு திகட்டாத பழம் என்பதால், நாம் அளவுக்கதிகமாக சாப்பிட்டு விடுவோம். அப்பொழுதுதான் பிரச்னை. அளவோடு சாப்பிடும் வரை இது அபூர்வமான பழம். முகெலும்பு பிதுக்கம் அல்ல நழுவல் காரணமாக வரும் கடுமயான வலிக்கு பப்பாளியில் உள்ள 'கமோ பாப்பன்' என்ற கெமிக்கல் நல்ல குணமளிப்பதாக அமெரிக்காவில் ஆய்வு செய்து கண்டுபிடித்துள்ளனர்.பொதுவாகவே பப்பாளி தலைமுடி, சருமம், கண்பார்வை, தொண்டை, வயிறு, சிறுநீரகம் அனைத்துக்கும் மிகவும் ஏற்றது. எக்காரணத்தைக் கொண்டும் பப்பாளியை நாம் தவிர்த்தால், நம் ஆரோக்கியத்தை நாம் தவிர்க்கிறோம் என்றுதான் அர்த்தம்."},{"question":"भगवान शिव","answer":"शिव हिन्दू धर्मका प्रमुख देवताहरू मध्ये एक हुन्। भगवानको तीन रूपहरू मध्येको एक शिवलाई विनाशकर्ताका रूपले चिनिन्छ। हिन्दू धर्मका विभिन्न सम्प्रदायहरू मध्ये शैव सम्प्रदायका अनुयायीहरू शिवलाई आफ्नो प्रमुख देवता मान्छन् र त्यसै अनुसार उनलाई महादेव, परमेश्वर आदि नामले सम्बोधन गर्दछन्। शिवलाई प्रायःजसो शिवलिङ्गको रूपमा पूजा गर्ने गरिन्छ।शिव हिन्दू धर्मको प्रमुख देवताहरू मध्यको एक ईश्वर को रुप हो। वेदमा यिनको नाम रुद्र भनिएको छ। यीनी व्यक्तिको चेतनाको अन्तर्यामी छन्। यिनको अर्धाङ्गिनी (शक्ति)को नाम पार्वती हो। यिनका दुईवटा पुत्रहरू छन्, जसमा एक स्कन्द र अर्का गणेश हुन्। हिन्दू मान्यता अनुसार ब्रह्माजी यो संसारका सृष्ठीकर्ता हुन् भने भगवान विष्णु यो संसारको पालन कर्ता र शिव यो संसारका संहार कर्ता हुन्। श+िव= शिव मिलेर बनेको शिवको नामको \\"ि\\" लाई हटाएमा \\"शव\\" शब्द बन्छ तसर्थ शिवलाई जिव अथवा प्राण भनेर चिनिन्छ। शिवले छोडेमा यो संसारमा देह अथवा शव मात्र रहन्छ। देहमा ब्रह्माको स्थान शिरमा छ, विष्णुको स्थान हृदय अथवा शरिरको मध्य भागमा छ र शिवको स्थान कमर भन्दा तलको भागमा छ। त्यसैले भगवान शिवलाई शिवलिंगको रूपमा पूजा गरिन्छ। शिव अधिकतर चित्रहरूमा योगीको रूपमा देखिन्छन् र उनको पूजा लिंगको रूपमा गरिन्छ। भगवान शिवलाई संहारको देवता भनिन्छ। भगवान शिव सौम्य आकृति एवं रौद्ररूप दुवैको लागि विख्यात छन्। अन्य देवहरू भन्दा शिवलाई भिन्न मानिएको छ। सृष्टिको उत्पात, स्थिति एवं संहारको अधिपति शिव हुन्। त्रिदेवहरूमा भगवान शिव संहारको देवता मानिन्छन्। शिव अनादि तथा सृष्टि प्रक्रियाको आदिस्रोत हुन् र यीनी काल महाकाल नै ज्योतिष शास्त्रका आधार हुन्। शिवको अर्थ यद्यपि कल्याणकारी मानिएको छ, तर उनले संधै लय एवं प्रलय दुवैलाई आफ्नो अधीन गरेका छन्। भगवान शिव देवताका पनि देवता भएकाले उनलाई महादेव भनिन्छ भने ईश्वरका पनि ईश्वर भएकोले उनलाई महेश्वर भनेर चिनिन्छ।"},{"question":"Inona matetika no manomboka adim-poko?","answer":"Ny antony mahatonga ny adim-poko dia mety ho maro, fa ny fifanolanana ara-poko, ara-pivavahana na ara-politika dia matetika miteraka."},{"question":"inona no lokon'ny lanitra ?","answer":"ny lokon'ny lanitra dia manga "},{"question":"Cos bao nhiêu quốc gia và vùng lãnh thổ sử dụng bảng Anh làm đơn vị tiền tệ?","answer":"Hiện có 10 quốc gia sử dụng bảng Anh làm đơn vị tiền tệ chính thức, bao gồm Vương Quốc Anh, Syria, Sudan, Nam Sudan, Lebanon, Jersey, Isle of Man, Guernsey, Gibraltar và Ai Cập."},{"question":"Ahoana no ahafahanao mandamina fifandirana na tsy fifanarahana amin’ireo rahalahinao amin’ny fomba izay hihazonana rivo-piainana tsara?","answer":"Zava-dehibe ny fifandraisana. Miresaha ampahibemaso, mihainoa amim-pahavitrihana, ary mitadiava marimaritra iraisana izay mahafa-po ny rehetra mandray anjara."},{"question":"வினா: விலங்குகளை அதன் வாழும் இடத்திலேயே பாதுகாத்தலுக்கு பெயர் என்ன.?","answer":"விடை:விலங்குகளை அதன் வாழும் இடத்திலேயே பாதுகாத்தலுக்குப்  பெயர் சரணாலயம் . விலங்குகள் சரணாலயம் என்பது விலங்குகள் வாழ்வதற்கும், வாழ்நாள் முழுவதும் பாதுகாக்கப்படுவதற்கும் ஒரு வசதி. விலங்குகள் தங்குமிடங்களைப் போலன்றி, சரணாலயங்கள் விலங்குகளை தனிநபர்கள் அல்லது குழுக்களுடன் வைக்க முயலுவதில்லை, அதற்குப் பதிலாக ஒவ்வொரு விலங்கையும் அதன் இயற்கையான மரணம் வரை பராமரிக்கிறது."},{"question":"खालील श्लोकाचा सोप्या मराठीत अर्थ सांगा श्लोक:जे माहापुरुषाची भार्या । अति सलग्न अवस्था तुर्या ।जयेकरितां महत्कार्या । प्रवर्तले साधु ॥ ४॥","answer":"अर्थ:ती ईश्वराची भार्या असून प्रत्यगात्मा ब्रह्माच्या अत्यंत निकट असणारी तुर्यावस्थाही तीच आहे. तिच्या आधारानेच साधुपुरुष महान कार्ये करण्यास प्रवृत्त होतात. (४)"},{"question":"ارجع إلى الفقرة أدناه ثم أجب عن السؤال بعد ذلك بنفس اللغة مثل الفقرة:  كانت الحرب الأنجلو-البورمية الثالثة، والمعروفة أيضًا باسم حرب بورما الثالثة، صراعًا وقع خلال 7 إلى 29 نوفمبر 1885، مع استمرار المقاومة المتفرقة والتمرد حتى عام 1887. كانت الأخيرة من ثلاث حروب خاضت في القرن التاسع عشر بين البورميين والبريطانيين. شهدت الحرب فقدان سيادة بورما المستقلة تحت سلالة كونباونغ، التي تم تقليص حكمها بالفعل إلى الأراضي المعروفة باسم بورما العليا، وقد ضمت بريطانيا منطقة بورما السفلى في عام 1853، نتيجة للحرب الإنجليزية البورمية الثانية.  السؤال: متى سقطت بورما السفلى تحت سيطرة البريطانيين؟","answer":"سقطت بورما السفلى في قبضة البريطانيين في عام 1885."},{"question":"No anime Bleach, quem é Yachiru Kusajishi?","answer":"Yachiru Kusajishi é a tenente da 11ª Divisão da Soul Society, liderada por Kenpachi Zaraki. Ela é conhecida por sua aparência fofa e personalidade excêntrica."},{"question":"Maxaa u baahanahay inaad garato caynabinta heerarka caafimaadka Soomaalida?","answer":"Caynabinta heerarka caafimaadka Soomaalida waxay u baahan yihiin heerarka jiritaanka, xannuunka, barashada caafimaadka, iyo horumarinta caafimaadka."},{"question":"- من أول وزيرة خارجية تتولى هذا المنصب فيالعالم ؟","answer":"- باندرة"},{"question":"নিচের অনুচ্ছেদের বিষয় কি ?২০১১ সালে জোলি ড্রিমওয়ার্কস ধারাবাহিক \\"কুং ফু পান্ডা ২\\"-এ মাস্টার টিগ্রেসের ভূমিকায় কণ্ঠ প্রদান করেন। আন্তর্জাতিক বক্স অফিসে ৬৬.৩ কোটি ডলার আয় করা এই চলচ্চিত্রটি তার পূর্বের সবচেয়ে ব্যবসাসফল চলচ্চিত্রের রেকর্ড ছাড়িয়ে যায়। এ বছর তিনি পরিচালক হিসেবে তার দ্বিতীয় চলচ্চিত্রটি নির্মাণ করেন। \\"ইন দ্য ল্যান্ড অফ ব্লাড অ্যান্ড হানি\\" (২০১১) নামক চলচ্চিত্রটির কাহিনী গড়ে উঠেছিলো একজন সার্বীয় সৈনিক ও বসনীয় নারী যুদ্ধাবন্দীর প্রেমকাহিনীকে কেন্দ্র করে। ছবিটিতে ১৯৯২-৯৫-এ সংঘটিত বসনিয়ার যুদ্ধের সময়কালকে ফুটিয়ে তোলা হয়। জাতিসংঘ শরণার্থীবিষয়ক হাইকমিশনার শুভেচ্ছাদূত হিসেবে জোলি দুইবার বসনিয়া ও হার্জেগোভিনা পরিদর্শন করেছিলেন, এবং সমকালীন ইতিহাসে সংঘটিত যুদ্ধগুলোতে টিকে যাওয়া জনগোষ্ঠীর বাস্তবতার দিকে বিশ্ববাসীর দৃষ্টি আকর্ষণ করার লক্ষ্যেই তিনি এই ছবিটি নির্মাণ করেছেন বলে জানান। বসনিয়ার রাজধানী সারায়েভোতে ছবিটির চিত্রায়ণের সময় অ্যাসোসিয়েশন অফ উইমেন ভিকটিমস অফ ওয়ারের বিক্ষোভের মুখে বসনিয়াতে ছবিটির কাজের লাইসেন্স বাতিল হয়ে যায়; কারণ গুজব ওঠে যে, জোলির ছবির চিত্রনাট্যে একজন ধর্ষিতার প্রেম কাহিনী ফুটিয়ে তোলা হয়েছে, যেখানে ধর্ষিতা তার ধর্ষকেরই প্রেমে পড়ে। পরবর্তীতে জোলি যখন বসনিয়ার যুদ্ধে ক্ষতিগ্রস্থদের সহায়তা প্রদানকারী সংগঠনগুলোর প্রতিনিধিদের কাছে সম্পূর্ণ চলচ্চিত্রটি পরিবেশন করেন তখন তাদের প্রতিক্রিয়া ছিলো খুব বেশি মাত্রায় ইতিবাচক। \\"দ্য হলিউড রিপোর্টারের\\" টড ম্যাককার্থি লিখেন, \\"জোলি এরকম একটি পীড়াদায়ক আবহ সৃষ্টি ও আতঙ্কজনক ঘটনাকে বিশ্বাসযোগ্যভাবে মঞ্চস্থ করার জন্য কৃতজ্ঞতা পাওয়ার যোগ্য, এমনকি এই ঘটনাগুলো এতোই বাস্তবরূপী ছিলো যে মানুষ পর্দায় যা দেখেছে তা বাস্তবে দেখতে চাইবে না।\\" ছবিটি সেরা বিদেশি ভাষার চলচ্চিত্র বিভাগে গোল্ডেন গ্লোব পুরস্কারের মনোনয়ন লাভ করে এবং যুদ্ধের বিরুদ্ধে সচেতনতা সৃষ্টির জন্য জোলিকে সারায়েভোর সম্মানসূচক নাগরিকত্ব প্রদান করা হয়।","answer":"বসনিয়ার যুদ্ধ |"},{"question":"ما هو الحيوان المائي الاسرع في العالم؟","answer":"الحيوان المائي الاسرع في العالم هو سمكة أبوشراع."},{"question":"Isalin ang talata mula sa Ingles:\\"The San Juanico Bridge connects the islands of Leyte and Samar by linking the city of Tacloban to the town of Santa Rita, Samar. The road infrastructure is the second longest bridge spanning a body of seawater in the Philippines after Cebu-Cordova Bridge, measuring 2,164 m (7,100 ft) in total length.\\"","answer":"Pinagdudugtong ng Tulay ng San Juanico ang lungsod ng Tacloban sa pulo ng Leyte at ang bayan ng Santa Rita sa pulo ng Samar. May haba ito na 2,164 na metro, kaya ito ang pangalawang pinakamahabang tulay sa bansa na tumatawid sa tubig pagkatapos ng Tulay ng Cebu-Cordova. "},{"question":"Чабалакейлер басканды билишеби?","answer":"Чабалекейлер басканды да, сүзгөндү да билишпейт, алар мыкты уча алышат. Эгер, жерге кончу болсо, ашыгы менен бир нече метр гана баса алат жана канаты дагы узун болуп, а буттары кыска болуп жерден учууга мүмкүнчүлүгү чектелип калат.Кара чабалекей түрү гана жерге конгондо, бутунун күчү себеп, секирип күүлөнүп олтуруп учуп кетет. Чабалекейлер учуп бара жатышып эле, суу ичишет, жуунушат жана 20 жылга чейин жашашат."},{"question":"You have the scrambled word:LLOHEGuess the correct word:","answer":"The correct word is “HELLO”. "},{"question":"Wọn rọ Onírọ̀ ti ilu Irọ̀, l’Ọbafẹmi Owode, loye","answer":"Lati ọdun 2014 ni ẹjọ ti wa ni kootu lori ipo ọba Ọnirọ ti Ilẹ Irọ, nijọba ibilẹ Ọbafẹmi-Owode, nipinlẹ Ogun, eyi ti Ọba Najeemdeen Alani Aromaye, di mu, ti wọn ni ki kabiyesi naa yee pe ara ẹ lọba, ṣugbọn ti ko gbọ, to jẹ niṣe lo n ṣajọyọ ipo ọba.Ni bayii, ileeṣẹ to n ri si ọrọ oye jijẹ nipinle Ogun ti dide si ọrọ naa, wọn si ti paṣẹ pe Aromaye ko gbọdọ gba owo-oṣu lọwọ ijọba mọ, bẹẹ si ni ko gbọdọ pe ara ẹ lọba Irọ mọ titi ti kootu yoo fi da ẹjọ rẹ sibi kan.Bo tilẹ jẹ pe ọjọ kẹrin, oṣu kejila yii, ni ileeṣẹ to n ri si ọrọ oye jijẹ ati ijọba ibilẹ nipinlẹ Ogun, kọ lẹta si ajọ lọbalọba ipinlẹ yii, (Egba Traditional Council) lati dawọ owo sisan duro fun Onirọ, lẹta naa ṣẹṣẹ jade sọwọ awọn akọroyin lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọjọ kẹrinla, oṣu kẹwaa yii, ni.ALAROYE pe kọmiṣanna fun ileeṣẹ yii, Afọlabi Afuwapẹ, lati fidi aṣẹ naa mulẹ. Afuwapẹ sọ pe ootọ ni, aṣẹ kootu wa nilẹ pe Najeemdeen ko gbọdọ pe ara ẹ lọba Onirọ, ko si gbọ, iyẹn lo fa a ti aṣẹ tun fi wa lọtẹ yii pe wọn ko gbọdọ sanwo fun un mọ, oun naa ko si gbọdọ pe ara ẹ lọba mọ titi digba ti kootu yoo fi dajọ, ṣugbọn ki wọn maa tọju owo-oṣu rẹ naa pamọ si asunwọn kan naa.Ohun to kọkọ bi wahala fun ọba yii ni pe lọjọ kẹrindinlogun, oṣu kẹsan-an, ọdun 2014, lo ṣeto iwuye, to si di ọba. Bẹẹ, ọjọ keji ti kootu paṣẹ pe ko gbọdọ dabaa igbesẹ ọba jijẹ naa ree, eyi ti ile-ejọ sọ pe o tumọ si itapa si aṣẹ ijọba.Adajọ  Gboyega Ogunfowora lo da ẹjọ naa lọjọ kẹẹẹdogun, oṣu kẹsan-an, ọdun 2014, ṣugbọn ọjọ keji rẹ ni Aromaye sọ ara rẹ dọba, bẹẹ lo si n ṣayẹyẹ bo ṣe wa lori ipo naa pẹlu.Ọdun 2016 ni kootu tun ṣiwee kan an, ti wọn ni ọkunrin naa jẹbi pipe ara rẹ lọba pẹlu bo ṣe ta ko aṣẹ kootu.Ṣugbọn ọba naa pe ẹjọ ko-tẹ-mi-lọrun n’Ibadan, wọn si fun un laaye lati wa nipo naa. Ṣugbọn ni bayii, ohun to kọja ko-tẹ-mi-lọrun ti ṣẹlẹ lori ẹjọ ọhun, nitori ileeṣẹ ọrọ oye jijẹ ṣalaye ninu lẹta wọn pe wọn ti fagi le anfaani ti wọn fun Aromaye lati maa jọba lọ, kootu si ti da ẹbẹ naa nu.Walaha ko deede ṣẹlẹ lori ipo ọba yii, awọn idile Ọlẹyọ tawọn naa jẹ ọmọ oye ni wọn ni Najeemdeen ko lẹtọọ si ipo naa, ti wọn ni awọn yoo jọ fi ofin fa ọrọ ọba yii ti yoo fi ja sibi to yẹ ni."},{"question":"كم عدد سور القرءان الكريم ؟ أجب على السؤال السابق.","answer":"الإجابة هي: 114 سورة."},{"question":"வினா: காவிரி நதி வங்காள விரிகுடாவில் எங்கு கலக்கிறது?","answer":"விடை: பூம்புகார்"},{"question":"Quem são os três Ronaldos famosos do futebol?","answer":"Os três Ronaldos mais famosos no mundo do futebol são: Cristiano Ronaldo, Ronaldo Nazário e Ronaldinho Gaúcho. Cristiano Ronaldo é português e passou por clubes como Manchester United, Real Madrid e Juventus. Ronaldo Nazário, também conhecido como Ronaldo Fenómeno, foi um jogador brasileiro, e jogou por clubes como Barcelona, Internazionale Milano, Real Madrid e AC Milan. Ronaldinho Gaúcho, conhecido simplesmente por Ronaldinho mas cujo nome real é Ronaldo de Assis Moreira, foi um jogador de brasileiro que passou por clubes como Barcelona e AC Milan. Os três jogadores são considerados como alguns dos melhores de futebol de sempre, tendo todos eles recebido a Ballon d'Or (Bola D'Ouro), que premeia o melhor jogador de futebol num dado ano."},{"question":"Кара-Кулжанын Кара-Туз айылындагы Тар дарыясынын боюндагы эски күмбөзгө кимдин сөөгү коюлган деп божомолдошот?а) Жаңыл Мырзанынб) Кыз Сайкалдынв) Каныкейдин г) Айчүрөктүн","answer":"KG Манас эпосу 📚б) Кыз Сайкалдын"},{"question":"Алмамбет кош колун сунуп, Бакай, Манас менен учурашып, ортосуна отурду, чаңкап турса да, кымыздан кылт этти, ал өзөгүнө түшсө да, адеп сактады, аны ким баалады?а) чоролор б) хандарв) бектер г) Манас баш болуп, баарысы","answer":"Алмамбет кош колун сунуп, Бакай, Манас менен учурашып, ортосуна отурду, чаңкап турса да, кымыздан кылт этти, ал өзөгүнө түшсө да, адеп сактады, аны Манас баш болуп, баарысы баалады. Туура жообу г) варианты болот."},{"question":"வினா:உலகிலேயே மிகச்சிறிய தீவாக உள்ள நாடு எது? ","answer":"விடை: நவுரு தீவு"},{"question":"Podsumuj artykuł:Kontrowersyjny australijski kucharz, Pete Evans, jest  ponownie atakowany przez ekspertów ostrzegających, że jego \\"przetworzona\\" mleczna formuła jest niebezpieczna dla niemowląt. Dietetycy wskazali \\"szczęśliwe dla brzucha warzywo\\" z książki kucharskiej Evansa, \\"Bubba Yum Yum: The Paleo Way, for New Moms, Babies and Toddlers\\", jako że zawiera prawie pięciokrotnie większą dawkę witaminy A dla dziecka. Oryginalny przepis na \\"formułę\\" zawierała ponad dziesięciokrotnie więcej witaminy A niż maksymalna dzienna dawka dla niemowląt. Dieta paleo jest jedną z najpopularniejszych diet, a jej promotorami są często celebryci. Stowarzyszenie dietetyków Australii stwierdziło, że zmieniona formuła wciąż stanowi zagrożenie dla niemowląt. 'Ta nowa receptura może poważnie zaszkodzić niemowlętom' - powiedziała rzecznik Stowarzyszenia Dietyków Australii  dla News Corp Australia. \\"Wydaje się, że autorzy popełnili poważny błąd w drugiej wersji receptury, sugerując, że nie rozumieją podstawowych informacji naukowych i żywieniowych istotnych dla karmienia niemowląt. \\"Publicznie wypowiadali się, że próbowali uczynić recepturę bezpieczną poprzez zmodyfikowanie oryginalnej, i zwiększenie wieku, dla którego jest sugerowane jej spożycie z 0-6 miesięcy do 6-12 miesięcy, ale nie udało im się spełnić żadnych standardów bezpieczeństwa\\". Współautorzy Evansa, blogerka Charlotte Carr i naturopatka Helen Padrin, wypowiedziały się w zeszłym tygodniu dla stacji Channel 7, że niebezpieczna formuła została przerobiona i przemianowana na \\"Happy Tummy Brew\\". Para powiedziała, że przepis został ulepszony. Dodaliśmy witaminę C i trochę wapnia - powiedział Carr w \\"The Morning Show\\".","answer":"Jasne, oto streszczenie tego artykułu:\\"Eksperci zdrowia uważają nową formułę mleczną Pete'a Evansa za niebezpieczną dla dzieci. Evans jest otwartym zwolennikiem diety paleo i stylu życia. Dietetycy twierdzą, że odżywka zaproponowane w jego nowej książce zawiera pięć razy więcej witaminy A niż dzienne zapotrzebowanie niemowląt. \\""},{"question":"Ògbójú Ọdẹ nínú Igbó Irúnmọlẹ̀","answer":"Ògbójú Ọdẹ nínú Igbó Irúnmọlẹ̀ jẹ́ ìwé ìtàn-àròsọ tí ọ̀mọ̀wé D.O. Fágúnwà kọ ní ọdún 1938. Ó jẹ́ ìwé ìtàn-àròsọ tí a kọ́kọ́ kọ ní èdè Yorùbá, tí ó sì jẹ́ ọ̀kan lára ìwé ìtàn tí a máa kọ́kọ́ kọ ní èdè Àfíríkà. Ó sọ̀rọ̀ nípa ìgbòkègbodò ògbójú ọdẹ kan tí orúkọ rẹ̀ ń jẹ́ Àkàràoògùn, àti ohun tí ojú rẹ̀ rí lóríṣiríṣi nínú ìrìn-àjò rẹ̀ nínú igbó. Àwọn nkan bí idán, iwin, ẹbọra àti àwọn òòṣà orísirísi ṣe fìtínà rẹ̀ nínú igbó tí òǹkọ̀wé pè ní igbó irúnmọlẹ̀. Ó jẹ́ ìwé ìtàn-àròsọ méèrírí tí a ka ní èdè Yorùbá. Ìwé ìtàn àròsọ tí ó tẹ̀lẹ́ ìwé yí láti ọwọ́ òǹkọ̀wé kan náà ni Ìgbó Olódùmarè. Ọ̀jọ̀gbọ́n Wọlé Sóyinká ni ó ṣe ògbufọ̀ ìwé ìtàn àròsọ Ògbójú Ọdẹ nínú Igbó Olódùmarè sí èdè Gẹ̀ẹ́sì."},{"question":"أول دول العالم إنتاجاً للصمغ هي…؟","answer":"السودان"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai asal selamat ke seberang, biar bergantung di ekor buaya\\"?","answer":"Maksud peribahasa ini ialah amat memerlukan pertolongan, apa jua bentuk pertolongan pun diterima."},{"question":"Eni chipatala cha Mwaiwathu ndani?","answer":"Technical Partner ndi/kapena Ma sheya Akuluakulu: Eni ake masheya akulu a polojekiti ndi: Prof. Jack Wirima (7%); Malawi Development Corporation (18%); Indebank (18%); National Insurance Corporation (18%); Medical Aid Society (6%); Malawi Savings Bank (9%), Medical Research Institute (MRI) (7%) ndi mabizinesi ena."},{"question":"등록금을 납부했어도, 타 대학 등록이 가능해?","answer":"이 아래 3개만 명심하시면 됩니다.(1) 등록금은 환불 가능하다(2) 등록금 환불은 등록 포기를 의미한다(3) 환불 '신청'만 하고 다른 대학에 등록해도 이중지원이 아니다(환불금액이 내 통장에 들어오지 않았더라도) 예시를 통해 설명해드리자면Q1) A대학에 합격해서 27일까지 등록금을 납부하라는데, 저는 B대학 추가합격을 기다리고 있어요. A대학에 등록하면 무조건 거기로 가야하나요? B대학은 포기해야 하나요?A) 등록금은 언제든지 환불이 가능합니다. 우선 A대학에 등록금을 납부하고 향후 B대학에 추가합격하시면 그때 A대학에 등록금 환불 신청을하고 B대학에 등록하면 됩니다. Q2) 이미 합격한 A대학의 등록금을 25일까지 납부해야하는데, 가고 싶은 B대학은 26일에 발표가 나요.A) 우선 합격하신 A대학에 등록금을 납부하시고 B대학에 합격했다면 A대학에 등록금 환불을 신청하고 B대학에 등록금을 납부하시면 됩니다.등록금 환불 방법은 보통 대학에서 제출하라는 서류를 팩스로 보내는 경우가 일반적이며 정확한 내용은 대학 입학처에 문의해보셔야 합니다. "},{"question":"Какой цвет символизирует мир в большинстве культур? Выберите один ответ.A) КрасныйB) ЗеленыйC) СинийD) Белый","answer":"Правильный ответ: D) Белый. В многих культурах белый цвет ассоциируется с миром, чистотой и нейтральностью. Например, во многих странах белый флаг используется как символ мира и призыв к прекращению вооруженных конфликтов. Белый цвет также часто используется на свадьбах как символ надежды и нового начала."},{"question":"Hlama karabo ya potšišo ye e raraganego: Colin Brady o ile a bapala go filimi efe ya 2004 ya metlae a raloka karolo ya lefifi yeo e hlamilwego ke Brad Silberling?","answer":"Lemony Snicket's A Series of Unfortunate Events (Lelokelelo la Ditiragalo tše di sa Thabišego)"},{"question":"Sheeg saladii ugu horeysay uu nabi Muxamed tukado ?","answer":"Waa Salaada Duhur. "},{"question":"ਕਿਰਪਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਇਸ ਬਾਰੇ ਵਿਸਥਾਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਦੱਸੋ ਕਿ ਹੇਠਾਂ ਦਿੱਤੇ ਦਾ ਕੀ ਅਰਥ ਹੈ।\\"ਆਸਾ ਮਹਲਾ ੫ ॥ਦੂਖ ਰੋਗ ਭਏ ਗਤੁ ਤਨ ਤੇ ਮਨੁ ਨਿਰਮਲੁ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਗੁਣ ਗਾਇ ॥ਭਏ ਅਨੰਦ ਮਿਲਿ ਸਾਧੂ ਸੰਗਿ ਅਬ ਮੇਰਾ ਮਨੁ ਕਤ ਹੀ ਨ ਜਾਇ ॥੧॥ਤਪਤਿ ਬੁਝੀ ਗੁਰ ਸਬਦੀ ਮਾਇ ॥ਬਿਨਸਿ ਗਇਓ ਤਾਪ ਸਭ ਸਹਸਾ ਗੁਰੁ ਸੀਤਲੁ ਮਿਲਿਓ ਸਹਜਿ ਸੁਭਾਇ ॥੧॥ ਰਹਾਉ ॥ਧਾਵਤ ਰਹੇ ਏਕੁ ਇਕੁ ਬੂਝਿਆ ਆਇ ਬਸੇ ਅਬ ਨਿਹਚਲੁ ਥਾਇ ॥ਜਗਤੁ ਉਧਾਰਨ ਸੰਤ ਤੁਮਾਰੇ ਦਰਸਨੁ ਪੇਖਤ ਰਹੇ ਅਘਾਇ ॥੨॥ਜਨਮ ਦੋਖ ਪਰੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਪਾਛੈ ਅਬ ਪਕਰੇ ਨਿਹਚਲੁ ਸਾਧੂ ਪਾਇ ॥ਸਹਜ ਧੁਨਿ ਗਾਵੈ ਮੰਗਲ ਮਨੂਆਅਬ ਤਾ ਕਉ ਫੁਨਿ ਕਾਲੁ ਨ ਖਾਇ ॥੩॥ਕਰਨ ਕਾਰਨ ਸਮਰਥ ਹਮਾਰੇ ਸੁਖਦਾਈ ਮੇਰੇ ਹਰਿ ਹਰਿ ਰਾਇ ॥ਨਾਮੁ ਤੇਰਾ ਜਪਿ ਜੀਵੈ ਨਾਨਕੁ ਓਤਿ ਪੋਤਿ ਮੇਰੈ ਸੰਗਿ ਸਹਾਇ ॥੪॥੯॥\\"","answer":"ਇਹ ਸ੍ਰੀ ਗੁਰੂ ਗ੍ਰੰਥ ਸਾਹਿਬ ਜੀ ਦੇ ਪੰਨਾ 372 ਤੋਂ ਲਿਆ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ। ਗੁਰੂ ਅਰਜਨ ਦੇਵ ਜੀ ਇਹਨਾਂ ਬਾਣੀਆਂ ਦੇ ਲਿਖਾਰੀ ਹਨ।ਇਸ ਨੂੰ ਹੇਠ ਲਿਖੇ ਅਨੁਸਾਰ ਵਿਖਿਆਨ ਕੀਤਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ,\\"(ਹੇ ਮਾਂ!) ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਦੀ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੇ ਗੀਤ ਗਾ ਗਾ ਕੇ ਮੇਰਾ ਮਨ ਪਵਿੱਤਰ ਹੋ ਗਿਆ ਹੈ, ਮੇਰੇ ਸਰੀਰ ਤੋਂ ਸਾਰੇ ਦੁੱਖ ਤੇ ਰੋਗ ਦੂਰ ਹੋ ਗਏ ਹਨ । ਗੁਰੂ ਦੀ ਸੰਗਤ ਵਿਚ ਮਿਲ ਕੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰ ਆਨੰਦ ਹੀ ਆਨੰਦ ਬਣਿਆ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ । ਹੁਣ ਮੇਰਾ ਮਨ ਕਿਸੇ ਭੀ ਪਾਸੇ ਨਹੀਂ ਭਟਕਦਾ ।੧।ਹੇ ਮਾਂ! ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਸਬਦ ਦੀ ਬਰਕਤਿ ਨਾਲ (ਮੇਰੇ ਅੰਦਰੋਂ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਦੀ) ਸੜਨ ਮਿਟ ਗਈ ਹੈ । ਮੇਰੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਦੁੱਖ ਕਲੇਸ਼ ਤੇ ਸਹਮ ਨਾਸ ਹੋ ਗਏ ਹਨ । ਆਤਮਕ ਠੰਡ ਦੇਣ ਵਾਲਾ ਗੁਰੂ ਮੈਨੂੰ ਮਿਲ ਪਿਆ ਹੈ । ਹੁਣ ਮੈਂ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਵਿਚ ਟਿਕਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹਾਂ, ਹੁਣ ਮੈਂ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ-ਪ੍ਰੇਮ ਵਿਚ ਮਗਨ ਹਾਂ ।੧।ਰਹਾਉ।(ਹੇ ਮਾਂ!) ਜਦੋਂ ਦੀ ਮੈਂ ਸਿਰਫ਼ ਇਕ ਪਰਮਾਤਮਾ ਨਾਲ ਸਾਂਝ ਪਾਈ ਹੈ ਮੇਰੀਆਂ ਸਾਰੀਆ ਭਟਕਣਾਂ ਮੁੱਕ ਗਈਆਂ ਹਨ, ਹੁਣ ਮੈਂ ਅਡੋਲ-ਚਿੱਤ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਚਰਨਾਂ ਵਿਚ ਆ ਟਿਕਿਆ ਹਾਂ ।(ਹੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ!) ਸਾਰੇ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਨੂੰ ਵਿਕਾਰਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਬਚਾਣ ਵਾਲੇ ਤੇਰੇ ਸੰਤ ਜਨਾਂ ਦਾ ਦਰਸ਼ਨ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਮੇਰੀ ਸਾਰੀ ਤ੍ਰਿਸ਼ਨਾ ਮੱੁਕ ਗਈ ਹੈ ।੨।(ਹੇ ਮਾਂ!) ਹੁਣ ਮੈਂ ਅਡੋਲ-ਚਿੱਤ ਹੋ ਕੇ ਗੁਰੂ ਦੇ ਪੈਰ ਫੜ ਲਏ ਹਨ, ਮੇਰੇ ਅਨੇਕਾਂ ਜਨਮਾਂ ਦੇ ਪਾਪ ਮੇਰੀ ਖ਼ਲਾਸੀ ਕਰ ਗਏ ਹਨ ।ਮੇਰਾ ਮਨ ਆਤਮਕ ਅਡੋਲਤਾ ਦੀ ਸੁਰ ਵਿਚ ਸਿਫ਼ਤਿ-ਸਾਲਾਹ ਦੇ ਗੀਤ ਗਾਂਦਾ ਰਹਿੰਦਾ ਹ ਹੁਣ ਇਸ ਮਨ ਨੂੰ ਕਦੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਮੌਤ ਹੜੱਪ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਦੀ ।੩।ਹੇ ਮੇਰੇ ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਪਾਤਸ਼ਾਹ! ਹੇ ਸੁਖਾਂ ਦੇ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਣ ਵਾਲੇ! ਹੇ ਸਭ ਕੁਝ ਕਰਨ ਤੇ ਕਰਾਣ ਦੀ ਸ਼ਕਤੀ ਰੱਖਣ ਵਾਲੇ! (ਤੇਰਾ ਦਾਸ) ਨਾਨਕ ਤੇਰਾ ਨਾਮ ਯਾਦ ਕਰ ਕਰ ਕੇ ਆਤਮਕ ਜੀਵਨ ਹਾਸਲ ਕਰ ਰਿਹਾ ਹੈ, ਤੂੰ ਮੇਰੇ ਨਾਲ (ਇਉਂ ਹਰ ਵੇਲੇ ਦਾ) ਸਾਥੀ ਹੈਂ, (ਜਿਵੇਂ) ਤਾਣੇ ਪੇਟੇ ਵਿਚ (ਸੂਤਰ ਮਿਲਿਆ ਹੋਇਆ ਹੁੰਦਾ ਹੈ) ।੪।੯।\\""},{"question":"Ngiyogiya ngiqephuze,Ngihay' izibongo.Ngingqabashiye ngihalalise ngokuqhashambulaSengiphumelel' ukufez' ezeminyak' izifisoNezinhloso zami ngelokujaja ilanga.Senginqwanjiswe umnqwamb' oqavile.Sengiyikazel' iminyezane yakomfundo.Ngiyogiya ngiqephuze.Ngigiye ngiqephuze ngiqeketh' izindabaNgigiye ngilokoth' amagam' angalokothwayoAlab' abayibekil' induk' ebandla.Abachathazil' emagulen' abo ezangqondo'Ze ngiqwal' eqonsayo imimango.Ngiyogiya ngiqephuze.Ngigiye kuyiyize omame nezalukazi.Besho bempongoloza ngamaphimbo emizwilili.Usho mfo kaShandu ukuth' uyalazi leliBhobhodleyana lakoMshibe.Usho liphekwe kweyakh' imbizaUgiye kanye nalo ngaphimbo linyeNingqabashiye ze nakwabezay' ixoxw' indaba.Bhala uhlobo lomsebenzi owenziwa ngumfokaShandu.","answer":"Unguthisha / Uyafundisa. "},{"question":"Iyawo David ti aṣita ibọn ọlọpaa pa ni Ṣagamu n bẹbẹ fun iranlọwọ","answer":"Lọjọ kejilelogun, oṣu keji, ọdun 2020, ti iku pa agbabọọlu Rẹmọ STARS nni, Kazeem Tiamiyu tawọn eeyan n pe ni Kaka, latọwọ awọn ọlọpaa SARS, ọpọlọpọ eeyan lo dun, paapaa ni Ṣagamu tọmọ naa ti wa, wọn si bẹrẹ si i fẹhohun han kiri.Lara ifẹhonu han ti ko ṣee gbagbe ọhun ni eyi to waye lọjọ kẹta iku Kaka, iyẹn lọjọ kẹrinlelogun, oṣu keji naa. Nibi ti wọn ti n fẹhonu han sawọn ọlọpaa, tawọn iyẹn naa n yinbọn pada ni aṣita ibọn ti ba baale ile kan, David Amusan, ẹni to n bọ lati ibi iṣẹ rẹ jẹẹjẹ. Bi ọkunrin ẹni ọdun mejilelọgbọn to niyawo ati ọmọ meji nile naa ṣe faye silẹ lojiji niyẹn.Gẹgẹ bi iyawo oloogbe, Ọdunayọ, ṣe ṣalaye fun ALAROYE lọjọ Aiku, Sannde, ọsẹ yii, iyẹn lẹyin oṣu mẹsan-an ti ọkọ rẹ ti ku, o ni iṣẹ birikila lọkọ oun n ṣe, ibi iṣẹ lo si ti n bọ lọjọ Aje, Mọnde, ọjọ kẹrinlelogun, oṣu keji, ọdun 2020 yii. Bo ṣe bọ saarin awọn ti wọn n fẹhonu han nitori Kaka tawọn SARS pa niyẹn, lo ba di pe ibọn ba a, bẹẹ ibọn awọn ọlọpaa ni.Obinrin naa fi kun un pe ọmọ Ilọra, nipinlẹ Ọyọ, lọkọ oun, ko niyaa, bẹẹ ni ko ni baba mọ, awọn aburo meji lo ni David ni lẹyin, ilu Ilọra naa si ni awọn mọlẹbi rẹ yooku wa, ko si ẹnikan toun ri fun iranlọwọ lati oṣu kẹsan-an sẹyin ti ọkọ oun ti ku.‘‘Mi o tete mọ pe nnkan ti ṣe mi lọjọ ti ọkọ mi ku, ile ni mo wa ti iyawo ọrẹ ẹ waa ba mi to beere pe ọkọ mi nkọ, mo ni wọn ti lọ sibi iṣẹ. Igba to ya ni wọn jẹ ki n mọ pe wọn ti gbe e lọ si Ọsibitu Ọlabisi Ọnabanjọ, ni Ṣagamu. Wọn o tete tọju ẹ lọsibitu yẹn, ilẹẹlẹ bayii ni wọn tẹ ẹ si, wọn ko ya si i, o dẹ ti padanu ẹjẹ pupọ gan-an. Boya ka ni wọn tete tọju ẹ ni, o le ma ku. ‘‘Oun lo n gbọ gbogbo bukaata ile, o n dẹ n tọju emi atawọn ọmọ wa daadaa (akọbi jẹ ọmọ ọdun meje, ikeji jẹ ọmọ ọdun marun-un).‘‘Ọkọ mi ko fẹ ki n maa ṣiṣẹ tẹlẹ, emi ni mo ni mi o kan le maa sun ki n maa ji, nitori ẹ ni mo ṣẹ n ta atẹ niwaju ile wa. David ti yawo ra ilẹ, owo LAPO lo gba, ori ilẹ yẹn la sinku ẹ si. Ẹni to ra ilẹ lọwọ ẹ gan-an ṣi n beere balansi bayii, mi o ti i rowo yẹn fun un.‘‘Emi naa yawo LAPO, mo fi n taja. A o ti i sanwo yẹn bayii, gbese ẹgbẹrun lọna ọgọrun-un kan ati mẹwaa (110,000) lowo tọkọ mi ya ṣẹku lati san, emi naa ṣi n jẹ wọn lẹgbẹrun lọna aadọrin naira (70,000).‘‘Mi o rowo taja mọ bayii, nitori emi nikan lo ku ti mo n gbọ jijẹ-mimu awọn ọmọ mi, mo tun n sanwo ileewe wọn, ko dẹrun fun mi rara. Emi naa o dẹ ni baba, iya nikan ni mo ni. Lanlọọdu ti ni ki n kuro nile ti emi atọkọ mi n gbe ki wahala yii too de, Disẹmba to n bọ yii lo ni ki n kẹru mi jade, ko dẹ sibi ti mo le lọ, mo n waṣẹ ti mo le ṣe, mi o ri i.‘‘Ẹ jọọ, ẹ ṣaanu mi o. O dun mi bijọba ipinlẹ Ogun ṣe lawọn ko mọ pe ẹnikan ku lẹyin iku Kaka, aburo Kaka gan-an waa ki mi nigba to gbọ pe ọkọ mi ku. Ẹ ba mi bẹ ijọba ipinlẹ Ogun ki wọn ṣaanu mi, kawọn ọmọ Naijiria naa dide iranlọwọ fun mi. Mo le ṣiṣẹ ti wọn ba fun mi niṣẹ ṣe, to ba si jẹ wọn fẹẹ fowo ranṣẹ si mi ni, akanti mi ree:0235483775, Wema Bank, Ọdunayọ Amusan.’’"},{"question":"Awọn ọdọ Naijria yoo tun jade ṣewọde lẹẹkan si i","answer":"Aarẹ ile igbimọ aṣofin agba,  Ahmad Lawan, ti sọ pe awọn ọdọ orilẹ-ede yii yoo tun ya jade lẹẹkan si i, lati fẹhonu han, bẹẹ ni yoo lagbara ju tatẹyinwa lo, ti ipese iṣẹ lọpọ yanturu ko ba tete bẹrẹ bayii.Ana Monde, ọjọ Aje, lasiko ti minisita fun iṣẹ ọgbin ati idagbasoke igberiko wa siwaju awọn ọmọ ile igbimọ aṣofin lati ṣe atotonu lori bo ṣe fẹẹ nawo ninu eto iṣuna owo lọdun 2021, ni olori ile igbimọ aṣofin agba yii pe akiyesi ọhun.O ni o ṣe pataki ki ijọba, awọn aṣofin atawọn mi-in ti ọrọ kan gbiyanju lati pese iṣẹ lọpọ yanturu fun awọn ọdọ, nitori iṣẹ ọfiisi ati iṣẹ epo ko fẹẹ ka awọn eeyan orilẹ-ede yii mọ, paapaa awọn ọdọ to nilo iṣẹ.Bakan naa lo fi kun un pe eto iṣuna owo fọdun 2021 ti kaluku wa n ṣe atotonu lori bi yoo ti ṣe na an yii loju awọn aṣofin gbọdọ ni eto ipese iṣẹ f’awọn ọdọ ninu, ki iwọde mi-in ma tun bẹ silẹ laipẹ ọjọ.Lawan sọ pe, iwọde tawọn ọdọ ṣe kọja yii, gbogbo aye pata lo gbọ ohun wọn, ti wọn si ri i pe ootọ pọnbele loun ti wọn n beere fun, bo tilẹ jẹ pe awọn janduku alainikanṣe kan fi iwa aitọ da iwọde ọhun ru nigbẹyin.O ni, asiko niyi lati tete pese silẹ fun wọn, ki wọn ma tun lọ jade lẹẹkan si i."},{"question":"Xaasle miyaa tahay?","answer":"waan kaxumahay, aniga qof nool ma ihi, wax lataabankarana ma ihi.kaliya waxaa lay diyaariyay inaan adiga ku caawiyo, haddii ay jiraan wax aan kaa caawiyo fadlan ila wadaag?"},{"question":"السؤال: ما معنى الأعراف؟","answer":"الإجابة: هي إحدى سور القرآن الكريم وهي عبارة عن تلال مرتفعة تقع بين النار والجنة"},{"question":"ඇරිස්ටෝටල් ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"ග්‍රීක දාර්ශනිකයෙකු වූ ඇරිස්ටෝටල් ප්ලේටෝගේ ශිෂ්‍යයෙකු වූ අතර මහා ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර් රජුගේ ගුරුවරයා ද විය. ඔහු බහුශාස්ත්‍රඥයෙක් ලෙසින් සැලකේ.බටහිර දර්ශනවාදයේ නිර්මාතෘවරු හැටියට සැලකෙන ප්ලේටෝ සහ සොක්‍රටීස් සමඟින් ඇරිස්ටෝටල් ද එහි නිර්මාතෘත්වයේ ඉතා වැදගත් පුද්ගලයෙක් සේ සැලකිල්ලට පාත්‍ර වෙයි. අධ්‍යාත්ම විද්‍යාව, දේශපාලනය, ත‍ර්ක ශාස්ත්‍රය, සෞන්දර්ය විද්‍යාව සහ සදාචාරය යන කොටස්වලින් සමන්විත පූර්ණ සහ ක්‍රමානුකූල දර්ශනවාදයක් මුල්වරට හඳුන්වාදීමේ ගෞරවය ඇරිස්ටෝටල්ට හිමි වේ.භොතික විද්‍යා ක්ෂේත්‍ර පිළිබද ඇරිස්ටෝටල් පළ කළ මතවාද මධ්‍යතන යුගයේ අධ්‍යාපනික ක්‍රමවේදයන් හැඩගස්වන ලද අතර ඒවායේ බලපෑම් විද්‍යාත්මක පුනරුදය දක්වා පැතිර ගොස් අවසානයේ දී නිව්ටන්ගේ භෞතික විද්‍යා ඉදිරිපත් කිරීම් වලින් නිශ්ප්‍රභා විය. ඇරිස්ටෝටල් විසින් සත්ව විද්‍යාව පිළිබඳ පළ කළ සමහර අදහස් සත්‍ය බව ඔප්පු කිරීම සිදුවූයේ 19 වැනි සියවසේ දී ය. දැනට හඳුනාගෙන ඇති ලොව ප්‍රථම ක්‍රමානුකූල තර්ක ශාස්ත්‍ර අධ්‍යයනයන් ඇරිස්ටෝටල් විසින් ඉදිරිපත් කරන ලද අතර ඔහුගේ එම අධ්‍යයනයන් මගින් හෙළි වූ කරුණු 19 වැනි සියවස අගභාගයේ දී නූතන ක්‍රමානුකූල තර්ක ශාස්ත්‍රය හා මුහුකර ගන්නා ලදී. යුදෙව් හා ඉස්ලාමීය දේවධර්ම සම්ප්‍රදායන් හි ආගමික හා දාර්ශනික චින්තනයට ඇරිස්ටෝටලියානුවාදය සහ පාරභෞතික විද්‍යාව බෙහෙවින් බලපාන ලදි. වර්තමානයේ පවා ක්‍රිස්තියානු දේවධර්මයට ඇරිස්ටෝටල්ගේ මතවාද බලපෑම් කරනු දැකිය හැකිය. ඇරිස්ටෝටල් චින්තනයේ සියලු පැතිකඩවල් වර්තමානයේ දී ක්‍රියාකාරී ශාස්ත්‍රීය අධ්‍යයනයන්ට භාජනය වෙති. ශාස්ත්‍රීය ග්‍රන්ථ හා සම්භාෂණ රාශියක් පළ කළ ද වර්තමානයේ ඇරිස්ටෝටල්ගේ ග්‍රන්ථවලින් ඉතිරිව ඇත්තේ තුනෙන් එකක ප්‍රමාණයක් පමණක් බව විශ්වාස කෙරේ. වරක් සිසෙරෝ විසින් ඇරිස්ටෝටල්ගේ ග්‍රන්ථයන් හා සාහිත්‍ය ක්‍රමය \\"රත්තරන් ගංඟාවකට\\" උපමා කරන ලදී.ඇරිස්ටෝටල් උපදින්නේ ග්‍රීසියේ එවක ස්ටැජියිරා නමින් වූ නගරයේ ය. ඔහුගේ පියා වූ නිකොමාකස් මැසඩොන් හි ඇමින්ටාස් රජුගේ පුද්ගලික වෛද්‍යවරයා විය. රදළ පංතියට දායාද වූ අධ්‍යාපනයක් හා පුහුණුවක් ඇරිස්ටෝටල්ට ලැබුණි. වයස අවුරුදු දහඅටේ දී පමණ ඔහු ඇතැන්ස් හි පැවති ප්ලෝටෝගේ ඇකඩමියේ ඉගෙනුම පටන් ගනියි. ඔහු වසර විස්සක් පමණ එහි ගෙවා දැමූ බව සටහන් වෙයි. ප්ලේටෝගේ අභාවයෙන් පසු ඔහු ඇකඩමිය හැර ගියේ එහි නව පාලනය ලැබි ප්ලේටෝගේ ඥාති පුත් ස්පියුසිප්පස් සමඟ ඇතිකරගත් අමනාපයක් බැවින් යැයි කියැවේ. එහෙත් තවත් අර්ථ කතනයක් වන්නේ ඇරිස්ටෝටල් ප්ලේටෝගේ අභාවයට පෙර, මැසිඩෝනියානුවන්ට එරෙහි වූ හැඟීම් බහුල වෙද්දී ඇකඩමිය හැර දා ගිය බවයි. තියෝෆ්‍රැස්ටස් සමඟ ලෙස්බොස් නම් වූ දූපත කරා යන ඇරිස්ටෝටල් එහි දී ඔහු සමඟ එක් වී දුපතේ පැලෑටි විද්‍යාව හා සත්ව විද්‍යාව පිළිබඳ පර්යේෂණ පවත්වති. පිතියාස් නම් වූ ඇටැර්නියුස් හි හර්මියාස් නම් වූවාගේ සුළු දියණිය (ඥාති දුවක් ද වන්නට පිළිවන) හා ඇරිස්ටෝටල් විවාහ වෙයි. ඔවුනට ලැබෙන දියණිය ඔවුන් පිතියාස් යැයි නම් කරති.හර්මියාසේගේ මරණයෙන් පසු මැසඩොන් හි දෙවැනි පිලිප් සිය පුත් ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර්ට ගුරුවරයෙක් වන්නට යැයි කියා ඇරිස්ටෝටල්ට ආරාධනා කරන්නේ ක්‍රි. පූ. 343 දී ය. මැසඩොන් හි රාජකීය ඇකඩමියේ ප්‍රධානියා ලෙසින් ඇරිස්ටෝටල් පත්වීමක් ලබයි.ක්‍රි. පූ. 335 දී ඔහු නැවතත් ඇතැන්ස් වෙත පැමිණ එහි දී ලයිසියම් නමින් තම අධ්‍යාපන ආයතනය පිහිටුවා ගනියි. ඊ ළඟ වසර දොළහක කාලයක් ඔහු එහි පාඨමාලා උගන්වයි. ප්ලේටෝගේ දර්ශනය එහි ඉගැන්වෙන අතර එය විවේචනයට ද භාජනය කෙරෙයි. එහි දී ඔහුගේ භාර්යාව වූ පිතියාස් මිය යන්නීය. ස්ටැජියිරා හි හර්ෆිලිස් නම් කාන්තාවක් හා සම්බන්ධකමක් ඇති කරගන්නා ඇරිස්ටෝටල් ලැබෙන පුත්‍රයා ඔවුන් නිකොමාකස් යැයි නම් කරති. ක්‍රි. පූ. 335 සිට 323 කාලය, ඇරිස්ටෝටල් සිය නිර්මාණ වැඩි ම ප්‍රමාණයක් බිහි කරන ලද කාලය සේ සැලකේ. ඔහු අතින් සම්පාදනය වූ වැදගත් ම කෘති ලෙසින් සැලකෙන්නේ භෞතික විද්‍යාව, පාර භෞතිකවිද්‍යාව, නිකොමාකියන් ආචාර ධර්ම, දේශපාලනය, ආත්මය ගැන සහ ගද්‍ය යන ඒවාය.ඇලෙක්සැන්ඩර්ගේ මරණයෙන් පසුව, ඇතැන්ස් හි නැවතත් මැසඩෝනියානුවන්ට එරෙහි හැඟීම් බහුලව පැතිර ගියේය. දෙවියන් නිසි ගරුත්වයෙන් සලකන්නේ නැතැයි ඇරිස්ටෝටල්ව දෝෂාරෝපණයට පත්විය. ඇතැන්ස් වලින් පැන ඇරිස්ටෝටල් ඔහුගේ මවගේ ඥාතීන්ට අයත් වූ නිවෙසක ජීවත් වෙන්නට යයි. දර්ශනයට එරෙහිව දෙවතාවක් පව් කරන්නට ඇතීනියානුවන්ට ඉඩක් ලබා නොදෙන බව ඇරිස්ටෝටල් කියන්නේ ඊට කළින් සිදු වූ සොක්‍රටීස්ට මරණය පැමිණ වූ අන්දම සිහි කරමිනි. ක්‍රි. පූ. 322 දී ඔහු ඉයුබෝයා හි ස්වභාවික මරණයකට ගොදුරු වෙයි. තම සිසුවෙක් වූ ඇන්පේටර් වෙත අන්තිම කැමති පත්‍රයකින් බලතල පවරන ඇරිස්ටෝටල් තමාව තම භාර්යාව අසලින් මිහිදන් කරන්න යැයි ලියැවිල්ලෙන් ඉල්ලීය."},{"question":"ਬਾੜਮੇਰ, 27 ਫਰਵਰੀਰਾਜਸਥਾਨ ਦੇ ਸਰਹੱਦੀ ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹੇ ਬਾੜਮੇਰ ਦੇ ਦੋ ਪਿੰਡਾਂ ਪੋਸ਼ਾਲ ਅਤੇ ਰਾਤਾਸਰ ’ਚ ਬੁੱਧਵਾਰ ਦੇਰ ਸ਼ਾਮ ਧਾਤ ਦੇ ਟੁਕੜੇ ਡਿੱਗਣ ਨਾਲ ਦਹਿਸ਼ਤ ਫੈਲ ਗਈ। ਕੁਝ ਲੋਕਾਂ ਨੇ ਧਮਾਕੇ ਦੀਆਂ ਆਵਾਜ਼ਾਂ ਸੁਣੇ ਜਾਣ ਦਾ ਦਾਅਵਾ ਵੀ ਕੀਤਾ। ਰੱਖਿਆ ਤਰਜਮਾਨ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਮਾਮਲੇ ਦੀ ਪੜਤਾਲ ਕੀਤੀ ਜਾ ਰਹੀ ਹੈ। ਬਾੜਮੇਰ ਜ਼ਿਲ੍ਹਾ ਕੁਲੈਕਟਰ ਹਿਮਾਂਸ਼ੂ ਗੁਪਤਾ ਨੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਪਿੰਡ ਵਾਸੀਆਂ ਮੁਤਾਬਕ ਧਾਤ ਦੇ ਟੁਕੜੇ ਜਹਾਜ਼ ਦੇ ਲੱਗਦੇ ਹਨ। ਉਨ੍ਹਾਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਏਜੰਸੀਆਂ ਤੋਂ ਸੂਚਨਾ ਮੁਹੱਈਆ ਕਰਵਾਏ ਜਾਣ ਤਕ ਕੁਝ ਵੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਿਹਾ ਜਾ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੈ। ਡੀਐਸਪੀ ਸੁਰੇਂਦਰ ਕੁਮਾਰ ਨੇ ਥਾਂ ਦਾ ਮੁਆਇਨਾ ਕਰਕੇ ਕਿਹਾ ਕਿ ਤਿੰਨ ਥਾਵਾਂ ਤੋਂ ਤਿੰਨ ਵੱਖ ਵੱਖ ਧਾਤਾਂ ਦੇ ਟੁਕੜੇ ਮਿਲੇ ਹਨ। ਬਾੜਮੇਰ ਦੇ ਐਸਪੀ ਰਾਸ਼ੀ ਡੋਗਰਾ ਡੂਡੀ ਨੇ ਦੱਸਿਆ ਕਿ ਇਸ ਘਟਨਾ ਬਾਰੇ ਸੁਰੱਖਿਆ ਏਜੰਸੀਆਂ ਨੂੰ ਇਤਲਾਹ ਦੇ ਦਿੱਤੀ ਗਈ ਅਤੇ ਪੁਲੀਸ ਦੀਆਂ ਟੀਮਾਂ ਮੌਕੇ ’ਤੇ ਭੇਜੀਆਂ ਗਈਆਂ ਹਨ।ਦੋ ਪਿੰਡਾਂ ਪੋਸ਼ਾਲ ਅਤੇ ਰਤਾਸਰ ਵਿੱਚ ਕੀ ਹੋਇਆ?","answer":"ਦੋ ਪਿੰਡਾਂ ਪੋਸ਼ਾਲ ਅਤੇ ਰਾਤਾਸਰ ’ਚ ਬੁੱਧਵਾਰ ਦੇਰ ਸ਼ਾਮ ਧਾਤ ਦੇ ਟੁਕੜੇ ਡਿੱਗਣ ਨਾਲ ਦਹਿਸ਼ਤ ਫੈਲ ਗਈ।"},{"question":"Menene yaren Jumhuriyar Larabawa ta Siriya?","answer":"Larabci ne Harshensu"},{"question":"Ẹyà àrà wò ni o wà fún irìràn?","answer":"Ojú "},{"question":"Tamin'ny taona firy no nitondra Radama I ?","answer":"Radama I dia mpanjaka nitondra tamin'ny taona 1810 sy 1828 teto Madagasikara."},{"question":"Ito ang iskor ng anim na mag-aaral sa HEKASI: 45, 50, 39, 34, 42, ___Kung 43 ang average na iskor ng anim, ano ang iskor ng huling mag-aaral?","answer":"48 ang iskor ng huling mag-aaral. Upang makuha ito, kuhanin ang total kung 43 ang iskor ng bawat estudyante, o 43 x 6 = 258. Kuhanin din ang total ng limang iskor na alam natin, o 45 + 50 + 39 + 34 + 42 = 210. Ibawas ang pangalawang total na nakuha natin mula sa nauna para makuha ang iskor ng huling mag-aaral. Kaya, ang iskor ay 258 - 210 = 48. "},{"question":"ለአንድ ሰዓት ያህል መዝናናት የምችልባቸውን 5 መንገዶች ስጠኝ","answer":"ጥቂት ሐሳቦች ከዚህ በታች ቀርበዋል1. ለእግር ጉዞ ሂድ ።2. ተኛ ።3. አንድ መጽሐፍ አንብብ ።4. ነትፍሊክስን ተመልከት ።5. ወዳጆችህን ደውልላቸው ።"},{"question":"Wọn yinbọn pa tọkọ-tiyawo mọle l’Ọta","answer":"Ipohunrere ẹkùn lo n lọ lọwọ bayii ninu ìle bàbá kan, Alagba Kẹ́hìndé Ibidunni ati iyawo ẹ, Elizabeth, tawọn agbebọn wọle wọn laago mẹ́ta oru Ọjọ́ Ìṣègùn, Tusidee, ọjọ kẹtadinlọgbọn, òṣu kẹrin yii, ti wọn si yinbọn pa wọn mọnu ile wọn l’Ọta.Ojúlé Kẹẹẹdogun,  Opopona Tẹlla Ojo, l’Atan Ọta, ipinlẹ Ogun,  lawọn tọkọ-taya yii n gbe. Olotẹẹli ni Ọgbẹni Ibidunni, iṣẹ́ to n ṣe niyẹn.Ṣadeede lawọn agbebọn kan bo ile náa loru ọjọ yii, oju irin ferese ti wọn n pe ni bọgilari (burgler proof) ni wọn gba wọle, bi wọn si ti n ba irin naa fa a ki wọn le raaye wọle ni ọmọbinrin kekere to n gbé pẹlu wọn wọle lọ lati sọ ohun to n ṣẹlẹ fun baba.Bi ọkunrin olotẹẹli naa ṣe jade si wọn lati mọ ohun to n ṣẹlẹ̀ ninu ile ẹ ni wọn yinbọn lu u láya, lọgangan ọkan rẹ, ẹsẹkẹsẹ lo ṣubú lulẹ to ku sinu agbara ẹ̀jẹ́. Bi wọn ṣe pa Kẹ́hìndé Ibidunni tan ni wọn mu iyawo é, Elizabeth.Wọn gun un lọbẹ, wọn si tun yinbọn fun un. Bi wọn ṣe ri i pe awọn mejeeji ti ku ni wọn sa lọ.Ọmọ awọn olóogbe yii to n jẹ Ọlayinka, fidi ẹ mulẹ pe awọn kan lo waa pa awọn obi oun. O ni wọn da gbogbogbo inu ile ru pelu, wọn si ko iwọnba owo ti wọ́n ba ninu ile naa lọ.Awọn oku mejeeji ti wa ni mọṣuari bi omọ wọn ti wi. Bi nnkan kan ko ba si yípadà ninu eto alakalẹ fun isinku, ọmọ naa sọ pe ọjọ Ẹti, Furaidee yii, lawọn yoo sinku awọn obi oun."},{"question":"મને સિદ્ધાર્થ DEY એક પ્રેરક વક્તા વિશે કહો.","answer":"સિદ્ધાર્થ DEY માર્કેટિંગ નિષ્ણાત અને પ્રેરક વક્તા છે જે વ્યવસાયોને તેમના માર્કેટિંગ લક્ષ્યો હાંસલ કરવામાં મદદ કરવાની તેમની ક્ષમતા માટે જાણીતા છે. તેઓ 'સિદ્ધાર્થ ડે માર્કેટિંગ એકેડેમી'ના સ્થાપક છે, જે ડિજિટલ માર્કેટિંગ અને સોશિયલ મીડિયા માર્કેટિંગ પર અભ્યાસક્રમો, વર્કશોપ અને સેમિનાર ઓફર કરે છે."},{"question":"Mene ma’anar ‘kugiya?","answer":"Yana nufin abinda ake sawa a dakko guga idan ta fada rijiya."},{"question":"Dame un ejemplo de trivia en está categoría : política. ","answer":"¿Cuántos países lucharon contra los EE. UU. en la Guerra del Golfo?. "},{"question":"બાજીરાવ મસ્તની ફિલ્મ સમીક્ષાઓ લખો .","answer":"બાજીરાવ મસ્તની ફિલ્મ સમીક્ષાઓબાજીરાવ મસ્તની બોલિવૂડની એક ઐતિહાસિક રોમાંટિક ફિલ્મ છે જે 2015 માં રિલીઝ થઈ હતી. આ ફિલ્મને વિવેદકો અને પ્રેક્ષકો બંને પાસેથી ખૂબ સારી સમીક્ષાઓ મળી હતી. ફિલ્મે ઘણા ખ્યાતનામ ઇનામો પણ જીત્યા હતા, જેમાં 12 ફિલ્મફેર એવોર્ડ્સનો સમાવેશ થાય છે.ફિલ્મ તેના શાનપૂર્ણ સંગીત, અદભૂત ફોટોગ્રાફી, શક્તિશાળી પાત્રો અને ઐતિહાસિક સાચવણીને કારણે પ્રશંસા મેળવી હતી. ફિલ્મના કલાકારોએ પણ તેમના અભિનય માટે ખૂબ પ્રશંસા મેળવી હતી, ખાસ કરીને શાહરૂખ ખાને તેમના પ્રદર્શન માટે.બાજીરાવ મસ્તની ભારતના ઇતિહાસમાંથી એક મહાન યુગની વાર્તા છે. તે પ્રેમ, સંઘર્ષ અને સ્વપ્નો વિશે વાત કરે છે. તે એક સાહસિક અને રોમાંચક ફિલ્મ છે જે દરેકને ગમશે."},{"question":"Sheeg Asxaabigii Ey Ka Xishoon Jirtay Malaa’iigta?","answer":"Wuxu Ahaa Cusmaan Bin Cafaan."},{"question":"Chọn đáp án đúng cho câu sau:Ảo ảnh trên sa mạc hay trên mặt đường nhựa xuất hiện các vũng nước khi thời tiết nắng nóng là kết quả của hiện tượng:A. Khúc xạ ánh sángB. Tán xạ ánh sángC. Phản xạ toàn phần","answer":"C. Phản xạ toàn phầnBình thường, không khí càng lên cao càng loãng, do đó chiết suất của không khí tăng dần theo chiều từ trên cao xuống mặt đất. Ánh sáng truyền từ trên xuống dưới bị khúc xạ với xu hướng góc khúc xạ giảm dần. Do đó, ảnh của Mặt trời, các ngôi sao trên bầu trời... mà ta quan sát được sẽ là ảnh ảo, cao hơn một chút so với vị trí thực tế của chúng.Sự khúc xạ này cũng làm cho hình ảnh của các ngôi sao mà ta quan sát được trên bầu trời dường như nhấp nháy (lấy lánh) do nhiễu loạn của không khí.Vào những ngày nắng nóng, mặt đường (nhất là đường nhựa) hấp thụ ánh sáng Mặt trời mạnh nên rất nóng. Lượng nhiệt này sau đó bức xạ trở lại làm nóng những lớp không khí trên mặt đường dẫn đến lớp không khí càng gần mặt đường càng bị giãn nở. Chiết suất của không khí giảm dần theo chiều từ trên cao xuống dưới.Vì vậy, tia sáng từ một vật thể ở xa như ôtô, cây cối, tòa nhà... khi truyền xuống phía dưới sẽ bị khúc xạ với góc khúc xạ có xu hướng tăng dần. Đến một lúc góc khúc xạ đạt giá trị giới hạn (xấp xỉ 90 độ), tia sáng sẽ không thể khúc xạ được nữa mà sẽ bị phản xạ trở lại phía trên (hiện tượng phản xạ toàn phần).Lớp không khí gây ra phản xạ toàn phần ở gần sát mặt đường, giống như một tấm gương phẳng. Do đó ngoài hình ảnh quan sát trực tiếp ôtô, cây cối, ngôi nhà... ta còn nhìn thấy ảnh ảo của chúng, ngược chiều, đối xứng qua lớp không khí gây ra phản xạ toàn phần.Ảnh này thường chỉ lờ mờ, lấp lánh như vũng nước trên mặt đường vì không khí sát mặt đường bị nhiễu loạn rất mạnh bởi các dòng khí đối lưu liên tục. Hiện tượng này cũng xảy ra tương tự ở trên sa mạc nóng bức, những vị trí nhô cao ở phía xa như các đồi cát... có thể cho ảnh ảo như vũng nước ở phía dưới. Khi đến gần ảnh ảo biến mất vì ta phải quan sát vật ở xa, để các góc tới và góc khúc xạ lớn, mới có thể xảy ra hiện tượng phản xạ toàn phần."},{"question":"Naijiria wa lara orilẹ-ede to n fun Singapore lounjẹ, to n fun wọn laṣọ, ki nnkan too yiwọ fun wa-Akintọla","answer":"Gbajugbaja nla nidii iṣẹ ofin, Amofin-Agba Akintọla Adeniyi ti sọ pe bo tilẹ jẹ pe Naijiria ko ti i si ni ipo to yẹ ko wa pẹlu ba a ṣe pe ọdun mọkanlelọgọta laipẹ yii, o ni sibẹ, o yẹ ka maa dupẹ ni nitori ki i ṣe pe o kuku bajẹ fun orileede wa patapata. O sọrọ naa ninu ifọrọ kan to ṣe pẹlu akọroyin ALAROYE lo ti sọrọ naaO sọ pe ‘‘Ti a ba ni ki a wo ọdun ti a ti gba ominira, paapaa lori boya ki a maa dunnu pe ọdun naa ti pẹ, oju meji ni a gbọdọ fi wo o, nitori ọrọ ọhun bii igba ti a ba sọ pe ohun to kọju si ẹnikan ni, ẹyin lo maa kọ si ẹlomi-in.‘‘Ni temi, o yẹ ka yọ, ka si dupẹ ibi ta a de loni-in, bo tilẹ jẹ pe a ko ti i delẹ ileri, a ṣi jinna sibẹ, ṣugbọn bibeli naa sọ pe ninu ohun gbogbo, a gbọdọ maa dupẹ fun Ọlọrun. Mo fẹ ka ranti pe awọn orilẹ-ede kan wa to jẹ pe wọn ṣẹṣe bọ loko ẹru ni, koda wọn ko ti i pe ọgbọn ọdun ti wọn bọ loko ẹru. Mi o fẹẹ maa daruko, bi wọn ti ṣe waa dagba to, sibẹ ko si ominira ọrọ aje fun wọn. Awa ti lọ sibẹ, a ri nnkan ti wọn n pe ni ominira ọrọ oṣelu ati ominira ọrọ aje. Awọn mejeeji yii ki i ṣe ọkan naa.‘‘Iru awa ti wọn bi ni ọdun diẹ ṣaaju ominira le maa sọ nigba ta a bẹrẹ ileewe lọdun 1966, nnkan ko ri bayii, titi digba ta a wọ yunifasiti, ṣugbọn ẹ ma jẹ ki a gbagbe pe ibi kan la ti n bọ.‘‘Ohun to baayan ninu jẹ ni pe ka ni awọn ologun ko ba gbajọba, ti wọn fi wa silẹ bi a ṣe n ba ijọba wa bọ ni apa Iwọ-Oorun, ijọba awọn Ọbafẹmi Awolọwọ, ti kaluku n ṣe ijọba ẹlẹkunjẹkun, awọn orilẹ-ede bii Singapore, South-Korea ni wọn iba jẹ akẹgbẹ fun ilẹ Yoruba. Ohun ibanujẹ lo jẹ nigba ti a lọ si orilẹ-ede South-Korea lọdun 2019, ti Aarẹ orilẹ-ede wọn ba wa sọrọ, iyẹn awa aṣoju orilẹ-ede lagbaye. Ninu ọrọ ẹ lo ti sọ itan ara wọn, njẹ ẹ le gbagbọ pe Naijiria wa lara orilẹ-ede to n fun wọn lounjẹ, to n fun wọn ni aṣọ, iyẹn aṣọ ti a ti wọku ni o.‘‘Orilẹ-ede yii wa lara awọn orilẹ-ede agbaye to maa n fi ounjẹ ati aṣọ ranṣẹ si wọn. Nigba naa lọhun-un, o lo buru fun awọn debii pe niṣe ni awọn obinrin awọn da yẹri eti wọn jọ, ti orilẹ-ede yẹn lọọ ta a lati fi ra ounjẹ.‘‘Loni-in, ẹ o le pe iru orilẹ-ede yẹn ni ilu to wa ninu ipo kẹta ninu idagbasoke, iyẹn ipo ti awa wa loni-in. Wọn ti lọ jinna-jinna, bẹẹ la ṣiwaju wọn gba ominira, koda a tun fun wọn ni ẹbun. Amunkun ẹru ẹ wọ, o ni oke lẹ n wo, ẹ o wo isalẹ. Awọn ologun ti wọn ja ijọba gba mọ awọn Awolọwọ lọwọ ni wọn ba nnkan jẹ, paapaa fun ilẹ Yoruba.‘‘Ni ti awa ọmọ kaaarọ-oo-jiire, ọpẹ lo yẹ ki awa maa du o, nitori ko sibi ti mi o ti i lọ ni gbogbo aye yii ti ọmọ eeyan n gbe. Ko wa sibi ti ẹ de ti ẹ o ti ni i ba ọmọ Yoruba. Ninu igbelewọn kan ti wọn ṣe ni ilu Houston, ni Texas, l’Amerika, wọn ni ti ẹ ba ri dokita alawọ dudu mẹjọ ni agbegbe yẹn, marun-un ninu wọn, ọmọ Yoruba ni. Eyi fidi ẹ mulẹ pe ninu ẹni to yẹ ki o maa dupẹ ni  iran Yoruba wa.‘‘Ohun to fun wa ni anfaani yẹn ni pe eto ẹkọ ti awọn Awolọwọ gbe wa ran awọn Yoruba lọwọ pupọ.  Nigba kan to rẹ mi ti mo lọọ gba itọju ni South Africa, nibi ti mo ti n duro de dokita to maa tọju mi, ni mo ba ri patako kan ti wọn kọ orukọ awọn dokita si loriṣiiriṣii, ninu orukọ mọkanlelogoji to wa lara patako, mẹtadinlogun ninu wọn, ọmọ Naijira ni wọn, ọmọ Yoruba ni mẹrindinlogun ninu awọn mẹtadinlogun yẹn, ẹni kan yooku, Osagie lo n jẹ, awọn ẹya kan ti wọn tun fara pẹ wa diẹ ni. Nnkan ti mo n sọ yii, igbesẹ awọn aṣaaju wa lori ọrọ ẹkọ ti wọn ti sare gbe lọwọ lo jẹ ki a maa wa nipo aṣaaju.‘‘Omi-in ti mo tun fẹẹ sọ ni ti Ọmọọba Ido-Ani, to ṣe ohun ti ẹnikan ko ṣeru ẹ ri lagbaye. O ṣiṣẹ abẹ fun alaboyun, o gbe oyun inu ẹ jade, o ṣiṣe abẹ fun ọmọ yẹn, lẹyin ẹ lo da a pada, ti ati ọmọ ati iya si wa laaye. Iwuri nla ni lagbaaye, bẹẹ ni Aare orilẹ-ede America nigba yen, Donald Trump, kan sara nla si i, bo tilẹ jẹ pe awa ta a ni ọmọ to ṣe gudugudu meje yii ko tiẹ ṣe bii pe a gbọ si ohun meriiri to ṣe yẹn.‘‘Gbogbo ẹ naa kọ lo bajẹ, awọn ologun naa gbiyanju nipa iṣẹ idagbasoke laarin ilu. Ẹ wo biriiji afara ẹlẹẹkẹta, iyẹn Third Mainland Bridge, awọn ni wọn ṣe e, gbogbo yunifasiti ta a ni yatọ sawọn to ti wa ki a too gba ominira, awọn ologun lo da wọn silẹ lasiko ti wọn fi wa nijọba. Ile ifọpo orilẹ-ede yii, yatọ si ẹyọ kan ti wọn ba nilẹ, awọn ni wọn kọ iyooku ta a ni, bi wọn ko tiẹ ṣiṣẹ mọ. Awọn naa ni wọn kọ ọ, awọn naa ni wọn ba a jẹ.Ọna onibeji ta a maa kọkọ ni, awọn ologun yii naa ni wọn ṣe wọn, ti a ba waa n sọ nipa ọrọ Naijria, ohun ti a fi maa maa dunnu wa, bo tilẹ jẹ pe ibi to yẹ ki a wa kọ la wa loni-in.”"},{"question":"ਜੇ ਜੁਗ ਚਾਰੇ ਆਰਜਾ ਹੋਰ ਦਸੂਣੀ ਹੋਇ ॥ ਨਵਾ ਖੰਡਾ ਵਿਚਿ ਜਾਣੀਐ ਨਾਲਿ ਚਲੈ ਸਭੁ ਕੋਇ ॥ਚੰਗਾ ਨਾਉ ਰਖਾਇ ਕੈ ਜਸੁ ਕੀਰਤਿ ਜਗਿ ਲੇਇ ॥ ਜੇ ਤਿਸੁ ਨਦਰਿ ਨ ਆਵਈ ਤ ਵਾਤ ਨ ਪੁਛੈ ਕੇ ॥ ਕੀਟਾ ਅੰਦਰਿ ਕੀਟੁ ਕਰਿ ਦੋਸੀ ਦੋਸੁ ਧਰੇ ॥ਨਾਨਕ ਨਿਰਗੁਣਿ ਗੁਣੁ ਕਰੇ ਗੁਣਵੰਤਿਆ ਗੁਣੁ ਦੇ ॥ ਤੇਹਾ ਕੋਇ ਨ ਸੁਝਈ ਜਿ ਤਿਸੁ ਗੁਣੁ ਕੋਇ ਕਰੇ ॥੭॥","answer":" ਜੇ ਕਿਸੇ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਦੀ ਉਮਰ ਚਾਰ ਜੁਗਾਂ ਜਿਤਨੀ ਹੋ ਜਾਏ, (ਨਿਰੀ ਇਤਨੀ ਹੀ ਨਹੀਂ, ਸਗੋਂ ਜੇ) ਇਸ ਤੋਂ ਭੀ ਦਸ ਗੁਣੀ ਹੋਰ (ਉਮਰ) ਹੋ ਜਾਏ, ਜੇ ਉਹ ਸਾਰੇ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਭੀ ਪਰਗਟ ਹੋ ਜਾਏ ਅਤੇ ਹਰੇਕ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਉਸ ਦੇ ਪਿੱਛੇ ਲੱਗ ਕੇ ਤੁਰੇ। ਜੇ ਉਹ ਚੰਗੀ ਨਾਮਵਰੀ ਖੱਟ ਕੇ ਸਾਰੇ ਸੰਸਾਰ ਵਿਚ ਸ਼ੋਭਾ ਭੀ ਪ੍ਰਾਪਤ ਕਰ ਲਏ, ਜੇਕਰ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਦੀ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਵਿਚ ਨਹੀਂ ਆ ਸਕਦਾ, ਤਾਂ ਉਹ ਉਸ ਬੰਦੇ ਵਰਗਾ ਹੈ ਜਿਸ ਦੀ ਕੋਈ ਖ਼ਬਰ ਭੀ ਨਹੀਂ ਪੁੱਛਦਾ (ਭਾਵ, ਇਤਨੀ ਮਾਣ ਵਡਿਆਈ ਵਾਲਾ ਹੁੰਦਿਆਂ ਭੀ ਅਸਲ ਵਿਚ ਨਿਆਸਰਾ ਹੀ ਹੈ) । (ਸਗੋਂ ਅਜਿਹਾ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਦੇ ਸਾਹਮਣੇ) ਇਕ ਮਮੂਲੀ ਜਿਹਾ ਕੀੜਾ ਹੈ (\\"ਖਸਮੈ ਨਦਰੀ ਕੀੜਾ ਆਵੈ\\"। ਆਸਾ ਮ: 1) ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਦੋਸੀ ਥਾਪ ਕੇ (ਉਸ ਉੱਤੇ ਨਾਮ ਨੂੰ ਭੁੱਲਣ ਦਾ) ਦੋਸ਼ ਲਾਉਂਦਾ ਹੈ।ਹੇ ਨਾਨਕ! ਉਹ ਅਕਾਲ ਪੁਰਖ ਗੁਣ-ਹੀਨ ਮਨੁੱਖ ਵਿੱਚ ਗੁਣ ਪੈਦਾ ਕਰ ਦੇਂਦਾ ਹੈ ਤੇ ਗੁਣੀ ਮਨੁੱਖਾਂ ਨੂੰ ਭੀ ਗੁਣ ਉਹੀ ਬਖ਼ਸ਼ਦਾ ਹੈ। ਇਹੋ ਜਿਹਾ ਕੋਈ ਹੋਰ ਨਹੀਂ ਦਿੱਸਦਾ, ਜੋ ਨਿਰਗੁਣ ਜੀਵ ਨੂੰ ਕੋਈ ਗੁਣ ਦੇ ਸਕਦਾ ਹੋਵੇ। (ਪ੍ਰਭੂ ਦੀ ਮਿਹਰ ਦੀ ਨਜ਼ਰ ਹੀ ਉਸ ਨੂੰ ਉੱਚਾ ਕਰ ਸਕਦੀ ਹੈ, ਲੰਮੀ ਉਮਰ ਤੇ ਜਗਤ ਦੀ ਸ਼ੋਭਾ ਸਹਾਇਤਾ ਨਹੀਂ ਕਰਦੀ) ।7।"},{"question":"Nhiều người nói dưa chuột đắng do tồn dư hóa chất và thuốc trừ sâu, đúng hay sai?","answer":"Dưa chuột có hàm lượng calo thấp, nhiều nước, vitamin, khoáng chất. Dưa chuột không chứa chất béo hoặc cholesterol, vỏ nhiều chất xơ giúp chống táo bón, bảo vệ đường ruột. Đây là loại quả có quanh năm, dễ trồng, dễ mua và có rất nhiều lợi ích cho sức khỏe, dùng ăn sống, làm salad, muối chua hoặc nộm, uống nước ép.Dưa chuột đắng không phải do tồn dư hóa chất mà là cơ chế tự bảo vệ của dưa chuột để tránh côn trùng xâm hại. Đây là chất nhựa đắng, thường ở phần đầu và đuôi dưa chuột. Chất nhựa này là cucurbitacin, được tiết ra với liều lượng nhỏ nên không gây hại. Bạn chỉ cần cắt đầu và đuôi, sau đó chà nhẹ theo hình vòng tròn để loại bỏ chất nhựa. Trường hợp cả quả dưa chuột bị đắng thì nên loại bỏ.Không nên quá lo lắng và hoang mang. Nếu vẫn cảm nhận được mùi vị của hóa chất như thuốc trừ sâu khi ăn thì bạn ăn sẽ bị ngộ độc.Ngoài ra, dưa chuột nhiều nước cũng không nên ăn nhiều gây khó tiêu, đi tiểu nhiều. Ăn dưa chuột nhiều dẫn tới dư thừa kali khiến đầy hơi, đau bụng. Người bị bệnh đường ruột, hệ tiêu hóa kém, mắc bệnh thận nên cân nhắc khi ăn."},{"question":"Quais são as consequências irreversíveis causadas pela crise climática em relação à biodiversidade e aos ecossistemas?","answer":"As consequências são a extinção de espécies e a redução ou perda irreversível de ecossistemas e seus serviços, incluindo ecossistemas de água doce, terrestres e oceânicos."},{"question":"Sheeg Nabigii laga soo saaray wadan Afrikaan ah?","answer":"Waa Nabi Muuse (C.S)."},{"question":"புதிர்:  உயிர் இல்லாத நீதிபதியிடம் ஒழுங்கான நியாயம் அது என்ன?","answer":"விடை: தராசு"},{"question":"පරිගණක පාදක තොරතුරු සැකසීම ගැන විස්තර කරන්න.","answer":"අත්යුරු ක්‍රමයේ අඩුපාඩු මඟහරවා ගනිමින් තොරකුරු හා සන්නිවේදනයේ දියුණුවත් සමඟ පරිගණක පාදක තොරතුරු පද්ධති නිර්මානය විය. මින් ලැබී ඇති ප්‍රයෝජන ලෙස,හදිසි විකාශන සංඥාඅනතුරු ඇඟවීමේ පද්ධතිඅහිතකර විකිරණ සහිත පරිසරවල, අව්‍යවකාශයේ පරීක්ෂණ කටයුතු කිරීමආදීය හැඳින්විය හැකිය."},{"question":"ஆங்கிலேய கிழக்கிந்திய குழுமத்திற்கு சூரத்தில் வணிகமையம் அமைக்க அனுமதியளித்த முகலாய மன்னர் யாரஂ? \\t1. ஹுமாயூன்2. ஔரங்கசீப்3. ஜஹாங்கீர்4. ஷாஜஹான்","answer":"3. ஜஹாங்கீர்"},{"question":"Inona avy ireo fepetra takiana amin’ny olona hanao fati-dra?","answer":"Ireot avy ny fepetra takiana amin’ny olona hanao fati-dra:- Olona roa tsy mpihavana ara-pianahana sy ara-panambadina. - Mpinamana roa vonona hifanao soa mandrakizay.- Tsy maintsy mitovitovy ny fari-piainan’ny roa tonta."},{"question":"முதலில் இரவு வரும் (சிறுகதைத் தொகுப்பு) எனும் நூலை இயற்றியவர் யார்?    ","answer":"விடை : முதலில் இரவு வரும் (சிறுகதைத் தொகுப்பு) எனும் நூலை இயற்றியவர் ஆதவன். இவர் இந்தியாவின் தமிழ்நாட்டைச் சேர்ந்த ஒரு தமிழ் எழுத்தாளராவார். இவரது இயற்பெயர் கே.எசு.சுந்தரம் ஆகும். 1942 ஆம் ஆண்டு மார்ச்சு மாதம் இருபத்து ஒன்று ஆம் நாள் இவர் பிறந்தார். அறுபதுகளில் எழுதத் துவங்கி, தமிழ்ச் சிறுகதை உலகில் பல குறிப்பிடத் தக்க சாதனைகளை நிகழ்த்தினார். முதலில் இரவு வரும் என்ற சிறுகதை நூலுக்கு 1987 ஆம் ஆண்டு சாகித்ய அகாடமி விருது ஆதவனுக்கு வழங்கப்பட்டது"},{"question":"ما هي أقصر سورة في القرآن الكريم ؟","answer":"\\tسورة الكوثر"},{"question":"Apakah maksud \\"bagai beban sudah ke tepi\\"? Berikan satu contoh ayat bagi peribahasa tersebut. ","answer":"Ia bermaksud masalah hampir selesai. Contoh ayat: Natrah berasa lega apabila masalah itu ibarat beban sudah di tepi."},{"question":"السؤال: ما السورة التي بُدأت بكلمة (سورة) ؟","answer":"الإجابة : النور"},{"question":"Quais não são planetas anões trans-Netuno?","answer":"Os principais planetas anões trans-Netuno são Plutão, Haumea, Makemake e Eris. Ganimedes é uma das luas de Júpiter, o maior planeta do Sistema Solar. Embora seja uma lua de um planeta, é maior que Mercúrio."},{"question":"ෆෝමියුලා වන් තරඟයකට සහභාගි වූ ලාබාලතම ක්‍රීඩකයා  කවුද?","answer":"බෙල්ජියන් - නෙදර්ලන්ත ජාතික මැක්ස් ව'ස්ටැපන්(Max Verstappen)  ෆෝමියුලා වන් ධාවන තරඟයකට තරඟ කළ ලාබාලතම ධාවකයා  ලෙස වාර්තාව තබා  ඇත. ඔහු වයස අවුරුදු 17 යි දින 166 දී 2015 හි ඕස්ට්‍රේලියානු ග්‍රෑන්ඩ් ප්‍රීක්ස්හිදී Scuderia Toro Rosso කණ්ඩායමට රිය පැදවීය. ෆෝමියුලා වන් වෙත මෙම වාර්තාගත ප්‍රවේශය වර්ස්ටැපන් සිය වෘත්තීය දිවියේ ආරම්භයේ සිටම ක්‍රීඩාවේ කැපී පෙනෙන චරිතයක් බවට පත් කළේය. මෙතරම් තරුණ වියේදී ඔහු ෆෝමියුලා වන් වෙත පිවිසීම, ෆෝමියුලා වන් හි පාලන අධිකාරිය වන FIA වෙත, රියදුරන්ට අවම වශයෙන් අවුරුදු 18ක් විය යුතු අතර ෆෝමියුලා වන් තරඟාවලියට තරඟ කිරීමට සුදුසුකම් ලැබීමට පෙර යම් පළපුරුද්ද නිර්ණායක සපුරාලීමට අවශ්‍ය වන නව රීතියක් ක්‍රියාත්මක කිරීමට හේතු විය."},{"question":"Riassume il seguente: Offri a te stesso qualcosa di speciale e forse anche un po' decadente la mattina del tuo compleanno. Anche se devi andare al lavoro, passa un po' di tempo in più a prepararti qualcosa di speciale, come un toast. Se avete fatto i preparativi la sera prima, dovrebbe essere facile preparare il piatto in fretta. Anche se sei solo un tipo di toast-e-caffè-in-la-matina, si tratta di una birra migliore di quello che si beve normalmente al mattino. La maggior parte della vostra giornata dovrebbe essere una fuga dalla normale routine della vostra vita. Nel tentativo di sfruttare al meglio il tuo compleanno, considera di trovare il modo di uscire per goderti la fuga che la natura può offrire. L'esercizio fisico e l'aria fresca possono aiutarvi a ringiovanirvi, e possono darvi la possibilità di riflettere sul vostro anno. Prendete in considerazione di fare una corsa in città o di percorrere un sentiero naturalistico vicino, o anche di fare un'escursione più lunga. Sicuramente vi divertirete lungo il vostro sentiero o sentiero preferito, ma pensate a esplorare nuovi territori, se possibile. Potreste anche andare a fare un giro in bicicletta o semplicemente a fare una passeggiata in città. Se non possiedi una bicicletta e vivi in città, cerca di scoprire se ci sono dei programmi di bicicletta condivisa nelle tue vicinanze, che stanno diventando sempre più comuni e che offrono un modo economico per visitare i siti. Qual è il tuo appuntamento dei sogni? Una serata accogliente passata sul divano a guardare vecchi film e a mangiare il tuo piatto preferito? Un pomeriggio tranquillo trascorso al museo? A fare shopping tutto il giorno? Una cena al miglior ristorante della citta'? Il tuo compleanno da solista dovrebbe essere quello in cui fai esattamente quello che vuoi fare, quindi se decidi di stare a casa o di uscire, assicurati di scegliere un'attività divertente o rilassante di qualche tipo. Poiché la giornata è completamente vostra, non dovete preoccuparvi di soddisfare i gusti o le preferenze di qualcun altro! Una delle cose migliori del tuo compleanno e' che puoi decidere cosa ci sara' sul menu' per i tuoi pasti. Ovviamente, è così che dovrebbe essere, ma se festeggiamo con altre persone, potremmo sentirci costretti a adattare le selezioni alle altre persone a tavola. Se festeggi da solo, però, hai il controllo assoluto! Se vuoi mangiare la torta di compleanno e nient'altro per cena, allora nessuno ti fermerà! Se vi piace trascorrere del tempo in cucina, provate a gustare classici come le patate dolci e il pane arrosto. Potresti anche registrare in anticipo uno dei tuoi programmi di cucina preferiti e provare una nuova ricetta; cucina insieme all'ospite e ti sembrerà una festa (specialmente se cucini con un bicchiere di vino!). Se non avete voglia di cucinare o non avete tempo, potete ordinare o andare al vostro ristorante preferito. Assicurati di ordinare qualcosa che vuoi e goditi! Oggi si tratta solo di te! Nessuna festa di compleanno e' completa senza una specie di regalo. Se non volete essere tentati dall'avere un'intera torta di compleanno sul bancone per tutta la settimana, fermatevi in una pasticceria locale e comprate una o due cupcake decadenti. Puoi anche fargli mettere \\"Buon compleanno\\" in glassa sopra. Se vi piace la cottura, gustate un dessert fatto da zero, come la torta al formaggio o la torta di albicocche. Se preferisci uscire e prendere un dessert, puoi farlo! Se anche tu vai a cena fuori, considera la possibilità di scegliere un posto con un ottimo menu di dessert (non essere timido nel far sapere al cameriere che è il tuo compleanno - potresti ricevere il dessert a casa), ma potrebbe essere divertente andare da un'altra parte per il dessert e il caffè o il vino. Se non ti piacciono i dolci, allora scegli un piatto di formaggio con un ottimo abbinamento di vino, o qualsiasi cosa che consideri un piacere che non mangi tutti i giorni. Se festeggi il tuo compleanno da solo perché sei fisicamente separato dai tuoi amici e dalla tua famiglia, questo sarebbe un ottimo momento per fare FaceTime o Skype con loro. Metti una candela sul tuo dessert e lascia che qualcun altro ti canti \\"Tanti auguri\\". Mentre il tuo compleanno da solista finisce, trova un modo per rilassarti e coccolare un po' di piu'. Prendete una doccia bollente o fate un lungo tuffo nella vasca. Pensate di comprare un nuovo paio di pigiami super morbidi e rilassanti come uno dei vostri regali a voi stessi. Speriamo che oggi sia stato uno dei tuoi migliori compleanni!  ","answer":"Riassunto: Fai una colazione speciale. Sii il tuo compagno. Mangiate quello che volete per cena. Selezionate una prelibatezza speciale come dessert. Rilassati e rilassati prima di andare a letto."},{"question":"Fakir dini anlamda ne demek?","answer":"Bu konuda farklı görüşler olsa da genel olarak nisab miktarı malı olmayan ve aslî ihtiyaçlarını karşılayamayan kimselere fakir, hiç malı olmayan ve dilenmek zorunda kalan kimselere de miskin denileceği ifade edilmiştir."}]`),B={name:"App",components:{PoemCard:x},data(){return{searchQuery:"",visibleCount:6,poemsData:M,isLoading:!1}},computed:{filteredPoems(){return this.searchQuery.trim()?this.poemsData.filter(e=>{const a=this.searchQuery.toLowerCase();return e.question.toLowerCase().includes(a)||e.answer.toLowerCase().includes(a)}).slice(0,this.visibleCount):this.poemsData.slice(0,this.visibleCount)},hasMorePoems(){return this.visibleCount<this.poemsData.length}},methods:{async loadMore(){this.isLoading=!0,await new Promise(e=>setTimeout(e,1e3)),this.visibleCount+=6,this.isLoading=!1}}},I={class:"search-container"},C={class:"card-container"},D=["disabled"],O={key:0},L={key:1};function K(e,a,s,m,t,u){const d=b("PoemCard");return i(),o("section",null,[a[3]||(a[3]=n("div",{class:"top-banner"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title"},[n("div",{class:"top-banner-title-text"},"🤔 AI effective tips collection 🧠")])],-1)),n("div",I,[a[2]||(a[2]=n("span",{class:"search-icon"},null,-1)),y(n("input",{type:"text",class:"search-input","onUpdate:modelValue":a[0]||(a[0]=r=>t.searchQuery=r),placeholder:"Search..."},null,512),[[w,t.searchQuery]])]),n("div",C,[(i(!0),o(c,null,p(u.filteredPoems,(r,g)=>(i(),f(d,{key:g,poem:r},null,8,["poem"]))),128))]),u.hasMorePoems?(i(),o("button",{key:0,class:"load-more-button",disabled:t.isLoading,onClick:a[1]||(a[1]=(...r)=>u.loadMore&&u.loadMore(...r))},[t.isLoading?(i(),o("span",L,"Loading...")):(i(),o("span",O,"See more"))],8,D)):j("",!0)])}const P=k(B,[["render",K],["__scopeId","data-v-4770b3ca"]]),R=JSON.parse('{"title":"","description":"","frontmatter":{"page":true},"headers":[],"relativePath":"chatai/25.md","filePath":"chatai/25.md"}'),E={name:"chatai/25.md"},F=Object.assign(E,{setup(e){return(a,s)=>(i(),o("div",null,[v(P)]))}});export{R as __pageData,F as default};
